<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in Hallucinogen-associated Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations in California from 2016-2021
Authors: Tate, S.; Garel, N.; Nash, K.; Lembke, A.
Score: 54.0, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294275
ObjectivesHallucinogens encompass a diverse range of compounds with increasing scientific and public interest. Risks associated with hallucinogen use are poorly understood. This study aims to evaluate the trends in hallucinogen-related emergency department visits and hospitalizations in California from 2016 to 2021, as compared to alcohol and cannabis visits and hospitalizations MethodsWe conducted a descriptive study on publicly available data on diagnosis codes associated with emergency department (ED) visits and hospitalizations from the California Department of Healthcare Access and Information (HCAI) to describe hallucinogen, alcohol, and cannabis associated encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 325.7, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 127.0, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been restricted to social or object interaction. Here we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel. We demonstrate that flies exhibit idiosyncratic carousel interactions that qualify as play-like behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>The resting state of the human T-cell receptor
Authors: Notti, R. Q.; Yi, F.; Heissel, S.; Molina, H.; Klebanoff, C. A.; Walz, T.
Score: 35.5, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554360
The T-cell receptor (TCR) is central to the ligand-dependent activation of T lymphocytes and as such orchestrates both adaptive and pathologic immune processes1. However, major questions remain regarding the structure and function of the human TCR2-4. Here, we present cryogenic electron microscopy structures for the unliganded human TCR in a native-like lipid bilayer, revealing three related conformations that are distinct from previously reported structures of receptors in detergent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Reengineering of a flavin-binding fluorescent protein using ProteinMPNN
Authors: Nikolaev, A.; Kuzmin, A.; Markeeva, E.; Kuznetsova, E.; Semenov, O.; Anuchina, A.; Remeeva, A.; Gushchin, I.
Score: 18.7, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554855
Recent advances in machine learning techniques have led to development of a number of protein design and engineering approaches. One of them, ProteinMPNN, predicts an amino acid sequence that would fold and match user-defined backbone structure. In this short report, we test whether ProteinMPNN can be used to reengineer a flavin-binding fluorescent protein, CagFbFP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>SSDraw: software for generating comparative protein secondary structure diagrams
Authors: Chen, E. A.; Porter, L. L.
Score: 53.5, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554905
The program SSDraw generates publication-quality protein secondary structure diagrams from three-dimensional protein structures. To depict relationships between secondary structure and other protein features, diagrams can be colored by conservation score, B-factor, or custom scoring. Diagrams of homologous proteins can be registered according to an input multiple sequence alignment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Deep reconstructing generative networks for visualizing dynamic biomolecules inside cells
Authors: Rangan, R.; Khavnekar, S.; Lerer, A.; Johnston, J.; Kelley, R.; Obr, M.; Kotecha, A.; Zhong, E. D.
Score: 142.5, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553799
Advances in cryo-electron tomography (cryo-ET) have produced new opportunities to visualize the structures of dynamic macromolecular machinery in native cellular environments. Here, we describe a machine learning approach that can reconstruct the structural landscape and dynamics of biomolecular complexes present in cryo-ET subtomograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>KRAS allelic imbalance drives tumour initiation yet suppresses metastasis in colorectal cancer in vivo
Authors: Najumudeen, A. K.; Fey, S. K.; Millet, L. M.; Ford, C. A.; Gilroy, K.; Gunduz, N.; Ridgway, R. A.; Anderson, E.; Strathdee, D.; Clark, W.; Nixon, C.; Morton, J. P.; Campbell, A. D.; Sansom, O. J.
Score: 18.1, Published: 2023-08-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.555396
Oncogenic KRAS mutations are well-described functionally and are known to drive tumorigenesis. Recent reports describe a significant prevalence of KRAS allelic imbalances or gene dosage changes in human cancers, including loss of the wild-type allele in KRAS mutant cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Determinants of Bluetooth-enabled Self Measured Blood Pressure Monitoring in Federally Qualified Health Centers
Authors: Hellem, A.; Whitfield, C.; Mansour, M.; Curran, Y.; Dinh, M.; Warden, K.; Skolarus, L. E.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294249
BackgroundIn 2021, the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) launched the National Hypertension Control Initiative (HTN Initiative) with the goal to enhance HTN control through Bluetooth-enabled self-measured blood pressure (BT SMBP) monitoring and use this data to inform clinical decisions in Federally Qualified Health Centers (FQHCs) with large proportion of their population with uncontrolled BP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Lineage tracing of newly accrued nuclei in skeletal myofibers uncovers distinct transcripts and interplay between nuclear populations
Authors: Sun, C.; Swoboda, C.; Petrany, M.; Parameswaran, S.; VonHandorf, A.; Weirauch, M. T.; Lepper, C.; Millay, D.
Score: 24.7, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.554609
Multinucleated skeletal muscle cells have an obligatory need to acquire additional nuclei through fusion with activated skeletal muscle stem cells when responding to both developmental and adaptive growth stimuli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Morphodynamics of human early brain organoid development
Authors: Jain, A.; Gut, G.; Sanchis Calleja, F.; Okamoto, R.; Streib, S.; He, Z.; Zenk, F.; Santel, M.; Seimiya, M.; Holtackers, R.; Jansen, S. M. J.; Camp, J. G.; Treutlein, B.
Score: 75.4, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.553827
Brain organoids enable the mechanistic study of human brain development, and provide opportunities to explore self-organization in unconstrained developmental systems. Here, we establish long-term, live light sheet microscopy on unguided brain organoids generated from fluorescently labeled human induced pluripotent stem cells, which enables tracking of tissue morphology, cell behaviors, and subcellular features over weeks of organoid development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Metagenomic analysis of individual mosquitos reveals the ecology of insect viruses
Authors: Pan, Y.-f.; Zhao, H.; Gou, Q.-y.; Shi, P.-b.; Tian, J.-h.; Feng, Y.; Li, K.; Yang, W.-h.; Wu, D.; Tang, G.; Zhang, B.; Ren, Z.; Peng, S.; Luo, G.-y.; Le, S.-j.; Xin, G.-y.; Wang, J.; Hou, X.; Peng, M.-w.; Kong, J.-b.; Chen, X.-x.; Yang, C.-h.; Mei, S.-q.; Liao, Y.-q.; Cheng, J.-x.; Wang, J.; n/a, C.; Wu, Y.-h.; Wang, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Attacks on Ukrainian healthcare facilities during the first year of the full-scale Russian invasion of Ukraine
Authors: Barten, D.; Tin, D.; Granholm, F.; Rusnak, D.; van Osch, F.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 7.5, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294763
BackgroundAlthough the Geneva Conventions and Rome Statute demand protections for healthcare facilities during war, breaches of these protections are frequently reported. The ongoing war in Ukraine is no exception, with several healthcare attacks eliciting widespread condemnation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>3D genomic features across &amp;gt;50 diverse cell types reveal insights into the genomic architecture of childhood obesity
Authors: Trang, K. B.; Pahl, M. C.; Pippin, J. A.; Su, C.; Littleton, S. H.; Sharma, P.; Kulkarni, N. N.; Ghanem, L. R.; Terry, N. A.; O&amp;#39;Brien, J. M.; Wagley, Y.; Hankenson, K. D.; Jermusyk, A.; Hoskins, J. W.; Amundadottir, L. T.; Xu, M.; Brown, K. M.; Anderson, S. A.; Yang, W.; Titchenell, P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected during a SARS-CoV-2 Omicron wave - Australia, 2022
Authors: Woldegiorgis, M.; Cadby, G.; Ngeh, S.; Korda, R.; Armstrong, P.; Maticevic, J.; Knight, P.; Jardine, A.; Bloomfield, L.; Effler, P.
Score: 2370.5, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293706
ObjectiveTo characterise Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected by Omicron. DesignFollow-up survey of persons testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 in Western Australia, 16 July-3 August 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evo-devo dynamics of hominin brain size
Authors: Gonzalez-Forero, M.
Score: 33.4, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.20.533421
Brain size tripled in the human lineage over four million years, but why this occurred remains uncertain. To advance our understanding of what caused hominin-brain expansion, I mechanistically replicate it in-silico by modelling the evolutionary and developmental (evo-devo) dynamics of hominin-brain size. I show that, starting from australop-ithecine brain and body sizes, the model recovers the evolution of brain and body sizes of seven hominin species, the evolution of the hominin brain-body allometry, and major patterns of human development and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Utility of EsoGuard as a Triage Test for Endoscopy to Identify Barrett&amp;#39;s Esophagus in Fire Fighters
Authors: Hamblin, R.; Lee, V. T.; deGuzman, B. J.; Verma, S.; Aklog, L.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294176
BackgroundFirefighters have frequent exposure to smoke and compounds that have been shown to increase the risk of developing esophageal neoplasia. EsoGuard(R) is a DNA biomarker assay that can be utilized with efficiency and high tolerability as a triage test in the diagnosis of patients with Barretts Esophagus (BE) and/or esophageal adenocarcinoma (EAC) in this population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Investigating misclassification of type 1 diabetes in a population-based cohort of British Pakistanis and Bangladeshis using polygenic risk scores
Authors: Liu, T.; Sankareswaran, A.; Paterson, G.; Genes &amp;amp; Health Research Team, ; Fraser, D. P.; Hodgson, S.; Huang, Q. Q.; Heng, T. H.; Ladwa, M.; Thomas, N.; van Heel, D. A.; Weedon, M. N.; Yajnik, C. S.; Oram, R. A.; Chandak, G. R.; Martin, H. C.; Finer, S.
Score: 23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Ancient farmer and steppe pastoralist-related founding lineages contributed to the complex landscape of episodes in the diversification of Chinese paternal lineages
Authors: Wang, M.; Huang, Y.; Liu, K.; Yuan, H.; Duan, S.; Wang, Z.; Wei, L.; Yao, H.; Sun, Q.; Zhong, J.; Tang, R.; Chen, J.; Sun, Y.; Li, X.; Su, H.; Yang, Q.; Hu, L.; Yun, L.; Yang, J.; Nie, S.; Cai, Y.; Yan, J.; Zhou, K.; 10K_CPGDP Consortium, ; Wang, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Predicting RNA-seq coverage from DNA sequence as a unifying model of gene regulation
Authors: Linder, J.; Srivastava, D.; Yuan, H.; Agarwal, V.; Kelley, D. R.
Score: 77.3, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.555582
Sequence-based machine learning models trained on genome-scale biochemical assays improve our ability to interpret genetic variants by providing functional predictions describing their impact on the cis-regulatory code. Here, we introduce a new model, Borzoi, which learns to predict cell- and tissue-specific RNA-seq coverage from DNA sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>RCT-based Social Return on Investment (SROI) of a home exercise programme for people with early dementia comparing in-person and blended delivery before and during the COVID-19 pandemic
Authors: Doungsong, K.; Hartfiel, N.; Gladman, J.; Harwood, R. H.; Edwards, R. T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294408
BackgroundRegular exercise and community engagement may slow the rate of function loss for people with dementia. However, the evidence is uncertain regarding the cost-effectiveness and social return on investment (SROI) of home exercise with community referral for people with dementia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Subtyping Social Determinants of Health in All of Us: Network Analysis and Visualization Approach
Authors: Bhavnani, S. K.; Zhang, W.; Bao, D.; Raji, M.; Ajewole, V.; Hunter, R.; Kuo, Y.-f.; Schmidt, S.; Pappadis, M.; Bokov, A.; Reistetter, T.; Visweswaran, S.; Downer, B.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.01.27.23285125
A.BackgroundSocial determinants of health (SDoH), such as financial resources and housing stability, account for between 30-55% of peoples health outcomes. While many studies have identified strong associations among specific SDoH and health outcomes, most people experience multiple SDoH that impact their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The Effects of Development Assistance on Sexual and Reproductive Health Services in Low- and Middle-Income Countries: A Cross-Country Panel Data Analysis
Authors: Ekman, B.; Sundewall, J.; Schmit, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294532
Using data on 119 low- and lower-middle income countries from 2002 to 2020, we apply fixed-effects (FE) methods to evaluate the impacts of three different classifications of development assistance on access to three types of sexual and reproductive health (SRH) services: access to skilled birth attendance, prevalence of modern contraceptives, and coverage of antiretroviral therapies against HIV/AIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>ACCORD (ACcurate COnsensus Reporting Document): A reporting guideline for consensus methods in biomedicine developed via a modified Delphi
Authors: Gattrell, W. T.; Logullo, P.; van Zuuren, E. J.; Price, A.; Hughes, E. L.; Blazey, P.; Winchester, C. C.; Tovey, D.; Goldman, K.; Hungin, A. P.; Harrison, N.
Score: 10.5, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294261
BackgroundIn biomedical research, it is often desirable to seek consensus among individuals who have differing perspectives and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Clinical pattern and diagnostic of comorbidity of respiratory tuberculosis and viral pneumonia caused by Herpesvirus Simplex, Human Cytomegalovirus and SARS-CoV-2 in patients with late-stage HIV infection with immunodeficiency
Authors: Mishin, V. Y.; Mishina, A. V.; Shashenkov, I. V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294716
Aim. To study features of social status, clinical pattern and diagnosis in cases of comorbidity of respiratory tuberculosis and viral pneumonia caused by Herpesvirus Simplex of type 1, Human Cytomegalovirus and SARS-CoV-2 in patients with late-stage HIV infection with immunodeficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 Spike Protein COVID-19 Vaccine Induces Broadly Neutralizing and Cellular Immune Responses Against EG.5.1 and Emerging XBB Variants
Authors: Patel, N.; Trost, J. F.; Guebre-Xabier, M.; Zhou, H.; Norton, J.; Jiang, D.; Cai, Z.; Zhu, M.; Marchese, A. M.; Greene, A. M.; Mallory, R. M.; Kalkeri, R.; Dubovsky, F.; Smith, G.
Score: 156.1, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.554497
Monovalent SARS-CoV-2 Prototype (Wuhan-Hu-1) and bivalent (Prototype &amp;#43; BA.4/5) COVID-19 vaccines have demonstrated a waning of vaccine-mediated immunity highlighted by lower neutralizing antibody responses against SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB sub-variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 650.9, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Characterization of an EG.5.1 clinical isolate in vitro and in vivo
Authors: Uraki, R.; Kiso, M.; Iwatsuki-Horimoto, K.; Yamayoshi, S.; Ito, M.; Chiba, S.; Sakai-Tagawa, Y.; Imai, M.; Kashima, Y.; Koga, M.; Fuwa, N.; Okumura, N.; Hojo, M.; Iwamoto, N.; Kato, H.; Nakajima, H.; Ohmagari, N.; Yotsuyanagi, H.; Suzuki, Y.; Kawaoka, Y.
Score: 52.3, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555819
EG.5.1 is a subvariant of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB variant that is rapidly increasing in prevalence worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dysregulation of extracellular vesicle protein cargo in female ME/CFS cases and sedentary controls in response to maximal exercise
Authors: Giloteaux, L.; Glass, K. A.; Germain, A.; Zhang, S.; Hanson, M. R.
Score: 84.9, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.28.555033
In healthy individuals, physical exercise improves cardiovascular health and muscle strength, alleviates fatigue, and reduces risk of chronic diseases. Although exercise is suggested as a lifestyle intervention to manage various chronic illnesses, it negatively affects people with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), who suffer from exercise intolerance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Digital cognitive test performance and relationship to plasma biomarkers in Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Toniolo, S.; Zhao, S.; Scholcz, A.; Amein, B.; Ganse-Dumrath, A.; Heslegrave, A.; Thompson, S.; Manohar, S. G.; Zetterberg, H.; Husain, M.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.23293786
A major limitation in current Alzheimers disease (AD) research is the lack of the ability to measure cognitive performance at scale--robustly, remotely, and frequently. For the purposes of screening, recruitment, stratification, and longitudinal follow-up in clinical trials, there are no established online digital platforms validated against plasma biomarkers of AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Spike amyloid fibrils specifically and selectively accelerates amyloid fibril formation of human prion protein and the amyloid β peptide
Authors: Larsson, J. N.; Hellstrand, E.; Hammarström, P.; Nyström, S.
Score: 546.5, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555834
An increasing number of reports suggest an association between COVID-19 infection and initiation or acceleration of neurodegenerative diseases including Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease (AD) and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease (CJD). Both these diseases and several other neurodegenerative diseases are caused by conversion of human proteins into a misfolded, aggregated amyloid fibril state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Wastewater-based surveillance is an efficient monitoring tool for tracking influenza A virus in the community
Authors: Lehto, K.-M.; Hyder, R.; Länsivaara, A.; Luomala, O.; Lipponen, A.; Hokajärvi, A.-M.; Heikinheimo, A.; Pitkänen, T.; Oikarinen, S.; WastPan Study Group, Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.28.23294723
Around the world, influenza A virus has caused severe pandemics, and the risk of future pandemics remains high. Currently, influenza A virus surveillance is based on the clinical diagnosis and reporting of disease cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Genomic Profiling to Contextualize the Results of Intervention for High-Risk Smoldering Myeloma
Authors: Kazandjian, D.; Diamond, B.; Papadimitriou, M.; Hill, E.; Sklavenitis-Pistofidis, R.; Ziccheddu, B.; Blaney, P.; Chojnacka, M.; Durante, M.; Maclachlan, K.; Young, R.; Usmani, S.; Davies, F.; Getz, G.; Ghobrial, I.; Korde, N.; Morgan, G.; Maura, F.; Landgren, O.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294483
Early intervention for High-Risk Smoldering Multiple Myeloma (HR-SMM) achieves deeper and more prolonged responses compared to Newly Diagnosed (ND) MM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Forensic Facial Approximation of Achondroplastic Dwarf from Medieval Cemetery in Central Europe
Authors: Moraes, C.; Krenz-Niedbała, M.; Łukasik, S.; Prada, C. S.
Score: 45.5, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.26.553833
Achondroplasia (ACH, achondroplastic dwarfism) represents the most common form of skeletal dysplasia, occurring in c. 4 out of every 100,000 births. This study presents a computer-based facial approximation of the skull of a male individual suffering from ACH, who died at 30-45 years of age and was buried in ekno, Poland between the 9th and 11th centuries AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Absence of Lipopolysccharide (LPS) expression in Breast Cancer Cells
Authors: de Miranda, N. F.; Smit, V. T.; van der Ploeg, M.; Wesseling, J.; Neefjes, J.
Score: 44.6, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.28.555057
The association between bacterial activity and tumorigenesis has gained attention in recent years, alongside the well-established link between viruses and cancer. A recent study proposed the presence of intracellular bacteria in cancer cells, particularly in melanomas and breast cancers, with detectable bacterial DNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Pediatric and Adult Patients with ME/CFS following COVID-19: A Structured Approach to Diagnosis Using the Munich Berlin Symptom Questionnaire (MBSQ)
Authors: Peo, L. C.; Wiehler, K.; Paulick, J.; Gerrer, K.; Leone, A.; Viereck, A.; Haegele, M.; Stojanov, S.; Warlitz, C.; Augustin, S.; Alberer, M.; Hattesohl, D. R. B.; Froehlich, L.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Mihatsch, L. L.; Pricoco, R.; Behrends, U.
Score: 7.6, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.23293081
PurposeA subset of patients with post-COVID-19 condition (PCC) fulfill the clinical criteria of myalgic encephalomyelitis / chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Psilocybin desynchronizes brain networks
Authors: Siegel, J. S.; Subramanian, S.; Perry, D. A.; Kay, B. P.; Gordon, E. M.; Laumann, T. O.; Chacko, R. V.; Reneau, T. R.; Metcalf, N. V.; Horan, C.; Schweiger, J. A.; Wong, D.; Bender, D.; Padawer-Curry, J.; Raison, C. L.; Carhart-Harris, R.; Raichle, M. E.; Lenze, E. J.; Snyder, A. Z.; Dosenbach, N. U. F.; Nicol, G. E.
Score: 81.3, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294131</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>PROTAC-mediated Degradation of HIV-1 Nef Efficiently Restores Cell-surface CD4 and MHC-I Expression and Blocks HIV-1 Replication
Authors: Emert-Sedlak, L. A.; Tice, C. M.; Shi, H.; Alvarado, J. J.; Shu, S. T.; Reitz, A. B.; Smithgall, T. E.
Score: 7.4, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553289
The HIV-1 Nef accessory factor is critical to the viral life cycle in vivo where it promotes immune escape of HIV-infected cells and viral persistence. While these features identify Nef as an attractive antiretroviral drug target, Nef lacks enzymatic activity and an active site, complicating development of occupancy-based drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>A neuronal circuit driven by GLP-1 in the olfactory bulb regulates insulin secretion
Authors: Montaner, M.; Denom, J.; Simon, V.; Jiang, W.; Holt, M. K.; Brierley, D.; Rouch, C.; Foppen, E.; Kassis, N.; Jarriault, D.; Khan, D.; Eygret, L.; Mifsud, F.; Hodson, D. J.; Broichhagen, J.; Van Oudenhove, L.; Fioramonti, X.; Gault, V.; Cota, D.; Reimann, F.; Gribble, F. M.; Migrenne-Li, S.; Trapp, S.; Gurden, H.; Magnan, C.
Score: 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Water fluxes contribute to growth patterning in shoot meristems
Authors: Alonso-Serra, J.; Cheddadi, I.; Kiss, A.; Cerutti, G.; Lionnet, C.; Godin, C.; Hamant, O.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.27.554993
In multicellular organisms, localized tissue outgrowth creates a new water sink thereby modifying hydraulic patterns at the organ level. These fluxes are often considered passive by-products of development and their patterning and potential contribution to morphogenesis remains largely unexplored. Here, we generated a complete map of cell volumetric growth and deformation across the shoot apex in Arabidopsis thaliana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Profiling an integrated network of cellular senescence and immune resilience measures in natural aging: a prospective multi-cohort study
Authors: Mitin, N.; Entwistle, A.; Knecht, A.; Strum, S. L.; Ross, A.; Nyrop, K. A.; Muss, H. B.; Tsygankov, D.; Raffaele, J. M.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294589
BackgroundBiological aging begins decades before the onset of age-related clinical conditions and is mediated by both cellular senescence and declining adaptive immune function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review of Interventions for Prevention and Treatment of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Following Childbirth
Authors: Dekel, S.; Papadakis, J. E.; Quagliarini, B.; Jagodnik, K. M.; Nandru, R.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294230
Structured AbstractO_ST_ABSObjectiveC_ST_ABSPostpartum women can develop post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in response to complicated, traumatic childbirth; prevalence of these events remains high in the U.S. Currently, there is no recommended treatment approach in routine peripartum care for preventing maternal childbirth-related PTSD (CB-PTSD) and lessening its severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Genomic epidemiology of the cholera outbreak in Malawi 2022-2023
Authors: Chabuka, L.; Choga, W. T.; Mavian, C. N.; Moir, M.; Tegally, H.; Wilkinson, E.; Naidoo, Y.; Inward, R.; Morgenstern, C.; Bhatt, S.; Wint, W. G. R.; Khan, K.; Bogoch, I. I.; Kraemer, M. U. G.; Baxter, C.; Tagliamonte, M.; Salemi, M.; Lessells, R.; Mitambo, C.; Chitatanga, R.; Bango, J. B.; Chiwaula, M.; Chavula, Y.; Bukhu, M.; Manda, H.; Chitenje, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Perceptions and experiences of different Long COVID community rehabilitation service models from the perspectives of people living with Long COVID and healthcare professionals
Authors: Duncan, E.; Alexander, L.; Cowie, J.; Love, A.; Morris, J.; Moss, R.; Ormerod, J.; Preston, J.; Shim, J.; Stage, E.; Tooman, T.; Cooper, K.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-08-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.23293876
ObjectivesTo explore the perceptions and experiences of barriers and facilitators to accessing Long COVID community rehabilitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A genome-wide association study of adults with community-acquired pneumonia
Authors: Suarez-Pajes, E.; Marcelino-Rodriguez, I.; Hernandez Brito, E.; Gonzalez-Barbuzano, S.; Ramirez-Falcon, M.; Tosco-Herrera, E.; Rubio-Rodriguez, L. A.; Briones, M. L.; Rajas, O.; Borderias, L.; Ferreres, J.; Payeras, A.; Lorente, L.; Aspa, J.; Lorenzo-Salazar, J. M.; Valencia-Gallardo, J. M.; Carbonell, E.; Freixinet, J.; Rodriguez de Castro, F.; Sole Violan, J.; Flores, C.; Rodriguez-Gallego, C.
Score: 12.1, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294759
IntroductionCommunity-acquired pneumonia (CAP) is associated with high morbidity and hospitalization rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Gender differences in submission behavior exacerbate publication disparities in elite journals
Authors: Basson, I.; Ni, C.; Badia, G.; Tufenkji, N.; Sugimoto, C. R.; Lariviere, V.
Score: 29.3, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554192
Women are particularly underrepresented in journals of the highest scientific impact, with substantial consequences for their careers. While a large body of research has focused on the outcome and the process of peer review, fewer articles have explicitly focused on gendered submission behavior and the explanations for these differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Severe preeclampsia is not associated with significant DNA methylation changes but cell proportion changes in the cord blood - caution on the importance of confounding adjustment
Authors: Liu, W.; Yang, X.; Mao, Z.; Du, Y.; Lassiter, C.; AlAkwaa, F. M.; Benny, P.; Garmire, L.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294898
Epigenome-wide DNA methylation analysis (EWAS) is an important approach to identify biomarkers for early disease detection and prognosis prediction, yet its results could be confounded by other factors such as cell-type heterogeneity and patient characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Role of the exercise professional in metabolic and bariatric surgery
Authors: Stults-Kolehmainen, M. A.; Bond, D. S.; Richardson, L. A.; Herring, L. Y.; Mulone, B.; Garber, C. E.; Morton, J.; Ghiassi, S.; Duffy, A. J.; Balk, E.; Abolt, C. J.; Howard, M. C.; Ash, G. I.; Williamson, S.; Marcon, E. R.; De Los Santos, M.; Bond, S.; Huehls, J.; Alowaish, O.; Heyman, N. B.; Gualano, B. A.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Ultralow background membrane editors for spatiotemporal control of lipid metabolism and signaling
Authors: Li, X.-L.; Tei, R.; Uematsu, M.; Baskin, J. M.
Score: 19.6, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555787
Phosphatidic acid (PA) is a multifunctional lipid with important metabolic and signaling functions, and efforts to dissect its pleiotropy demand strategies for perturbing its levels with spatiotemporal precision. Previous membrane editing approaches for generating local PA pools used light-mediated induced proximity to recruit a PA-synthesizing enzyme, phospholipase D (PLD), from the cytosol to the target organelle membrane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>The interplay between lumen pressure and cell proliferation determines organoid morphology in a multicellular phase field model
Authors: Tanida, S.; Fuji, K.; Lu, L.; Guyomar, T.; Lee, B. H.; Honigmann, A.; Grapin-Botton, A.; Riveline, D.; Nonomura, M.; Sano, M.; Hiraiwa, T.
Score: 13.8, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553655
Organoids are ideal systems to predict the phenotypes of organs. However, there is currently a lack of understanding regarding the generalized rules that enable use of simple cellular principles to make morphological predictions of entire organoids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 10:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of human skin microbiome odorants that manipulate mosquito landing behavior
Authors: Coutinho-Abreu, I. V.; Jamshidi, O.; Raban, R.; Atabakhsh, K.; Merriman, J. A.; Fischbach, M. A.; Akbari, O. S.
Score: 47.3, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553996
The resident human skin microbiome is responsible for the production of most of the human scents that are attractive to mosquitoes. Hence, engineering the human skin microbiome to synthesize less of mosquito attractants or produce repellents could potentially reduce bites and prevent the transmission of deadly mosquito-borne pathogens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
