<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Human ASXL1 Deficiency Causes Epigenetic Dysfunction, Combined Immunodeficiency and EBV-Associated Hodgkin Lymphoma
Authors: Fu, M. P.; Sharma, M.; Merrill, S. M.; Yousefi, P.; Tan, R.; Modi, B. P.; Del Bel, K.; Deyell, R. J.; Rozmus, J.; Rehmus, W.; Hildebrand, K. J.; James, E.; Blanchard-Rohner, G.; Lin, S.; Shopsowitz, K. E.; Setiadi, A.; Terry, J.; Lee, A. F.; Drogemoller, B. I.; Matthews, A.; Tarailo-Graovac, M.; Sauve, L.; Mitchell, H.; Prendiville, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Sex- and strain-dependent effects of ageing on sleep and activity patterns in Drosophila
Authors: Woodling, N.
Score: 13.0, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.573701
The fruit fly Drosophila is a major discovery platform in the biology of ageing due to its balance of relatively short lifespan and relatively complex physiology and behaviour. Previous studies have suggested that some important phenotypes of ageing, for instance increasingly fragmented sleep, are shared from humans to Drosophila and can be useful measures of behavioural change with age: these phenotypes therefore hold potential as readouts of healthy ageing for genetic or pharmacological interventions aimed at the underpinning biology of ageing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Atomic context-conditioned protein sequence design using LigandMPNN
Authors: Dauparas, J.; Lee, G. R.; Pecoraro, R.; An, L.; Anishchenko, I.; Glasscock, C.; Baker, D.
Score: 38.8, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.573103
Protein sequence design in the context of small molecules, nucleotides, and metals is critical to enzyme and small molecule binder and sensor design, but current state-of-the-art deep learning-based sequence design methods are unable to model non-protein atoms and molecules. Here, we describe a deep learning-based protein sequence design method called LigandMPNN that explicitly models all non-protein components of biomolecular systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Structure-conditioned masked language models for protein sequence design generalize beyond the native sequence space
Authors: Akpinaroglu, D.; Seki, K.; Guo, A.; Zhu, E.; Kelly, M. J.; Kortemme, T.
Score: 23.3, Published: 2023-12-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.571823
Machine learning has revolutionized computational protein design, enabling significant progress in protein backbone generation and sequence design. Here, we introduce Frame2seq, a structure-conditioned masked language model for protein sequence design. Frame2seq generates sequences in a single pass, achieves 49.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Eukfinder: a pipeline to retrieve microbial eukaryote genomes from metagenomic sequencing data.
Authors: Zhao, D.; Salas-Leiva, D. E.; Williams, S. K.; Dunn, K. A.; Roger, A. J.
Score: 44.3, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573569
Whole-genome shotgun (WGS) metagenomic sequencing of microbial communities allows us to discover the functions, physiologies, and evolutionary histories of microbial prokaryote and eukaryote members of diverse ecosystems. Despite their importance, metagenomic studies of microbial eukaryotes lag behind those of prokaryotes, due to the difficulty in identifying and assembling high-quality eukaryotic genomes from WGS data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Quantification of cell phenotype transition manifolds with information geometry
Authors: Huang, M.; Ying, J.; Wang, Y.; Zhou, H.; Zhang, L.; Wang, W.
Score: 18.5, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573500
Cell phenotype transition (CPT) is a common occurrence in many biological processes, such as development, and the precise control of CPT is critical in these processes. Recent advancements in single-cell sequencing techniques have revealed that cell transition dynamics in development are confined to low-dimensional manifolds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mechanisms underpinning osteosarcoma genome complexity and evolution
Authors: Espejo Valle-Inclan, J.; De Noon, S.; Trevers, K.; Elrick, H.; Tanguy, M.; Butters, T.; Muyas, F.; Amary, F.; Tirabosco, R.; Giess, A.; Sosinky, A.; Elgar, G.; Flanagan, A. M.; Cortes-Ciriano, I.
Score: 26.7, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573403
Osteosarcoma is the most common primary cancer of bone with a peak incidence in children and young adults. Despite progress, the genomic aberrations underpinning osteosarcoma evolution remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Association between Cardiovascular Disease Risk and long COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis
Authors: Huang, Y.; Wen, Z.; Luo, H.; Liao, Y.; Chen, Z.
Score: 16.6, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300656
ObjectivateTo assess demographic characteristics and investigate the correlation between cardiovascular diseases and long COVID-19 patients. MethodsComprehensive details, encompassing the first authors name, publication year, sample inclusion criteria, sample size, and demographic characteristics, including age and gender of participants, were systematically extracted from all incorporated studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Constitutive Endolysosomal Perforation in Neurons allows Induction of alpha-Synuclein Aggregation by Internalized Pre-Formed Fibrils
Authors: Sanyal, A.; Scanavachi, G.; Somerville, E.; Saminathan, A.; Nair, A.; Oikonomou, A.; Hatzakis, N. S.; Kirchhausen, T.
Score: 13.5, Published: 2024-01-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.573738
The endocytic pathway is both an essential route of molecular uptake in cells and a potential entry point for pathology-inducing cargo. The cell-to-cell spread of cytotoxic aggregates, such as those of alpha-synuclein (alpha-syn) in Parkinson s Disease (PD), exemplifies this duality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Preliminary Analysis of the Melanoma Multimedia Educational programme for general practitioners on behalf of the Italian Melanoma Intergroup
Authors: Zamagni, F.; Falcini, F.; Magi, S.; Bucchi, L.; Mancini, S.; Vattiato, R.; Crocetti, E.; Falcinelli, S.; Feliciani, C.; Lombardo, M.; Melandri, D.; Re, P.; Ricci, F.; Satta, R. R.; Gandini, s.; Stanganelli, I.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300602
IntroductionAccording to the National Oncological Plan 2023-2027 on the importance of multidisciplinary and interactive e-learning training, the Italian Melanoma Intergroup (IMI) has developed MelaMEd (Melanoma Multimedia Education), a national project for general practitioners (GPs) on the prevention and detection of cutaneous melanoma through an online platform and an online course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Gene module reconstruction elucidates cellular differentiation processes and the regulatory logic of specialized secretion
Authors: Wang, Y.; Liu, J.; Du, L. Y.; Wyss, J. L.; Farrell, J. A.; Schier, A. F.
Score: 9.6, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573643
During differentiation, cells become structurally and functionally specialized, but comprehensive views of the underlying remodeling processes are elusive. Here, we leverage scRNA-seq developmental trajectories to reconstruct differentiation using two secretory tissues as a model system - the zebrafish notochord and hatching gland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Biodiversity in mountain soils above the treeline
Authors: Praeg, N.; Steinwandter, M.; Urbach, D.; Snethlage, M. A.; Alves, R. P.; Apple, M. E.; Britton, A. J.; Bruni, E. P.; Chen, T.-W.; Dumack, K.; Fernandez-Mendoza, F.; Freppaz, M.; Frey, B.; Fromin, N.; Geisen, S.; Grube, M.; Guariento, E.; Guisan, A.; Ji, Q.-Q.; Jimenez, J. J.; Maier, S.; Malard, L. A.; Minor, M. A.; Mc Lean, C. C.; Mitchell, E. A. D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>BNT162b2 XBB1.5-adapted Vaccine and COVID-19 Hospital Admissions and Ambulatory Visits in US Adults
Authors: Tartof, S. Y.; Slezak, J. M.; Frankland, T. B.; Puzniak, L.; Hong, V.; Ackerson, B. K.; Stern, J. A.; Simmons, S.; Jodar, L.; McLaughlin, J. M.
Score: 1635.7, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.24.23300512
ImportanceData describing the early additional protection afforded by recently recommended XBB1.5- adapted COVID-19 vaccines are limited. ObjectiveWe estimated the association between receipt of BNT162b2 XBB1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Complex allometric relationships and ecological factors shape the development and evolution of eye size in the modular visual system of spiders
Authors: Chong, K. L.; Grahn, A.; Perl, C. D.; Sumner-Rooney, L.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573503
Eye size affects many aspects of visual function, most notably including contrast sensitivity and achievable spatial resolution, but eyes are costly to grow and maintain. The allometry of eyes can provide insight to this trade-off in the context of visual ecology, but to date, this has mainly been explored in species that have a single pair of eyes of equal size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Polygenic prediction of major depressive disorder and related traits in African ancestries UK Biobank participants.
Authors: Kanjira, S. C.; Adams, M. C.; Jiang, Y.; Tian, C.; 23andMe Research Team, ; Lewis, C.; Kuchenbaecker, K.; McIntosh, A. M.
Score: 7.3, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.24.23300412
IntroductionGenome-Wide Association Studies (GWAS) over-represent European ancestries compared to the global population, neglecting all other ancestry groups and low-income nations. Consequently, polygenic risk scores (PRS) more accurately predict complex traits in Europeans than African Ancestries groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Extreme restructuring of cis-regulatory regions controlling a deeply conserved plant stem cell regulator
Authors: Ciren, D.; Zebell, S.; Lippman, Z.
Score: 22.7, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572550
A striking paradox is that genes with conserved protein sequence, function and expression pattern over deep time often exhibit extremely divergent cis-regulatory sequences. It remains unclear how such drastic cis-regulatory evolution across species allows preservation of gene function, and to what extent these differences influence how cis-regulatory variation arising within species impacts phenotypic change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>CRISPRmap: Sequencing-free optical pooled screens mapping multi-omic phenotypes in cells and tissue
Authors: Gu, J.; Iyer, A.; Wesley, B.; Taglialatela, A.; Leuzzi, G.; Hangai, S.; Decker, A.; Gu, R.; Klickstein, N.; Shuai, Y.; Jankovic, K.; Parker-Burns, L.; Jin, Y.; Zhang, J. Y.; Hong, J.; Niu, X.; Chou, J.; Landau, D. A.; Azizi, E.; Chan, E. M.; Ciccia, A.; Gaublomme, J. T.
Score: 49.3, Published: 2023-12-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.572587
Pooled genetic screens are powerful tools to study gene function in a high-throughput manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare utilisation in people with long COVID: an OpenSAFELY cohort study
Authors: Lin, L.-Y.; Henderson, A. D.; Carlile, O.; Dillingham, I.; Butler-Cole, B. F.; Marks, M.; Briggs, A.; Jit, M.; Tomlinson, L. A.; Bates, C.; Parry, J.; Bacon, S. C.; Goldacre, B.; Mehrkar, A.; MacKenna, B.; The OpenSAFELY Collaborative, ; Eggo, R. M.; Herrett, E.
Score: 346.3, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300305
BackgroundLong COVID, characterised by various symptoms and complications, potentially increases healthcare utilisation and costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Infection is Associated with an Increase in New Diagnoses of Schizophrenia Spectrum and Psychotic Disorder: A Study Using the US National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C)
Authors: Rahman, A.; Russell, M.; Zheng, W.; Eckrich, D.; Ahmed, I.; on behalf of the N3C Consortium, Score: 700.6, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299473
Amid the ongoing global repercussions of SARS-CoV-2, its crucial to comprehend its potential long-term psychiatric effects. Several recent studies have suggested a link between COVID-19 and subsequent mental health disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell analysis of bone marrow CD8&amp;#43; T cells in Myeloid Neoplasms predicts response to treatment with Azacitidine
Authors: Tasis, A.; Papaioannou, N.; Grigoriou, M.; Paschalidis, N.; Loukogiannaki, K.; Filia, A.; Katsiki, K.; Lamprianidou, E.; Papadopoulos, V.; Rimpa, C. M.; Chatzigeorgiou, A.; Kourtzelis, I.; Gerasimou, P.; Kyprianou, I.; Kosteas, P.; Liakopoulos, P.; Liapis, K.; Kolovos, P.; Chavakis, T.; Alissafi, T.; Kotsianidis, I.; Mitroulis, I.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300608</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 1419.9, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 pandemic re-shaped the global dispersal of seasonal influenza viruses
Authors: Chen, Z.; Tsui, J. L.- H.; Gutierrez, B.; Moreno, S. B.; Plessis, L. d.; Deng, X.; Cai, J.; Bajaj, S.; Suchard, M. A.; Pybus, O. G.; Lemey, P.; Kraemer, M. U. G.; Yu, H.
Score: 32.9, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.23300299
Understanding how the global dispersal patterns of seasonal influenza viruses were perturbed during and after the COVID-19 pandemic is needed to inform influenza intervention and vaccination strategies in the post-pandemic period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effect of Heparin and Tocilizumab in Patients with Severe COVID-19: The HEPMAB Randomized Clinical Trial
Authors: Ribeiro, L.; Landoni, G.; Quintao, V. C.; de Lacerda, M. V. G.; Rizk, S. I.; da Silva Costa, I. B. S.; de Almeida Andrade, F. T.; Melo, E. d. S.; dos Santos Neto, N. C.; de Gonzalez, T. B.; Ferreira Reis, L. B.; de Freitas Costa, V.; Machado, T. I. V.; da Costa Ribeiro, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical students&amp;#39; perceptions towards artificial intelligence in education and practice: A multinational, multicenter cross-sectional study
Authors: Busch, F.; Hoffmann, L.; Truhn, D.; Ortiz-Prado, E.; Makowski, M. R.; Bressem, K. K.; Adams, L. C.; COMFORT Consortium, Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.23299744
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) is anticipated to fundamentally change the educational and professional landscape for the next generation of physicians, but its successful integration depends on the global perspectives of all stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Persistence of an infectious form of SARS-CoV-2 post protease inhibitor treatment of permissive cells in vitro
Authors: Nair, M. S.; Luck, M. I.; Huang, Y.; Sabo, Y.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 67.9, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572655
Reports have described SARS-CoV-2 rebound in COVID-19 patients treated with nirmatrelvir, a 3CL protease inhibitor. The cause remains a mystery, although drug resistance, re-infection, and lack of adequate immune responses have been excluded. We now present virologic findings that provide a clue to the cause of viral rebound, which occurs in [~]20% of the treated cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Interplay between Two Paralogous Human Silencing Hub (HuSH) Complexes in Regulating LINE-1 Element Silencing
Authors: Jensvold, Z. D.; Christenson, A. E.; Flood, J. R.; Lewis, P. W.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573526
The Human Silencing Hub (HuSH) complex is composed of TASOR, MPP8, and PPHLN1 subunits and serves as a conserved protein complex responsible for silencing transposable elements in vertebrate animals. Despite its importance, the regulatory mechanisms and recruitment dynamics governing this complex remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The decline of renal function aggravates arterial stiffness: a large-scale cross-sectional and longitudinal study
Authors: Wang, W.; Zhao, Q.; Leng, Y.; Wang, J.; Rujia, M.; Chen, Z.; wang, j.; Cai, J.; Yuan, H.; Li, F.; Lu, Y.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.01.24300697
ABSTRACT Purpose: Many studies investigated the one-single-direction relationship between arterial stiffness and chronic kidney dysfunction, particularly in patients with end-stage renal disease. The bidirectional relevance between kidney function decline and arterial stiffness in general population remains unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Neuroimaging markers of patient-reported outcome measures in acute ischemic stroke
Authors: Oliveira, L. C.; Bonkhoff, A. K.; Regenhardt, R. W.; Alhadid, K.; Tuozzo, C.; Etherton, M. R.; Rost, N. S.; Schirmer, M. D.
Score: 4.1, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299829
ObjectivesTo determine the relationship between patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) and volumetric imaging markers in acute ischemic stroke (AIS). Patients and MethodsPatients presenting at Massachusetts General Hospital between February 14, 2017 and February 5, 2020 with a confirmed AIS by MRI were eligible and underwent a telephone interview including PROM-10 questionnaires 3-15 months after stroke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A neural network for religious fundamentalism derived from patients with brain lesions
Authors: Ferguson, M. A.; Asp, E. W.; Kletenik, I.; Tranel, D.; Boes, A.; Nelson, J. M.; Schaper, F. L.; Siddiqi, S. H.; Anderson, J. S.; Nielsen, J. A.; Bateman, J. R.; Grafman, J.; Fox, M. D.
Score: 172.6, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572527
Religious fundamentalism, characterized by rigid adherence to a set of beliefs putatively revealing inerrant truths, is ubiquitous across cultures and has a global impact on society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>The Effect of Mindfulness Based Stress Reduction on Glycemic Control and Psychological Well-being of Diabetes Mellitus Patients: A Review of Experimental Studies
Authors: Qona&amp;#39;ah, A.; Pandin, M. G. R.; Nursalam, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23300572
Most diabetes mellitus patients experience psychological problems resulting from the disease, disease management, and complications. Inadequate management of psychological problems may place patients at greater risk for depression. This systematic review aims to identify the effects of mindful interventions in controlling glycemic levels and psychological well-being in diabetes mellitus patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 152.4, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Exposure to Wood dust and its Respiratory Health Effects Among Wood Workers in Yaounde (Cameroon)
Authors: Takougang, I.; Bukam Guemnyem, G. W.; Edzamba, M. F.; Lekeumo Cheuyem, F. Z.; Assomo Ndemba, P. B.; Yone Pefura, W.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300613
BackgroundOccupational respiratory diseases are responsible of one-third of all documented work-related deaths. Exposure to wood dust leads to multiple respiratory manifestations including cough, chest pain, asthma and altered lung function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping inherited genetic variation with opposite effects on autoimmune disease and cancer identifies candidate drug targets associated with the anti-tumor immune response
Authors: Chen, J.; Epstein, M. P.; Schildkraut, J. M.; Kar, S. P.
Score: 7.8, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.23.23300491
BackgroundGermline alleles near genes that encode certain immune checkpoints (CTLA4, CD200) are associated with autoimmune/autoinflammatory disease and cancer but in opposite directions. This motivates a systematic search for additional germline alleles which demonstrate this pattern with the aim of identifying potential cancer immunotherapeutic targets using human genetic evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Aberrant connective tissue sheath contraction drives premature hair follicle regression by inducing progenitor cell depletion in androgenetic alopecia
Authors: Deng, Z.; Yang, L.; Duan, S.; Chen, M.; Zhang, Y.; Liu, F.; Tang, Y.; Wang, Y.; Li, J.; Xu, S.; Wu, Z.; Wang, B.; Zhao, Z.; Shi, W.; Xie, H.; Li, G.; Li, J.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.25.573294
Androgenetic alopecia (AGA) is characterized by progressive miniaturization of hair, forming a distinctive patterned baldness in the scalp; yet, the mechanisms for hair miniaturization in this disease remain largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>The Prevalence, Etiology, And Outcome Of Anemia In Children Under Five On Admission In Three Hospitals Of Dar-Es-Salaam
Authors: Msinde, P. S.
Score: 26.1, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300509
IntroductionChildhood anemia remains a persistent global challenge, emerging as the most prevalent blood disorder among children worldwide. Its enduring prevalence underscores its significance as a hematological concern of substantial public health importance, owing to its wide prevalence and potential severity. Anemias impact is particularly pronounced among children and expectant mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Refining the impact of genetic evidence on clinical success
Authors: Minikel, E. V.; Painter, J. L.; Dong, C. C.; Nelson, M. R.
Score: 59.6, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23291765
The cost of drug discovery and development is driven primarily by failure, with just [~]10% of clinical programs eventually receiving approval. We previously estimated that human genetic evidence doubles the success rate from clinical development to approval. In this study we leverage the growth in genetic evidence over the past decade to better understand the characteristics that distinguish clinical success and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Drug promiscuity: problems and promises.
Authors: VanDongen, A. M.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573633
Therapeutic drugs exert their effect by binding to a specific target protein (receptor) and altering its activity. However, all drugs have undesirable side effects, which likely result from the drug binding to other protein targets. Drug promiscuity refers to the ability of small molecule compounds to bind with high affinity to multiple proteins. This drug property is responsible for the problems caused by their side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Preliminary Insights into the Effects of Spinal Manipulation Therapy of Different Force Magnitudes on Blood Biomarkers of Oxidative Stress and Pro-Resolution of Inflammation Mediators
Authors: Duarte, F. C. K.; Funabashi, M.; Starmer, D.; Partata, W. A.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573549
IntroductionEvidence has reported that spinal manipulation therapy (SMT) leads to spine segmental hypoalgesia through neurophysiological and peripheral mechanisms related to regulating inflammatory biomarker function. However, these studies also showed substantial inter-individual variability in the biomarker responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Autophagy Restricts Tomato Fruit Ripening Via a General Role in Ethylene Repression
Authors: Kumaran, G.; Pathak, P. K.; Quandoh, E.; Mursalimov, S. R.; Devi, J.; Tuvia-Alkalai, S.; Leong, J. X.; Schenstnyi, K.; Levin, E.; Üstün, S.; Michaeli, S.
Score: 12.9, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572633
Autophagy, a cellular degradation pathway, and the phytohormone ethylene function in plant development, senescence, and stress responses. However, the manner of their interaction is mostly unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>A participatory action research study to explore adolescents experiences of adverse childhood experiences through creative workshops: a protocol
Authors: Butcher, I.; Mankee Williams, A.; Hugh-Jones, S.; Cooke, P.; Teasdale, B.; Shaughnessy, N.; Pavarini, G.; Smith, L.; Bhui, K.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300349
IntroductionAdverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) are associated with poor mental health in adolescence. There are critical gaps in understanding how and why ACEs are experienced by particular groups of young people and what factors contribute to risk and resilience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1329.7, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
ImportancePhase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects which are not assessed within the current regulatory framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Five dominant dimensions of brain aging are identified via deep learning: associations with clinical, lifestyle, and genetic measures
Authors: Yang, Z.; Wen, J.; Erus, G.; Govindarajan, S. T.; Melhem, R.; Mamourian, E.; Cui, Y.; Srinivasan, D.; Abdulkadir, A.; Parmpi, P.; Wittfeld, K.; Grabe, H. J.; Bulow, R.; Frenzel, S.; Tosun, D.; Bilgel, M.; An, Y.; Yi, D.; Marcus, D. S.; LaMontagne, P.; Benzinger, T. L. S.; Heckbert, S. R.; Austin, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Financial Cost Analysis Associated with a Locomotor Exercise Randomized Controlled Trial in Chronic Stroke
Authors: Hazen, E. M.; Bartsch, B. L.; Billinger, S. A.
Score: 13.2, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.23300342
BackgroundPost-stroke recovery trials pose distinct recruitment and retention challenges, and understanding the financial requirements of conducting randomized controlled trials is crucial to ensure sufficient resources for successful study execution. The purpose of this analysis was to quantify the costs at a single site with a large catchment area of the Moderate-Intensity Exercise Versus High-Intensity Interval Training to Recover Walking Post-Stroke, HIT Stroke Trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Rendering protein structures inside cells at the atomic level with Unreal Engine
Authors: Chen, M.
Score: 135.0, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570879
While the recent development of cryogenic electron tomography (CryoET) makes it possible to identify various macromolecules inside cells and determine their structure at near-atomic resolution, it remains challenging to visualize the complex cellular environment at the atomic level. One of the main hurdles in cell visualization is to render the millions of molecules in real time computationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Fractal correlation properties of heart rate variability as a marker of exercise intensity during incremental and constant-speed treadmill running
Authors: van Rassel, C. R.; Ajayi, O. O.; Sales, K. M.; Clermont, A. C.; Rummel, M.; MacInnis, M. J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.23300234
The short-term scaling exponent of detrended fluctuation analysis (DFA1) applied to interbeat intervals may provide a method to identify ventilatory thresholds and indicate systemic perturbation during prolonged exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Surgical diagnoses and post-operative outcomes of intestinal obstruction among adults at regional referral hospitals in Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania: a prospective, observational hospital-based study
Authors: Mponzi, S. S.; Wandwi, W. B.; Mbembati, N. A.; Leshabari, K. M.
Score: 0.2, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.31.23300678
Background There is limited available published information regarding surgical diagnoses and postoperative outcomes of intestinal obstruction among adult patients in East African hospitals. The observation is despite available anecdotal evidence of the condition to be among the commonest surgical emergencies in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Species-specific design of artificial promoters by transfer-learning based generative deep-learning model
Authors: Xia, Y.; Du, X.; Liu, B.; Guo, S.; Huo, Y.-X.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-12-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.573416
Native prokaryotic promoters share common sequence patterns, but are species dependent. For understudied species with limited data, it is challenging to predict the strength of existing promoters and generate novel promoters. Here, we developed PromoGen, a collection of nucleotide language models to generate species-specific functional promoters, across dozens of species in a data and parameter efficient way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Highly multiplexed, image-based pooled screens in primary cells and tissues with PerturbView
Authors: Kudo, T.; Meireles, A. M.; Moncada, R.; Chen, Y.; Wu, P.; Gould, J.; Hu, X.; Kornfeld, O.; Jesudason, R.; Foo, C.; Hockendorf, B.; Bravo, H. C.; Town, J. P.; Wei, R.; Rios, A.; Chandrasekar, V.; Heinlein, M.; Cai, S.; Lu, C. S.; Celen, C.; Kljavin, N.; Jiang, J.; Hleap, J. S.; Kayagaki, N.; Melo, F. d. S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) - a new record of butterfly for Saudi Arabia
Authors: ALFAKIH, A.; AL FAIFY, E. A.
Score: 37.5, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572884
The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) was recorded for the first time in Saudi Arabia. At this stage, we confirmed the presence of this species in the southernmost part of Saudi Arabia based on photographs taken in 2020-2023 from Fayfa and the adjacent mountains in Jazan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
