<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Chronic Pain, Cannabis Legalization and Cannabis Use Disorder in Veterans Health Administration Patients, 2005 to 2019
Authors: Hasin, D. S.; Wall, M. M.; Alschuler, D.; Mannes, Z. L.; Malte, C.; Olfson, M.; Keyes, K. M.; Gradus, J. L.; Cerda, M.; Maynard, C. C.; Keyhani, S.; Martins, S. S.; Fink, D. S.; Livne, O.; McDowell, Y.; Sherman, S.; Saxon, A. J.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292453
Abstract/SummaryO_ST_ABSBackgroundC_ST_ABSThe risk for cannabis use disorder (CUD) is elevated among U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 30.2, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Protein Ensemble Generation through VariationalAutoencoder Latent Space Sampling
Authors: Mansoor, S.; Baek, M.; Park, H.; Lee, G. R.; Baker, D.
Score: 28.9, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.551540
Mapping the ensemble of protein conformations that contribute to function and can be targeted by small molecule drugs remains an outstanding challenge. Here we explore the use of soft-introspective variational autoencoders for reducing the challenge of dimensionality in the protein structure ensemble generation problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell precision nanotechnology in vivo
Authors: MOLBAY, M.; Kick, B.; Zhao, S.; Todorov, M. I.; Ohn, T.-L.; Roth, S.; Simats, A.; Singh, V.; Khalin, I.; Pan, C.; Singh Bhatia, H.; Hellal, F.; Zeidler, R.; Liesz, A.; Plesnila, N.; Dietz, H.; Erturk, A.
Score: 141.7, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550304
Targeting nanoparticle therapeutics with cellular accuracy in whole organisms could open breakthrough opportunities in precision medicine. However, evaluating and fine-tuning the biodistribution of such systems in the whole organism at the cellular level remains a major obstacle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>phytools 2.0: An updated R ecosystem for phylogenetic comparative methods (and other things)
Authors: Revell, L. J.
Score: 198.2, Published: 2023-08-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.08.531791
Phylogenetic comparative methods comprise the general endeavor of using an estimated phylogenetic tree (or set of trees) to make secondary inferences: about trait evolution, diversification dynamics, biogeography, community ecology, and a wide range of other phenomena or processes. Over the past ten years or so, the phytools R package (Revell 2012) has grown to become an important research tools for phylogenetic comparative analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Cell Membranes Sustain Phospholipid Imbalance Via Cholesterol Asymmetry
Authors: Doktorova, M.; Symons, J. L.; Zhang, X.; Wang, H.-Y.; Schlegel, J.; Lorent, J. H.; Heberle, F. A.; Sezgin, E.; Lyman, E.; Levental, K. R.; Levental, I.
Score: 111.0, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.30.551157
Membranes are molecular interfaces that insulate cells from external stresses, compartmentalize the cytoplasm, and control the flow of nutrients and information1. These functions are facilitated by diverse collections of lipids, nearly all of which are distributed asymmetrically between the two leaflets of living bilayers2,3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 361.6, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Global longitudinal strain and plasma biomarkers for prognosis in heart failure complicated by diabetes
Authors: Iyer, N.; Chan, S.-P.; Liew, O. W.; Chong, J. P. C.; Bryant, J.; Le, T.-T.; Cozzone, P.; Eisenhaber, F.; Foo, R.; Richards, A. M.; Lam, C. S. P.; Ugander, M.; Chin, C. W.-L.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.20.23287472
BackgroundHeart failure (HF) and diabetes are associated with increased incidence and worse prognosis of each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>An adaptive biomolecular condensation response is conserved across environmentally divergent species
Authors: Keyport Kik, S.; Christopher, D.; Glauninger, H.; Wong Hickernell, C.; Bard, J. A. M.; Ford, M.; Sosnick, T. R.; Drummond, D. A.
Score: 42.9, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.551061
Cells must sense and respond to sudden maladaptive environmental changes--stresses--to survive and thrive. Across eukaryotes, stresses such as heat shock trigger conserved responses: growth arrest, a specific transcriptional response, and biomolecular condensation of protein and mRNA into structures known as stress granules under severe stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Oral health vulnerability and its associated risk factors among tribal elderly people in Bangladesh: a pilot study
Authors: Barua, S.; Bosu, S.; Haque, M. F.; Bosak, L.; Rashid, M. R.; Zaman, S. R.; Rahman, M. F.; Rahman, M. M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293159
BackgroundTribal elderly is a vulnerable population due to their geographic location and lack of access to healthcare services. This study aims to assess the oral health status of tribal elderly in Bangladesh and identify any associated risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Global decoupling of cell differentiation from cell division in early embryo development
Authors: Kukreja, K.; Patel, N.; Megason, S. G.; Klein, A. M.
Score: 45.1, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.551123
As tissues develop, cells divide and differentiate concurrently. Conflicting evidence shows that cell division is either dispensable or required for formation of cell types. To determine the role of cell division in differentiation, we arrested the cell cycle in zebrafish embryos using two independent approaches and profiled them at single-cell resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Predictive microbial community changes across a temperature gradient
Authors: Sun, X.; Folmar, J.; Favier, A.; Pyenson, N.; Sanchez, A.; Rebolleda-Gomez, M.
Score: 32.5, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550899
A central challenge in community ecology is predicting the effects of abiotic factors on community assembly. In particular, microbial communities play a central role in the ecosystem, but we do not understand how changing factors like temperature are going to affect community composition or function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Diabetes Detection from Diabetic Retinopathy-Absent Images Using Deep Learning Methodology
Authors: Rom, Y.; Aviv, R.; Cohen, G. Y.; Friedman, Y. E.; Dvey-Aharon, Z.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.23287515
AimsDiabetes is one of the leading causes of morbidity and mortality in the United States and worldwide. This research aimed to develop an artificial intelligence (AI) machine learning model which can detect the presence of diabetes from fundus imagery of eyes without diabetic eye disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Lineage replacement and evolution captured by the United Kingdom Covid Infection Survey
Authors: Lythgoe, K. A.; Golubchik, T.; Hall, M.; House, T.; Cahuantzi, R.; MacIntyre-Cockett, G.; Fryer, H.; Thomson, L.; Nurtay, A.; Ghafari, M.; Buck, D.; Green, A.; Trebes, A.; Piazza, P.; Lonie, L. J.; Studley, R.; Rourke, E.; Smith, D.; Bashton, M.; Nelson, A.; Crown, M.; McCann, C.; Young, G. R.; de Santos, R. A. N.; Richards, Z.; Tariq, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Fruitless mating with the exes: the irreversible parthenogenesis in a stick insect
Authors: Nozaki, T.; Chikami, Y.; Yano, K.; Sato, R.; Suetsugu, K.; Kaneko, S.
Score: 204.2, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550994
Parthenogenetic lineages, common in many animals, have sparked debate about their evolutionary persistence. Even after the loss of male individuals, males can survive on the genomes; in fact, rarely occurring males were described in many asexual lineages. Theoretical predictions suggest that genes related to male sexual traits in parthenogenetic lineages will decay over long evolutionary times free from the pressure of stabilizing selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Unraveling COVID-19 Relationship with Anxiety Disorders and Symptoms
Authors: Asgel, Z.; Kouakou, M.; Koller, D.; Pathak, G. A.; Cabrera-Mendoza, B.; Polimanti, R.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.23293001
BackgroundWhile COVID-19 outcomes are associated with increased anxiety, individuals affected by anxiety disorders are more likely to develop severe COVID-19 outcomes. MethodsWe used genome-wide data from UK Biobank (up to 420,531 participants), FinnGen Project (up to 329,077 participants), Million Veteran Program (175,163 participants), and COVID-19 Host Genetics Initiative (up to 122,616 cases and 2,475,240 controls) to investigate possible causal effects and shared genetic mechanisms linking COVID-19 outcomes to anxiety disorders and symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Interpreting SNP heritability in admixed populations
Authors: Huang, J.; Basu, S.; Shriver, M. D.; Zaidi, A. A.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.551959
SNP heritability (h2snp) is defined as the proportion of phenotypic variance explained by genotyped SNPs and is believed to be a lower bound of heritability (h2), being equal to it if all causal variants are known. Despite the simple intuition behind h2snp, its interpretation and equivalence to h2 is unclear, particularly in the presence of population structure and assortative mating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>A multiplex, prime editing framework for identifying drug resistance variants at scale
Authors: Chardon, F. M.; Suiter, C.; Daza, R.; Smith, N. T.; Parrish, P.; McDiarmid, T.; Lalanne, J.-B.; Martin, B. K.; Calderon, D.; Ellison, A.; Berger, A.; Shendure, J.; Starita, L. M.
Score: 38.3, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550902
CRISPR-based genome editing has revolutionized functional genomics, enabling screens in which thousands of perturbations of either gene expression or primary genome sequence can be competitively assayed in single experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The principal component-based clinical aging clock (PCAge) identifies signatures of healthy aging and provides normative targets for clinical intervention
Authors: Fong, S.; Pabis, K.; Latumalea, D.; Dugersuren, N.; Unfried, M.; Tolwinski, N.; Kennedy, B.; Gruber, J.
Score: 25.3, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292604
Clinical healthy aging recommendations are disease-centric and reactive rather than focusing on holistic, organismal aging. In contrast, biological age (BA) estimation informs risk stratification by predicting all-cause mortality, however current BA clocks do not pinpoint aging mechanisms making it difficult to intervene clinically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Normalization of Drug and Therapeutic Concepts with TheraPy
Authors: Cannon, M.; Stevenson, J.; Kuzma, K.; Kiwala, S.; Warner, J.; Griffith, O. L.; Griffith, M.; Wagner, A. H.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.23293245
Working with therapeutic terminology in the field of medicine can be challenging due to both the number of ways terms can be addressed and the ambiguity associated with different naming strategies. A therapeutic concept can be identified across many facets from ontologies and vocabularies of varying focus, including natural product names, chemical structures, development codes, generic names, brand names, product formulations, or treatment regimens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Recommended distances for physical distancing during COVID-19 pandemics reveal cultural connections between countries
Authors: Chai, D.; El Mossadeq, L.; Raymond, M.; Orgogozo, V.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293497
During COVID-19 pandemic several public health measures were implemented by diverse countries to reduce the risk of COVID-19, including social distancing. Here we collected the minimal distance recommended by each country for physical distancing at the onset of the pandemic and aimed to examine whether it had an impact on the outbreak dynamics and how this specific value was chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>The T cell receptor sequence influences the likelihood of T cell memory formation
Authors: Lagattuta, K. A.; Nathan, A.; Rumker, L.; Birnbaum, M. E.; Raychaudhuri, S.
Score: 49.8, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549939
T cell differentiation depends on activation through the T cell receptor (TCR), whose amino acid sequence varies cell to cell. Particular TCR amino acid sequences nearly guarantee Mucosal-Associated Invariant T (MAIT) and Natural Killer T (NKT) cell fates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Phenotyping the virulence of SARS-CoV-2 variants in hamsters by digital pathology and machine learning
Authors: Meehan, G. R.; Herder, V.; Allan, J.; Huang, X.; Kerr, K.; Mendonca, D. C.; Ilia, G.; Wright, D.; Nomikou, K.; Gu, Q.; Arias, S. M.; De Lorenzo, G.; Cowton, V.; Upfold, N.; Palmalux, N.; Brown, J. C.; Barclay, W.; Filipe, A. D. S.; Furnon, W.; Patel, A.; Palmarini, M.
Score: 915.1, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Intra-host variation in the spike S1/S2 region of a feline coronavirus type-1 in a cat with persistent infection
Authors: Olarte-Castillo, X. A.; Licitra, B. N.; Andre, N. M.; Sierra, M. A.; Mason, C. E.; Goodman, L. B.; Whittaker, G.
Score: 40.3, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.551356
Feline coronavirus type 1 (FCoV-1) is widely known for causing feline infectious peritonitis (FIP), a systemic infection that is often fatal, with the virus known as the FIPV biotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The use of machine learning methods in neurodegenerative disease research: A scoping review
Authors: Ciampi, A.; Rouette, J.; Pellegrini, F.; Simoneau, G.; Caba, B.; Gafson, A.; de Moor, C.; Belachew, S.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293414
Machine learning (ML) methods are increasingly used in clinical research, but their extent is complex and largely unknown in the field of neurodegenerative diseases (ND). This scoping review describes state-of-the-art ML in ND research using MEDLINE (PubMed), Embase (Ovid), Central (Cochrane), and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Xplore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Constructed languages are processed by the same brain mechanisms as natural languages
Authors: Malik-Moraleda, S.; Taliaferro, M.; Shannon, S.; Jhingan, N.; Swords, S.; Peterson, D. J.; Frommer, P.; Okrand, M.; Sams, J.; Cardwell, R.; Freeman, C.; Fedorenko, E.
Score: 160.1, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550667
What constitutes a language? Natural languages share some features with other domains: from math, to music, to gesture. However, the brain mechanisms that process linguistic input are highly specialized, showing little or no response to diverse non-linguistic tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Mistletoe as a Therapeutic Option in Cancer Patients: a scoping review protocol
Authors: Cordeiro, M. M.; Malta, F. A. P. S.; Goncalves, D. C.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.23293280
ObjectiveThis scoping review aims to identify, map and provide an overview of the studies investigating the therapeutic use of Viscum Album L. (mistletoe) in cancer patients. By identifying pivotal patterns and research gaps in the existing literature on Viscum therapy, this review intends to offer valuable insights and supportive information to better inform future research efforts in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omic spatial effects on high-resolution AI-derived retinal thickness
Authors: Jackson, V. E.; Wu, Y.; Bonelli, R.; Owen, J.; Farashi, S.; Kihara, Y.; Gantner, M. L.; Egan, C.; Williams, K. M.; Ansell, B. R.; Tufail, A.; Lee, A. Y.; Bahlo, M.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293176
Retinal thickness is a marker of retinal health and more broadly, is seen as a promising biomarker for many systemic diseases. Retinal thickness measurements are procured from optical coherence tomography (OCT) as part of routine clinical eyecare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Lack of early animal fossils: insights from taphonomic experiments on placozoans and their traces
Authors: Naimark, E.; Lyupina, Y. V.; Nikitin, M. A.; Finoshin, A. D.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551688
Placozoa are simple two-layered multicellular animals. Can such a simple animal preserve in the fossil record? The results of our taphonomic experiments showed that it is chemically possible; however, the chances of the presevation are negligible for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>One-Year Follow-up of Young People with ME/CFS Following Infectious Mononucleosis by Epstein-Barr Virus
Authors: Pricoco, R.; Meidel, P.; Hofberger, T.; Zietemann, H.; Mueller, Y.; Wiehler, K.; Michel, K.; Paulick, J.; Leone, A.; Haegele, M.; Mayer-Huber, S.; Gerrer, K.; Mittelstrass, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Renz-Polster, H.; Mihatsch, L.; Behrends, U.
Score: 65.5, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293082
BackgroundInfectious mononucleosis, caused by the Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV-IM), has been linked to the development of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue-syndrome (ME/CFS) in children, adolescents, and young adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>A new paradigm of intracrine free fatty acid receptor 4 signaling at lipid droplets
Authors: Calebiro, D.; O&amp;#39;Brien, S. L.; Tripp, E.; Smith, G.; Boufersaoui, A.; Roberts, J.; Pike, J. A.; Correia, J.; Miljus, T. A.; Tennant, D. A.; Hudson, B. D.; Milligan, G.; Gerhart-Hines, Z.; Schwartz, T. W.
Score: 17.4, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550805
G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs), once thought to be active exclusively at the plasma membrane, have been shown to signal from multiple intracellular membrane compartments, including endosomes and the Golgi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of RyR2 distribution in HEK293 cells and mouse cardiac myocytes using 3D MINFLUX microscopy
Authors: Clowsley, A. H.; Meletiou, A.; Lucinskaite, E.; Jansen, I.; Jones, P. P.; Louch, W. E.; Soeller, C.
Score: 12.1, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550636
The cardiac type 2 ryanodine receptor (RyR2) is a large homotetramer of a [~]560 kD subunit and is the molecular pathway through which the majority of Ca2&amp;#43; enters the cytosol during cardiac activation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>GreenGate 2.0: backwards compatible addons for assembly of complex transcriptional units and their stacking with GreenGate
Authors: Piepers, M.; Erbstein, K.; Reyes-Hernandez, J.; Song, C.; Tessi, T.; Petrasiunaite, V.; Faerber, N.; Distel, K.; Maizel, A.
Score: 32.4, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551719
Molecular cloning is a crucial technique in genetic engineering that enables the precise design of synthetic transcriptional units (TUs) and the manipulation of genomes. GreenGate and several other modular molecular cloning systems were developed about ten years ago and are widely used in plant research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic analysis of human serum Extracellular Vesicles reveals early diagnostic markers for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis
Authors: Vassileff, N.; Leblanc, P.; Bernard, E.; Fourier, A.; Lowe, R. G. T.; Spiers, J. G.; Hill, A. F.; Cheng, L.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23292854
Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disease characterized by the deposition of misfolded proteins leading to the death of motor neurons. Several ALS-associated proteins, including TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) and Superoxide dismutase-1 (SOD-1), have been linked to small extracellular vesicles (EVs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Familial risk of postpartum psychosis
Authors: Kepinska, A. P.; Robakis, T.; Humphreys, K.; Liu, X.; Kahn, R. S.; Munk-Olsen, T.; Bergink, V.; Mahjani, B.
Score: 20.4, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23292910
BackgroundPostpartum psychosis, a mood disorder triggered by childbirth, is one of the most severe psychiatric conditions, with high risks of suicide and infanticide if untreated. While it is evident that genetic factors play a crucial role in disorder risk, the exact extent of their importance is yet to be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 890.6, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Frequency of Atypical Pulmonary Manifestations of COVID-19 Patients on Chest CTscan: A cross-sectional study
Authors: Borji, S.; Isavand, P.; Azami, M.; Ghafouri, E.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.23293261
BackgroundChest CT examination is significant in COVID-19 diagnosis due to its high sensitivity. Although typical chest CT findings have been discussed thoroughly in the literature throughout the pandemic, we aimed to investigate the prevalence of the atypical conclusions during the start of the Omicron variant insurgency and compare the results to studies conducted before its outbreak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 14.5, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT identifies gender disparities in scientific peer review
Authors: Verharen, J. P. H.
Score: 14.4, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549552
The peer review process is a critical step in ensuring the quality of scientific research. However, its subjectivity has raised concerns. To investigate this issue, I examined over 500 publicly available peer review reports from 200 published neuroscience papers in 2022-2023. OpenAIs generative artificial intelligence ChatGPT was used to analyze language use in these reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The MidPIC study: Midwives knowledge, perspectives and learning needs regarding preconception and interconception care
Authors: Bradfield, Z.; Leefhelm, E.; Soh, S.-E.; Black, K.; Boyle, J.; Kuliukas, L.; Harrison, C.; Homer, C. S.; Smith, R. M.; Skouteris, H.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293432
BackgroundPreconception and interconception care improves the health outcomes of women and communities. ProblemLittle is known about how prepared and willing Australian midwives are to provide preconception and interconception care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alterations of the gut microbiome are associated with epigenetic age acceleration and physical fitness
Authors: Torma, F.; Kerepesi, C.; Jokai, M.; Bakonyi, P.; Koltai, E.; Babszki, G.; Ligeti, B.; Kalcsevszki, R.; McGreevy, K. M.; Horvath, S.; Radak, Z.
Score: 38.0, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292191
Epigenetic clocks can measure aging and predict the incidence of diseases and mortality. Higher levels of physical fitness are associated with a slower aging process and a healthier lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Chemogenetic manipulation of endogenous proteins in fission yeast using a self-localizing ligand-induced protein translocation (SLIPT) system
Authors: Nakamura, A.; Goto, Y.; Sugiyama, H.; Tsukiji, S.; Aoki, K.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550911
Cells sense extracellular stimuli through membrane receptors and process the information through an intracellular signaling network. Protein translocation triggers intracellular signaling, and techniques such as chemically induced dimerization (CID) have been used to manipulate signaling pathways by altering the subcellular localization of signaling molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic exploration of prokaryotic form I rubisco maximal carboxylation rates
Authors: de Pins, B.; Greenspoon, L.; Bar-On, Y. M.; Shamshoum, M.; Ben-Nissan, R.; Milshtein, E.; Davidi, D.; Sharon, I.; Mueller-Cajar, O.; Noor, E.; Milo, R.
Score: 18.4, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550689
Autotrophy is the basis for complex life on Earth. Its physiological limits are largely constrained by rubisco - the enzyme that catalyzes almost all carbon fixation on the planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Welding fume exposure is associated with medial temporal lobe microstructural features resembling early Alzheimer disease
Authors: Lee, E.; Kim, J.; Prado-Rico, J. M.; Du, G.; Lewis, M. M.; Kong, L.; Yanosky, J. D.; Eslinger, P. J.; Kim, B.-G.; Hong, Y.-S.; Mailman, R. B.; Huang, X.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292828
IntroductionWelding fumes contain a mixture of metals and are an epitype for environmental metal-related neurotoxicity. Past studies of welders focused largely on basal ganglia regions and their association with parkinsonism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Routine surveillance of kidney allograft rejection using a fully automated urinary CXCL9 and CXCL10 immunoassay
Authors: Tinel, C.; Sauvaget, V.; Aouni, L.; Lamarthee, B.; Leclaire, C.; Legendre, C.; Marquet, P.; Normand, C.; Rabant, M.; Terzi, F.; Anglicheau, D.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293106
BackgroundFor kidney transplant recipients, assessing non-invasively the individualized risk of acute rejection is one of the most unmet need. Urinary chemokines are one of the short-term most promising biomarkers, because of their simple and low-cost analytical method in easily accessible samples, and their high diagnostic performance consistently assessed over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms in a prospective cohort of COVID-19 survivors
Authors: Gomes, C. M.; Hisano, M.; Souza, J. D.; Henriques, J. V. T.; De Bessa, J.; Moromizato, J.; Bosi, T.; Mazoni, R.; Gismondi, J.; Camargo, B.; Sammour, Z. M.; Bruschini, H.; Battistella, L. R.; Nahas, W. C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293500
PurposeTo analyze the prevalence of lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in patients who survived moderate and severe forms of COVID-19 and the risk factors for LUTS six months after hospital discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 10:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>If it&amp;#39;s there, could it be a bear?
Authors: Foxon, F.
Score: 814.5, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.01.14.524058
It has been suggested that the American black bear (Ursus americanus) may be responsible for a significant number of purported sightings of an alleged unknown species of hominid in North America. Previous analyses have identified correlation between sasquatch or bigfoot sightings and black bear populations in the Pacific Northwest using ecological niche models and simple models of expected animal sightings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
