<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends and Adverse Outcomes of Xylazine Misuse: A Digital Surveillance Study
Authors: Bhagavathula, A. S.; Aldhaleei, W. A.; Kim, S.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302075
BackgroundXylazine is an animal tranquilizer without approved medical use in humans that is increasingly being misused as an adulterant in illicit drugs. This study aimed to characterize national trends and adverse outcomes associated with the emerging misuse of xylazine using digital surveillance data. MethodsWe examined online search trends and social media discussions related to xylazine misuse in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Repeated Hand Grip Strength is an Objective Marker for Disability and Severity of Key Symptoms in Post-COVID ME/CFS
Authors: Paffrath, A.; Kim, L.; Kedor, C.; Stein, E.; Rust, R.; Freitag, H.; Hoppmann, U.; Hanitsch, L. G.; Bellmann-Strobl, J.; Wittke, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Sotzny, F.
Score: 92.8, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301776
Post-COVID Syndrome (PCS) refers to a diverse array of symptoms that persist beyond 3 months of the acute phase of a SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Noxious stimulation induces self-protective behaviour in bumblebees
Authors: Gibbons, M.; Pasquini, E.; Kowalewska, A.; Read, E.; Gibson, S.; Crump, A.; Solvi, C.; Versace, E.; Chittka, L.
Score: 148.1, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575734
Self-grooming directed towards a noxiously-stimulated body part is one indicator that an animal may feel pain. In insects, the lack of evidence for such behaviour has been widely argued to reflect the absence of pain experiences. Here, we tested whether bumblebees (Bombus terrestris) selectively groom one of their antennae that was touched with a noxiously-heated (65 {square}C) probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Molecular basis of ligand promiscuity, structural mimicry, and atypical dimerization in the chemokine receptors
Authors: Saha, S.; Sano, F. K.; Sharma, S.; Ganguly, M.; Saha, S.; Akasaka, H.; Kobayashi, T. A.; Zaidi, N.; Mishra, S.; Dalal, A.; Mohapatra, S.; Yadav, M.; Itoh, Y.; Leurs, R.; Chevigne, A.; Banerjee, R.; Shihoya, W.; Nureki, O.; SHUKLA, A. K.
Score: 26.3, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.578380
Selectivity of natural agonists for their cognate receptors is one of the hallmarks of the members of GPCR family, and it is crucial for the specificity of downstream signal-transduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>A general platform for targeting MHC-II antigens via a single loop
Authors: Du, H.; Liu, J.; Jude, K. M.; Yang, X.; Li, Y.; Bell, B.; Yang, H.; Kassardjian, A.; Mobedi, A.; Parekh, U.; Sperberg, A.; Julien, J.-P.; Mellins, E.; Garcia, K. C.; Huang, P.
Score: 39.3, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577489
Class-II major histocompatibility complexes (MHC-IIs) are central to the communications between CD4&amp;#43; T cells and antigen presenting cells (APCs), but intrinsic structural features associated with MHC-II make it difficult to develop a general targeting system with high affinity and antigen specificity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>LazyAF, a pipeline for accessible medium-scale in silico prediction of protein-protein interactions
Authors: McLean, T. C.
Score: 102.6, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.577767
Artificial intelligence has revolutionized the field of protein structure prediction. However, with more powerful and complex software being developed, it is accessibility and ease of use rather than capability that is quickly becoming a limiting factor to end users. Here, I present a Google Colaboratory-based pipeline, named LazyAF, which integrates the existing ColabFold BATCH to streamline the process of medium-scale protein-protein interaction prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>The accomplices: Heparan sulfates and N-glycans foster SARS-CoV-2 spike:ACE2 receptor binding and virus priming
Authors: Paiardi, G.; Ferraz, M.; Rusnati, M.; Wade, R. C.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.578888
The SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein mediates virus attachment to human host cells by binding angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) and heparan sulfate (HS) proteoglycans. To elucidate the structure, dynamics, and functional consequences of these interactions, we carried out microsecond-long all-atom molecular dynamics simulations, followed by random acceleration molecular dynamics simulations, of the fully glycosylated spike:ACE2 complex with and without heparin chains bound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Three-dimensional assessments are necessary to determine the true, spatially-resolved composition of tissues
Authors: Forjaz, A.; Vaz, E.; Romero, V. M.; Joshi, S.; Braxton, A. M.; Jiang, A. C.; Fujikura, K.; Cornish, T.; Hong, S.-M.; Hruban, R. H.; Wu, P.-H.; Wood, L. D.; Kiemen, A. L.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 52.8, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569986
Methods for spatially resolved cellular profiling using thinly cut sections have enabled in-depth quantitative tissue mapping to study inter-sample and intra-sample differences in normal human anatomy and disease onset and progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Treadmill Exercise Stress Echocardiography Exposes Impaired Left Ventricular Function in Patients Recovering from Hospitalization with COVID-19 Without Overt Myocarditis Versus Historical Controls
Authors: Goldstein, R. E.; Hulten, E.; Arnold, T. B.; Thomas, V. M.; Heroy, A.; Walker, E. N.; Fox, K.; Lee, H.; Libbus, J.; Marcos, B.; Hood, M. N.; Harrell, T. E.; Haigney, M. C.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.24302037
BackgroundUsual clinical testing rarely reveals cardiac abnormalities persisting after hospitalization for COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dissecting reprogramming heterogeneity at single-cell resolution using scTF-seq
Authors: Liu, W.; Saelens, W.; Rainer, P.; Biocanin, M.; Gardeux, V.; Gralak, A.; van Mierlo, G.; Russeil, J.; Liu, T.; Chen, W.; Deplancke, B.
Score: 26.6, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.577921
Reprogramming approaches often produce heterogeneous cell fates and the mechanisms behind this heterogeneity are not well-understood. To address this gap, we developed scTF-seq, a technique inducing single-cell barcoded and doxycycline-inducible TF overexpression while quantifying TF dose-dependent transcriptomic changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Somite-independent regeneration of the axolotl primary body axis
Authors: Masselink, W.; Gerber, T.; Falcon, F.; Deshayes, T.; Papadopoulos, S.-C.; Pende, M.; Singh Jamwal, V.; Taniguchi-Sugiura, Y.; Lin, T.-Y.; Kurth, T.; Wang, J.; Arendt, D.; Fei, J.-F.; Treutlein, B.; Tanaka, E. M.; Murawala, P.
Score: 22.6, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.577464
Primary body axis development is a highly conserved process that proceeds through somitogenesis and further subdivision into dermatome, myotome, and sclerotome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Sonic restoration: Acoustic stimulation enhances soil fungal biomass and activity of plant growth-promoting fungi
Authors: Robinson, J. M.; Cando-Dumancela, C.; Breed, M. F.
Score: 117.2, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575298
Ecosystem restoration interventions often utilise visible elements to restore an ecosystem (e.g., replanting native plant communities and reintroducing lost species). However, using acoustic stimulation to restore ecosystems has received little attention. Our study aimed to (a) investigate the potential effects of acoustic stimulation on fungal biomass and organic matter decomposition, which are both crucial components of ecosystem functioning and (b) assess the effect of acoustic stimulation on the growth rate and sporulation of the plant growth-promoting fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The CoLab-score rapidly and efficiently excludes COVID-19 at the emergency department without need for SARS-CoV-2 testing: a multicenter case-control study
Authors: Boer, A.-K.; Deneer, R.; Maas, M.; Ammerlaan, H.; van Balkom, R. H. H.; Leers, M. P.; Martens, R. J. H.; Buijs, M. M.; Kerremans, J. J.; Messchaert, M.; van Suijlen, J. D. E.; van Riel, N. A. W.; Scharnhorst, V.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301996
BackgroundRapid identification of emergency department (ED) patients with a possible COVID-19 infection is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the genetic contribution of cumulative behavioral factors associated with longitudinal type 2 diabetes risk highlights adiposity and the brain-metabolic axis
Authors: Carvalho, N.; He, Y.; Smadbeck, P.; Flannick, J.; Mercader, J.; Udler, M.; Manrai, A. K.; Merino, J.; Patel, C. J.
Score: 5.2, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24302019
While genetic factors, behavior, and environmental exposures form a complex web of interrelated associations in type 2 diabetes (T2D), their interaction is poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Unreliability in Simulations of COVID-19 Cases and Deaths Based on Transmission Models
Authors: Kakeya, H.; Itoh, M.; Kamijima, Y.; Nitta, T.; Umeno, Y.
Score: 316.7, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302123
Two papers authored by the same research group were published in academic journals in October 2023, both of which simulate counterfactual COVID-19 cases and deaths using transmission models. One paper estimates that the COVID-19 cases and deaths from Feb 17 to Nov 30, 2021 in Japan would have been as many as 63.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Effect of iris pigmentation of blue and brown eyed individuals with European ancestry on ability to see in low light conditions after a short-term dark adaption period.
Authors: Cain, F. E.; Yamaguchi, K.
Score: 61.8, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576074
The effect of iris depigmentation on ability to see in low light conditions has not been thoroughly investigated as an adaptive advantage that could have contributed to the evolution and persistence of blue eyes in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Functional variation in human Carbohydrate-Active enZYmes (hCAZymes) in relation to the efficacy of a FODMAP-reducing diet in IBS patients
Authors: Zamfir-Taranu, A.; Loescher, B.-S.; Carbone, F.; Hoter, A.; Esteban-Blanco, C.; Bozzarelli, I.; Torices, L.; Routhiaux, K.; Van den Houte, K.; Bonfiglio, F.; Mayr, G.; Corsetti, M.; Naim, H. Y.; Franke, A.; Tack, J.; D Amato, M.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302204
Objective: Limiting the dietary intake of carbohydrates poorly absorbed in the small intestine (FODMAPs) has therapeutic effects in some but not all irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide association analysis of composite sleep health scores in 413,904 individuals
Authors: Goodman, M.; Faquih, T.; Paz, V.; Nagarajan, P.; Lane, J.; Spitzer, B.; Maher, M.; Chung, J.; Cade, B. E.; Purcell, S. M.; Zhu, X.; Noordam, R.; Phillips, A. J. K.; Kyle, S.; Spiegelhalder, K.; Weedon, M. N.; Lawlor, D. A.; Rotter, J. I.; Taylor, K.; Isasi, C.; Sofer, T.; Dashti, H. S.; Rutter, M.; Redline, S.; Saxena, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Helicase-assisted continuous editing for programmable mutagenesis of endogenous genomes
Authors: Chen, X. D.; Chen, Z.; Wythes, G.; Zhang, Y.; Orr, B. C.; Sun, G.; Thao, K.; Vallurupalli, M.; Sun, J.; Borji, M.; Tkacik, E.; Chen, H.; Bernstein, B. E.; Chen, F.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.577593
A major challenge in human genomics is to decipher the context specific relationship of sequence to function. However, existing tools for locus specific hypermutation and evolution in the native genome context are limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Giant polyketide synthase enzymes biosynthesize a giant marine polyether biotoxin.
Authors: Fallon, T. R.; Shende, V. V.; Wierzbicki, I. H.; Auber, R. P.; Gonzalez, D. J.; Wisecaver, J. H.; Moore, B. S.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.577497
Prymnesium parvum are harmful haptophyte algae that cause massive environmental fish-kills. Their polyketide polyether toxins, the prymnesins, are amongst the largest nonpolymeric compounds in nature, alongside structurally-related health-impacting &amp;#34;red-tide&amp;#34; polyether toxins whose biosynthetic origins have been an enigma for over 40 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Unequal access to diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis in England
Authors: Ponting, C. P.; Samms, G. L.
Score: 12.0, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302070
BackgroundPeople with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS; sometimes referred to as chronic fatigue syndrome) experience very poor health-related quality of life and only rarely recover. ME/CFS has no curative treatment and no single diagnostic test. Public health and policy decisions relevant to ME/CFS require knowledge of its prevalence and barriers to diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The policy formulation process, and the role of actors in the policy formulation and implementation process: A policy analysis of the Kenyan free maternity policy
Authors: Oyugi, B.; Audi-Poquillon, Z.; Kendall, S.; Peckham, S.; Barasa, E.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.23300268
Kenya is one of the many African countries committed to advancing its health system reforms by providing affordable and equitable access to essential health services. In 2016, the Government of Kenya unveiled an expanded free maternity care policy called Linda Mama to provide essential health services for pregnant women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Prescribing pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) for HIV prevention: A cross-sectional survey of General Practitioners in Australia
Authors: Wu, J.; Fairley, C. K.; Grace, D.; Bavinton, B. R.; Fraser, D.; Chan, C.; Chow, E. P. F.; Ong, J. J.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301757
BackgroundPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is a safe and effective medication for preventing HIV acquisition. We examined Australian general practitioners (GP) knowledge of PrEP efficacy, characteristics associated with ever prescribing PrEP, and barriers to prescribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent booster improves antibody binding and neutralization against emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variants
Authors: Jain, S.; Kumar, S.; Lai, L.; Linderman, S.; Malik, A. A.; Ellis, M. L.; Godbole, S.; Solis, D.; Sahoo, M. K.; Bechnak, K.; Paredes, I.; Tanios, R.; Kazzi, B.; Dib, S. M.; Litvack, M. B.; Wimalsena, S. T.; Ciric, C.; Rostad, C.; West, R.; Teng, I.-T.; Wang, D.; Kwong, P. D.; Rouphael, N.; Pinsky, B. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Altered IgG4 Antibody Response to Repeated mRNA versus Protein COVID Vaccines
Authors: Kalkeri, R.; Zhu, M.; Cloney-Clark, S.; Plested, J. S.; Parekh, A.; Gorinson, D.; Cai, R.; Mahato, S.; Ramanathan, P.; Aurelia, L. C.; John Selva, K.; Marchese, A. M.; Fries, L.; Chung, A. W.; Dunkle, L. M.
Score: 478.3, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301374
Repeated mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination has been associated with increases in the proportion of IgG4 in spike-specific antibody responses and concurrent reductions in Fc{gamma}-mediated effector functions that may limit control of viral infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>An Empirical Study on KDIGO-Defined Acute Kidney Injury Prediction in the Intensive Care Unit
Authors: Lyu, X.; Fan, B.; Hüser, M.; Hartout, P.; Gumbsch, T.; Faltys, M.; Merz, T. M.; Rätsch, G.; Borgwardt, K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.24302063
MotivationAcute kidney injury (AKI) is a syndrome that affects a large fraction of all critically ill patients, and early diagnosis to receive adequate treatment is as imperative as it is challenging to make early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Viroid-like colonists of human microbiomes
Authors: Zheludev, I. N.; Edgar, R. C.; Galiano, M. J. L.; De la Pena, M.; Babaian, A.; Bhatt, A. S.; Fire, A. Z.
Score: 738.1, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576352
Here, we describe the &amp;#34;Obelisks,&amp;#34; a previously unrecognised class of viroid-like elements that we first identified in human gut metatranscriptomic data. &amp;#34;Obelisks&amp;#34; share several properties: (i) apparently circular RNA [~]1kb genome assemblies, (ii) predicted rod-like secondary structures encompassing the entire genome, and (iii) open reading frames coding for a novel protein superfamily, which we call the &amp;#34;Oblins&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Programmable RNA writing with trans-splicing
Authors: Schmitt-Ulms, C.; Kayabolen, A.; Manero-Carranza, M.; Zhou, N.; Donnelly, K.; Nuccio, S. P.; Kato, K.; Nishimasu, H.; Gootenberg, J. S.; Abudayyeh, O. O.
Score: 118.8, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.578223
RNA editing offers the opportunity to introduce either stable or transient modifications to nucleic acid sequence without permanent off-target effects, but installation of arbitrary edits into the transcriptome is currently infeasible. Here, we describe Programmable RNA Editing &amp;amp; Cleavage for Insertion, Substitution, and Erasure (PRECISE), a versatile RNA editing method for writing RNA of arbitrary length and sequence into existing pre-mRNAs via 5&amp;#39; or 3&amp;#39; trans-splicing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Lesions causing Alice in Wonderland Syndrome map to a common brain network linking body and size perception
Authors: Friedrich, M. U.; Baughan, E. C.; Kletenik, I.; Younger, E.; Zhao, C. W.; Howard, C.; Ferguson, M. A.; Chen, A.; Zeller, D.; Piervincenzi, C.; Tommasin, S.; Pantano, P.; Blanke, O.; Prasad, S.; Nielsen, J.; Fox, M. D.
Score: 28.0, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301332
BackgroundIn Lewis Carrolls 1865 novel &amp;#34;Alices Adventures in Wonderland&amp;#34;, the protagonist experiences distortions in the size of her body and those of others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Adult sex change leads to extensive forebrain reorganization in clownfish
Authors: Parker, C. G.; Gruenhagen, G. W.; Hegarty, B. E.; Histed, A. R.; Streelman, J. T.; Rhodes, J. S.; Johnson, Z. V.
Score: 41.0, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.577753
Sexual differentiation of the brain occurs in all major vertebrate lineages but is not well understood at a molecular and cellular level. Unlike most vertebrates, sex-changing fishes have the remarkable ability to change reproductive sex during adulthood in response to social stimuli, offering a unique opportunity to understand mechanisms by which the nervous system can initiate and coordinate sexual differentiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of cancer incidence among Marines and Navy personnel and civilian workers exposed to contaminated drinking water at USMC Base Camp Lejeune
Authors: Bove, F. J.
Score: 101.8, Published: 2024-01-29 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.27.24301873
BackgroundDrinking water at U.S. Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, North Carolina was contaminated with trichloroethylene and other industrial solvents from 1953 to 1985. MethodsA cohort cancer incidence study was conducted of Marines/Navy personnel who, between 1975 and 1985, began service and were stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina (N=154,821) or Camp Pendleton, California (N=163,484), and civilian workers employed at Camp Lejeune (N=6,494) or Camp Pendleton (N=5,797) between October 1972 and December 1985.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Convergence for Inactivation of TGFβ Signaling Is a Common Feature of Advanced Pancreatic Cancer
Authors: Hong, J.; Kohutek, Z.; Zhang, H.; Karnoub, E.-R.; Kappagantula, R.; Wood, L. D.; Iacobuzio-Donahue, C.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301554
We performed WES of 250 unique tumor tissues from 30 multiregion sampled pancreatic cancer research autopsies from patients diagnosed with advanced stage disease. We find that most genetic alterations in PDAC occur in a subclonal manner, and some genes occurred in a subclonal manner exclusively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Digital PCR-based deep quantitative profiling delineates heterogeneity and evolution of uveal melanoma
Authors: Nell, R. J.; Versluis, M.; Menger, N. V.; Verdijk, R. M.; Kroes, W. G. M.; Kapiteijn, E. H. W.; Luyten, G. P. M.; Jager, M. J.; van der Velden, P. A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301871
Uveal melanoma is an aggressive intraocular tumour characterised by a limited number of genetic alterations. However, the evolution of this malignancy remains enigmatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Adequacy of Morphological Models used in Palaeobiology
Authors: Mulvey, L. P. A.; May, M. R.; Brown, J. M.; Hoehna, S.; Wright, A. M.; Warnock, R. C. M.
Score: 31.7, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577179
Reconstructing the evolutionary history of different groups of organisms provides insight into how life originated and diversified on Earth. Phylogenetic trees are commonly used to estimate this evolutionary history, providing a hypothesis of the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>A drug cocktail of rapamycin, acarbose, and phenylbutyrate enhances resilience to features of early-stage Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease in aging mice
Authors: Wezeman, J.; Darvas, M.; Postupna, N.; Klug, J.; Mangalindan, R. S.; Keely, A.; Nguyen, K.; Johnson, C.; Rosenfeld, M.; Ladiges, W.
Score: 9.3, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577437
The process of aging is defined by the breakdown of critical maintenance pathways leading to an accumulation of damage and its associated phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Predictors of mortality among low birth weight neonates after hospital discharge in a low-resource setting: A case study in Uganda.
Authors: NSUBUGA, R.; NYENDE, S.; RUJUMBA, J.; KISAKA, S.; NANKUNDA, J.; IDRO, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292109
BackgroundMost neonatal deaths occur among low birth weight infants. However, in resource-limited settings, these infants are commonly discharged early which further exposes them to mortality. Previous studies on morbidity and mortality among low birth weight infants after early discharge mainly focused on very low birth weight infants, and none described post-discharge neonatal mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Selective degradation of multimeric proteins via chemically induced proximity to TRIM21
Authors: Lu, P.; Cheng, Y.; Xue, L.; Ren, X.; Chen, C.; Li, J.; Wu, Q.; Sun, S.; Hou, J.; Jia, W.; Li, C.; Qi, X.; Huang, N.; Han, T.
Score: 7.6, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.578122
Targeted protein degradation (TPD) has emerged as an effective strategy to eliminate disease-causing proteins by inducing their interactions with the protein degradation machinery. First-generation TPD agents exploit a limited set of broadly expressed E3 ubiquitin ligases with constitutive activity, forbidding their application to proteins requiring higher levels of targeting selectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>MXRA8 promotes adipose tissue whitening to drive obesity
Authors: Jia, W.; Giwa, R.; Moley, J. R.; Smith, G. I.; Petersen, M. C.; Field, R. L.; Abousaway, O.; Kim, A. S.; Coffey, S. R.; Varnum, S.; Wright, J. M.; Zhang, X.; Krysa, S.; Lodhi, I. J.; Abumrad, N. A.; Klein, S.; Diamond, M. S.; Brestoff, J. R.
Score: 13.1, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.578211
Matrix-remodeling associated 8 (MXRA8), also known as Dual immunoglobulin domain cell adhesion molecule (DICAM), is a type 1 transmembrane protein that reportedly binds the V{beta}3 integrin1 and regulates the differentiation of osteoclasts2 and chondrocytes3, tumor growth4, T cell trafficking5, and angiogenesis6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 190.7, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Environmental risk factors for self-harm during imprisonment: a prospective cohort study
Authors: Stephenson, T.; Harris, I.; Armstrong, C.; Fazel, S.; Short, R.; Blackwood, N.
Score: 6.2, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302059
IntroductionSelf-harm is a major public health issue in the imprisoned population. Limited high-quality evidence exists for the potential impact of prison environmental factors such as solitary confinement. This pilot prospective cohort study in a large male remand prison in England sought to estimate effect sizes of a comprehensive range of prison environmental factors on self-harming behaviours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Safety Monitoring of Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA Vaccines Among Recipients 6 months and Older in the United States
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Smith, E. R.; Gruber, J. F.; Ondari, M.; Wong, H. L.; Hu, M.; Clarke, T. C.; McEvoy, R.; Amend, K. L.; Bleacher, D. C.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Seeger, J. D.; Secora, A.; Djibo, D. A.; Song, J.; Selvam, N.; DeShazo, J. P.; Clifford, R.; Abente, E.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Automated Deep Learning Segmentation of Cardiac Inflammatory FDG PET
Authors: Poitrasson-Riviere, A.; Vanderver, M.; Hagio, T.; Arida-Moody, L.; Moody, J. B.; Renaud, J. M.; Ficaro, E. P.; Murthy, V. L.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302113
BackgroundFluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography (FDG PET) with glycolytic metabolism suppression plays a pivotal role in diagnosing cardiac sarcoidosis. Reorientation of images to match perfusion datasets is critical and myocardial segmentation enables consistent image scaling and quantification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>The effect of post-acute rehabilitation setting on 90-day mobility after stroke: A difference-in-difference analysis
Authors: French, M. A.; Hayes, H. A.; Johnson, J. K.; Young, D. L.; Roemmich, R. T.; Raghavan, P.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24301026
BackgroundAfter discharged from the hospital for acute stroke, individuals typically receive rehabilitation in one of three settings: inpatient rehabilitation facilities (IRFs), skilled nursing facilities (SNFs), or home with community services (i.e., home health or outpatient clinics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Hip shape shows a causal effect on hip fracture but not hip osteoarthritis: findings from a GWAS meta-analysis and causal analyses
Authors: Faber, B. G.; Frysz, M.; Zheng, J.; Lin, H.; Flynn, K.; Ebsim, R.; Saunders, F. R.; Beynon, R. A.; Gregory, J. S.; Aspden, R. M.; Harvey, N. C.; Lindner, C.; Cootes, T.; Evans, D.; Davey Smith, G.; Gao, X.; Wang, S.; Kemp, J.; Tobias, J.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Structured Peer Review: Pilot results from 23 Elsevier Journals
Authors: Malicki, M.; Mehmani, B.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.578440
Background. Reviewers rarely comment on the same aspects of a manuscript, making it difficult to properly assess manuscripts&amp;#39; quality and the quality of the peer review process. It was the goal of this pilot study to evaluate structured peer review implementation by: 1) exploring if and how reviewers answered structured peer review questions, 2) analysing reviewer agreement, 3) comparing that agreement to agreement before implementation of structured peer review, and 4) further enhancing the piloted set of structured peer review questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA-Diffusion: Leveraging Generative Models for Controlling Chromatin Accessibility and Gene Expression via Synthetic Regulatory Elements
Authors: Ferreira DaSilva, L.; Senan, S.; Patel, Z. M.; Reddy, A. J.; Gabbita, S.; Nussbaum, Z.; Cordova, C. M. V.; Wenteler, A.; Weber, N.; Tunjic, T. M.; Khan, T. A.; Li, Z.; Smith, C. R.; Bejan, M.; Louis, L. K.; Cornejo, P.; Connell, W.; Wong, E. S.; Meuleman, W.; Pinello, L.
Score: 64.6, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Organellomics: AI-driven deep organellar phenotyping of human neurons
Authors: Molitor, L.; Krispin, S.; Van-Zuiden, W.; Danino, Y. M.; Rudberg, N.; Bar, C.; Amzallag, E.; Lubliner, J.; Siany, A.; Eitan, C.; Cohen, Y.; Yacovzada, N. S.; Hornstein, E.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.572110
Systematic assessment of organelle architectures in cells, known as the organellome, could provide valuable insights into cellular states and disease pathologies but remains largely uncharted. Here, we devised a novel pipeline combining self-supervised deep learning and transfer learning to generate a Neuronal Organellomics Vision Atlas (NOVA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 10:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Microalgal biofilm induces larval settlement in the model marine worm Platynereis dumerilii
Authors: Hird, C.; Jekely, G.; Williams, E. A.
Score: 8.3, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576855
A free-swimming larval stage features in many marine invertebrate life cycles. To transition to a seafloor-dwelling juvenile stage, larvae need to settle out of the plankton, guided by specific environmental cues that lead them to an ideal habitat for their future life on the seafloor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
