<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Gene expression differences associated with alcohol use disorder in human brain
Authors: Willis, C.; White, J. D.; Minto, M. S.; Quach, B. C.; Han, S.; Tao, R.; Shin, J. H.; Deep-Soboslay, A.; Hyde, T.; Mayfield, R. D.; Webb, B. T.; Johnson, E. O.; Kleinman, J. E.; Bierut, L. J.; Hancock, D. B.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24301386
Excessive alcohol consumption is a leading cause of preventable death worldwide. Neurobiological mechanisms associated with alcohol use disorder (AUD) remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Noxious stimulation induces self-protective behaviour in bumblebees
Authors: Gibbons, M.; Pasquini, E.; Kowalewska, A.; Read, E.; Gibson, S.; Crump, A.; Solvi, C.; Versace, E.; Chittka, L.
Score: 70.0, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575734
Self-grooming directed towards a noxiously-stimulated body part is one indicator that an animal may feel pain. In insects, the lack of evidence for such behaviour has been widely argued to reflect the absence of pain experiences. Here, we tested whether bumblebees (Bombus terrestris) selectively groom one of their antennae that was touched with a noxiously-heated (65 {square}C) probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging co-evolutionary insights and AI-based structural modeling to unravel receptor-peptide ligand-binding mechanisms
Authors: Snoeck, S.; Lee, H. K.; Schmid, M. W.; Bender, K. W.; Neeracher, M. J.; Fernandez-Fernandez, A. D.; Santiago, J.; Zipfel, C.
Score: 31.0, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.575556
Secreted signaling peptides are central regulators of growth, development, and stress responses, but specific steps in the evolution of these peptides and their receptors are not well understood. In addition, the molecular mechanisms of peptide-receptor binding are only known for a few examples, primarily owing to the limited availability of structural capabilities to few laboratories worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Surface Patterned Omniphobic Tiles (SPOTs): a versatile platform for scalable liquid handling
Authors: Shiri, S.; Qazi, M. J.; Tan, S.; Albo, J.; Chen, A.; Fukuda, R.; Jain, M. S.; Menesses, M.; Nchinda, N.; Ahmed, G.; Gallegos, A.; Gangishetty, M.; Congreve, D.; Cira, N. J.
Score: 23.4, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.575712
Manipulating liquids is a ubiquitous need for experiments across numerous scientific disciplines. To overcome limitations of current methods, we introduce Surface Patterned Omniphobic Tiles (SPOTs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>When the pen is mightier than the sword: semi-automatic 2 and 3D image labelling
Authors: Hollandi, R.; Bauer, D.; Diosdi, A.; Schrettner, B.; Toth, T.; Hirling, D.; Hollandi, G.; Harmati, M.; Molnar, J.; Horvath, P.
Score: 38.4, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575658
Data is the driving engine of learning-based algorithms, the creation of which fundamentally determines the performance, accuracy, generalizability and quality of any model or method trained on it. When only skilled or trained personnel can create reliable annotations, assisted software solutions are desirable to reduce the time and effort the expert must spend on labelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Localising elements in single-particle reconstructions by REEL-EM: Reconstructed Electron Energy-Loss - Elemental Mapping
Authors: Pfeil-Gardiner, O.; Rosa, H. V. D.; Riedel, D.; Chen, Y. S.; Lorks, D.; Kukelhan, P.; Linck, M.; Muller, H.; Van Petegem, F.; Murphy, B. J.
Score: 34.5, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.575858
For structures determined by single particle cryo-EM, no technique currently exists for mapping elements to defined locations, leading to errors in the assignment of metals and other ions, cofactors, substrates, inhibitors, and lipids that play essential roles in activity and regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Deciphering the diversity and sequence of extracellular matrix and cellular spatial patterns in lung adenocarcinoma using topological data analysis
Authors: Yoon, I. H. R.; Jenkins, R.; Colliver, E.; Zhang, H.; Novo, D.; Moore, D.; Ramsden, Z.; Rullan, A.; Fu, X.; Yuan, Y.; Harrington, H. A.; Swanton, C.; Byrne, H. M.; Sahai, E.
Score: 31.1, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574362
Extracellular matrix (ECM) organization influences cancer development and progression. It modulates the invasion of cancer cells and can hinder the access of immune cells to cancer cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Sildenafil&amp;#39;s Effectiveness in the Primary Coronary Slow Flow Phenomenon: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial
Authors: Andishmand, A.; Seyed Hossaini, S. M.; Namayandeh, s. M.; Mirjalili, S. R.; Adelzadeh, E.; Entezari, A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301510
BackgroundOn the one hand, the coronary slow flow phenomenon (CSFP) may cause recurrence of chest pain, prompting medical examinations and further healthcare expenses, and on the other side, it can result in myocardial infarction, ventricular arrhythmia, and sudden cardiac death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>A centromere-derived retroelement RNA localizes in cis and is a core element of the transcriptional landscape of Drosophila centromeres
Authors: Santinello, B.; Sun, R.; Amjad, A.; Hoyt, S. J.; Ouyang, L.; Courret, C.; Drennan, R.; Leo, L.; Larracuente, A. M.; Core, L. M.; O&amp;#39;Neill, R. J.; Mellone, B. G.
Score: 25.2, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.574223
Centromeres are essential chromosomal landmarks that dictate the point of attachment between chromosomes and spindle microtubules during cell division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Data-driven personalised recommendations for eczema treatment using a Bayesian model of severity dynamics
Authors: Hurault, G.; Stalder, J. F.; Saint Aroman, M.; Tanaka, R. J.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.24301575
Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a chronic inflammatory skin disease. AD has heterogeneous phenotypes, making it challenging to predict treatment effects for each patient and to generate personalised treatment recommendations. Here we aim to develop a computational model that predicts the evolution of AD severity and generates treatment recommendations for individual patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Sox9 links biliary maturation to branching morphogenesis
Authors: Hrncir, H. R.; Bombin, S.; Goodloe, B.; Hogan, C. B.; Jadi, O.; Gracz, A. D.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.574730
Branching morphogenesis couples cellular differentiation with development of tissue architecture. Intrahepatic bile duct (IHBD) morphogenesis is initiated with biliary epithelial cell (BEC) specification and eventually forms a heterogeneous network of large ducts and small ductules. Here, we show that Sox9 is required for developmental establishment of small ductules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>eDITH: an R-package to spatially project eDNA-based biodiversity across river networks with minimal prior information
Authors: Carraro, L.; Altermatt, F.
Score: 30.3, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575835
O_LIEcological and ecosystem monitoring is rapidly shifting towards using environmental DNA (eDNA) data, particularly in aquatic systems. This approach enables a combined coverage of biodiversity across all major organismal groups and the assessment of ecological indices. Yet, most current approaches are not exploiting the full potential of eDNA data, largely interpreting results in a localized perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence of metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver disease and its association with glycemic control in persons with type 2 diabetes in Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Ekpor, E.; Akyirem, S.; Adade Duodu, P.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.24300699
Metabolic dysfunction-associated fatty liver (MAFLD) and type 2 diabetes (T2D) are interconnected metabolic disorders that pose serious repercussions on health, yet a comprehensive understanding of the extent of their co-occurrence in Africa is lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Estimated number of lives directly saved by COVID-19 vaccination programs in the WHO European Region, December 2020 to March 2023
Authors: Mesle, M. M.; Brown, J.; Mook, P.; Katz, M. A.; Hagan, J.; Pastore, R.; Nitzan, D.; Benka, B.; Redlberger-Fritz, M.; Bossuyt, N.; Stouten, V.; Vernemmen, C.; Constantinou, E.; Kyncl, J.; Maly, M.; Sanca, O.; Grove Krause, T.; Skafte Vestergaard, L.; Leino, T.; Poukka, E.; Gkolfinopoulou, K.; Mellou, K.; Maria Tsintziloni, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Effect of iris pigmentation of blue and brown eyed individuals with European ancestry on ability to see in low light conditions after a short-term dark adaption period.
Authors: Cain, F. E.; Yamaguchi, K.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576074
The effect of iris depigmentation on ability to see in low light conditions has not been thoroughly investigated as an adaptive advantage that could have contributed to the evolution and persistence of blue eyes in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Clonal hematopoiesis associated non-small cell lung cancer risk is potentiated by small particulate matter air pollution
Authors: Vlasschaert, C.; Buttigieg, M.; Pershad, Y.; Lanktree, M. B.; Aldrich, M. C.; Rauh, M. J.; Bick, A. G.
Score: 26.2, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301439
Small particulate matter air pollution (PM2.5) is a recognized driver of non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) among non-smoking individuals. Inhaled PM2.5 recruits pro-inflammatory macrophages to the air-lung interface, which promotes malignant lung epithelial cell growth and progression to overt cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Accurate inference of population history in the presence of background selection
Authors: Cousins, T.; Tabin, D.; Patterson, N.; Reich, D.; Durvasula, A.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576291
1All published methods for learning about demographic history make the simplifying assumption that the genome evolves neutrally, and do not seek to account for the effects of natural selection on patterns of variation. This is a major concern, as ample work has demonstrated the pervasive effects of natural selection and in particular background selection (BGS) on patterns of genetic variation in diverse species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Comparative analysis of multiplexed in situ gene expression profiling technologies
Authors: Hartman, A.; Satija, R.
Score: 137.8, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575135
The burgeoning interest in in situ multiplexed gene expression profiling technologies has opened new avenues for understanding cellular behavior and interactions. In this study, we present a comparative benchmark analysis of six in situ gene expression profiling methods, including both commercially available and academically developed methods, using publicly accessible mouse brain datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Hypertension: Examining Variable Blood Pressure&amp;#39;s Role in Cognition and Brain Structure
Authors: Morrison, C.; Oliver, M. D.; Kamal, F.; Dadar, M.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.24301335
Structured AbstractO_ST_ABSImportanceC_ST_ABSHypertension is a known risk factor for cognitive decline and structural brain changes in aging and dementia. In addition to high blood pressure (BP), individuals may also experience variable BP, meaning that their BP fluctuates between normal and high. It is currently unclear what the effects of variable BP are on cognition and brain structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of higher uptake of plant-based diets in England: model-based estimates of health care resource use and health-related quality of life
Authors: Henderson, N.; Sampson, C. J.
Score: 11.8, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300536
Plant-based diets have grown in popularity in recent years, in part because of the perceived health benefits; higher consumption of vegetables and other healthy foods is associated with better nutrition and reduced risk of disease. In this study, we estimate the potential impact of higher uptake of a 100% plant-based (vegan) diet in England from the perspective of the National Health Service (NHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Patient Portal Engagement Associated with Improved Weight Loss Outcomes in Post-Bariatric Surgery Patients
Authors: Zhang, X.; Kang, K.; Yan, C.; Feng, Y.; Vandekar, S.; Yu, D.; Rosenbloom, S. T.; Samuels, J.; Srivastava, G.; Williams, B.; Albaugh, V. L.; English, W. J.; Flynn, C. R.; Chen, Y.
Score: 5.6, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24301550
BackgroundBariatric surgery is an effective intervention for obesity, but it requires comprehensive postoperative self-management to achieve optimal outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>A Healthcare Service Delivery and Epidemiological Model for Investigating Resource Allocation for Health: The Thanzi La Onse Model
Authors: Hallett, T. B.; Mangal, T. D.; Tamuri, A. U.; Arinaminpathy, N.; Cambiano, V.; Chalkley, M.; Collins, J. H.; Cooper, J.; Gillman, M. S.; Giordano, M.; Graham, M. M.; Graham, W.; Janouskova, E.; Jewell, B. L.; Lin, I. L.; Smith, R. M.; Manthalu, G.; Mnjowe, E.; Mohan, S.; Molaro, M.; Ngambi, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Are socio-demographic factors associated with electronic Health Information System utilization? A cross sectional study of the District Health Information System -2 (DHIS-2) in Burundi
Authors: Yandemye, I.; Nimubona, A.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300804
The utilization of Electronic Health Information System is crucial in informing credible decision-making process, especially in developing countries. We aimed to investigate the socio-demographic factors of Health workers that are associated with their utilization of the DHIS-2 platform in Burundi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Proliferative History Is a Novel Driver of Clinical Outcome in Splenic Marginal Zone Lymphoma
Authors: Parker, H.; Mirandari, A.; Jaramillo Oquendo, C.; Duran-Ferrer, M.; Stevens, B.; Buermann, L.; Amarasinghe, H. E.; Thomas, J.; Kadalayil, L.; Carr, L.; Syeda, S.; Sakthipakan, M.; Parry, M.; Davis, Z.; McIver-Brown, N.; Xochelli, A.; Ennis, S.; Scarfo, L.; Ghia, P.; Kalpadakis, C.; Pangalis, G.; Rossi, D.; Wagner, S.; Ahearne, M.; Seifert, M.; Plass, C.; Weichenhan, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>A Randomised Clinical Trial of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of VRC07-523LS Administered via Different Routes and Doses (HVTN 127/HPTN 087)
Authors: Walsh, S. R.; Gay, C. L.; Karuna, S. T.; Hyrien, O.; Skalland, T.; Mayer, K. H.; Sobieszczyk, M. E.; Baden, L. R.; Goepfert, P. A.; del Rio, C.; Pantaleo, G.; Andrew, P.; Karg, C.; He, Z.; Lu, H.; Paez, C. A.; Baumblatt, J. A. G.; Polakowski, L. L.; Chege, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Intestinal helminth infection impairs vaccine-induced T cell responses and protection against SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Desai, P.; Karl, C. E.; Ying, B.; Liang, C.-Y.; Garcia-Salum, T.; Santana, A. C.; Caten, F. T.; Urban, J. F.; Elbashir, S. M.; Edwards, D. K.; Ribeiro, S. P.; Thackray, L. B.; Sekaly, R.-P. K.; Diamond, M. S.
Score: 52.8, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.575588
Although vaccines have reduced COVID-19 disease burden, their efficacy in helminth infection endemic areas is not well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Blood transcriptomics reveal persistent SARS-CoV-2 RNA and candidate biomarkers in Long COVID patients
Authors: MENEZES, S. M.; JAMOULLE, M.; Carletto, M. P.; Van Holm, B.; Moens, L.; Meyts, I.; Maes, P.; Van Weyenbergh, J.
Score: 292.8, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.24301293
With an estimated 65 million individuals suffering from Long COVID, validated therapeutic strategies as well as non-invasive biomarkers are direly needed to guide clinical management. We used blood digital transcriptomics in search of viral persistence and Long COVID diagnostic biomarkers in a real-world, general practice-based setting with a long clinical follow-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>An infection and pathogenesis mouse model of SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 4150.5, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) is highly attenuated, but can cause mortality in a specifically designed human ACE2-transgenic mouse model, making it an invaluable surrogate model for evaluating the efficacy of drugs and vaccines against SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Discovery and Characterization of a Pan-betacoronavirus S2-binding antibody
Authors: Johnson, N. V.; Wall, S.; Kramer, K.; Holt, C.; Periasamy, S.; Richardson, S.; Suryadevara, N.; Andreano, E.; Paciello, I.; Pierleoni, G.; Piccini, G.; Huang, Y.; Ge, P.; Allen, J.; Uno, N.; Shiakolas, A.; Pilewski, K.; Nargi, R.; Abu-Shmais, A.; Sutton, R.; Parks, R.; Haynes, B.; Carnahan, R.; Crowe, J.; Montomoli, E.; Rappuoli, R.; Bukreyev, A.; Ross, T.; Sautto, G.; Georgiev, I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>A pathogenic variant in RAB32 causes autosomal dominant Parkinsons disease and activates LRRK2 kinase
Authors: Gustavsson, E. K.; Follett, J.; Trinh, J.; Barodia, S. K.; Real, R.; Liu, Z.; Grant-Peters, M.; Fox, J. D.; Appel-Cresswell, S.; Stoessl, J. A.; Rajput, A.; Rajput, A. H.; Auer, R.; Tilney, R.; Sturm, M.; Haack, T. B.; Lesage, S.; Tesson, C.; Brice, A.; Vilarino-Gueell, C.; Ryten, M.; Goldberg, M. S.; West, A. B.; Hu, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A hierarchical atlas of the human cerebellum for functional precision mapping
Authors: Nettekoven, C. R.; Zhi, D.; Shahshahani, L.; Luisa Pinho, A.; Saadon-Grosmann, N.; Buckner, R. L.; Diedrichsen, J.
Score: 69.4, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.557689
The human cerebellum is activated by a wide variety of cognitive and motor tasks. Previous functional atlases have relied on single task-based or resting-state fMRI datasets. Here, we present a functional atlas that integrates information from 7 large-scale datasets, outperforming existing group atlasses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 95.0, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Understanding diagnostic delay for endometriosis: a scoping review
Authors: Fryer, J.; Mason-Jones, A. J.; Woodward, A.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24300988
IntroductionDiagnostic delay for endometriosis is a well-established phenomenon. Despite this, little is known about where in the health care system these delays occur or why they occur. Our review is the first attempt to synthesise and analyse this evidence. MethodsA systematic scoping review with a pre-specified protocol was used to incorporate the global mixed methods literature on diagnostic delay for endometriosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Automation risk and subjective wellbeing in the UK
Authors: Zheng, J.; Rohenkohl, B.; Barahona, M.; Clarke, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301484
The personal well-being of workers may be influenced by the risk of job automation brought about by technological innovation. Here we use data from the Understanding Society survey in the UK and a fixed-effects model to examine associations between working in a highly automatable job and life and job satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Early evolution of the ecdysozoan body plan
Authors: Wang, D.; Qiang, Y.; Guo, J.; Vannier, J.; Song, Z.; Peng, J.; Zhang, B.; Sun, J.; Yu, Y.; Zhang, Y.; Zhang, T.; Yang, X.; Han, J.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575973
Extant ecdysozoans (moulting animals) are represented by a great variety of vermiform or articulated organisms. However, controversies remain about the nature of their ancestral body plan although the vermiform hypothesis seems to prevail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Innate Immune Activation and Mitochondrial ROS Invoke Persistent Cardiac Conduction System Dysfunction after COVID-19
Authors: Ashok, D.; Liu, T.; Criscione, J.; Prakash, M.; Kim, B.; Chow, J.; Craney, M.; Papanicolaou, K.; Sidor, A.; Foster, D. B.; Pekosz, A.; Villano, J.; Kim, D.-H.; O&amp;#39;Rourke, B.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574280
BackgroundCardiac risk rises during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and in long COVID syndrome in humans, but the mechanisms behind COVID-19-linked arrhythmias are unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Asymptomatic hypoglycemia among preterm newborns: a cross-sectional analysis.
Authors: Salum, S. S.; Kalabamu, F. S.; Fataki, M. R.; Omary, S. A.; Mohamed, U. H.; Kizwi, H. A.; Leshabari, K. M.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300665
BackgroundHypoglycemia is the commonest metabolic abnormality encountered in newborns. Preterm newborns are the group with the highest risk of clinically significant hypoglycemia. However exact factors associated with asymptomatic neonatal hypoglycemia is not known. ObjectiveTo assess factors associated with asymptomatic hypoglycemia among preterm newborns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Pharmacogenomic diversity in psychiatry: Challenges and Opportunities in Africa
Authors: Ahmed, M. B.; Mulugeta, A.; Okewole, N.; Schubert, K. O.; Clark, S.; Iyegbe, C.; Amare, A. T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.24301341
BackgroundPharmacogenomic studies on psychiatric drugs have slowly identified genetic variations that influence drug metabolism and treatment effectiveness in patients with mental illness. Because most of these studies predominantly centered on people of European descent, there remains a substantial knowledge gap on the clinical implications of current pharmacogenomic evidence in multi-ancestry populations such as Africans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Noncaloric monosaccharides induce excessive sprouting angiogenesis in zebrafish via foxo1a-marcksl1a signal
Authors: Wang, X.; Zhao, J.; Xu, J.; Li, B.; Liu, X.; Xie, G.; Duan, X.; Liu, D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576182
Artificially sweetened beverages containing noncaloric monosaccharides were suggested as healthier alternatives to sugar-sweetened beverages. Nevertheless, the potential detrimental effects of these noncaloric monosaccharides on blood vessel function remain inadequately understood. Presently, we have established a zebrafish model that exhibits significant excessive angiogenesis induced by high glucose, resembling the hyperangiogenic characteristics observed in proliferative diabetic retinopathy (PDR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Intestinal barrier function in the naked mole-rat: an emergent model for gastrointestinal insights
Authors: Aguilera-Lizarraga, J.; Ritoux, A.; Bulmer, D.; Smith, E. S. J.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576063
The intestinal barrier plays a crucial role in homeostasis, both by facilitating absorption of nutrients and providing a tight shield to prevent the invasion by either pathogen or commensal microorganisms. Intestinal barrier malfunction is associated with systemic inflammation, oxidative stress, and decreased insulin sensitivity, which may lead to the dysregulation of other tissues such as the liver, fat, skeletal muscle, and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>LysM-RLK plays an ancestral symbiotic function in plants
Authors: Teyssier, E.; Grat, S.; Rich, M. K.; Delaux, P.-M.; Mbengue, M.
Score: 37.7, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575821
To ensure their water and mineral nutrition, most land plants form arbuscular mycorrhiza (AM) with soil-borne Glomeromycota fungi 1. This [~]450 million years old symbiosis was key in driving land colonisation by plants2. In angiosperms, AM is thought to be initiated via the perception by the host plant of AM-fungi derived chito- and lipochito-oligosaccharides leading to the activation of a conserved signalling pathway referred to as the Common Symbiosis Pathway3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>The antidepressant effects of vaporized N,N-Dimethyltryptamine: a preliminary report in treatment-resistant depression
Authors: Falchi-Carvalho, M.; Barros, H.; Bolcont, R.; Laborde, S.; Wiessner, I.; Silva, S. R. B.; Montanini, D.; Barbosa, D.; Teixeira, E.; Florence-Vilela, R.; Almeida, R.; Macedo, R. K. A.; Arichelle, F.; J. Pantrigo, E.; Arcoverde, E.; Galvao-Coelho, N.; Araujo, D. B.; Palhano-Fontes, F.
Score: 32.2, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.23300610
IntroductionN,N-Dimethyltryptamine (DMT), a naturally occurring psychedelic tryptamine contained in the indigenous ayahuasca brew has shown antidepressant effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1350.5, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
ImportancePhase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects. ObjectiveConduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of the phase 3 trials to assess overall and non-specific health effects of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 20.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathogenic autoantibody internalization in myositis
Authors: Pinal-Fernandez, I.; Munoz-Braceras, S.; Casal-Dominguez, M.; Pak, K.; Torres-Ruiz, J.; Musai, J.; Dell&amp;#39;Orso, S.; Naz, F.; Islam, S.; Gutierrez-Cruz, G.; Dolores Cano, M.; Matas-Garcia, A.; Padrosa, J.; Tobias-Baraja, E.; Garrabou, G.; Aldecoa, I.; Espinosa, G.; Simeon-Aznar, C. P.; Guillen-Del-Castillo, A.; Gil-Vila, A.; Trallero-Araguas, E.; Christopher-Stine, L.; Lloyd, T. E.; Liewluck, T.; Naddaf, E.; Stenzel, W.; Greenberg, S. A.; Maria Grau, J.; Selva-O&amp;#39;Callaghan, A.; Milisenda, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Anticipatory Emotions and Academic Performance: The Role of Boredom in a Preservice Teachers&amp;#39; Lab Experience
Authors: Ochoa de Alda, J. A. G.; Marcos-Merino, J. M.; Valares-Masa, C.; Esteban-Gallego, R.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575518
Affective experiences within academic contexts significantly influence educational outcomes. Despite this, the literature reveals a gap in generalising these effects to specific classroom activities, partly arising from the absence of suitable instruments to measure emotions in situational educational scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of exercise, metformin, and their combination on glucose metabolism in individuals with impaired glycemic control: A systematic review and network meta-analysis
Authors: Zhao, T.; Yang, Q.; Feuerbacher, J. F.; Yu, B.; Brinkmann, C.; Cheng, S.; Bloch, W.; Schumann, M.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.24301604
Objective: To compare the efficacy of exercise, metformin, and their combination on glucose metabolism in individuals with prediabetes and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM), and rank these treatments by exercise modality and metformin dosage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Orthogonalized human protease control of secreted signals
Authors: Aldrete, C. A.; Vlahos, A. E.; Pei, J.; Cong, Q.; Gao, X. J.
Score: 8.4, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576308
Synthetic circuits that regulate protein secretion in human cells could support cell-based therapies by enabling control over local environments. While protein-level circuits enable such potential clinical applications, featuring orthogonality and compactness, their non-human origin poses a potential immunogenic risk. Here, we developed Humanized Drug Induced Regulation of Engineered CyTokines (hDIRECT) as a platform to control cytokine activity exclusively using human-derived proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Statistical inference with a manifold-constrained RNA velocity model uncovers cell cycle speed modulations
Authors: Lederer, A. R.; Leonardi, M.; Talamanca, L.; Herrera, A.; Droin, C.; Khven, I.; Carvalho, H. J.; Valente, A.; Dominguez Mantes, A.; Mulet Arabi, P.; Pinello, L.; Naef, F.; La Manno, G.
Score: 37.0, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576093
Across a range of biological processes, cells undergo coordinated changes in gene expression, resulting in transcriptome dynamics that unfold within a low-dimensional manifold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Endangered Przewalski&amp;#39;s horse, Equus przewalskii, cloned from historically cryopreserved cells
Authors: Novak, B. J.; Ryder, O. A.; Houck, M. L.; Putnam, A. S.; Walker, K.; Russell, L.; Russell, B.; Walker, S.; Arenivas, S. S.; Aston, L.; Veneklasen, G.; Ivy, J. A.; Koepfli, K.-P.; Rusnak, A.; Simek, J.; Zhuk, A.; Phelan, R.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572538
Two endangered Przewalskis horse stallions were cloned from fibroblast cells cultured and cryopreserved in 1980.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
