<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in Hallucinogen-associated Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations in California from 2016-2021
Authors: Tate, S.; Garel, N.; Nash, K.; Lembke, A.
Score: 62.0, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294275
ObjectivesHallucinogens encompass a diverse range of compounds with increasing scientific and public interest. Risks associated with hallucinogen use are poorly understood. This study aims to evaluate the trends in hallucinogen-related emergency department visits and hospitalizations in California from 2016 to 2021, as compared to alcohol and cannabis visits and hospitalizations MethodsWe conducted a descriptive study on publicly available data on diagnosis codes associated with emergency department (ED) visits and hospitalizations from the California Department of Healthcare Access and Information (HCAI) to describe hallucinogen, alcohol, and cannabis associated encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 396.5, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>African elephants address one another with individually specific calls
Authors: Pardo, M. A.; Fristrup, K.; Lolchuragi, D. S.; Poole, J.; Granli, P.; Moss, C.; Douglas-Hamilton, I.; Wittemyer, G.
Score: 95.0, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554872
Personal names are a universal feature of human language, yet few analogs exist in other species. While dolphins and parrots address conspecifics by imitating the calls of the addressee 1,2, human names are not imitations of the sounds typically made by the names owner 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>AlphaFold2 can predict single-mutation effects
Authors: Mcbride, J. M.; Reinharz, V.; Polev, K.; Grzybowski, B. A.; Tlusty, T.
Score: 123.9, Published: 2023-09-03 DOI: 10.1101/2022.04.14.488301
AlphaFold2 (AF) is a promising tool, but is it accurate enough to predict single mutation effects? Here, we report that the localized structural deformation between protein pairs differing by only 1-3 mutations - as measured by the effective strain - is correlated across 3,901 experimental and AF-predicted structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Human gut metagenomic mining reveals an untapped source of peptide antibiotics
Authors: Torres, M. D. T.; Brooks, E. F.; Cesaro, A.; Sberro, H.; Nicolaou, C.; Bhatt, A. S.; de la Fuente, C.
Score: 30.3, Published: 2023-09-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555711
Drug-resistant bacteria are outpacing traditional antibiotic discovery efforts. Here, we computationally mined 444,054 families of putative small proteins from 1,773 human gut metagenomes, identifying 323 peptide antibiotics encoded in small open reading frames (smORFs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Accurate human genome analysis with Element Avidity sequencing
Authors: Carroll, A.; Kolesnikov, A.; Cook, D. E.; Brambrink, L.; Wiseman, K. N.; Billings, S. M.; Kruglyak, S.; Lajoie, B. R.; Zhao, J.; Levy, S. E.; McLean, C. Y.; Shafin, K.; Nattestad, M.; Chang, P.-C.
Score: 543.5, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.553043
We investigate the new sequencing technology Avidity from Element Biosciences. We show that Element whole genome sequencing achieves higher mapping and variant calling accuracy compared to Illumina sequencing at the same coverage, with larger differences at lower coverages (20x-30x).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>In situ cryoET reveals inhibitor-induced perturbations in Pf80S GTPase interactions
Authors: Anton, L.; Cheng, W.; Haile, M.; Cobb, D. W.; Zhu, X.; Han, L.; Li, E.; Nair, A.; Lee, C. L.; Ke, H.; Zhang, G.; Doud, E. H.; Ho, C.-M.
Score: 96.7, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.03.556115
Malaria parasites rely heavily on rapid, high fidelity protein synthesis to infect and replicate in human erythrocytes, making translation an attractive target for new antimalarials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Harnessing extracellular vesicles for efficient siRNA delivery in vitro and in vivo
Authors: Qiu, T.; Zhai, Y.; Yi, Y.; Wang, X.; Hu, R.; Niu, S.; Wang, C.; Cui, C.; Xu, K.; He, X.
Score: 433.5, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.26.554924
To fulfill the potential of small interference RNA (siRNA) therapeutics, diverse and efficient delivery platforms for siRNA are urgently needed. Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are endogenous, cell secreted nano-vehicles which have been explored for functional siRNA delivery, yet impurities in EVs preparation and lack of efficient siRNA loading method have been limiting its further development into clinical applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Distinct biological signature and modifiable risk factors underly the comorbidity between major depressive disorder and cardiovascular disease
Authors: Bergstedt, J.; Pasman, J. A.; Ma, Z.; Harder, A.; Yao, S.; Parker, N.; Treur, J. L.; Smit, D. J. A.; Frei, O.; Shadrin, A.; Meijsen, J. J.; Shen, Q.; Tornvall, P.; Buil, A.; Werge, T.; Hjerling-Leffler, J.; Als, T. D.; Borglum, A. D.; Lewis, C. M.; McIntosh, A. M.; Valdimarsdottir, U. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>The anti-SARS-CoV-2 BNT162b2 vaccine suppresses mithramycin-induced erythroid differentiation and expression of embryo-fetal globin genes in human erythroleukemia K562 cells
Authors: Zurlo, M.; Gasparello, J.; Verona, M.; Papi, C.; Cosenza, L. C.; Finotti, A.; Marzaro, G.; Gambari, R.
Score: 593.5, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556634
The COVID-19 severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) the ongoing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic. The SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein (S-protein) plays an important role in the early phase of SARS-CoV2 infection through efficient interaction with ACE2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>PUFFFIN: A novel, ultra-bright, customisable, single plasmid system for labelling cell neighbourhoods
Authors: Lebek, T.; Malaguti, M.; Elfick, A.; Lowell, S.
Score: 34.5, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.556381
Cell communication orchestrates development, homeostasis, and disease. Understanding these processes depends on effective methods to study how cells influence their neighbours. Here, we present Positive Ultra-bright Fluorescent Fusion For Identifying Neighbours (PUFFFIN), a novel cell neighbour-labelling system based upon secretion and uptake of a positively supercharged fluorescent protein s36GFP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Neonicotinoids, more than herbicides, land use, and climate, drive recent butterfly declines in the American Midwest
Authors: Van Deynze, B.; Swinton, S. M.; Hennessy, D. A.; Haddad, N.; Ries, L.
Score: 48.7, Published: 2023-08-26 DOI: 10.1101/2022.07.29.502042
Mounting evidence shows insects are in decline globally. Habitat loss, climate change, and pesticides have all been implicated, but their relative effects have never been evaluated in a comprehensive large-scale study. We harmonized 17 years of land use, climate, multiple classes of pesticides and butterfly data across 60 counties in five states in the US Midwest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Attacks on Ukrainian healthcare facilities during the first year of the full-scale Russian invasion of Ukraine
Authors: Barten, D.; Tin, D.; Granholm, F.; Rusnak, D.; van Osch, F.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294763
BackgroundAlthough the Geneva Conventions and Rome Statute demand protections for healthcare facilities during war, breaches of these protections are frequently reported. The ongoing war in Ukraine is no exception, with several healthcare attacks eliciting widespread condemnation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Morning exercise and pre-breakfast metformin interact to reduce glycaemia in people with Type 2 Diabetes: a randomized crossover trial
Authors: Pena Carrillo, B. J.; Cope, E.; Gurel, S.; Traslosheros, A.; Kenny, A.; Mody, N.; Delibegovic, M.; Philip, S.; Thies, F.; Blana, D.; Gabriel, B. M.
Score: 15.7, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295059
Exercise is recommended in the treatment of Type 2 Diabetes and can improve insulin sensitivity [1]. However, previous evidence suggests that exercise at different times of the day in people with type 2 diabetes may have opposing outcomes on glycaemia [2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Serological outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection by vaccination status and variant in England
Authors: Quinot, C.; Lunt, R.; Kirsebom, F.; Andrews, N.; Whitaker, H.; Skarnes, C.; Letley, L.; Haskins, D.; Angel, C.; Firminger, S.; Ratcliffe, K.; Sheridan, A.; Rajan, S.; Akindele, L.; Ijaz, S.; Zambon, M.; Brown, K.; Ramsay, M.; Lopez Bernal, J.
Score: 22.6, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295073
BackgroundThroughout the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, several vaccines have been rolled out and distinct variants with different severity and immune profiles emerged in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Quantitative Genetic Model of Background Selection in Humans
Authors: Buffalo, V.; Kern, A. D.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556762
Across the human genome, there are large-scale fluctuations in genetic diversity caused by the indirect effects of selection. This &amp;#34;linked selection signal&amp;#34; reflects the impact of selection according to the physical placement of functional regions and recombination rates along chromosomes. Previous work has shown that purifying selection acting against the steady influx of new deleterious mutations at functional portions of the genome shapes patterns of genomic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Utility of EsoGuard as a Triage Test for Endoscopy to Identify Barrett&amp;#39;s Esophagus in Fire Fighters
Authors: Hamblin, R.; Lee, V. T.; deGuzman, B. J.; Verma, S.; Aklog, L.
Score: 243.7, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294176
BackgroundFirefighters have frequent exposure to smoke and compounds that have been shown to increase the risk of developing esophageal neoplasia. EsoGuard(R) is a DNA biomarker assay that can be utilized with efficiency and high tolerability as a triage test in the diagnosis of patients with Barretts Esophagus (BE) and/or esophageal adenocarcinoma (EAC) in this population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Long-term longitudinal analysis of 4,187 participants reveals new insights into determinants of incident clonal hematopoiesis
Authors: Uddin, M. M.; Saadatagah, S.; Niroula, A.; Yu, B.; Hornsby, W.; Ganesh, S.; Lannery, K.; Shuermans, A.; Honigberg, M. C.; Bick, A. G.; Libby, P.; Ebert, B. L.; Ballantyne, C. M.; Natarajan, P.
Score: 8.4, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295093
Clonal hematopoiesis (CH), characterized by blood cells predominantly originating from a single mutated hematopoietic stem cell, is linked to diverse aging-related diseases, including hematologic malignancy and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease (ASCVD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>The simplicity of protein sequence-function relationships
Authors: Park, Y.; Metzger, B. P. H.; Thornton, J. W.
Score: 29.8, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.02.556057
How complicated is the relationship between a proteins sequence and its function? High-order epistatic interactions among residues are thought to be pervasive, making a proteins function difficult to predict or understand from its sequence. Most prior studies, however, used methods that misinterpret measurement errors, small local idiosyncracies around a designated wild-type sequence, and global nonlinearity in the sequence-function relationship as rampant high-order interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Predicting RNA-seq coverage from DNA sequence as a unifying model of gene regulation
Authors: Linder, J.; Srivastava, D.; Yuan, H.; Agarwal, V.; Kelley, D. R.
Score: 120.3, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.555582
Sequence-based machine learning models trained on genome-scale biochemical assays improve our ability to interpret genetic variants by providing functional predictions describing their impact on the cis-regulatory code. Here, we introduce a new model, Borzoi, which learns to predict cell- and tissue-specific RNA-seq coverage from DNA sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>RCT-based Social Return on Investment (SROI) of a home exercise programme for people with early dementia comparing in-person and blended delivery before and during the COVID-19 pandemic
Authors: Doungsong, K.; Hartfiel, N.; Gladman, J.; Harwood, R. H.; Edwards, R. T.
Score: 5.6, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294408
BackgroundRegular exercise and community engagement may slow the rate of function loss for people with dementia. However, the evidence is uncertain regarding the cost-effectiveness and social return on investment (SROI) of home exercise with community referral for people with dementia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Representing multimorbid disease progressions using directed hypergraphs
Authors: Burke, J.; Bailey, R.; Akbari, A.; Fasusi, K.; Lyons, R. A.; Pearson, J.; Rafferty, J.; Schofield, D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294903
ObjectiveTo introduce directed hypergraphs as a novel tool for assessing the temporal relationships between coincident diseases, addressing the need for a more accurate representation of multimorbidity and leveraging the growing availability of electronic healthcare databases and improved computational resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>ACCORD (ACcurate COnsensus Reporting Document): A reporting guideline for consensus methods in biomedicine developed via a modified Delphi
Authors: Gattrell, W. T.; Logullo, P.; van Zuuren, E. J.; Price, A.; Hughes, E. L.; Blazey, P.; Winchester, C. C.; Tovey, D.; Goldman, K.; Hungin, A. P.; Harrison, N.
Score: 12.0, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294261
BackgroundIn biomedical research, it is often desirable to seek consensus among individuals who have differing perspectives and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Plasmatic HIV-1 soluble gp120 is associated with immune dysfunction and inflammation in ART-treated individuals with undetectable viremia
Authors: Benlarbi, M.; Richard, J.; Bourassa, C.; Tolbert, W. D.; Chartrand-Lefebvre, C.; Gendron-Lepage, G.; Sylla, M.; El-Far, M.; Messier-Peet, M.; Guertin, C.; Turcotte, I.; Fromentin, R.; Verly, M. M.; Prevost, J.; Clark, A.; Mothes, W.; Kaufmann, D. E.; Maldarelli, F.; Chomont, N.; Begin, P.; Tremblay, C.; Baril, J.-G.; Trottier, B.; Trottier, S.; Duerr, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Sensitivity of BA.2.86 to prevailing neutralising antibody responses
Authors: Sheward, D. J.; Yang, Y.; Westerberg, M.; Öling, S.; Muschiol, S.; Sato, K.; Peacock, T. P.; Karlsson Hedestam, G. B.; Albert, J.; Murrell, B.
Score: 545.2, Published: 2023-09-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.02.556033
A new SARS-CoV-2 variant, designated BA.2.86, has recently emerged with over 30 spike mutations relative to its parental BA.2, raising questions about its degree of resistance to neutralising antibodies. Using a spike-pseudotyped virus model we characterise neutralisation of BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Wu, K.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 2048.9, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
Background: Subvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Neutralization Escape by SARS-CoV-2 Omicron Subvariant BA.2.86
Authors: Lasrado, N.; Collier, A.-r.; Hachmann, N.; Miller, J.; Rowe, M.; Schonberg, E.; Rodrigues, S.; LaPiana, A.; Patio, R.; Anand, T.; Fisher, J.; Mazurek, C.; Guan, R.; Wagh, K.; Theiler, J.; Korber, B.; Barouch, D. H.
Score: 539.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.556272
The continued evolution of SARS-CoV-2 may lead to evasion of vaccine immunity and natural immunity. A highly mutated Omicron variant BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>High-confidence 3D template matching for cryo-electron tomography
Authors: Cruz-Leon, S.; Majtner, T.; Hoffmann, P. C.; Kreysing, J. P.; Tuijtel, M. W.; Schaefer, S. L.; Geissler, K.; Beck, M.; Turonova, B.; Hummer, G.
Score: 40.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.556310
Cryo-electron tomography (CryoET) resolves individual macromolecules inside living cells. However, the complex composition and high density of cells challenge the faithful identification of features in tomograms. Here, we capitalize on recent advances in electron tomography and demonstrate that 3D template matching (TM) localizes a wide range of structures inside crowded eukaryotic cells with confidence 10 to 100-fold above the noise level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The citrate transporter SLC13A5 as a therapeutic target for kidney disease: evidence from Mendelian randomization to inform drug development
Authors: Gill, D.; Zagkos, L.; Gill, R.; Benzing, T.; Jordan, J.; Birkenfeld, A.; Burgess, S.; Zahn, G.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294760
BackgroundSolute carrier family 13 member 5 (SLC13A5) is a Na -coupled citrate co-transporter that mediates the entry of extracellular citrate into the cytosol. SLC13A5 inhibition has been proposed as a therapeutic target for reducing progression of kidney disease via its effects on citrate metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The ABCs of Subarachnoid Hemorrhage Blood Volume Measurement: A Simplified Quantitative Method Predicts Outcomes and Delayed Cerebral Ischemia.
Authors: Foettinger, F.; Sharma, R.; Salman, S.; Weston, A. D.; Erickson, B. J.; Huynh, T.; Tawk, R. G.; Freeman, W. D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295090
Background: We sought to develop an easy-to-use quantifiable and more precise method to estimate total blood volume in patients with aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH) and explore its volumetric extent on incidence of delayed cerebral ischemia (DCI) and poor outcomes by modified Rankin Scale by hospital discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Spike amyloid fibrils specifically and selectively accelerates amyloid fibril formation of human prion protein and the amyloid β peptide
Authors: Larsson, J. N.; Hellstrand, E.; Hammarström, P.; Nyström, S.
Score: 2035.8, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555834
An increasing number of reports suggest an association between COVID-19 infection and initiation or acceleration of neurodegenerative diseases (NDs) including Alzheimers disease (AD) and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease (CJD). Both these diseases and several other NDs are caused by conversion of human proteins into a misfolded, aggregated amyloid fibril state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Disruption of maternal IgA by prenatal antibiotics precedes intestinal E. coli colonization and late-onset sepsis in neonates
Authors: McDonald, K.; Browning, D.; Greenfield, K.; Lin, K.; Meier, J.; Sasaki, A.; Megli, C.; Knoop, K.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.23295031
Neonates, most notably prematurely born neonates, are particularly vulnerable to enteric pathogens. It is recommended that all pregnant patients receive antibiotics following Preterm Premature Rupture of Membranes (PPROM) to prolong pregnancy, yet not all antibiotic regimens have been studied for efficacy, especially when considering neonatal outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Early Morning Checkpoint Inhibitor Infusion and Overall Survival of Patients with Metastatic Cancer: an In-depth Chronotherapeutic Study
Authors: Catozzi, S.; Assaad, S.; Delrieu, L.; Favier, B.; Dumas, E.; Hamy, A.-S.; Latouche, A.; Crochet, H.; Blay, J.-Y.; Mullaert, J.; Ballesta, A.; Heudel, P.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.23295010
IntroductionRecent retrospective studies suggest potential large patients benefit through proper timing of immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICI). The association between ICI treatment timing and patient survival, neoplastic response and toxicities was investigated, together with interactions with performance status (PS) and sex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Savoring Meditation on Positive Emotions and Pain-Related Brain Function: A Mechanistic Randomized Controlled Trial in People With Rheumatoid Arthritis
Authors: Finan, P.; Hunt, C.; Keaser, M. L.; Smith, K.; Lerman, S.; Bingham, C. O.; Barrett, F.; Garland, E. L.; Zeidan, F.; Seminowicz, D. A.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23294949
Positive emotions are a promising target for intervention in chronic pain, but mixed findings across trials to date suggest that existing interventions may not be optimized to efficiently engage the target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Characterizing the phenotypic and genetic structure of psychopathology in UK Biobank
Authors: Williams, C. M.; Peyre, H.; Wolfram, T.; Lee, Y. H.; Ge, T.; Smoller, J. W.; Mallard, T. T.; Ramus, F.
Score: 19.0, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295086
Mental conditions exhibit a higher-order transdiagnostic factor structure which helps to explain the widespread comorbidity observed in psychopathology. However, the phenotypic and genetic structures of psychopathology may differ, raising questions about the validity and utility of these factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Psilocybin desynchronizes brain networks
Authors: Siegel, J. S.; Subramanian, S.; Perry, D. A.; Kay, B. P.; Gordon, E. M.; Laumann, T. O.; Chacko, R. V.; Reneau, T. R.; Metcalf, N. V.; Horan, C.; Schweiger, J. A.; Wong, D.; Bender, D.; Padawer-Curry, J.; Raison, C. L.; Carhart-Harris, R.; Raichle, M. E.; Lenze, E. J.; Snyder, A. Z.; Dosenbach, N. U. F.; Nicol, G. E.
Score: 80.9, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294131</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular Basis of Human Trace Amine-Associated Receptor 1 Activation
Authors: Zilberg, G.; Parpounas, A. K.; Warren, A. L.; Yang, S.; Wacker, D.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.556555
The human trace amine-associated receptor 1 (hTAAR1, hTA1) is a key regulator of monoaminergic neurotransmission and the actions of psychostimulants. Despite preclinical research demonstrating its tractability as a drug target, its molecular mechanisms of activation remain unclear. Moreover, poorly understood pharmacological differences between rodent and human TA1 complicate the translation of findings from preclinical disease models into novel pharmacotherapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Effects of shoe heel height on ankle dynamics in running
Authors: Yawar, A.; Lieberman, D. E.
Score: 10.8, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552471
Shoes alter the evolved biomechanics of the foot, potentially affecting running kinematics and kinetics that can in turn influence injury and performance. An important feature of conventional running shoes is heel height, whose effects on foot and ankle biomechanics remain understudied. Here, we investigate the effects of 6 - 26 mm increases in heel height on ankle dynamics in 8 rearfoot strike runners who ran barefoot and in minimal shoes with added heels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Single-Nucleus Atlas of Seed-to-Seed Development in Arabidopsis
Authors: Lee, T. A.; Nobori, T.; Illouz-Eliaz, N.; Xu, J.; Jow, B.; Nery, J. R.; Ecker, J. R.
Score: 193.5, Published: 2023-09-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.23.533992
Extensive studies of the reference plant Arabidopsis have enabled a deep understanding of tissues throughout development, yet a census of cell types and states throughout development is lacking. Here, we present a single-nucleus transcriptome atlas of seed-to-seed development employing over 800,000 nuclei, encompassing a diverse set of tissues across ten developmental stages, with spatial transcriptomic validation of the dynamic seed and silique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Co-existence of negative and positive associations between cognition and intergenerational psychiatric symptoms reveal necessity of socioeconomic and clinical enrichment
Authors: Pines, A.; Tozzi, L.; Bertrand, C.; Keller, A. S.; Zhang, X.; Whitfield-Gabrieli, S.; Hastie, T.; Larsen, B.; Leikauf, J.; Williams, L. M.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.28.23294743
BackgroundMental illnesses are a leading cause of disability globally. Across 17 psychiatric disorders, functional disability is often in part caused by cognitive impairments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>High-Dose Naloxone Formulations Are Not as Essential as We Thought
Authors: Lemen, P. M.; Garrett, D. P.; Thompson, E.; Aho, M.; Vasquez, C.; Park, J.
Score: 17.3, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.23293781
Naloxone is a U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved opioid antagonist for reversing opioid overdoses. Naloxone is available to the public, and can be administered through intramuscular (IM), intravenous (IV), and intranasal spray (IN) routes. Our literature review aimed to improve understanding regarding the adequacy of the regularly distributed two doses of low-dose IM or IN naloxone in effectively reversing fentanyl overdoses and whether high-dose naloxone formulations (HDNF) formulations are an optimal solution to this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>A Mutual Knowledge Distillation-Empowered AI Framework for Early Detection of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease Using Incomplete Multi-Modal Images
Authors: Kwak, M. G.; Su, Y.; Chen, K.; Weidman, D.; Wu, T.; Lure, F.; Li, J.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294574
Early detection of Alzheimers Disease (AD) is crucial to ensure timely interventions and optimize treatment outcomes for patients. While integrating multi-modal neuroimages, such as MRI and PET, has shown great promise, limited research has been done to effectively handle incomplete multi-modal image datasets in the integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Being responsible for COPD - lung disease as a manifestation of structural violence.
Authors: Williams, P. J.; Buttery, S. C.; Laverty, A. A.; Hopkinson, N. S.
Score: 7.2, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.23295021
Lung health, the development of lung disease, and how well a person with lung disease is able to live, all depend on a wide range of societal factors. Considering COPD as a manifestation of structural violence, something that continues to be done to people, despite it being largely preventable, makes the causal processes more apparent and the responsibility to interrupt or alleviate these clearer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Characterising the neurobiological mechanisms of action of exercise and cognitive behavioural interventions for rheumatoid arthritis fatigue: an MRI brain study
Authors: Dehsarvi, A.; Al-Wasity, S.; Stefanov, K.; Wiseman, S.; Ralston, S.; Wardlaw, J. M.; Emsley, R.; Bachmair, E.-m.; Cavanagh, J.; Waiter, G. D.; Basu, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.23294366
BackgroundChronic Fatigue is a major clinical unmet need among patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). Current therapies are limited to non-pharmacological interventions, such as personalised exercise programmes (PEP) and cognitive behavioural approaches (CBA), however, still most patients continue to report severe fatigue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>A Quantitative Study of Inappropriate Image Duplication in the Journal Toxicology Reports
Authors: David, S.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.03.556099
Inappropriate image duplication is a type of scientific error that can be detected by examining published literature. Few estimates of the frequency of this problem have been published. This study aimed to quantify the rate of image duplication in the journal Toxicology Reports. In total 1540 unique articles (identified by DOI) were checked for the presence of research related images (microscopy, photography, western blot scans, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Does screening for Neisseria gonorrhoeae and Chlamydia trachomatis affect the incidence of these infections in men who have sex with men taking HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) ? Results from a randomized, multicentre controlled trial (the Gonoscreen study)
Authors: Vanbaelen, T.; Tsoumanis, A.; Florence, E.; Van Dijck, C.; Huis in &amp;#39;t Veld, D.; Sauvage, A. S.; Herssens, N.; De Baetselier, I.; Rotsaert, A.; Verhoeven, V.; Henrard, S.; Van Herrewege, Y.; Van den Bossche, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review on the Effects of Exercise on Gut Microbial Diversity, Taxonomic Composition, and Microbial Metabolites: Identifying Research Gaps and Future Directions
Authors: Cullen, J.; Shahzad, S.; Dhillon, J.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23294991
The gut microbiome, hosting a diverse microbial community, plays a pivotal role in metabolism, immunity, and digestion. While the potential of exercise to influence this microbiome has been increasingly recognized, findings remain incongruous. This systematic review examined the effects of exercise on the gut microbiome of human and animal models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Microbial cell factory optimisation using genome-wide host-pathway interaction screens
Authors: Cachera, P. P.-Y. J.; Kurt, N. C.; Ropke, A.; Strucko, T.; Mortensen, U. H.; Jensen, M. K.
Score: 7.1, Published: 2023-08-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.555557
The ubiquity of genetic interactions in living cells challenges the concept of parts orthogonality, which is a cornerstone of synthetic biology. Parts, such as heterologously expressed genes, draw from shared pools of limited cellular resources and interactions between parts themselves and their host are inevitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Efficient gene knockout and genetic interactions: the IN4MER CRISPR/Cas12a multiplex knockout platform
Authors: Esmaeili Anvar, N.; Lin, C.; Ma, X.; Wilson, L. L.; Steger, R.; Sangree, A. K.; Colic, M.; Wang, S. H.; Doench, J. G.; Hart, T.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.01.03.522655
Genetic interactions mediate the emergence of phenotype from genotype, but initial technologies for combinatorial genetic perturbation in mammalian cells suffer from inefficiency and are challenging to scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 10:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>An integrative taxonomic treatment of the Mycetophilidae (Diptera: Bibionomorpha) from Singapore reveals 115 new species on 730km2
Authors: Amorim, D. d. S.; Oliveira, S. S.; Balbi, M. I. P. A.; Ang, Y.; Yeo, D.; Srivathsan, A.; Meier, R.
Score: 38.2, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.02.555672
&amp;#34;Open ended&amp;#34; or &amp;#34;dark taxa&amp;#34; are species-rich clades that are so abundant and diverse that conventional taxonomic methods tend to struggle with the onslaught of specimens and species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
