<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Specific diagnostic criteria identify those at high risk for progression from &amp;#39;preaddiction&amp;#39; to severe alcohol use disorder
Authors: Miller, A. P.; Kuo, S. I.-C.; Johnson, E. C.; Tillman, R.; Brislin, S. J.; Dick, D. M.; Kamarajan, C.; Kinreich, S.; Kramer, J.; McCutcheon, V. V.; Plawecki, M. H.; Porjesz, B.; Schuckit, M. A.; Salvatore, J. E.; Edenberg, H. J.; Bucholz, K. K.; Meyers, J. L.; Agrawal, A.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Anti-SARS-CoV-2 IgG profile of protein subunit, adenovector and mRNA vaccines
Authors: Reinig, S.; Kuo, C.; Wu, C.-C.; Huang, S.-y.; Yu, J.-S.; Shih, S.-R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.16.23291455
Different vaccine platforms were developed in 2019 and 2020 to provide immunization for protection against the SARS-CoV-2-caused disease COVID-19. The majority of vaccinated individuals will develop antibodies against SARS-CoV-2. The isotype (subclass) and Fc-glycosylation of IgG antibodies determine their affinity for secondary effector functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Snow flies self-amputate freezing limbs to sustain behavior at sub-zero temperatures
Authors: Golding, D.; Rupp, K.; Sustar, A.; Pratt, B.; Tuthill, J.
Score: 285.7, Published: 2023-05-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.29.541388
All living things are profoundly affected by temperature. In spite of the thermodynamic constraints on biology, some animals have evolved to live and move in extremely cold environments. Here, we investigate behavioral mechanisms of cold tolerance in the snow fly (Chionea spp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Intrinsically Disordered Regions Promote Protein Refoldability and Facilitate Retrieval from Biomolecular Condensates
Authors: To, P.; Bhagwat, A. M.; Tarbox, H. E.; Ecer, A.; Wendorff, H.; Jamieson, Z.; Trcek, T.; Fried, S. D.
Score: 109.3, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.25.546465
Many eukaryotic proteins contain intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs) that intersperse globular folded domains, in contrast with bacterial proteins which are typically highly globular. Recent years have seen great progress in identifying biological functions associated with these elusive protein sequence: in specific cases, they mediate liquid-liquid phase separation, perform molecular recognition, or act as sensors to changes in the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Direct 3D-bioprinting of hiPSC-derived cardiomyocytes to generate functional cardiac tissues
Authors: Esser, T. U.; Anspach, A.; Muenzebrock, K. A.; Kah, D.; Schruefer, S.; Schenk, J.; Heinze, K. G.; Schubert, D. W.; Fabry, B.; Engel, F. B.
Score: 26.2, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.12.544557
3D-bioprinting is a promising technology to produce human tissues as drug screening tool or for organ repair. However, direct printing of living cells has proven difficult. Here, we present a method to directly 3D-bioprint human induced pluripotent stem cell (hiPSC)-derived cardiomyocytes embedded in a collagen-hyaluronic acid ink generating centimeter-sized functional ring- and ventricle-shaped cardiac tissues in an accurate and reproducible manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>QuantUMS: uncertainty minimisation enables confident quantification in proteomics
Authors: Kistner, F.; Grossmann, J. L.; Sinn, L. R.; Demichev, V.
Score: 49.3, Published: 2023-06-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545604
Mass spectrometry-based proteomics has been rapidly gaining traction as a powerful analytical method both in basic research and translation. While the problem of error control in peptide and protein identification has been addressed extensively, the quality of the resulting quantities remains challenging to evaluate. Here we introduce QuantUMS (Quantification using an Uncertainty Minimising Solution), a machine learning-based method which minimises errors and eliminates bias in peptide and protein quantification by integrating multiple sources of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Adhesion energy controls lipid binding-mediated endocytosis
Authors: Groza, R.; Schmidt, K. V.; Muller, P. M.; Ronchi, P.; Schlack-Leigers, C.; Neu, U.; Puchkov, D.; Dimova, R.; Matthaus, C.; Taraska, J. W.; Weikl, T.; Ewers, H.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.546235
Several bacterial toxins and viruses can deform membranes through multivalent binding to lipids for clathrin-independent endocytosis. However, it remains unclear, how membrane deformation and endocytic internalization are mechanistically linked. Here we show that many lipid-binding virions induce membrane deformation and clathrin-independent endocytosis, suggesting a common mechanism based on multivalent lipid binding by globular particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Deep intravital brain tumor imaging enabled by tailored three-photon microscopy and analysis
Authors: Schubert, M. C.; Soyka, S. J.; Tamimi, A.; Maus, E.; Denninger, R.; Wissmann, N.; Reyhan, E.; Tetzlaff, S. K.; Beretta, C.; Drumm, M.; Schroers, J.; Steffens, A.; Walshon, J.; McCortney, K.; Heiland, S.; Golebiewska, A.; Kurz, F. T.; Wick, W.; Winkler, F.; Kreshuk, A.; Kuner, T.; Horbinski, C.; Prevedel, R.; Venkataramani, V.
Score: 44.5, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Integrative metabolomics differentiate coronary artery disease, peripheral artery disease, and venous thromboembolism risks
Authors: Lee, J.; Gilliland, T.; Koyama, S.; Nakao, T.; Dron, J.; Lannery, K.; Wong, M.; Peloso, G. M.; Hornsby, W.; Natarajan, P.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291103
Rationale Venous and arterial cardiovascular conditions, such as venous thromboembolism (VTE), coronary artery disease (CAD), and peripheral arterial disease (PAD), are genetically correlated. Interrogating distinct and overlapping mechanisms may shed new light on disease mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Combinatorial selective ER-phagy remodels the ER during neurogenesis
Authors: Hoyer, M. J.; Smith, I. R.; Paoli, J. C.; Jiang, Y.; Paulo, J. A.; Harper, W.
Score: 24.5, Published: 2023-06-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.546565
The endoplasmic reticulum (ER) has a vast proteomic landscape to perform many diverse functions including protein and lipid synthesis, calcium ion flux, and inter-organelle communication. The ER proteome is remodeled in part through membrane-embedded receptors linking ER to degradative autophagy machinery (selective ER-phagy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Topical application of Urolithin A slows intrinsic skin aging and protects from UVB-mediated photodamage: Findings from Randomized Clinical Trials
Authors: D&amp;#39;Amico, D.; Fouassier, A.; Faitg, J.; Hennighausen, N.; Brandt, M.; Konstantopoulos, D.; Rinsch, C.; Singh, A.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.16.23291378
Urolithin A is a gut microbiome derived postbiotic that has been shown to stimulate mitophagy, and improve muscle and mitochondrial health when administered orally to humans. In three separate randomized trials, we have now investigated the effect of topical administration of Urolithin A on skin aging features and on UVB-mediated photodamaged skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Transgene-Free Ex Utero Derivation of A Human Post-Implantation Embryo Model Solely from Genetically Unmodified Naive PSCs
Authors: Oldak, B.; Wildschutz, E.; Bondarenko, V.; Aguilera-Castrejon, A.; Zhao, C.; Tarazi, S.; Comar, M.-Y.; Ashouokhi, S.; Lokshtanov, D.; Roncato, F.; Viukov, S.; Ariel, E.; Rose, M.; Livnat, N.; Shani, T.; Joubran, C.; Cohen, R.; Addadi, Y.; Kedmi, M.; Keren-Shaul, H.; Petropoulos, S.; Lanner, F.; Novershtern, N.; Hanna, J. H.
Score: 1057.3, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Genome-scale community modelling reveals conserved metabolic cross-feedings in epipelagic bacterioplankton communities
Authors: Giordano, N.; Gaudin, M.; Trottier, C.; Delage, E.; Nef, C.; Bowler, C.; Chaffron, S.
Score: 13.0, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.545869
Marine microorganisms form complex communities of interacting organisms that influence central ecosystem functions in the ocean such as primary production and nutrient cycling. Identifying the mechanisms controlling their assembly and activities is a major challenge in microbial ecology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage substantially decrease the incidence of electric scooter injuries
Authors: Pakarinen, O.; Kobylin, A.; Harjola, V.-P.; Castren, M.; Vasara, H.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291641
Objective: To investigate the effectiveness of restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage on the incidence of e-scooter-related injuries. Design: A retrospective comparative study. We compared shared e-scooter injuries from two periods: Unrestricted period (1.1-31.8.2021), and Restricted period (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Brain Dopamine Receptor System is Not Altered in Obesity: Bayesian and Frequentist Meta-Analyses
Authors: Pak, K.; Nummenmaa, L.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291735
Background: Feeding induces dopamine release in the striatum, and a dysfunction of the dopaminergic reward system can lead to overeating, and obesity. Studies have reported inconsistent findings of dopamine receptor (DR) positron emission tomography (PET) scans in obesity. Here we investigated the association between DR availability and overweight/obesity using Bayesian and frequentist meta-analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>BharatSim: An agent-based modelling framework for India
Authors: Cherian, P.; Kshirsagar, J.; Neekhra, B.; Deshkar, G.; Hayatnagarkar, H.; Kapoor, K.; Kaski, C.; Kathar, G.; Khandekar, S.; Mookherje, S.; Ninawe, P.; Noronha, R. F.; Ranka, P.; Sinha, V.; Vinod, T.; Yadav, C.; Gupta, D.; Menon, G. I.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.15.23291292
BharatSim is an open-source agent-based modelling framework for the Indian population. It can simulate populations at multiple scales, from small communities to states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Genomic and ecological factors shaping specialism and generalism across an entire subphylum
Authors: Opulente, D. A.; LaBella, A. L.; Harrison, M.-C.; Wolters, J. F.; Liu, C.; Li, Y.; Kominek, J.; Steenwyk, J. L.; Stoneman, H. R.; VanDenAvond, J.; Miller, C. R.; Langdon, Q. K.; Silva, M.; Goncalves, C.; Ubbelohde, E. J.; Li, Y.; Buh, K. V.; Jarzyna, M.; Haase, M. A. B.; Rosa, C. A.; Cadez, N.; Libkind, D.; DeVirgilio, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Novel autoantibody targets identified in patients with autoimmune hepatitis (AIH) by PhIP-Seq reveal pathogenic insights
Authors: Klepper, A.; Kung, A.; Vazquez, S. E.; Mitchell, A.; Mann, S.; Avila-Vargas, I.; Kari, S.; Tekeste, M.; Castro, J.; Lee, B.; Duarte, M.; Khalili, M.; Wilson, M. R.; Yang, M.; Wolters, P.; Price, J.; Perito, E.; Feng, S.; Maher, J. J.; Lai, J. C.; Weiler-Normann, C.; Lohse, A.; DeRisi, J.; Tana, M.
Score: 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The relationship between genotype- and phenotype-based estimates of genetic liability to human psychiatric disorders, in practice and in theory.
Authors: Dybdahl Krebs, M.; Appadurai, V.; Georgii Hellberg, K.-L.; Ohlsson, H.; Steinbach, J.; Pedersen, E. M.; iPSYCH Study Consortium, ; Werge, T.; Sundquist, J.; Sundquist, K.; Cai, N.; Zaitlen, N.; Dahl, A. W.; Vilhjalmsson, B. J.; Flint, J.; Bacanu, S.-A.; Schork, A. J.; Kendler, K. S.
Score: 24.3, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Nucleus-Independent Transgenerational Small RNA Inheritance in C. elegans
Authors: Rieger, I.; Weintraub, G.; Lev, I.; Goldstein, K.; Bar-Zvi, D.; Anava, S.; Gingold, H.; Shaham, S.; Rechavi, O.
Score: 155.9, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545749
Studies using C. elegans nematodes demonstrated that, against the dogma, animals can transmit epigenetic information transgenerationally. While it is now clear that in these worms ancestral RNA interference (RNAi) responses continue to regulate gene expression for many generations, it is still debated whether the primary agent that perpetuates heritable silencing is RNA or chromatin, and whether the information is communicated to the next generation inside or outside of the nucleus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Identification of a novel HKU4-related coronavirus in single-cell datasets and clade viral host analysis
Authors: Jones, A.; Massey, S. E.; Nemzer, L. R.; Zhang, D.; Deigin, Y.; Quay, S. C.
Score: 49.4, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545480
HKU4-related coronaviruses (CoVs) are merbecoviruses related to Middle Eastern Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV). In 2022 and 2023, two HKU4-related CoV strains were discovered in Manis javanica (Malayan pangolin) metagenomic datasets derived from organ samples: HKU4-P251T and MjHKU4r-CoV-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Multicenter analysis of COVID-19 hospitalizations and stacking machine learning algorithms for prediction of high-risk patients
Authors: Shaw, R.; Bassily, D.; Patel, L.; O&amp;#39;Connor, T.; Rafidi, R.; Formanek, P.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291685
ObjectiveTo create and validate an ensemble of machine learning algorithms to accurately predict ICU admission or mortality upon initial presentation to the emergency department. MethodsThis is a retrospective cohort study of a multicenter hospital system in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Review of spatial planning policy as an intervention for improving public health: protocol for a health-focused content review of local plans in England
Authors: Chang, M.; Carhart, N.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291736
IntroductionEach local authority in England is required to create a statutory local plan that sets out their land use priorities as the basis of decision-making on urban development. Only recently has there been an explicit recognition the local plan is capable of being a legal determinant of and important public policy intervention in influencing population physical and mental health and wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>HIV self-testing positivity rate and linkage to confirmatory testing and care: a telephone survey in Cote d&amp;#39;Ivoire, Mali and Senegal
Authors: Kouassi, K. D. A.; Fotso, A. S.; Rouveau, N.; Maheu-Giroux, M.; Boily, M.-C.; Silhol, R.; d&amp;#39;Elbee, M.; Vautier, A.; Larmarange, J.; ATLAS Team, Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.10.23291206
AO_SCPLOWBSTRACTC_SCPLOWHIV self-testing (HIVST) empowers individuals by allowing them to decide when and where to test and with whom to share their results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Infection-induced vascular inflammation in COVID-19 links focal microglial dysfunction with neuropathologies through IL-1/IL-6-related systemic inflammatory states
Authors: Fekete, R.; Simats, A.; Biro, E.; Cserep, C.; Schwarcz, A. D.; Posfai, B.; Szabadits, E.; Kornyei, Z.; Toth, K.; Kellermayer, A.; David, C.; Acsady, L.; Kontra, L.; Silvestre-Roig, C.; Moldvay, J.; Fillinger, J.; Hortobagyi, T.; Liesz, A.; Benko, S.; Denes, A.
Score: 20.8, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.546214
COVID-19 is associated with diverse neurological abnormalities, which predict poor outcome in patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) among Those Up-to-Date and Not Up-to-Date on COVID-19 Vaccination
Authors: Shrestha, N. K.; Burke, P. C.; Nowacki, A. S.; Gordon, S. M.
Score: 5163.1, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.09.23290893
BackgroundThe CDC recently defined being &amp;#34;up-to-date&amp;#34; on COVID-19 vaccination as having received at least one dose of a COVID-19 bivalent vaccine. The purpose of this study was to compare the risk of COVID-19 among those &amp;#34;up-to-date&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;not up-to-date&amp;#34; on COVID-19 vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Type IV-A3 CRISPR-Cas systems drive inter-plasmid conflicts by acquiring spacers in trans
Authors: Benz, F.; Camara-Wilpert, S.; Russel, J.; Wandera, K. G.; Cepaite, R.; Ares-Arroyo, M.; Gomes-Filho, J. V.; Englert, F.; Kuehn, J.; Gloor, S.; Cuenod, A.; Aguila-Sans, M.; Maccario, L.; Egli, A.; Randau, L.; Pausch, P.; Rocha, E.; Beisel, C. L.; Madsen, J. S.; Bikard, D.; Hall, A. R.; Soerensen, S. J.; Pinilla-Redondo, R.
Score: 74.8, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA methylation governs the sensitivity of repeats to restriction by the HUSH-MORC2 corepressor
Authors: Pandiloski, N.; Horvath, V.; Karlsson, O. E.; Christoforidou, G.; Dorazehi, F.; Koutounidou, S.; Matas, J.; Gerdes, P.; Garza, R.; Jönsson, M. E.; Adami, A.; Atacho, D.; Johansson, J. G.; Englund, E.; Kokaia, Z.; Jakobsson, J.; Douse, C. H.
Score: 13.1, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.545516
The human silencing hub (HUSH) complex binds to transcripts of LINE-1 retrotransposons (L1s) and other genomic repeats, recruiting MORC2 and other effectors to remodel chromatin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Vagus nerve inflammation contributes to dysautonomia in COVID-19
Authors: Woo, M. S.; Shafiq, M.; Fitzek, A.; Dottermusch, M.; Altmeppen, H.; Mohammadi, B.; Mayer, C.; Bal, L. C.; Raich, L.; Matschke, J.; Krasemann, S.; Pfefferle, S.; Brehm, T. T. S.; Luetgehetmann, M.; Schaedler, J.; Addo, M. M.; Schulze Zur Wiesch, J.; Ondruschka, B.; Friese, M. A.; Glatzel, M.
Score: 94.9, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.23291320
Dysautonomia has substantially impacted acute COVID-19 severity as well as symptom burden after recovery from COVID-19 (long COVID), yet the underlying causes remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A window to the brain: ultrasound imaging of human neural activity through a permanent acoustic window
Authors: Rabut, C.; Norman, S. L.; Griggs, W. S.; Russin, J. J.; Jann, K.; Christopoulos, V.; Liu, C.; Andersen, R. A.; Shapiro, M. G.
Score: 424.1, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.544094
Recording human brain activity is crucial for understanding normal and aberrant brain function. However, available recording methods are either highly invasive or have relatively low sensitivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>More spice, less salt: how capsaicin affects liking for and perceived saltiness of foods in people with smell loss.
Authors: Hunter, S.; Beatty, C.; Dalton, P. H.
Score: 39.7, Published: 2023-06-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.05.23290966
People who lose their sense of smell self-report consuming more salt to compensate for a lack of flavor and enhance eating enjoyment. However, this can contribute to excess sodium intake and a poor diet. Capsaicin may help increase salt taste intensity and eating enjoyment in this population, but this has not been studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Implementing midwifery twinning partnerships: challenges and facilitators. A rapid evidence summary
Authors: Edwards, D.; Csontos, J. K.; Thomas, G.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-06-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.23291377
Twinning is a partnership method that focuses on mutual transfer of knowledge and skills between two parties, including organisations, clinical practices, universities, or individual health professionals. In midwifery, twinning is a particularly important tool that can help countries with high maternal and infant morbidity and mortality rates to make connections with countries where sickness and death rates related to birth are lower and the role of midwives is better developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Characterization of copy number alterations in Pakistani patients with colorectal cancer
Authors: Marcinak, C. T.; McDonald, B. R.; Zubairi, H.; Siddique, S.; Stephens, M. D.; Moosajee, M.; Ahmed, R.; Zafar, S. N.; Murtaza, M.; Ghias, K.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.19.23291601
PurposeIncidence and mortality rates of colorectal cancer (CRC) in South Asia are expected to rise by 70% between 2020 and 2040. Despite recent advances in the understanding of molecular alterations in CRC, the representation of South Asians in published genomic datasets is very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>Cross-modal sensory boosting to improve high-frequency hearing loss
Authors: Kohler, I.; Perrotta, M. V.; Ferreira, T.; Eagleman, D. M.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-06-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.01.23290351
High frequency hearing loss is one of the most common problems in the aging population and with those who have a history of exposure to loud noises. To address high-frequency hearing loss, we developed a multi-motor wristband that uses machine learning to listen for specific high frequency phonemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Evidence for deliberate burial of the dead by Homo naledi
Authors: Berger, L. R.; Makhubela, T.; Molopyane, K.; Kruger, A.; Randolph-Quinney, P.; Elliott, M.; Peixotto, B.; Fuentes, A.; Tafforeau, P.; Beyrand, V.; Dollman, K.; Jinnah, Z.; Brewer Gillham, A.; Broad, K.; Brophy, J.; Chinamatira, G.; Dirks, P.; Feuerriegel, E.; Gurtov, A.; Hlophe, N.; Hunter, L.; Hunte, R.; Jakata, K.; Jaskolski, C.; Morris, H.; Pryor, E.; Ramaphela, M.; Roberts, E.; Smilg, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>TDP-43-stratified single-cell proteomic profiling of postmortem human spinal motor neurons reveals protein dynamics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis
Authors: Guise, A. J.; Misal, S. A.; Carson, R.; Boekweg, H.; Van Der Watt, D.; Truong, T.; Liang, Y.; Chu, J.-H.; Welsh, N.; Gagnon, J.; Payne, S. H.; Plowey, E. D.; Kelly, R. T.
Score: 24.9, Published: 2023-06-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.08.544233
Unbiased proteomics has been employed to interrogate central nervous system (CNS) tissues (brain, spinal cord) and fluid matrices (CSF, plasma) from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients; yet, a limitation of conventional bulk tissue studies is that motor neuron (MN) proteome signals may be confounded by admixed non-MN proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>The fungal intestinal microbiota predict the development of bronchopulmonary dysplasia in very low birthweight newborns
Authors: Willis, K. A.; Silverberg, M.; Martin, I.; Abdelgawad, A.; Karabayir, I.; Halloran, B. A.; Myers, E. D.; Desai, J. P.; White, C. T.; Lal, C. V.; Ambalavanan, N.; Peters, B. M.; Jain, V. G.; Akbilgic, O.; Tipton, L.; Jilling, T.; Cormier, S. A.; Pierre, J. F.; Talati, A. J.
Score: 9.7, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Low Dose Naltrexone use for the management of post acute sequelae of COVID 19
Authors: Bonilla, H.; Tian, L.; Marconi, V.; Shafer, R. W.; Mccomsey, G.; Miglis, M. G.; Yang, P. C.; Geng, L. N.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.08.23291102
Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC), also known as Long COVID, is globally estimated to have affected up to 40-50% of individuals who were infected with SARS-CoV-2. The causes of PASC are being investigated, and there are no established therapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Dysregulated Platelet Function and Thrombosis in Patients with Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19
Authors: Aggarwal, A.; Singh, T. K.; Pham, M.; Godwin, M.; Chen, R.; McIntyre, T. M.; Chung, M. K.; Jennings, C.; Ali, M.; Park, H.; Englund, K.; Khorana, A. A.; Svensson, L.; Kapadia, S. R.; McCrae, K. R.; Cameron, S. J.
Score: 57.7, Published: 2023-06-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545507
ObjectivePost-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC, also referred as Long-COVID) sometimes follows COVID-19, a disease caused by SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Hip thrust and back squat training elicit similar gluteus muscle hypertrophy and transfer similarly to the deadlift
Authors: Plotkin, D. L.; Rodas, M. A.; Vigotsky, A.; McIntosh, M. C.; Breeze, E.; Ubrik, R.; Robitzsch, C.; Agyin-Birikorang, A.; Mattingly, M. L.; Michel, J. M.; Kontos, N. J.; Fruge, A. D.; Wilborn, C. M.; Weimar, W. H.; Bashir, A.; Beyers, R. J.; Henselmans, M.; Contreras, B. M.; Roberts, M. D.
Score: 40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the landscape of transcription factor promoter activity during vegetative development in Marchantia
Authors: Romani, F.; Sauret-Güeto, S.; Rebmann, M.; Annese, D.; Bonter, I.; Tomaselli, M.; Dierschke, T.; Delmans, M.; Frangedakis, E.; Silvestri, L.; Rever, J.; Bowman, J. L.; Romani, I.; Haseloff, J.
Score: 46.0, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.17.545419
Transcription factors (TFs) are essential for the regulation of gene expression and cell fate determination. Characterising the transcriptional activity of TF genes in space and time is a critical step towards understanding complex biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Red flags for potential serious pathologies masquerading as musculoskeletal neck pain: a protocol for a systematic review of clinical practice guidelines
Authors: Feller, D.; Chiarotto, A.; Koes, B.; Maselli, F.; Mourad, F.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291691
BackgroundAlthough benign most of the time, neck pain (NP) has been observed as the early manifestation of various serious cervical pathologies (e.g., malignancies, fractures). Red flags (RF) are signs and symptoms that raise suspicion of serious spinal pathology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping neurodevelopmental diversity in executive function
Authors: Mareva, S.; The CALM Team, ; Holmes, J.
Score: 22.2, Published: 2023-06-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.15.23291392
Executive functions can be conceptualised as either a set of higher-order cognitive skills that enable us to engage in flexible thinking and regulate our thoughts and behaviours, or as the ability to integrate knowledge, beliefs, and values when applying cognitive control in everyday situations. These two perspectives map onto the ways in which executive function is measured in childhood - using either structured laboratory tasks or ratings of everyday behaviours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>A unified framework for estimating country-specific cumulative incidence for 18 diseases stratified by polygenic risk
Authors: Jermy, B.; Läll, K.; Wolford, B. N.; Wang, Y.; Zguro, K.; Cheng, Y.; Kanai, M.; Kanoni, S.; Yang, Z.; Hartnonen, T.; Monti, R.; Wanner, J.; Youssef, O.; Estonian Biobank research team, ; FinnGen, ; Lippert, C.; van Heel, D. A.; Okada, Y.; McCartney, D. L.; Hayward, C.; Marioni, R.; Furini, S.; Renieri, A.; Martin, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Quantitative analysis of chest computed tomography of COVID-19 pneumonia using a software widely used in Japan
Authors: Suzuki, M.; Fujii, Y.; Nishimura, Y.; Yasui, K.; Fujisawa, H.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291669
This study aimed to determine the optimal conditions to measure the percentage of area considered as pneumonia (pneumonia volume ratio, PVR) and the computed tomography (CT) score due to coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) using the Ziostation2 image analysis software (Z2; Ziosoft, Tokyo, Japan), which is popular in Japan, and to evaluate its usefulness in assessing the clinical severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Lower Dynamic Cerebral Autoregulation following Acute Bout of Low-Volume High-Intensity Interval Exercise in Chronic Stroke Compared to Healthy Adults
Authors: Whitaker, A. A.; Aaron, S. E.; Chertoff, M.; Brassard, P.; Buchanan, J.; Nguyen, K.; Vidoni, E.; Waghmare, S.; Eickmeyer, S.; Billinger, S.
Score: 5.6, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.13.23291289
Fluctuating blood pressure during high-intensity interval exercise (HIIT) may challenge dynamic cerebral autoregulation (dCA), specifically post-stroke after an injury to the cerebrovasculature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced real-time mass spectrometry breath analysis for the diagnosis of COVID-19
Authors: Roquencourt, C.; Salvator, H.; Bardin, E.; Lamy, E.; Farfour, E.; Naline, E.; Devillier, P.; Grassin Delyle, S.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291712
BackgroundAlthough rapid screening for and diagnosis of COVID-19 are still urgently needed, most current testing methods are either long, costly, and/or poorly specific. The objective of the present study was to determine whether or not artificial-intelligence-enhanced real-time MS breath analysis is a reliable, safe, rapid means of screening ambulatory patients for COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Tiny Earth CURE improves student persistence in science
Authors: Miller, S.; Aldana, C. C.; Du, W.; Lee, H.; Maldonado, N.; Sandoval, P.; Vong, J.; Young, G.; Handelsman, J.; Broderick, N. A.; Hernandez, P. R.; Estrada, M.
Score: 7.5, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.543782
Course-based undergraduate research experiences (CUREs) enhance student retention in STEM, particularly among students who belong to historically excluded communities. Yet the mechanisms by which CUREs contribute to student integration and persistence are poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>A synthetic biology approach to assemble and reboot clinically-relevant Pseudomonas aeruginosa tailed phages
Authors: Ipoutcha, T.; Racharaks, R.; Huttelmaier, S.; Wilson, C. J.; Ozer, E. A.; Hartmann, E. M.
Score: 12.1, Published: 2023-06-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.546310
The rise in frequency of antibiotic resistance has made bacterial infections, specifically Pseudomonas aeruginosa, a cause for greater concern. Phage therapy is a promising solution that uses naturally isolated phages to treat bacterial infections. Ecological limitations, which stipulate a discrete host range and the inevitable evolution of resistance, may be overcome through a better understanding of phage biology and the utilization of engineered phages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Storm: Incorporating transient dynamics to infer the RNA velocity with metabolic labeling information
Authors: Peng, Q.; Qiu, X.; Li, T.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.545990
AO_SCPLOWBSTRACTC_SCPLOWThe time-resolved scRNA-seq (tscRNA-seq) provides the possibility to infer physically meaningful kinetic parameters, e.g., the transcription, splicing or RNA degradation rate constants with correct magnitudes, and RNA velocities by incorporating temporal information. Previous approaches utilizing the deterministic dynamics and steady-state assumption on gene expression states are insufficient to achieve favorable results for the data involving transient process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Role of renal venous oxygen pressure for renal function monitoring after related living-donor kidney transplantation: cohort study
Authors: Escarraman-Martinez, D.; Fernandez-Bravo, M.; Kammar-Garcia, A.; Guerrero-Gutierrez, M. A.; Meza-Comparan, H. D.; Mancilla-Galindo, J.; Sanchez-Diaz, J. S.; Cendejas-Rios, E.; Escorza-Molina, C. A.; Noriega-Salas, L.; Bernaldez-Gomez, G.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.15.23291421
IntroductionMonitoring of renal function after kidney transplantation (KT) is performed by measuring serum creatinine (SCr), urine volumes (UV), and glomerular filtration rate (GFR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Physiological phenotypes differ among color morphs in introduced populations of the common wall lizard, Podarcis muralis
Authors: Amer, A.; Spears, S.; Vaughn, P. L.; Colwell, C.; Livingston, E. H.; McQueen, W.; Schill, A.; Reichard, D.; Gangloff, E. J.; Brock, K. M.
Score: 7.9, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.17.545449
Many species exhibit color polymorphisms which have distinct physiological and behavioral characteristics. However, the consistency of morph trait covariation patterns across species, time, and ecological contexts remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
