<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Extracellular Matrix Abnormalities in the Hippocampus of Subjects with Substance Use Disorder
Authors: Valeri, J.; Stiplosek, C.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, S. M.; Sinclair, D.; Grant, K. A.; Bollavarapu, R.; Platt, D. M.; Stockmeier, C. A.; Gisabella, B.; Pantazopoulos, H.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295222
Contextual triggers are significant factors contributing to relapse in substance use disorders (SUD). Emerging evidence points to a critical role of extracellular matrix (ECM) molecules as mediators of reward memories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 403.4, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A history of avoidance does not impact extinction learning in male rats
Authors: Lopez-Moraga, A.; Luyten, L.; Beckers, T.
Score: 11.0, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.558816
Pervasive avoidance is one of the central symptoms of all anxiety-related disorders. In treatment, avoidance behaviors are typically discouraged because they are assumed to maintain anxiety. Yet, it is not clear that engaging in avoidance is always detrimental. In this study, we used a platform-mediated avoidance task to investigate the influence of avoidance history on extinction learning in male rats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Target DNA-dependent activation mechanism of the prokaryotic immune system SPARTA
Authors: Finocchio, G.; Koopal, B.; Potocnik, A.; Heijstek, C.; Jinek, M.; Swarts, D. C.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.23.559129
In both prokaryotic and eukaryotic innate immune systems, TIR domains function as NADases that degrade the key metabolite NAD&amp;#43; or generate signaling molecules. Catalytic activation of TIR domains requires oligomerization, but how this is achieved varies in distinct immune systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Click editing enables programmable genome writing using DNA polymerases and HUH endonucleases
Authors: da Silva, J. F.; Tou, C. J.; King, E. M.; Eller, M. L.; Ma, L.; Rufino-Ramos, D.; Kleinstiver, B. P.
Score: 104.7, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.557440
Genome editing technologies that install diverse edits can widely enable genetic studies and new therapeutics. Here we develop click editing, a genome writing platform that couples the advantageous properties of DNA-dependent DNA polymerases with RNA-programmable nickases (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Structural phylogenetics unravels the evolutionary diversification of communication systems in gram-positive bacteria and their viruses
Authors: Moi, D.; Bernard, C.; Steinegger, M.; Nevers, Y.; Langleib, M.; Dessimoz, C.
Score: 172.6, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.558401
Recent advances in AI-based protein structure modeling have yielded remarkable progress in predicting protein structures. Since structures are constrained by their biological function, their geometry tends to evolve more slowly than the underlying amino acids sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Pattern formation by bacteria-phage interactions
Authors: Martinez-Calvo, A.; Wingreen, N. S.; Datta, S. S.
Score: 37.3, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.558479
The interactions between bacteria and phages--viruses that infect bacteria--play critical roles in agriculture, ecology, and medicine; however, how these interactions influence the spatial organization of both bacteria and phages remain largely unexplored. Here, we address this gap in knowledge by developing a theoretical model of motile, proliferating bacteria that aggregate via motility-induced phase separation (MIPS) and encounter phage that infect and lyse the cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Tumor sialylation is a barrier against CD8 T cell-mediated anti-tumor responses and anti-PD-1 resistance in breast cancer
Authors: Mereiter, S.; Jonsson, G.; Oliveira, T.; Helm, J.; Hoffmann, D.; Abeln, M.; Jochum, A.-K.; Jochum, W.; Kellner, M. J.; Feith, M.; Tkalec, V.; Wasilewska, K.; Jiao, J.; Emsenhuber, L.; Holstein, F.; Obenauf, A.; Lordello, L.; Scoazec, J.-Y.; Kroemer, G.; Zitvogel, L.; Ali, O. H.; Flatz, L.; Gerardy-Schahn, R.; Muenster-Kuehnel, A.; Stadlmann, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Common and Rare Variant Contributions to Bradyarrhythmias from Multi-Ancestry Meta-Analyses
Authors: Weng, L.-C.; Rämö, J. T.; Jurgens, S. J.; Khurshid, S.; Chaffin, M.; Hall, A. W.; Morrill, V. N.; Nauffal, V.; Sun, Y. V.; Beer, D.; Lee, S.; Nadkarni, G.; Duong, T.; Wang, B.; Czuba, T.; Austin, T. R.; Yoneda, Z. T.; Friedman, D. J.; Clayton, A.; Hyman, M. C.; Judy, R. L.; Skanes, A. C.; Orland, K. M.; Treu, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the ultrastructural landscape of native extracellular matrix via lift-out cryo-FIBSEM and cryo-ET
Authors: Zens, B.; Faessler, F.; Hansen, J. M.; Hauschild, R.; Datler, J.; Hodirnau, V.-V.; Zheden, V.; Alanko, J.; Sixt, M.; Schur, F. K.
Score: 43.3, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.559261
The extracellular matrix (ECM) is a highly hydrated, three-dimensional network composed of various macromolecules and signaling factors. It serves as a structural scaffold for cells and plays an essential role in the regulation of numerous cellular processes, including cell migration, adhesion, and proliferation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Testing the Limits of Language Models: A Conversational Framework for Medical AI Assessment
Authors: Johri, S.; Jeong, J.; Tran, B. A.; Schlessinger, D. I.; Wongvibulsin, S.; Cai, Z. R.; Daneshjou, R.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 40.5, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295399
Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise for medical diagnosis, but traditional evaluations using static exam questions overlook the complexity of real-world clinical dialogues. We introduce a multi-agent conversational framework where doctor-AI and patient-AI agents interact to diagnose medical conditions, evaluated by a grader-AI agent and medical experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Endolysosomal dysfunction in radial glia progenitor cells leads to defective cerebral angiogenesis and compromised Blood-Brain Barrier integrity
Authors: Bassi, I.; Grunspan, M.; Hen, G.; Ravichandran, K. A.; Moshe, N.; Safriel, S. R.; Chen, A.; Ruiz De Almodovar, C.; Yaniv, K.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-09-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.559123
The neurovascular unit (NVU) is a complex structure comprising neurons, glia, and pericytes that interact with specialized endothelial cells to maintain cerebral homeostasis and blood-brain barrier (BBB) integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Disentangling non-random structure from random placement when estimating β-diversity through space or time
Authors: McGlinn, D.; Blowes, S. A.; Dornelas, M.; Engel, T.; Martins, I. S.; Shimadzu, H.; Gotelli, N. J.; Magurran, A.; McGill, B.; Chase, J. M.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.558467
There is considerable interest in understanding patterns of {beta}-diversity that measure the amount of change in species composition through space or time. Most hypotheses for {beta}-diversity evoke nonrandom processes that generate spatial and temporal within species aggregation; however, {beta}-diversity can also be driven by random sampling processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Glycemic outcomes of a family-focused intervention for adults with type 2 diabetes: Main, mediated, and subgroup effects from the FAMS 2.0 RCT
Authors: Nelson, L. A.; Spieker, A. J.; Greevy, R. A.; Roddy, M. K.; LeStourgeon, L. M.; Bergner, E. M.; El-Rifai, M.; Aikens, J. E.; Wolever, R. Q.; Elasy, T. A.; Mayberry, L. S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295374
AimsFamily/friends Activation to Motivate Self-care (FAMS) is a self-care support intervention delivered via mobile phones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Ventilation during COVID-19 in a school for students with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDD).
Authors: Zand, M. S.; Spallina, S.; Ross, A.; Zandi, K.; Pawlowski, A.; Seplaki, C.; Herington, J.; Corbett, A.; Kaukeinen, K.; Freedman, E.; Holden-Wiltse, J.; Alcantara, L.; Li, D.; Cameron, A.; Beaumont, N.; Dozier, A.; Dewhurst, S.; Foxe, J.
Score: 73.2, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295268
BackgroundThis study examined the correlation of classroom ventilation (air exchanges per hour (ACH)) and exposure to CO2 [&amp;amp;ge;]1,000 ppm with the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 over a 20-month period in a specialized school for students with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Self-assembling viral histones unravel early nucleosome evolution
Authors: Irwin, N. A. T.; Richards, T. A.
Score: 53.1, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558576
Nucleosomes are a core-component of eukaryotic nuclei, forming the structural basis of chromatin and co-ordinating processes from gene expression to chromosome segregation. Composed of a DNA-protein complex consisting of the four individual histones, H2A, H2B, H3, and H4, the nucleosome and its associated functions were key innovations during eukaryotic evolution1,2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>General purpose large language models match human performance on gastroenterology board exam self-assessments.
Authors: Ali, S.; Shahab, O.; Al Shabeeb, R.; Ladak, F.; Yang, J. O.; Nadkarni, G.; Echavarria, J.; Babar, S.; Shaukat, A.; Soroush, A.; El Kurdi, B.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.21.23295918
Introduction: While general-purpose large language models(LLMs) were able to pass USMLE-style examinations, their ability to perform in a specialized context, like gastroenterology, is unclear. In this study, we assessed the performance of three widely available LLMs: PaLM-2, GPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Distinct explanations underlie gene-environment interactions in the UK Biobank
Authors: Durvasula, A.; Price, A.
Score: 22.7, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295969
The role of gene-environment (GxE) interaction in disease and complex trait architectures is widely hypothesized, but currently unknown. Here, we apply three statistical approaches to quantify and distinguish three different types of GxE interaction for a given disease/trait and E variable. First, we detect locus-specific GxE interaction by testing for genetic correlation (rg) &amp;lt; 1 across E bins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Natural selection drives emergent genetic homogeneity in a century-scale experiment with barley
Authors: Landis, J. B.; Guercio, A. M.; Brown, K. E.; Fiscus, C. J.; Morrell, P. L.; Koenig, D.
Score: 26.0, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.557807
Direct observation is central to our understanding of the process of adaptation, but evolution is rarely documented in a large, multicellular organism for more than a few generations. Here, we observe genetic and phenotypic evolution across a century-scale competition experiment, barley composite cross II (CCII).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Biophysically Interpretable Inference of Cell Types from Multimodal Sequencing Data
Authors: Chari, T.; Gorin, G.; Pachter, L.
Score: 37.5, Published: 2023-09-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558131
Multimodal, single-cell genomics technologies enable simultaneous capture of multiple facets of DNA and RNA processing in the cell. This creates opportunities for transcriptome-wide, mechanistic studies of cellular processing in heterogeneous cell types, with applications ranging from inferring kinetic differences between cells, to the role of stochasticity in driving heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>A novel framework for assessing causal effect of microbiome on health: long-term antibiotic usage as pseudo-randomizer
Authors: Taba, N.; Fischer, K.; Org, E.; Aasmets, O.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295831
Gut microbiome (MB) has been widely shown to affect human health. Since MB in turn can be altered by various exposures, such as diet and medications, it holds immense potential for future treatments and healthy ageing. On the one hand, faecal microbiota transplantation and Mendelian Randomization have proven a causal link between treatment, MB and diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare system barriers impacting the care of Canadians with myalgic encephalomyelitis: a scoping review
Authors: Hussein, S.; Eiriksson, L.; MacQuarrie, M.; Merriam, S.; Dalton, M.; Stein, E.; Twomey, R.
Score: 33.3, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295809
BackgroundMyalgic encephalomyelitis (ME, also known as chronic fatigue syndrome or ME/CFS) is a debilitating, complex, multi-system illness. Developing a comprehensive understanding of the multiple and interconnected barriers to optimal care will help advance strategies and care models to improve quality of life for people living with ME in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>HIV incidence among non-migrating persons following a household migration event: a population-based, longitudinal study in Uganda
Authors: Young, R.; Ssekasanvu, J.; Kagaayi, J.; Ssekubugu, R.; Kigozi, G.; Reynolds, S. J.; Wawer, M. J.; Nonyane, B. A. S.; Nantume, B.; Quinn, T. C.; Tobian, A. A. R.; Santelli, J.; Chang, L. W.; Kennedy, C. E.; Paina, L.; Anglewicz, P. A.; Serwadda, D.; Nalugoda, F.; Grabowski, M. K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Immune Correlates of Hyperglycemia and Vaccination in a Non-human Primate Model of Long-COVID
Authors: Palmer, C. S.; Perdios, C.; Abdel-Mohsen, M.; Mudd, J.; Datta, P.; Maness, N.; Lehmicke, G.; Golden, N.; Hellmer, L.; Coyne, C.; Moore Green, K.; Midkiff, C.; Williams, K.; Tiburcio, R.; Fahlberg, M.; Boykin, K.; Kenway, C.; Russell-Lodrigue, K.; Bohm, R.; Blair, R. V.; Dufour, J.; Fischer, T.; Saied, A.; Rappaport, J.
Score: 36.3, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Wu, K.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 3355.8, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>TMPRSS2 activation of Omicron lineage Spike glycoproteins is regulated by TMPRSS2 cleavage of ACE2
Authors: Aggarwal, A.; Fichter, C.; Milogiannakis, V.; Akerman, A.; Ison, T.; Ruiz Silva, M.; Esneau, C.; Bartlett, N.; Burrell, L.; Patel, S.; Churchill, M.; Angelovich, T.; Parry, R.; Sng, J. D.; Neely, G. G.; Moreno, C. L.; Loo, L.; Kelleher, A. D.; Brilot, F.; Khromykh, A.; Turville, S. G.
Score: 65.1, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.558930</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>A paradigm for regulation at the effector interface with RNA-binding proteins
Authors: Shah, K.; He, S.; Turner, D. J.; Corbo, J.; Rebbani, K.; Bateman, J.; Cheloufi, S.; Igreja, C.; Valkov, E.; Murn, J.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558714
RNA-binding proteins (RBPs) are key regulators of gene expression, but how RBPs convey regulatory instructions to the core effectors of RNA processing is unclear. We address this problem by dissecting the effector interface responsible for regulation by a developmentally essential RBP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Navigating the Neurological Aftermath of COVID-19: An In-Depth Exploration
Authors: Butt, M.; Nagpal, S.; Phillips, E.; Shah, S. Q.; Dogar, Z.; Loh, H.; Mishra, S.; Vijayan, R.; Jeyakumar, R.; Makkar, S. S.; Jahan, S.; Diaz, G. M.; Franca, H.; Javed, S.; Belizaire, M.-P.; Reddy Somagutta, M.
Score: 140.7, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.10.23295343
BackgroundThe COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has affected millions of people and can result in both immediate and prolonged neurological effects, including severe complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neurological Imprints of Boys&amp;#39; Love Culture: Shaping Sexual Orientation Identity in the Digital Age&amp;#39;s Young females
Authors: Yanan, C.; Na, A.; Xiaowei, J.; Yingying, C.; Huihui, N.; Shuoyan, H.
Score: 576.9, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558088
With the omnipresence of social media, Boys Love (BL) culture has found a burgeoning audience among young females. While this cultural phenomenon offers a platform for self-expression to some, its potential implications remain underexplored. This study investigates whether immersion in BL culture impacts the process of young females forming self-recognition and identification of sexual orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Dietary sulfur amino acid restriction in humans with overweight and obesity: a translational randomized controlled trial
Authors: Olsen, T.; Stolt, E.; Ovrebo, B.; Elshorbagy, A.; Tore, E. C.; Lee-Oedegard, S.; Troensegaard, H.; Johannessen, H.; Doeland, B.; Vo, A. A. D.; Dahl, A. F.; Svendsen, K.; Thoresen, M.; Refsum, H.; Rising, R.; Barvikova, K.; Greevenbroek, M. v.; Kozich, V.; Retterstol, K.; Vinknes, K. J.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295155</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A clinicogenomic model including GARD predicts outcome for radiation treated patients with HPV&amp;#43; oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma
Authors: Ho, E.; DeCecco, L.; Cavalieri, S.; Sedor, G.; Hoebers, F.; Brakenhoff, R.; Scheckenbach, K.; Poli, T.; Yang, K.; Scarborough, J.; Campbell, S.; Koyfman, S.; Eschrich, S. A.; Caudell, J.; Kattan, M. W.; Licitra, L.; Torres-Roca, J.; Scott, J. G.
Score: 20.3, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.23295538
BackgroundTreatment decision-making in oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma (OPSCC) includes clinical stage, HPV status, and smoking history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Real-world gait and turning in individuals scheduled for total knee arthroplasty
Authors: Boekesteijn, R. J.; Keijsers, N. L. W.; Defoort, K.; Mancini, M.; Bruning, F. J.; El-Gohary, M.; Geurts, A. C. H.; Smulders, K.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295243
ObjectiveTo compare real-world gait and turning between individuals scheduled for total knee arthroplasty (TKA) and healthy controls, using continuous monitoring with inertial measurement units (IMUs). DesignReal-world gait and turning data were collected for 5-7 days in individuals scheduled for TKA (n=34) and healthy controls in the same age range (n=32) using IMUs on the feet and lower back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Savoring Meditation on Positive Emotions and Pain-Related Brain Function: A Mechanistic Randomized Controlled Trial in People With Rheumatoid Arthritis
Authors: Finan, P.; Hunt, C.; Keaser, M. L.; Smith, K.; Lerman, S.; Bingham, C. O.; Barrett, F.; Garland, E. L.; Zeidan, F.; Seminowicz, D. A.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23294949
Positive emotions are a promising target for intervention in chronic pain, but mixed findings across trials to date suggest that existing interventions may not be optimized to efficiently engage the target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Forensic Facial Approximation of Achondroplastic Dwarf from Medieval Cemetery in Central Europe
Authors: Moraes, C.; Krenz-Niedbała, M.; Łukasik, S.; Prada, C. S.
Score: 63.5, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.26.553833
Achondroplasia (ACH, achondroplastic dwarfism) represents the most common form of skeletal dysplasia, occurring in c. 4 out of every 100,000 births. This study presents a computer-based facial approximation of the skull of a male individual suffering from ACH, who died at 30-45 years of age and was buried in ekno, Poland between the 9th and 11th centuries AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Native ultrastructure of fresh human brain vitrified directly from autopsy revealed by cryo-electron tomography with cryo-plasma focused ion beam milling
Authors: Creekmore, B. C.; Kixmoeller, K.; Black, B. E.; Lee, E. B.; Chang, Y.-W.
Score: 28.6, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557623
Ultrastructure of human brain tissue has traditionally been examined using electron microscopy (EM) following chemical fixation, staining, and mechanical sectioning, which limit attainable resolution and introduce artifacts. Alternatively, cryo-electron tomography (cryo-ET) offers the potential to image unfixed cellular samples at higher resolution while preserving their native structures, but it requires samples to be frozen free from crystalline ice and thin enough to image via transmission EM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Corpus callosum abnormalities at term-equivalent age are associated with language development at two years corrected age in infants born very preterm
Authors: Kojima, K.; Kline, J. E.; Altaye, M.; Kline Fath, B. M.; Parikh, N. A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295848
We studied the impact of microstructural abnormalities in the corpus callosum on language development in 348 infants born very prematurely. We discovered that the fractional anisotropy of the corpus callosum anterior midbody was a significant predictor of standardized language scores at two years, independent of clinical and social risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Atazanavir/ritonavir increased tizoxanide exposure from oral nitazoxanide through pharmacokinetic interaction in healthy volunteers
Authors: Akinloye, A.; Oyedeji, T.; Eniayewu, O.; Adeagbo, B.; Bolaji, O.; Rannard, S.; Owen, A.; Olagunju, A.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295544
AimsNitazoxanide is a broad-spectrum antiviral with potential application in a number of viral infections. Its use is limited by gastrointestinal side effects associated with increasing dose. In this study, we investigated the possibility of enhancing the exposure of its active metabolite, tizoxanide, through pharmacokinetic interaction with atazanavir/ritonavir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Self-supervised deep learning uncovers the semantic landscape of drug-induced latent mitochondrial phenotypes
Authors: Natekar, P.; Wang, Z.; Arora, M.; Hakozaki, H.; Schoeneberg, J.
Score: 77.5, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557636
Imaging-based high-content screening aims to identify substances that modulate cellular phenotypes. Traditional approaches screen compounds for their ability to shift disease phenotypes toward healthy phenotypes, but these end point-based screens lack an atlas-like mapping between phenotype and cell state that covers the full spectrum of possible phenotypic responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of mammalian mtDNA transcription paradoxically activates liver fatty acid oxidation to reverse diet-induced hepatosteatosis and obesity
Authors: Jiang, S.; Yuan, T.; Kremer, L. S.; Rosenberger, F. A.; Hansen, F. M.; Borg, M.; Rubalcava-Gracia, D.; Mennuni, M.; Filograna, R.; Alsina, D.; Misic, J.; Koolmeister, C.; Ren, L.; Andersson, O.; Unger, A.; Bergbrede, T.; Lucrezia, R. D.; Wilbom, R.; Zierath, J. R.; Krook, A.; Giavalisco, P.; Mann, M.; Larsson, N.-G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Whole mount multiplexed visualization of DNA, mRNA, and protein in plant-parasitic nematodes
Authors: Sperling, A. L.; Eves-van den Akker, S.
Score: 20.3, Published: 2023-09-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.23.559107
Plant-parasitic nematodes compromise the agriculture of a wide variety of the most common crops worldwide. Obtaining information on the fundamental biology of these organisms and how they infect the plant has been restricted by the ability to visualize intact nematodes using small molecule stains, antibodies, or in situ hybridization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Prenatal cannabis exposure is associated with focal brain differences that partially mediate associations with increased adolescent psychopathology
Authors: Baranger, D. A.; Miller, A. P.; Gorelik, A. J.; Paul, S. E.; Hatoum, A. S.; Johnson, E. C.; Colbert, S. M. C.; Smyser, C. D.; Rogers, C. E.; Bijsterbosch, J. D.; Agrawal, A.; Bogdan, R.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.23295792
Prenatal cannabis exposure (PCE) is associated with mental health problems, but the neurobiological mechanisms remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Highly efficient and sensitive membrane-based concentration process allows quantification, surveillance, and sequencing of viruses in large volumes of wastewater.
Authors: El Soufi, G.; Di Jorio, L.; Gerber, Z.; Cluzel, N.; Van Assche, J.; Delafoy, D.; Olaso, R.; Daviaud, C.; Loustau, T.; Schwartz, C.; Trebouet, D.; Hernalsteens, O.; Marechal, V.; Raffestin, S.; Rousset, D.; Van Lint, C.; Deleuze, J.-F.; Boni, M.; OBEPINE Consortium, ; ROHR, O.; Villain-Gambier, M.; Wallet, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Radiomic-Based Prediction of Lesion-Specific Systemic Treatment Response in Metastatic Disease
Authors: Geady, C.; Abbas-Aghababazadeh, F.; Kohan, A.; Schuetze, S.; Shultz, D.; Haibe-Kains, B.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23294942
Despite sharing the same histologic classification, individual tumors in multi metastatic patients may present with different characteristics and varying sensitivities to anticancer therapies. In this study, we investigate the utility of radiomic biomarkers for prediction of lesion-specific treatment resistance in multi metastatic leiomyosarcoma patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Controlled experiment finds no detectable citation bump from Twitter promotion
Authors: Branch, T.; C?te, I. M.; David, S. R.; Drew, J. A.; LaRue, M.; Marquez, M. C.; Parsons, E. C. M.; Rabaiotti, D.; Shiffman, D.; Steen, D. A.; Wild, A. L.
Score: 227.5, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558161
Multiple studies across a variety of scientific disciplines have shown that the number of times that a paper is shared on Twitter (now called X) is correlated with the number of citations that paper receives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Computational design of sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins
Authors: Glasscock, C. J.; Pecoraro, R.; McHugh, R.; Doyle, L. A.; Chen, W.; Boivin, O.; Lonnquist, B.; Na, E.; Politanska, Y.; Haddox, H. K.; Cox, D.; Norn, C.; Coventry, B.; Goreshnik, I.; Vafeados, D.; Lee, G. R.; Gordan, R.; Stoddard, B. L.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 189.2, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558720
Sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins (DBPs) play critical roles in biology and biotechnology, and there has been considerable interest in the engineering of DBPs with new or altered specificities for genome editing and other applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Digitize your Biology! Modeling multicellular systems through interpretable cell behavior
Authors: Johnson, J. A. I.; Stein-O&amp;#39;Brien, G. L.; Booth, M.; Heiland, R.; Kurtoglu, F.; Bergman, D.; Bucher, E.; Deshpande, A.; Forjaz, A.; Getz, M.; Godet, I.; Lyman, M.; Metzcar, J.; Mitchell, J.; Raddatz, A.; Rocha, H. L.; Solorzano, J.; Sundus, A.; Wang, Y.; Gilkes, D. M.; Kagohara, L. T.; Kiemen, A. L.; Thompson, E. D.; Wirtz, D.; Wu, P.-H.; Zaidi, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Historical biogeography of New World Killifishes (Cyprinodontiformes: Funduloidea) recapitulates geographical history in the Gulf of Mexico watershed
Authors: Hernandez, S. G.; Hoagstrom, C. W.; Matamoros, W. A.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556706
We reconstructed the phylogenetic relationships of superfamily Funduloidea with a synthesis of its biogeographic history. We used DNA sequences from five genes for 135 species, with four fossil calibrations, to generate a time-calibrated phylogeny. We estimated diversification rates, ancestral areas (Nearctic or Neotropical), and ancestral habitat (coastal or upland), for each node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
