<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in Hallucinogen-associated Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations in California from 2016-2021
Authors: Tate, S.; Garel, N.; Nash, K.; Lembke, A.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294275
ObjectivesHallucinogens encompass a diverse range of compounds with increasing scientific and public interest. Risks associated with hallucinogen use are poorly understood. This study aims to evaluate the trends in hallucinogen-related emergency department visits and hospitalizations in California from 2016 to 2021, as compared to alcohol and cannabis visits and hospitalizations MethodsWe conducted a descriptive study on publicly available data on diagnosis codes associated with emergency department (ED) visits and hospitalizations from the California Department of Healthcare Access and Information (HCAI) to describe hallucinogen, alcohol, and cannabis associated encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Immunometabolic effects of lactate on B cell function in healthy individuals of different ages
Authors: Romero, M.; Miller, K.; Gelsomini, A.; Garcia, D.; Li, K.; Suresh, D.; Frasca, D.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.23293760
Aging is characterized by chronic systemic inflammation and metabolic changes. When we compared B cells from young and elderly donors, we found that aging induces higher oxygen consumption rates, and especially higher extracellular acidification rates, measures of oxidative phosphorylation and of anaerobic glycolysis, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 126.1, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been restricted to social or object interaction. Here we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel. We demonstrate that flies exhibit idiosyncratic carousel interactions that qualify as play-like behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>The resting state of the human T-cell receptor
Authors: Notti, R. Q.; Yi, F.; Heissel, S.; Molina, H.; Klebanoff, C. A.; Walz, T.
Score: 28.7, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554360
The T-cell receptor (TCR) is central to the ligand-dependent activation of T lymphocytes and as such orchestrates both adaptive and pathologic immune processes1. However, major questions remain regarding the structure and function of the human TCR2-4. Here, we present cryogenic electron microscopy structures for the unliganded human TCR in a native-like lipid bilayer, revealing three related conformations that are distinct from previously reported structures of receptors in detergent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Reengineering of a flavin-binding fluorescent protein using ProteinMPNN
Authors: Nikolaev, A.; Kuzmin, A.; Markeeva, E.; Kuznetsova, E.; Semenov, O.; Anuchina, A.; Remeeva, A.; Gushchin, I.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554855
Recent advances in machine learning techniques have led to development of a number of protein design and engineering approaches. One of them, ProteinMPNN, predicts an amino acid sequence that would fold and match user-defined backbone structure. In this short report, we test whether ProteinMPNN can be used to reengineer a flavin-binding fluorescent protein, CagFbFP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Voyager: exploratory single-cell genomics data analysis with geospatial statistics
Authors: Moses, L.; Einarsson, P. H.; Jackson, K. C.; Luebbert, L.; Booeshaghi, A. S.; Antonsson, S. E.; Bray, N.; Melsted, P.; Pachter, L.
Score: 130.7, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549945
Exploratory spatial data analysis (ESDA) can be a powerful approach to understanding single-cell genomics datasets, but it is not yet part of standard data analysis workflows. In particular, geospatial analyses, which have been developed and refined for decades, have yet to be fully adapted and applied to spatial single-cell analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Time-Resolved Cryo-EM Specimen Preparation with Single Millisecond Precision
Authors: Montano Romero, A.; Bonin, C.; Twomey, E. C.
Score: 47.1, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.554704
Molecular structures can be determined in vitro and in situ with cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM). Specimen preparation is a major obstacle in cryo-EM. Typical sample preparation is orders of magnitude slower than biological processes. Time-resolved cryo-EM (TR-cryo-EM) can capture short-lived states. Here, we present Cryo-EM Sample Preparation with light-Activated Molecules (C-SPAM), an open-source, photochemistry-coupled device for TR-cryo-EM with single millisecond resolution, tunable timescales, and broad biological applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 668.8, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Determinants of Bluetooth-enabled Self Measured Blood Pressure Monitoring in Federally Qualified Health Centers
Authors: Hellem, A.; Whitfield, C.; Mansour, M.; Curran, Y.; Dinh, M.; Warden, K.; Skolarus, L. E.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294249
BackgroundIn 2021, the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) launched the National Hypertension Control Initiative (HTN Initiative) with the goal to enhance HTN control through Bluetooth-enabled self-measured blood pressure (BT SMBP) monitoring and use this data to inform clinical decisions in Federally Qualified Health Centers (FQHCs) with large proportion of their population with uncontrolled BP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Lineage tracing of newly accrued nuclei in skeletal myofibers uncovers distinct transcripts and interplay between nuclear populations
Authors: Sun, C.; Swoboda, C.; Petrany, M.; Parameswaran, S.; VonHandorf, A.; Weirauch, M. T.; Lepper, C.; Millay, D.
Score: 20.3, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.554609
Multinucleated skeletal muscle cells have an obligatory need to acquire additional nuclei through fusion with activated skeletal muscle stem cells when responding to both developmental and adaptive growth stimuli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Morphodynamics of human early brain organoid development
Authors: Jain, A.; Gut, G.; Sanchis Calleja, F.; Okamoto, R.; Streib, S.; He, Z.; Zenk, F.; Santel, M.; Seimiya, M.; Holtackers, R.; Jansen, S. M. J.; Camp, J. G.; Treutlein, B.
Score: 53.2, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.553827
Brain organoids enable the mechanistic study of human brain development, and provide opportunities to explore self-organization in unconstrained developmental systems. Here, we establish long-term, live light sheet microscopy on unguided brain organoids generated from fluorescently labeled human induced pluripotent stem cells, which enables tracking of tissue morphology, cell behaviors, and subcellular features over weeks of organoid development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Island biogeography theory and the gut: why taller people tend to harbor more diverse gut microbiomes.
Authors: Ramos Sarmiento, K.; Carr, A.; Diener, C.; Locey, K. J.; Gibbons, S. M.
Score: 51.9, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552554
Prior work has shown a positive scaling relationship between vertebrate body size and gut microbiome alpha-diversity. This observation mirrors commonly observed species area relationships (SAR) in many other ecosystems. Here, we show a similar scaling relationship between human height and gut microbiome alpha-diversity across two large, independent cohorts, controlling for a wide range of relevant covariates, such as body mass index, age, sex, and bowel movement frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Combination low dose sulphonylurea and DPP4 inhibitor have potent glucose effect through augmentation of beta cell function without increase in hypoglycaemia: a randomised crossover study.
Authors: Cordiner, R. L.; Bedair, K.; Mari, A.; Pearson, E. R.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294403
Aims/HypothesisIt is important to address our use of cheaper generic therapies as the global prevalence of type 2 diabetes (T2DM) will surpass 600 million by 2035. Negative aspects of SU may be avoided by their use at low dose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>High proportions of post-exertional malaise and orthostatic intolerance in people living with post-COVID-19 condition: the PRIME post-COVID study
Authors: Pagen, D. M.; Van Herck, M.; van Bilsen, C. J.; Brinkhues, S.; Konings, K.; den Heijer, C. D.; Spruit, M. A.; Hoebe, C. J.; Dukers-Muijrers, N. H.
Score: 297.6, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294204
BackgroundExercise-based treatments can be harmful in people who were SARS-CoV-2 positive and living with post-COVID-19 condition (PL-PCC) and who have post-exertional malaise (PEM) or orthostatic intolerance (OI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Rapid turnover of centromeric DNA reveals signatures of genetic conflict in Drosophila
Authors: Courret, C.; Hemmer, L.; Wei, X.; Patel, P. D.; Santinello, B.; Geng, X.; Chang, C.-H.; Mellone, B.; Larracuente, A. M.
Score: 16.2, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554357
Despite their essential function in chromosome segregation, centromeres reside in rapidly evolving, repeat-rich genomic regions. Across organisms, centromeres are rich in selfish genetic elements like transposable elements and satellite DNAs that can bias their transmission through meiosis, but still need to contribute to centromere function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Utility of EsoGuard as a Triage Test for Endoscopy to Identify Barrett&amp;#39;s Esophagus in Fire Fighters
Authors: Hamblin, R.; Lee, V. T.; deGuzman, B. J.; Verma, S.; Aklog, L.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294176
Background: Firefighters have frequent exposure to smoke and compounds that have been shown to increase the risk of developing esophageal neoplasia. EsoGuard is a DNA biomarker assay that can be utilized with efficiency and high tolerability as a triage test in the diagnosis of patients with Barrett&amp;#39;s Esophagus (BE) and/or esophageal adenocarcinoma (EAC) in this population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Chromosome 20p11.2 deletions cause congenital hyperinsulinism via the likely disruption of FOXA2
Authors: Laver, T. W.; Wakeling, M. N.; Caswell, R. C.; Bunce, B.; Yau, D.; Houghton, J. A.; Hopkins, J. J.; Weedon, M. N.; Saraff, V.; Kershaw, M.; Honey, E.; Murphy, N.; Giri, D.; Nath, S.; Saredo, A. T.; Banerjee, I.; Hussain, K.; Owens, N. D.; Flanagan, S. E.
Score: 23.3, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294161
Persistent congenital hyperinsulinism (HI) is a rare genetically heterogeneous condition characterised by dysregulated insulin secretion leading to life-threatening hypoglycaemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Admixture as a source for HLA variation in Neolithic European farming communities
Authors: da Silva, N. A.; Ozer, O.; Haller, M.; Chen, Y.-R.; Kolbe, D.; Schade-Linding, S.; Wahl, J.; Berszin, C.; Francken, M.; Gorner, I.; Schierhold, K.; Pechtl, J.; Grupe, G.; Rinne, C.; Muller, J.; Lenz, T. L.; Nebel, A.; Krause-Kyora, B.
Score: 15.6, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.554285
The northern European Neolithic is characterized by two major demographic events: immigration of early farmers (EF) from Anatolia (5500 BCE) and their admixture (from [~]4200 BCE) with western hunter-gatherers (WHG) forming late farmers (LF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Reconstructing the genetic relationship between ancient and present-day Siberian populations
Authors: Gill, H.; Lee, J.; Jeong, C.
Score: 22.6, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554074
Human populations across a vast area in northern Eurasia, from Fennoscandia to Chukotka, share a distinct genetic component often referred to as the Siberian ancestry. Most enriched in present-day Samoyedic-speaking populations such as Nganasans, its origins and history still remain elusive despite the growing list of ancient and present-day genomes from Siberia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Subtyping Social Determinants of Health in All of Us: Network Analysis and Visualization Approach
Authors: Bhavnani, S. K.; Zhang, W.; Bao, D.; Raji, M.; Ajewole, V.; Hunter, R.; Kuo, Y.-f.; Schmidt, S.; Pappadis, M.; Bokov, A.; Reistetter, T.; Visweswaran, S.; Downer, B.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.01.27.23285125
A.BackgroundSocial determinants of health (SDoH), such as financial resources and housing stability, account for between 30-55% of peoples health outcomes. While many studies have identified strong associations among specific SDoH and health outcomes, most people experience multiple SDoH that impact their daily lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The Effects of Development Assistance on Sexual and Reproductive Health Services in Low- and Middle-Income Countries: A Cross-Country Panel Data Analysis
Authors: Ekman, B.; Sundewall, J.; Schmit, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294532
Using data on 119 low- and lower-middle income countries from 2002 to 2020, we apply fixed-effects (FE) methods to evaluate the impacts of three different classifications of development assistance on access to three types of sexual and reproductive health (SRH) services: access to skilled birth attendance, prevalence of modern contraceptives, and coverage of antiretroviral therapies against HIV/AIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>ACCORD (ACcurate COnsensus Reporting Document): A reporting guideline for consensus methods in biomedicine developed via a modified Delphi
Authors: Gattrell, W. T.; Logullo, P.; van Zuuren, E. J.; Price, A.; Hughes, E. L.; Blazey, P.; Winchester, C. C.; Tovey, D.; Goldman, K.; Hungin, A. P.; Harrison, N.
Score: 10.0, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294261
BackgroundIn biomedical research, it is often desirable to seek consensus among individuals who have differing perspectives and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Intraepithelial CD15 infiltration identifies high grade anal dysplasia in people with HIV
Authors: Burgos, J.; Mancebo, C.; Massana, N.; Astorga-Gamaza, A.; Castellvi, J.; Landolfi, S.; Curran, A.; Garcia-Perez, J. N.; Falco, V.; Buzon, M. J.; Genesca, M.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294199
Men who have sex with men (MSM) with HIV are at high risk for squamous intraepithelial lesion (SIL) and anal cancer. The identification of local immunological mechanisms involved in the development of anal dysplasia could aid treatment and diagnostics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Mucosal antibody responses to SARS-CoV-2 booster vaccination and breakthrough infection
Authors: Bhavsar, D.; Singh, G.; Sano, K.; Gleason, C.; Srivastava, K.; Carreno, J. M.; Simon, V.; Krammer, F.
Score: 54.9, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.554732
Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccines have saved millions of lives. However, variants of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) have emerged causing large numbers of breakthrough infections. These developments necessitated the rollout of COVID-19 vaccine booster doses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 493.0, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Neutralizing Antibodies Following a Second BA.5 Bivalent Booster
Authors: Wang, Q.; Bowen, A.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R.; Valdez, R.; Stoneman, E.; Gordon, A.; Lihong, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 355.7, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553148
Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA vaccines expressing both the ancestral D614G and Omicron BA.5 spike proteins were introduced in August 2022 with the goal of broadening immunity to emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariants. Subsequent studies on bivalent boosters found neutralizing antibody responses similar to boosters with the original monovalent vaccine, likely the result of immunological imprinting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>A bacterial expression cloning screen reveals tardigrade single-stranded DNA-binding proteins as potent desicco-protectants
Authors: Hibshman, J. D.; Clark-Hachtel, C. M.; Bloom, K. S.; Goldstein, B.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554171
Tardigrades are known for their ability to survive remarkable extremes, but relatively little is known about the molecular underpinnings that allow for their extraordinary stress tolerance. We devised an expression cloning approach to screen for novel protectants from desiccation-tolerant tardigrades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Use of the Selective Cytopheretic Device to Support Critically Ill Children Requiring Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy: A Probable Benefit-Risk Assessment
Authors: Goldstein, S. L.; Ollberding, N. J.; Askenazi, D. J.; Basu, R. K.; Selewski, D. T.; Krallman, K. A.; Yessayan, L.; Humes, H. D.
Score: 7.1, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294378
BackgroundCritically ill children with acute kidney injury (AKI) requiring continuous kidney replacement therapy (CRRT) are at increased risk of death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Transcobalamin Receptor Autoantibodies in Central Vitamin B12 Deficiency
Authors: Pluvinage, J. V.; Ngo, T.; Bartley, C. M.; Bodansky, A.; Alvarenga, B. D.; Zorn, K. C.; Fouassier, C.; Zamecnik, C.; McCann, A.; Huynh, T.; Browne, W.; Tubati, A.; Kondapavulur, S.; Anderson, M. S.; Green, A. J.; Green, R.; Douglas, V.; Louine, M.; Cree, B.; Hauser, S.; Seeley, W.; Holmes, B. B.; Wells, J. A.; Spudich, S.; Farhadian, S.; Ramachandran, P.; Gillum, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Ultra-high density electrodes improve detection, yield, and cell type specificity of brain recordings
Authors: Ye, Z.; Shelton, A. M.; Shaker, J. R.; Boussard, J. M.; Colonell, J.; Minavi, S.; Chen, S.; Windolf, C.; Hurwitz, C.; Namima, T.; Pedraja, F.; Weiss, S.; Raducanu, B.; Ness, T.; Einevoll, G. T.; Laurent, G.; Sawtell, N. B.; Bair, W.; Pasupathy, A.; Mora-Lopez, C.; Dutta, B.; Paninski, L.; Siegle, J. H.; Koch, C.; Olsen, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>The impact of live dietary microbes on health: a scoping review
Authors: Iyer, A.; Mukherjee, A.; Gomez-Sala, B.; O&amp;#39;Connor, E. M.; Kenny, J. G.; Cotter, P. D.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294168
BackgroundA systematic approach to collect, peruse and summarise the available information relating to the potential benefits of consuming dietary microbes was pursued in this scoping review. This review focused on the research endpoints, experimental designs, and microbial exposure in experimental as well as observational research work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing tuberculosis in artisanal and small-scale mining activities in sub-Saharan Africa: meta-analysis and a call for actions
Authors: Mayeri, D. G.; Kambale, R. M.; Bugeme, P. M.; Ngaboyeka, G. A.; Mushagalusa, C.; Zahinda, F. M.; Tamuzi, J. L.; Katoto, P. C.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294543
BackgroundTuberculosis (TB) is a significant health issue in sub-Saharan African (SSA) countries, and artisanal mining (AM) may be a contributing factor. However, no systematic review has investigated the association between AM and TB in SSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Insights into the Mechanisms and Structure of Breakage-Fusion-Bridge Cycles in Cervical Cancer using Long-Read Sequencing
Authors: Rodriguez, I.; Rossi, N. M.; Keskus, A.; Xie, Y.; Ahmad, T.; Bryant, A.; Lou, H.; Godinez Paredes, J.; Milano, R.; Rao, N.; Tulsyan, S.; Boland, J. F.; Luo, W.; Liu, J.; O&amp;#39;Hanlon, T.; Bess, J.; Mukhina, V.; Gaylalova, D.; Yuki, Y.; Malik, L.; Billingsley, K.; Blauwendraat, C.; Carrington, M.; Yeager, M.; Mirabello, L.; Kolmogorov, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>The three-dimensionally articulated oral apparatus of a Devonian heterostracan sheds light on feeding in Palaeozoic jawless fishes
Authors: Dearden, R. P.; Jones, A.; Giles, S.; Lanzetti, A.; Grohganz, M.; Johanson, Z.; Lautenschlager, S.; Randle, E.; Donoghue, P.; Sansom, I. J.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554283
Attempts to explain the origin and diversification of vertebrates have commonly invoked the evolution of feeding ecology, contrasting the passive suspension feeding of invertebrate chordate and larval lampreys with active predation in living jawed vertebrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Absence of Lipopolysccharide (LPS) expression in Breast Cancer Cells
Authors: de Miranda, N. F.; Smit, V. T.; van der Ploeg, M.; Wesseling, J.; Neefjes, J.
Score: 38.8, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.28.555057
The association between bacterial activity and tumorigenesis has gained attention in recent years, alongside the well-established link between viruses and cancer. A recent study proposed the presence of intracellular bacteria in cancer cells, particularly in melanomas and breast cancers, with detectable bacterial DNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Gain-of-function MARK4 variant associates with pediatric neurodevelopmental disorder and dysmorphism
Authors: Samra, S.; Sharma, M.; Vaseghi-Shanjani, M.; Del Bel, K. L.; Byres, L.; Lin, S.; Dalmann, J.; Salman, A.; Mwenifumbo, J.; Modi, B. P.; Biggs, C. M.; Boelman, C.; Clarke, L. A.; Lehman, A.; the CAUSES Study, ; Turvey, S. E.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294399
Microtubule affinity regulating kinase 4 (MARK4) is a serine/threonine kinase that plays a key role in tau phosphorylation and regulation of the mTOR pathway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Psilocybin desynchronizes brain networks
Authors: Siegel, J. S.; Subramanian, S.; Perry, D. A.; Kay, B. P.; Gordon, E. M.; Laumann, T. O.; Chacko, R. V.; Reneau, T. R.; Metcalf, N. V.; Horan, C.; Schweiger, J. A.; Wong, D.; Bender, D.; Padawer-Curry, J.; Raison, C. L.; Carhart-Harris, R.; Raichle, M. E.; Lenze, E. J.; Snyder, A. Z.; Dosenbach, N. U. F.; Nicol, G. E.
Score: 79.2, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294131</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>A Biotin Targeting Chimera (BioTAC) System to Map Small Molecule Interactomes in situ
Authors: Tao, A. J.; Jiang, J.; Gadbois, G. E.; Goyal, P.; Boyle, B. T.; Mumby, E. J.; Myers, S. A.; English, J. G.; Ferguson, F. M.
Score: 45.4, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554211
Unbiased chemical biology strategies for direct readout of protein interactome remodelling by small molecules provide advantages over target-focused approaches, including the ability to detect previously unknown targets, and the inclusion of chemical off-compete controls leading to high-confidence identifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Elephants develop wrinkles through both form &amp;amp; function
Authors: Schulz, A. K.; Kaufmann, L.; Reveyaz, N.; Ritter, C.; Hildebrandt, T.; Brecht, M. K.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.554618
Elephant trunks have folds and wrinkles, but we don&amp;#39;t know how wrinkles differ between elephant species and how trunks and their wrinkles develop. Adult Asian elephants have significantly more dorsal major trunk wrinkles (~126 &amp;#43;/- 25 SD) than African elephants (~83 &amp;#43;/- 13 SD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Uncovering the Infection Strategy of Phyllachora maydis during Maize Colonization: A Comprehensive Analysis
Authors: Caldwell, D. L.; Da Silva, C. R.; McCoy, A. G.; Avila, H.; Bonkowski, J. C.; Chilvers, M.; Helm, M.; Telenko, D. E.; Iyer-Pascuzzi, A. S.
Score: 21.2, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.26.554799
Tar spot, a disease caused by the ascomycete fungal pathogen Phyllachora maydis, is considered one of the most significant yield-limiting diseases of maize (Zea mays L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review of Interventions for Prevention and Treatment of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Following Childbirth
Authors: Dekel, S.; Papadakis, J. E.; Quagliarini, B.; Jagodnik, K. M.; Nandru, R.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294230
Structured AbstractO_ST_ABSObjectiveC_ST_ABSPostpartum women can develop post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in response to complicated, traumatic childbirth; prevalence of these events remains high in the U.S. Currently, there is no recommended treatment approach in routine peripartum care for preventing maternal childbirth-related PTSD (CB-PTSD) and lessening its severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence and pattern of Post Covid-19 symptoms in recovered patients of Delhi: A Population-Based study
Authors: Bhatnagar, N.; Singh, M. M.; Sharma, H.; Mishra, S.; Singh, G.; Rao, S.; Borle, A.; Anand, T.; Kumar, N.; Goswami, B.; Singh, S.; Kapoor, M.; Singla, S.; Khuraijam, B.; Khurana, N.; Sharma, U.; Garg, S.
Score: 37.7, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294654
Background: Post-coronavirus disease (COVID) is widely reported but the data of Post COVID-19 after infection with the Omicron variant is limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Characterizing patterns of DTI variance in aging brains
Authors: Gao, C.; Yang, Q.; Kim, M. E.; Mohd Khairi, N.; Cai, L. Y.; Newlin, N. R.; Kanakaraj, P.; Remedios, L. W.; Krishnan, A. R.; Yu, X.; Yao, T.; Zhang, P.; Schilling, K. G.; Moyer, D.; Archer, D. B.; Resnick, S. M.; Landman, B. A.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294381
PurposeAs large analyses merge data across sites, a deeper understanding of variance in statistical assessment across the sources of data becomes critical for valid analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Kinesiophobia and physical activity: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Goubran, M.; Farajzadeh, A.; Lahart, I. M.; Bilodeau, M.; Boisgontier, M. P.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294240
AbstractO_ST_ABSObjectiveC_ST_ABSPhysical activity is known to reduce the risk of disability, disease, and mortality. However, in some patients, an excessive, irrational, and debilitating fear of movement (i.e., kinesiophobia) is thought to induce avoidance behaviors, contributing to decreased engagement in physical activity. The aim of this study was to examine whether kinesiophobia is negatively associated with physical activity and what factors influence this relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A genome-wide association study of adults with community-acquired pneumonia
Authors: Suarez-Pajes, E.; Marcelino-Rodriguez, I.; Hernandez Brito, E.; Gonzalez-Barbuzano, S.; Ramirez-Falcon, M.; Tosco-Herrera, E.; Rubio-Rodriguez, L. A.; Briones, M. L.; Rajas, O.; Borderias, L.; Ferreres, J.; Payeras, A.; Lorente, L.; Aspa, J.; Lorenzo-Salazar, J. M.; Valencia-Gallardo, J. M.; Carbonell, E.; Freixinet, J.; Rodriguez de Castro, F.; Sole Violan, J.; Flores, C.; Rodriguez-Gallego, C.
Score: 5.2, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294759
Introduction. Community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) is associated with high morbidity and hospitalization rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of JAK-STAT pathway corrects salivary gland inflammation and interferon driven immune activation in Sjögren&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Warner, B. M.; Gupta, S.; Yamada, E.; Nakamura, H.; Perez, P.; Pranzatelli, T. J. F.; Dominick, K.; Jang, S.-I.; Abed, M.; Martin, D.; Burbelo, P.; Zheng, C.; French, B.; Alevizos, I.; Khavandgar, Z.; Beach, M.; Pelayo, E.; Walitt, B.; Hasni, S.; Kaplan, M.; Tandon, M.; Magone, M. T.; Kleiner, D.; Chiorini, J.; Baer, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Gender differences in submission behavior exacerbate publication disparities in elite journals
Authors: Basson, I.; Ni, C.; Badia, G.; Tufenkji, N.; Sugimoto, C. R.; Lariviere, V.
Score: 7.8, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554192
Women are particularly underrepresented in journals of the highest scientific impact, with substantial consequences for their careers. While a large body of research has focused on the outcome and the process of peer review, fewer articles have explicitly focused on gendered submission behavior and the explanations for these differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Protocol for a scoping review of literature on digital sexual, reproductive, and gender health care for LGBTQI&amp;#43; youth
Authors: McLeod, J.; Flowers, P.; Gibbs, J.; Estcourt, C. S.; MacDonald, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294615
Introduction: Lesbian, gay, bisexual, trans, queer, questioning, and other sexual and gender minority (LGBTQI&amp;#43;) youth are diverse populations who experience poor sexual health outcomes (e.g., high rates of sexually transmitted infections (STIs) and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), unplanned pregnancy, and sexual violence) and multiple barriers to sexual and reproductive health care (SRHC) and gender health care (GHC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A sweat lactate sensor for detecting anaerobic threshold in patients with heart failure: a prospective clinical trial (LacS-001)
Authors: KATSUMATA, Y.; Muramoto, Y.; Ishida, N.; Takemura, R.; Nagashima, K.; Ikoma, T.; Kawamatsu, N.; Araki, M.; Goda, A.; Okawara, H.; Sawada, T.; Kawakubo, Y.; Hattori, O.; Yamaoka, K.; Seki, Y.; Ryuzaki, T.; Ikura, H.; Nakashima, D.; Nagura, T.; Nakamura, M.; Sato, K.; Shiraishi, Y.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.23294144</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Rationally seeded computational protein design
Authors: Albanese, K. I.; Petrenas, R.; Pirro, F.; Naudin, E. A.; Borucu, U.; Dawson, W. M.; Scott, D. A.; Leggett, G. J.; Weiner, O. D.; Oliver, T.; Woolfson, D.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-08-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554789
Computational protein design is advancing rapidly. Here we describe efficient routes to two families of -helical-barrel proteins with central channels that bind small molecules. The designs are seeded by the sequences and structures of defined de novo oligomeric barrel-forming peptides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Large-scale analysis of the integration of enhancer-enhancer signals by promoters
Authors: Martinez-Ara, M.; Comoglio, F.; van Steensel, B.
Score: 25.7, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.552995
Genes are often regulated by multiple enhancers. It is poorly understood how the individual enhancer activities are combined to control promoter activity. Anecdotal evidence has shown that enhancers can combine sub-additively, additively, synergistically, or redundantly. However, it is not clear which of these modes are more frequent in mammalian genomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 variants Omicron BA.4/5 and XBB.1.5 significantly escape T cell recognition in solid organ transplant recipients vaccinated against the ancestral strain
Authors: Halvorson, T.; Ivison, S.; Huang, Q.; Ladua, G.; Yotis, D. M.; Mannar, D.; Subramaniam, S.; Ferreira, V. H.; Kumar, D.; Belga, S.; PREVenT Study Group, ; Levings, M.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.23293991
BackgroundImmune-suppressed solid organ transplant recipients (SOTRs) display impaired humoral responses to COVID-19 vaccination, but T cell responses are incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 10:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of human skin microbiome odorants that manipulate mosquito landing behavior
Authors: Coutinho-Abreu, I. V.; Jamshidi, O.; Raban, R.; Atabakhsh, K.; Merriman, J. A.; Fischbach, M. A.; Akbari, O. S.
Score: 44.9, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553996
The resident human skin microbiome is responsible for the production of most of the human scents that are attractive to mosquitoes. Hence, engineering the human skin microbiome to synthesize less of mosquito attractants or produce repellents could potentially reduce bites and prevent the transmission of deadly mosquito-borne pathogens.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
