<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>TLR8 escapes X chromosome inactivation in human monocytes and CD4&amp;#43; T cells
Authors: Youness, A.; Cenac, C.; Faz-Lopez, B.; Grunenwald, S.; Barrat, F.; Chaumeil, J.; Mejia, J. E.; Guery, J.-C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.23293823
Human endosomal Toll-like receptors TLR7 and TLR8 recognize self and non-self RNA ligands, and are important mediators of innate immunity and autoimmune pathogenesis. TLR7 and TLR8 are encoded by the adjacent X-linked genes, TLR7 and TLR8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>CD20 is a mammalian odorant receptor expressed in a subset of olfactory sensory neurons that mediates innate avoidance of predators
Authors: Jiang, H.-C.; Park, S. J.; Wang, I.-H.; Bear, D. M.; Nowlan, A.; Greer, P. L.
Score: 16.8, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552498
The mammalian olfactory system detects and discriminates between millions of odorants to elicit appropriate behavioral responses. While much has been learned about how olfactory sensory neurons detect odorants and signal their presence, how specific innate, unlearned behaviors are initiated in response to ethologically relevant odors remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>DNA end sensing and cleavage by the Shedu anti-phage defense system
Authors: Loeff, L.; Walter, A.; Rosalen, G. T.; Jinek, M.
Score: 39.2, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552762
The detection of molecular patterns associated with invading pathogens is a hallmark of innate immune systems. Prokaryotes deploy sophisticated host-defense mechanisms in innate anti-phage immunity. Shedu is a single-component defense system comprising a putative nuclease SduA. Here we report cryo-EM structures of apo- and dsDNA-bound tetrameric SduA assemblies, revealing that the N-terminal domains of SduA form a clamp that recognizes free DNA ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Transferrin Receptor Targeting Chimeras (TransTACs) for Membrane Protein Degradation
Authors: Zhang, D.; Duque-Jimenez, J.; Brixi, G.; Facchinetti, F.; Rhee, K.; Feng, W. W.; Jänne, P. A.; Zhou, X.
Score: 34.7, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552782
Cancer cells require high levels of iron for rapid proliferation, leading to a significant upregulation of the iron carrier protein Transferrin Receptor (TfR) on their cell surface. Leveraging this phenomenon and the exceptionally fast endocytosis rate of TfR, we introduce Transferrin Receptor TArgeting Chimeras (TransTAC), a novel molecular archetype for membrane protein degradation in cancers and other cell types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>NanoPyx: super-fast bioimage analysis powered by adaptive machine learning
Authors: Saraiva, B. M.; Cunha, I. M.; Brito, A. D.; Follain, G.; Portela, R.; Haase, R.; Pereira, P. M.; Jacquemet, G.; Henriques, R.
Score: 49.7, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553080
To overcome the challenges posed by large and complex microscopy datasets, we have developed NanoPyx, an adaptive bioimage analysis framework designed for high-speed processing. At the core of NanoPyx is the Liquid Engine, an agent-based machine-learning system that predicts acceleration strategies for image analysis tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Approximating conformational Boltzmann distributions with AlphaFold2 predictions
Authors: Brown, B. P.; Stein, R. A.; Meiler, J.; Mchaourab, H.
Score: 26.2, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.552168
Protein dynamics are intimately tied to biological function and can enable processes such as signal transduction, enzyme catalysis, and molecular recognition. The relative free energies of conformations that contribute to these functional equilibria are evolved for the physiology of the organism. Despite the importance of these equilibria for understanding biological function and developing treatments for disease, the computational and experimental methods capable of quantifying them are limited to systems of modest size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 648.7, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Humans with Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension display a global hypermethylation signature that worsens in patients who have a mutation in the gene encoding the methylation eraser, Tet Methylcytosine Dioxygenase 2 (TET2).
Authors: Hindmarch, C. C.; Potus, F.; Al-Qazazi, R.; Ring, B.; Nichols, W.; Rauh, M.; Archer, S. L.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293846
Epigenetic changes in gene expression due to DNA methylation are important physiologic and pathologic regulators of pulmonary vascular structure and function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Non-homologous end joining shapes the genomic rearrangement landscape of chromothripsis from mitotic errors
Authors: Hu, Q.; Espejo Valle-Inclan, J.; Dahiya, R.; Guyer, A.; Mazzagatti, A.; Maurais, E. G.; Engel, J. L.; Cortes-Ciriano, I.; Ly, P.
Score: 20.8, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552800
Errors in mitosis can generate micronuclei that entrap mis-segregated chromosomes, which are susceptible to catastrophic fragmentation through a process termed chromothripsis. The reassembly of fragmented chromosomes by error-prone DNA double-strand break (DSB) repair generates a spectrum of simple and complex genomic rearrangements that are associated with human cancers and disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reversal of Biological Age in Multiple Rat Organs by Young Porcine Plasma Fraction
Authors: Horvath, S.; Singh, K.; Raj, K.; Khairnar, S.; Sanghavi, A.; Shrivastava, A.; Zoller, J. A.; Li, C. Z.; Herenu, C. B.; Canatelli-Mallat, M.; Lehmann, M.; Habazin, S.; Vuckovic, F.; Solberg-Woods, L.; Garcia Martinez, A.; Wang, T.; Chiavellini, P.; Levine, A. J.; Chen, H.; Brooke, R. T.; Gordevicius, J.; Lauc, G.; Goya, R. G.; Katcher, H. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Island biogeography theory and the gut: why taller people tend to harbor more diverse gut microbiomes.
Authors: Ramos Sarmiento, K.; Carr, A.; Diener, C.; Locey, K. J.; Gibbons, S. M.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552554
Prior work has shown a positive scaling relationship between vertebrate body size and gut microbiome alpha-diversity. This observation mirrors commonly observed species area relationships (SAR) in many other ecosystems. Here, we show a similar scaling relationship between human height and gut microbiome alpha-diversity across two large, independent cohorts, controlling for a wide range of relevant covariates, such as body mass index, age, sex, and bowel movement frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 24.1, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Phenotype-based targeted treatment of SGLT2 inhibitors and GLP-1 receptor agonists in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Cardoso, P.; Young, K. G.; Nair, A. T. N.; Hopkins, R.; McGovern, A. P.; Haider, E.; Karunaratne, P.; Donnelly, L.; Mateen, B. A.; Sattar, N.; Holman, R. R.; Bowden, J.; Hattersley, A.; Pearson, E. R.; Jones, A. G.; Shields, B.; McKinley, T. J.; Dennis, J. M.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.23293636
A precision medicine approach in type 2 diabetes (T2D) could enhance targeting specific glucose-lowering therapies to individual patients most likely to benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected during a SARS-CoV-2 Omicron wave - Australia, 2022
Authors: Woldegiorgis, M.; Cadby, G.; Ngeh, S.; Korda, R.; Armstrong, P.; Maticevic, J.; Knight, P.; Jardine, A.; Bloomfield, L.; Effler, P.
Score: 1960.5, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293706
ObjectiveTo characterise Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected by Omicron. DesignFollow-up survey of persons testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 in Western Australia, 16 July-3 August 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>An evolutionary timescale for Bacteria calibrated using the Great Oxidation Event
Authors: Davin, A. A.; Woodcroft, B. J.; Soo, R. M.; Murali, R.; Schrempf, D.; Clark, J.; Boussau, B.; Moody, E. R. R.; Szantho, L. L.; Richy, E.; Pisani, D.; Hemp, J.; Fischer, W. W.; Donoghue, P.; Spang, A.; Hugenholtz, P.; Williams, T. A.; Szöllosi, G. J.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552427
Most of lifes diversity and history is microbial but it has left a meagre fossil record, greatly hindering understanding of evolution in deep time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genetic influences on circulating retinol and its relationship to human health
Authors: Reay, W. R.; Kiltschewskij, D. J.; Di Biase, M. A.; Gerring, Z. F.; Kundu, K.; Surendran, P.; Greco, L. A.; Clarke, E. D.; Collins, C. E.; Mondul, A. M.; Albanes, D.; Cairns, M. J.
Score: 20.6, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.23293796
Retinol is a fat-soluble vitamin that plays an essential role in many biological processes throughout the human lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging fine-scale population structure reveals conservation in genetic effect sizes between human populations across a range of human phenotypes
Authors: Hu, S.; Ferreira, L. A. F.; Shi, S.; Hellenthal, G.; Marchini, J.; Lawson, D. J.; Myers, S. R.
Score: 25.9, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552281
An understanding of genetic differences between populations is essential for avoiding confounding in genome-wide association studies (GWAS) and understanding the evolution of human traits. Polygenic risk scores constructed in one group perform poorly in highly genetically-differentiated populations, for reasons which remain controversial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Phage-plasmids promote genetic exchanges between phages and plasmids and create novel ones.
Authors: Pfeifer, E.; Rocha, E. P. C.
Score: 48.6, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552325
Phages and plasmids have key roles in bacterial evolution and are usually very different. Yet, they must recombine, since they sometimes carry nearly identical accessory genes. Phage-plasmids are both plasmids and phages and we found they connect them by being at their interface in the network of gene repertoire relatedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The effects of economic difficulties on social and health care costs of children: target trial emulation using complete birth cohort data in Finland
Authors: Hiilamo, A.; Keski-Santti, M.; Juutinen, A.; Makinen, L.; Ristikari, T.; Lallukka, T.
Score: 60.7, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23293974
It is unclear how much costs economic difficulties incur to the health and social care sector, which is a critical research gap to support the economic case for preventing child poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT, Enhanced with Clinical Practice Guidelines, is a Superior Decision Support Tool
Authors: Wang, Y.; Visweswaran, S.; Kappor, S.; Kooragayalu, S.; Wu, X.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293890
ChatGPT has gained remarkable traction since its inception in November 2022. However, it faces limitations in generating inaccurate responses, ignoring existing guidelines, and lacking reasoning when applied in clinical settings. This study introduces ChatGPT-CARE, a tool that integrates clinical practice guidelines with ChatGPT, focusing on COVID-19 outpatient treatment decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Measuring Mental Health in a Cost-of-Living Crisis: a rapid review
Authors: England, C.; Jarrom, D.; Washington, J.; Hasler, E.; Batten, L.; Lewis, R.; Edwards, R. T.; Davies, J.; Collins, B.; Cooper, A.; Edwards, A. G.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293078
Since 2021 the UK has experienced a sharp rise in inflation. For many, wages and welfare payments have not kept up with rising costs, leading to a cost of living crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Study Protocol for the Intraoperative Complications Assessment and Reporting with Universal Standards (ICARUS) Global Cross-Specialty Surveys Among Surgeons, Anesthesiologists, Nurses, Interventional Cardiologists, and Interventional Radiologists
Authors: Cacciamani, G. E.; Sholklapper, T.; Eppler, M. B.; Sayegh, A.; Storino Ramacciotti, L.; Abreu, A. L.; Sotelo, R.; Desai, M. M.; Gill, I. S.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.23293789
Every year, approximately 200 million surgeries are performed worldwide, and intraoperative adverse events (iAEs) have a significant impact on patients and surgeons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Megakaryocyte infection by SARS-CoV-2 drives the formation of pathogenic afucosylated IgG antibodies in mice
Authors: Mabrouk, M.; Jalali, F.; Zaid, N.; Naya, A.; Khyatti, M.; Khalki, L.; Guessous, F.; Zaid, Y.
Score: 697.0, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549113
More than 90% of total human plasma immunoglobulin G (IgG) is found in a fucosylated form, but specific IgGs with low core fucosylation (afucosylated IgGs) are found in response to infections with enveloped viruses and to alloantigens on blood cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Antiviral efficacy of the SARS-CoV-2 XBB breakthrough infection sera against Omicron subvariants including EG.5
Authors: Kaku, Y.; Kosugi, Y.; Uriu, K.; Ito, J.; Kuramochi, J.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Sato, K.
Score: 1010.3, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552415
As of July 2023, EG.5.1 (a.k.a. XBB.1.9.2.5.1), a XBB subvariant bearing the S:Q52H and S:F456L substitutions, alongside the S:F486P substitution (Figure S1A), has rapidly spread in some countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Eukaryotic RNA-guided endonucleases evolved from a unique clade of bacterial enzymes
Authors: Yoon, P. H.; Skopintsev, P.; Shi, H.; Chen, L.-X.; Adler, B. A.; Al-Shimary, M.; Craig, R. J.; Li, Z.; Amerasekera, J.; Trinidad, M.; Nisonoff, H.; Chen, K.; Lahiri, A.; Boger, R.; Jacobsen, S.; Banfield, J. F.; Doudna, J. A.
Score: 59.9, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.552727
RNA-guided endonucleases form the crux of diverse biological processes and technologies, including adaptive immunity, transposition, and genome editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Personalized chronic adaptive deep brain stimulation outperforms conventional stimulation in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Oehrn, C. R.; Cernera, S.; Hammer, L. H.; Shcherbakova, M.; Yao, J.; Hahn, A.; Wang, S.; Ostrem, J. L.; Little, S.; Starr, P. A.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293450
1.Deep brain stimulation is a widely used therapy for Parkinsons disease (PD) but currently lacks dynamic responsiveness to changing clinical and neural states. Feedback control has the potential to improve therapeutic effectiveness, but optimal control strategy and additional benefits of &amp;#34;adaptive&amp;#34; neurostimulation are unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neurons in the human entorhinal cortex map abstract emotion space
Authors: Qasim, S. E.; Reinacher, P. C.; Brandt, A.; Schulze-Bonhage, A.; Kunz, L.
Score: 65.0, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552884
When animals move through space, neurons in their entorhinal cortex activate periodically at multiple locations to form a map of the spatial environment. These grid cells may also map non-physical, conceptual spaces to support various other complex behaviors. Here, using intracranial recordings in neurosurgical patients performing an emotional memory task, we find that neurons in the human medial temporal lobe activate in a grid-like pattern across a two-dimensional feature space characterized by emotional valence and arousal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>High 3-hydroxybutyrate concentrations in the placenta-produced amniotic fluid in the human uterus
Authors: Satoh, T.; Shibata, T.; Takata, E.; Takakura, M.; Han, J.; Yamada, S.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293873
In this study, we report first high concentrations of a ketone body, 3-hydroxybutyrate (3HB) in the amniotic fluid in humans. Although 3HB concentrations in the maternal blood are approximately 0.1, those in the amniotic fluid are approximately 0.6 mM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Whole-genome mapping of APOBEC mutagenesis in metastatic urothelial carcinoma identifies driver hotspot mutations and a novel mutational signature
Authors: Nakauma-Gonzalez, J. A.; Rijnders, M.; Noordsij, M. T. W.; Martens, J. W. M.; van der Veldt, A.; Lolkema, M. P.; Boormans, J. L.; van de Werken, H. J. G.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293865
Background: In urothelial carcinoma (UC), apolipoprotein B mRNA-editing enzyme catalytic polypeptide-like (APOBEC) enzymes are major contributors to the mutational burden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Large language models approach expert-level clinical knowledge and reasoning in ophthalmology: A head-to-head cross-sectional study
Authors: Thirunavukarasu, A. J.; Mahmood, S.; Malem, A.; Foster, W. P.; Sanghera, R.; Hassan, R.; Zhou, S.; Wong, S. W.; Wong, Y. L.; Chong, Y. J.; Shakeel, A.; Chang, Y.-H.; Tan, B. K. J.; Jain, N.; Tan, T. F.; Rauz, S.; Ting, D. S. W.; Ting, D. S. J.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>An end-to-end workflow for non-destructive 3D pathology
Authors: Bishop, K. W.; Barner, L. A. E.; Han, Q.; Baraznenok, E.; Lan, L.; Poudel, C.; Gao, G.; Serafin, R. B.; Chow, S. S. L.; Glaser, A. K.; Janowczyk, A.; Brenes, D.; Huang, H.; Miyasato, D.; True, L. D.; Kang, S.; Vaughan, J. C.; Liu, J. T. C.
Score: 127.5, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551845
Recent advances in 3D pathology offer the ability to image orders-of-magnitude more tissue than conventional pathology while providing a volumetric context that is lacking with 2D tissue sections, all without requiring destructive tissue sectioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Vitamin D deficiency induces erectile dysfunction: role of superoxide
Authors: Olivencia, M. A.; Climent, B.; Barreira, B.; Morales-Cano, D.; Sanchez, A.; Fernandez, A.; Garcia-Gomez, B.; Romero-Otero, J.; Rodriguez, C.; Moreno, L.; Prieto, D.; Larriba, M. J.; Cogolludo, A.; Angulo, J.; Perez-Vizcaino, F.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.552595
Epidemiological studies suggest a relationship between vitamin D deficiency and erectile dysfunction (ED) but its causal relationship and the mechanism involved are unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Pantothenate Kinase 4 controls efficient skeletal muscle energy substrate metabolism via acetyl-CoA
Authors: Miranda-Cervantes, A.; Fritzen, A. M.; Raun, S. H.; Hodek, O.; Moller, L. L. V.; Johann, K.; Deisen, L.; Gregorevic, P.; Gudiksen, A.; Artati, A.; Adamski, J.; Andersen, N. R.; Schjerling, P.; Cebrian-Serrano, A.; Jaehnert, M.; Gottmann, P.; Burtscher, I.; Lickert, H.; Pilegaard, H.; Schuermann, A.; Tschoep, M. H.; Moritz, T.; Mueller, T. D.; Sylow, L.; Kiens, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Synergistic control of chloroplast biogenesis by MYB-related and Golden2-like transcription factors
Authors: Frangedakis, E.; Yelina, N.; Billakurthi, K.; Schreier, T. B.; Dickinson, P. J.; Tomaselli, M.; Haseloff, J.; Hibberd, J. M.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.552970
Chloroplast biogenesis is dependent on master regulators from the Golden2-like (GLK) family of transcription factors, but higher order glk mutants contain residual chlorophyll and therefore other proteins must also be involved. Here we identify MYB-related transcription factors as regulators of chloroplast biogenesis in the liverwort Marchantia polymorpha and angiosperm Arabidopsis thaliana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Examining Differences in the Genetic and Functional Architecture of ADHD Diagnosed in Childhood and Adulthood
Authors: Breunig, S.; Lawrence, J. M.; Foote, I. F.; Gebhardt, H. J.; Willcutt, E. G.; Grotzinger, A. D.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.23293439
BackgroundAttention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) is a neurodevelopmental disorder that is diagnosed when symptoms onset in childhood. Here we investigate whether individuals who are diagnosed as children differ from those who are diagnosed in adulthood with respect to shared and unique architecture at the genome-wide, functional, and gene expression level of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 892.7, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>The predictive role of pain catastrophising following genicular arterial embolisation for the treatment of mild and moderate knee osteoarthritis
Authors: Harrison, R.; Salomons, T.; MacGill, S.; Little, M.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23290995
Knee osteoarthritis (OA) is the most common form of OA and is not currently considered to be a curable disease. Specifically, mild-to-moderate knee OA that is resistant to conservative treatment, but does not warrant joint replacement, poses a significant clinical problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Randomized attention-placebo controlled trial of a digital self-management platform for adult asthma
Authors: Kandola, A.; Edwards, K.; Straatman, J.; Duehrkoop, B.; Hein, B.; Hayes, J. F.
Score: 53.3, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292865
BackgroundAsthma is one of the most common chronic conditions worldwide, with a substantial individual, societal and healthcare burden. Digital apps hold promise as a highly accessible, low-cost method of enhancing self-management in asthma, which is critical to effective asthma control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Somatic TET2 Mutations are Associated with Giant Cell Arteritis
Authors: Robinette, M. L.; Weeks, L. D.; Kramer, R. J.; Agrawal, M.; Gibson, C. J.; Yu, Z.; Sekar, A.; Mehta, A.; Niroula, A.; Brown, J. T.; McDermott, G. C.; Reshef, E. R.; Lu, J. E.; Liou, V. D.; Chiou, C. A.; Natarajan, P.; Freitag, S. K.; Rao, D. A.; Ebert, B. A.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23292945
ObjectiveGiant cell arteritis (GCA) is an age-related vasculitis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Analytical code sharing practices in biomedical research
Authors: Sharma, N. K.; Ayyala, R.; Deshpande, D.; Patel, Y. M.; Munteanu, V.; Ciorba, D.; Fiscutean, A.; Vahed, M.; Sarkar, A.; Guo, R.; Moore, A.; Darci-Maher, N.; Nogoy, N. A.; Abedalthagafi, M. S.; Mangul, S.
Score: 2.9, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.551384
Data-driven computational analysis is becoming increasingly important in biomedical research, as the amount of data being generated continues to grow. However, the lack of practices of sharing research outputs, such as data, source code and methods, affects transparency and reproducibility of studies, which are critical to the advancement of science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Machine-guided design of synthetic cell type-specific cis-regulatory elements
Authors: Gosai, S. J.; Castro, R. I.; Fuentes, N.; Butts, J. C.; Kales, S.; Noche, R. R.; Mouri, K.; Sabeti, P. C.; Reilly, S. K.; Tewhey, R.
Score: 57.7, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552077
Cis-regulatory elements (CREs) control gene expression, orchestrating tissue identity, developmental timing, and stimulus responses, which collectively define the thousands of unique cell types in the body. While there is great potential for strategically incorporating CREs in therapeutic or biotechnology applications that require tissue specificity, there is no guarantee that an optimal CRE for an intended purpose has arisen naturally through evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic discovery of protein interaction interfaces using AlphaFold and experimental validation
Authors: Lee, C. Y.; Hubrich, D.; Varga, J. K.; Schäfer, C.; Welzel, M.; Schumbera, E.; Đokic, M.; Strom, J. M.; Schönfeld, J.; Geist, J. L.; Polat, F.; Gibson, T. J.; Keller Valsecchi, C. I.; Kumar, M.; Schueler-Furman, O.; Luck, K.
Score: 46.1, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552219
Structural resolution of protein interactions enables mechanistic and functional studies as well as interpretation of disease variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms in a prospective cohort of COVID-19 survivors
Authors: Gomes, C. M.; Hisano, M.; Souza, J. D.; Henriques, J. V. T.; De Bessa, J.; Moromizato, J.; Bosi, T.; Mazoni, R.; Gismondi, J.; Camargo, B.; Sammour, Z. M.; Bruschini, H.; Battistella, L. R.; Nahas, W. C.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293500
PurposeTo analyze the prevalence of lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in patients who survived moderate and severe forms of COVID-19 and the risk factors for LUTS six months after hospital discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Worms on the Cape: an integrative survey of polydorid infestation in wild and cultivated oysters (Crassostrea virginica) from Massachusetts, USA
Authors: Davinack, A. A.; Strong, M.; Brennessel, B.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.12.553105
Polydorid infestations pose a significant challenge to shellfish aquaculture by impacting marketability and profitability of farms. In this study, we investigated the prevalence, intensity, identity and biogeography of shell-boring worms infecting both farmed and wild oysters (Crassostrea virginica) from three sites in Wellfleet Harbor, Massachusetts: an economically important shellfishing region in the northeastern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
