<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Prebiotic Supplements Correct Oral Probiotic Deficiency for Lasting Allergy Relief
Authors: Han, C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23291433
Allergic rhinitis has increased in the last fifty years from affecting less than a percent to more than twenty-six percent of the population[1]. Today, more than one hundred million people in the US suffer from these seasonal or yearlong allergies[2]. The hygiene hypothesis was proposed 30 years ago as a potential explanation for this phenomenon[3], and we built on that with the specific oral hygiene hypothesis[4].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous helping in pigs is mediated by helper&amp;#39;s social attention and distress signals of individuals in need
Authors: Moscovice, L. R.; Eggert, A.; Manteuffel, C.; Rault, J.-L.
Score: 117.2, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.17.533160
Helping behaviour is of special interest for prosociality because it appears to be motivated by the needs of others. We developed a novel paradigm to investigate helping in pigs (Sus scrofa domesticus) and tested 75 individuals in eight groups in their home pens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>A systems-scale, integrated view of the ubiquitylation site occupancy and dynamics
Authors: Prus, G.; Satpathy, S.; Weinert, B.; Narita, T.; Choudhary, C.
Score: 33.2, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549470
Ubiquitylation regulates virtually all proteins and biological processes in a cell. However, the global site-specific occupancy (stoichiometry) and turnover rate of ubiquitylation have never been quantified. Here, we present the first integrated picture of ubiquitylation site occupancy and half-life. Ubiquitylation occupancy spans four orders of magnitude, but the median ubiquitylation site occupancy is three orders of magnitude lower than that of phosphorylation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous multi-site editing of individual genomes using retron arrays
Authors: Gonzalez-Delgado, A.; Lopez, S. C.; Rojas-Montero, M.; Fishman, C. B.; Shipman, S. L.
Score: 29.4, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549397
Our understanding of genomics is limited by the scale of our genomic technologies. While libraries of genomic manipulations scaffolded on CRISPR gRNAs have been transformative, these existing approaches are typically multiplexed across genomes. Yet much of the complexity of real genomes is encoded within a genome across sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Scalable querying of human cell atlases via a foundational model reveals commonalities across fibrosis-associated macrophages
Authors: Heimberg, G.; Kuo, T. C.; DePianto, D.; Heigl, T.; Diamant, N.; Salem, O.; Scalia, G.; Biancalani, T.; Rock, J.; Turley, S.; Bravo, H. C.; Kaminker, J.; Vander Heiden, J. A.; Regev, A.
Score: 150.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549537
Single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) studies have profiled over 100 million human cells across diseases, developmental stages, and perturbations to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Coevolution-driven method for efficiently simulating conformational changes in proteins reveals molecular details of ligand effects in the beta2AR receptor
Authors: Mitrovic, D.; Chen, Y.; Marciniak, A.; Delemotte, L.
Score: 33.8, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549854
With the advent of AI-powered structure prediction, the scientific community is inching ever closer to solving protein folding. An unresolved enigma, however, is to accurately, reliably and deterministically predict alternative conformational states that are crucial for the function of e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Coordinated inheritance of extrachromosomal DNA species in human cancer cells
Authors: Hung, K. L.; Jones, M. G.; Wong, I. T.-L.; Lange, J. T.; Luebeck, J.; Scanu, E.; He, B. J.; Brückner, L.; Li, R.; Gonzalez, R. C.; Schmargon, R.; Dörr, J. R.; Belk, J. A.; Bafna, V.; Werner, B.; Huang, W.; Henssen, A. G.; Mischel, P. S.; Chang, H. Y.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549597
The chromosomal theory of inheritance has dominated human genetics, including cancer genetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiovascular Impact and Genetics of Pericardial Adiposity
Authors: Ramo, J. T.; Kany, S.; Hou, C. R.; Friedman, S. F.; Roselli, C.; Nauffal, V.; Koyama, S.; Karjalainen, J.; FinnGen, ; Maddah, M.; Palotie, A.; Ellinor, P. T.; Pirruccello, J. P.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.16.23292729
BackgroundWhile previous studies have reported associations of pericardial adipose tissue (PAT) with cardiovascular diseases such as atrial fibrillation and coronary artery disease, they have been limited in sample size or drawn from selected populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>An mTOR/RNA pol I axis shapes chromatin architecture in response to fasting
Authors: Al-Refaie, N.; Padovani, F.; Binando, F.; Hornung, J.; Zhao, Q.; Towbin, B. D.; Sarinay Cenik, E.; Stroustrup, N.; Schmoller, K. M.; Cabianca, D. S.
Score: 31.5, Published: 2023-07-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.22.550032
Chromatin architecture is a fundamental mediator of genome function. Fasting is a major environmental cue across the animal kingdom. Yet, how it impacts on 3D genome organization is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>BMP-dependent patterning of ectoderm tissue material properties modulates lateral mesendoderm cell migration during early zebrafish gastrulation
Authors: Tavano, S.; Brueckner, D. B.; Tasciyan, S.; Tong, X.; Kardos, R.; Schauer, A.; Hauschild, R.; Heisenberg, C.-P.
Score: 26.5, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.550024
Cell migration is a fundamental process during embryonic development. Most studies on cell migration in vivo have focussed on the migration of cells using the extracellular matrix (ECM) as their substrate for migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Biogeographic context mediates multifaceted diversity-productivity relationships in island and mainland forests
Authors: Tolmos, M. L.; Guerrero-Ramirez, N. R.; Ameztegui, A.; Barajas Barbosa, M. P.; Craven, D.; Kreft, H.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549319
AimGrowing evidence suggests that impacts of biodiversity loss on ecosystem functioning and natures contributions to people are usually negative, yet the magnitude and direction of these impacts can be variable across naturally-assembled ecosystems. A potential driver of variation in diversity-productivity relationships is the biogeographical context, which may alter these relationships via processes acting on the size and composition of the species pool like dispersal limitation, environmental filtering, speciation, and invasibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Decrease in multiple complement protein levels is associated with the development of islet autoimmunity and type 1 diabetes
Authors: Webb-Robertson, B.-J. M.; Nakayasu, E. S.; Dong, F.; Waugh, K.; Flores, J.; Bramer, L.; Schepmoes, A.; Gao, Y.; Fillmore, T.; Onengut-Gumuscu, S.; Frazer-Abel, A.; Rich, S.; Holers, M.; Metz, T.; Rewers, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292628
Type 1 diabetes (T1D) is a chronic condition caused by autoimmune destruction of the insulin-producing pancreatic {beta}-cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Risk of severe outcomes among Omicron sub-lineages BA.4.6, BA.2.75 and BQ.1 compared to BA.5 in England
Authors: Seghezzo, G.; Nash, S. G.; Abdul Aziz, N.; Hope, R.; Lopez Bernal, J.; Gallagher, E.; Dabrera, G.; Thelwall, S.
Score: 151.1, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292656
Since the emergence of Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2 in late 2021, a number of sub-lineages have arisen and circulated internationally. Little is known about the relative severity of Omicron sub-lineages BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Enamel proteins reveal biological sex and genetic variability within southern African Paranthropus
Authors: Madupe, P. P.; Koenig, C.; Patramanis, I.; Rüther, P. L.; Hlazo, N.; Mackie, M.; Tawane, M.; Krueger, J.; Taurozzi, A. J.; Troche, G. B.; Kibii, J.; Pickering, R.; Dickinson, M. R.; Sahle, Y.; Kgotleng, D.; Musiba, C.; Manthi, F.; Bell, L.; du Plessis, M.; Gilbert, C.; Zipfel, B.; Kuderna, L.; Lizano, E.; Welker, F.; Kyriakidou, P.; Cox, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic Age Acceleration in Surviving versus Deceased COVID-19 Patients with Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome following Hospitalization
Authors: Bejaoui, Y.; Humaira Amanullah, F.; Saad, M.; Taleb, S.; Bradic, M.; Megarbane, A.; Ait Hssain, A.; Abi Khalil, C.; El Hajj, N.
Score: 397.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549478
Aging has been reported as a major risk factor for severe symptoms and higher mortality rates in COVID-19 patients. Molecular hallmarks such as epigenetic alterations and telomere attenuation reflect the biological process of aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent profiling of multiscale 3D genome organization and gene expression in single mammalian cells
Authors: Zhou, T.; Zhang, R.; Jia, D.; Doty, R. T.; Munday, A. D.; Gao, D.; Xin, L.; Abkowitz, J. L.; Duan, Z.; Ma, J.
Score: 24.6, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549578
The organization of mammalian genomes within the nucleus features a complex, multiscale three-dimensional (3D) architecture. The functional significance of these 3D genome features, however, remains largely elusive due to limited single-cell technologies that can concurrently profile genome organization and transcriptional activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Uncertainty in serious illness: A national interdisciplinary consensus exercise to identify clinical research priorities
Authors: Etkind, S. N.; Barclay, S.; Spathis, A.; Hopkins, S.; Bowers, B.; Koffman, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.23293007
Background: Serious illness is characterised by uncertainty, particularly in older age groups. Uncertainty may be experienced by patients, family carers, and health professionals about a broad variety of issues. There are many evidence gaps regarding the experience and management of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of digital health insurance for low-income women in Kenya
Authors: de Groot, R.; Abajobir, A.; Wainaina, C.; Sidze, E. M.; Pradhan, M.; Janssens, W.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292292
ObjectiveThis study evaluates how a subsidized, mobile phone-based health insurance program affected insurance uptake, healthcare utilization and health expenditures for low-income women and their family members in Western Kenya. The program, targeting pregnant women and mothers of children below age four, addressed both demand- and supply-side constraints, providing subsidies through mobile money and support in digital registration while upgrading selected facilities and digitally training community health workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Coding Inequity: Assessing GPT-4&amp;#39;s Potential for Perpetuating Racial and Gender Biases in Healthcare
Authors: Zack, T.; Lehman, E.; Suzgun, M.; Rodriguez, J. A.; Celi, L. A.; Gichoya, J.; Jurafsky, D.; Szolovits, P.; Bates, D. W.; Abdulnour, R.-E. E.; Butte, A. J.; Alsentzer, E.
Score: 10.8, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292577
BackgroundLarge language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 hold great promise as transformative tools in healthcare, ranging from automating administrative tasks to augmenting clinical decision- making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics and quality of studies pertaining to masks published in the Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report
Authors: Hoeg, T. B.; Haslam, A.; Prasad, V.
Score: 625.4, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292338
ImportanceBecause the MMWR has substantial influence on United States public health policy and is not externally peer-reviewed, it is critical to understand the scientific process within the journal. Mask policies during COVID is one topic that has been highly influenced by data published in the MMWR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence in Biomedicine: Systematic Review
Authors: Gabashvili, I. S.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292672
Abstract Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a rapidly progressing technology with its applications expanding exponentially over the past decade. While initial breakthroughs predominantly focused on deep learning and computer vision, recent advancements have facilitated a shift towards natural language processing and beyond. This includes generative models, like ChatGPT, capable of understanding the &amp;#39;grammar&amp;#39; of software code, analog signals, and molecular structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Do people with disabilities have the same level of HIV knowledge and access to testing? Evidence from 513,252 people across 37 Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys
Authors: Rotenberg, S.; Chen, S.; Hanass-Hancock, J.; Davey, C.; Banks, L. M.; Kuper, H.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292845
BackgroundDisability and HIV are intricately linked, as people with disabilities are at higher risk of contracting HIV and HIV can lead to impairments and disability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Megakaryocyte infection by SARS-CoV-2 drives the formation of pathogenic afucosylated IgG antibodies in mice
Authors: Mabrouk, M.; Jalali, F.; Zaid, N.; Naya, A.; Khyatti, M.; Khalki, L.; Guessous, F.; Zaid, Y.
Score: 563.9, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549113
More than 90% of total human plasma immunoglobulin G (IgG) is found in a fucosylated form, but specific IgGs with low core fucosylation (afucosylated IgGs) are found in response to infections with enveloped viruses and to alloantigens on blood cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Early Biological Markers of Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection
Authors: Lu, S.; Peluso, M. J.; Glidden, D. V.; Davidson, M.; Lugtu, K.; Pineda-Ramirez, J.; Tassetto, M.; Garcia-Knight, M.; Zhang, A.; Goldberg, S. A.; Chen, J.; Forbes, M.; Park, S.; Martinez, A.; So, M.; Donovan, A.; Viswanathan, B.; Hoh, R.; Donohue, K.; McIlwain, D.; Gaudilliere, B.; Anglin, K.; Yee, B.; Chenna, A. A.; Winslow, J.; Petropoulos, C.; Briggs-Hagen, M.; Andino, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>A Taxonomically-informed Mass Spectrometry Search Tool for Microbial Metabolomics Data
Authors: Zuffa, S.; Schmid, R.; Bauermeister, A.; P. Gomes, P. W.; Caraballo-Rodriguez, A. M.; El Abiead, Y.; Aron, A. T.; Gentry, E. C.; Zemlin, J.; Meehan, M. J.; Avalon, N. E.; Cichewicz, R. H.; Buzun, E.; Carrillo Terrazas, M.; Hsu, C.-Y.; Oles, R.; Vasquez Ayala, A.; Zhao, J.; Chu, H.; Kuijpers, M. C. M.; Jackrel, S. L.; Tugizimana, F.; Nephali, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mechanism of outer kinetochore assembly on microtubules and its regulation by mitotic error correction
Authors: Muir, K. W.; Batters, C.; Dendooven, T.; Yang, J.; Zhang, Z.; Burt, A.; Barford, D.
Score: 50.2, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549907
Kinetochores couple chromosomes to the mitotic spindle and transduce the energy of microtubule depolymerization to segregate the genome during cell division. Kinetochore - microtubule attachments are often initially erroneous and subject to a mitotic error correction (EC) mechanism that drives their turnover until biorientation is achieved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>APOE loss-of-function variants: Compatible with longevity and associated with resistance to Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease pathology
Authors: Chemparathy, A.; Le Guen, Y.; Chen, S.; Lee, E.-G.; Leong, L.; Gorzynski, J.; Xu, G.; Belloy, M.; Kasireddy, N.; Pena-Tauber, A.; Williams, K.; Stewart, I.; Wingo, T.; Lah, J.; Jayadev, S.; Hales, C.; Peskind, E.; Child, D. D.; Keene, C. D.; Cong, L.; Ashley, E.; Yu, C.-E.; Greicus, M.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Sustaining wakefulness: Brainstem connectivity in human consciousness
Authors: Edlow, B. L.; Olchanyi, M.; Freeman, H. J.; Li, J.; Maffei, C.; Snider, S. B.; Zollei, L.; Iglesias, J. E.; Augustinack, J.; Bodien, Y. G.; Haynes, R. L.; Greve, D. N.; Diamond, B. R.; Stevens, A.; Giacino, J. T.; Destrieux, C.; van der Kouwe, A.; Brown, E. N.; Folkerth, R. D.; Fischl, B.; Kinney, H. C.
Score: 96.0, Published: 2023-07-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>An updated PREDICT breast cancer prognostic model including the benefits and harms of radiotherapy
Authors: Grootes, I.; Wishart, G. C.; Pharoah, P. D. P.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292777
BackgroundPredict Breast (www.breast.predict.nhs.uk) is an online prognostication and treatment benefit tool for early invasive breast cancer. However, the most recent version of PREDICT Breast (v2.2) was based on data for breast cancer cases diagnosed from 1999 to 2003 and did not incorporate the benefits of radiotherapy or the harms associated with theray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Oxygen isotopes in orangutan teeth reveal recent and ancient climate variation
Authors: Smith, T. M.; Arora, M.; Austin, C.; Avila, J. N.; Duval, M.; Lim, T. T.; Piper, P.; Vaiglova, P.; Vos, J. d.; Williams, I. S.; Zhao, J.-x.; Green, D. R.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549587
Studies of climate variation commonly rely on chemical and isotopic changes recorded in sequentially-produced growth layers, such as in corals, shells and tree rings, as well as in accretionary deposits--ice and sediment cores, and speleothems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>In situ cryo-electron tomography of beta-amyloid and tau in post-mortem Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease brain
Authors: Gilbert, M. A. G.; Fatima, N.; Jenkins, J.; O&amp;#39;Sullivan, T. J.; Schertel, A.; Halfon, Y.; Morrema, T. H. J.; Geibel, M.; Radford, S. E.; Hoozemans, J. J. M.; Frank, R. A. W.
Score: 59.9, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549278
A defining pathological feature of most neurodegenerative diseases is the assembly of proteins into amyloid that form disease-specific structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Multivariate patterns between brain network properties, polygenic scores, phenotypes, and environment in preadolescents
Authors: Seo, J.; Lee, E.; Kim, B.-G.; Kim, G.; Joo, Y. Y.; Cha, J.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293075
The brain network is an infrastructure for cognitive and behavioral processes. Genetic and environmental factors influence the development of the brain network. However, little is known about how specific genetic traits and children&amp;#39;s brain network properties are related.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Optical Control of G-Actin with a Photoswitchable Latrunculin
Authors: Veprek, N. A.; Cooper, M. H.; Laprell, L.; Yang, E. J.-N.; Folkerts, S.; Bao, R.; Oertner, T. G.; Pon, L. A.; Zuchero, J. B.; Trauner, D. H.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549222
Actin is one of the most abundant proteins in eukaryotic cells and a key component of the cytoskeleton. A range of small molecules have emerged that interfere with actin dynamics by either binding to polymeric F-actin or monomeric G-actin to stabilize or destabilize filaments or prevent their formation and growth, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of cambium stem cell factors and their positioning mechanism
Authors: Eswaran, G.; Rutten, J. P.; Han, J.; Iida, H.; Lopez Ortiz, J.; Makila, R.; Wybouw, B.; Vainio, L.; Porcher, A.; Leal Gavarron, M.; Zhang, J.; Blomster, T.; Wang, X.; Dolan, D. W. P.; Smetana, O.; Brady, S.; Kucukoglu Topcu, M.; ten Tusscher, K. H.; Etchells, P.; Mahonen, A. P.
Score: 28.8, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549889
Wood constitutes the majority of terrestrial biomass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Reactivation of herpesvirus type-6 and IgA/IgM-mediated responses to activin-A underpin Long COVID, including affective symptoms and chronic fatigue syndrome.
Authors: Vojdani, A.; Almulla, A. F.; Zhou, B.; Al-Hakeim, H. F.; Maes, M.
Score: 55.5, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23293046
Background: Persistent infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), reactivation of dormant viruses, and immune-oxidative responses are involved in Long COVID. Objectives: To investigate whether Long COVID and depressive, anxiety and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) symptoms, are associated with IgA/IgM/IgG to SARS-CoV-2, human Herpesvirus type 6 (HHV-6), Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV), and immune-oxidative biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Clinical manifestations and mortality among hospitalized COVID-19 patients in Tanzania, 2021-2022.
Authors: Osati, E. O.; Shayo, G. A.; Nagu, T.; Sangeda, R. Z.; Moshiro, C.; Vumilia, L.; Samwel, L.; Mhame, P.; Nkya, M. E.; Rainer, D.; John, M.; Mbije, C.; Nyaisonga, G.; Kilonzo, K. G.; Nicholaus, M. A.; Seni, J.; Muniko, A.; Wajanga, B.; Ramadhani, A.; Adams, N.; Shekalaghe, S.; Makubi, A.
Score: 86.8, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292643
BackgroundThere have been differential mortality rates from Corona Virus Disease of 2019 (COVID-19) in different parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Fronto-parietal network dynamics to understand deficits in attention performance in multiple sclerosis
Authors: Welton, T.; Meng, D.; das Nair, R.; Constantinescu, C. S.; Auer, D. P.; Dineen, R. A.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-07-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.08.23292404
IntroductionImpaired attention performance is a significant burden to people with multiple sclerosis (MS). Brain connectivity fluctuates with transitions between cognitive states, so measurement of network dynamics during these conditions may help to understand MS-related attention impairment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 12.4, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omics analysis in primary T cells elucidates mechanisms behind disease associated genetic loci
Authors: Shi, C.; Zhao, D.; Rossi, S.; Frantzeskos, A.; Ding, J.; Ferrazzano, C.; Wynn, C.; Hum, R.; Richards, E.; Gupta, M.; Yap, C. F.; Plant, D.; Grencis, R.; Martin, P.; Adamson, A.; Eyre, S.; Bowes, J.; Barton, A.; Ho, P.; Rattray, M.; Orozco, G.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292550
In this study, we present the most extensive dataset of chromatin conformation data with matching gene expression and chromatin accessibility from primary T cells to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Origami-based growing tube model for reproducing shell shapes
Authors: Ueda, M.; Fukunaga, N.; Yamashita, N.; Yokoyama, Y.; Kida, H.; Matsuda, K.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549674
Mathematical models for shell morphology have been well-studied in theoretical morphology. The growing tube model proposed by Takashi Okamoto was developed to reproduce heteromorph ammonoids and can generate various shells by changing three parameters: curvature, torsion, and enlarging ratio. Previous studies in theoretical morphology have employed computers to visualize mathematical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Accumulating Sedentary Time and Physical Activity from Childhood to Adolescence and Cardiac Function in Adolescence
Authors: Haapala, E.; Leppänen, M. H.; Lee, E. M.; Savonen, K. P.; Laukkanen, J. A.; Kähönen, M.; Brage, S.; Lakka, T. A.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292912
BackgroundLittle is known about the associations of a sedentary lifestyle from childhood with cardiac work and function during adolescence. We studied if cumulative sedentary time and physical activity from childhood to adolescence are associated with cardiac work and function in adolescence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>xTrimoPGLM: Unified 100B-Scale Pre-trained Transformer for Deciphering the Language of Protein
Authors: Chen, B.; Cheng, X.; Gengyang, L.-a.; Li, S.; Zeng, X.; Wang, B.; Gong, J.; Liu, C.; Zeng, A.; Dong, Y.; Tang, J.; Song, L.
Score: 98.1, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.547496
Protein language models have shown remarkable success in learning biological information from protein sequences. However, most existing models are limited by either autoencoding or autoregressive pre-training objectives, which makes them struggle to handle protein understanding and generation tasks concurrently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive atlas of the aging vertebrate brain reveals signatures of progressive proteostasis dysfunction
Authors: Di Fraia, D.; Marino, A.; Lee, J. H.; Kelmer Sacramento, E.; Baumgart, M.; Bagnoli, S.; Tomaz da Silva, P.; Kumar Sahu, A.; Siano, G.; Tiessen, M.; Gagneur, J.; Frydman, J.; Cellerino, A.; Ori, A.
Score: 25.5, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549210
Protein homeostasis is disrupted in aging and neurodegenerative diseases, yet, the specific impact of aging on brain proteostasis remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Shedding light on the Ophel biome: The Trans-Tethyan phylogeography of the sulfide shrimp Tethysbaena (Peracarida: Thermosbaenacea) in the Levant
Authors: Guy-Haim, T.; Kolodny, O.; Frumkin, A.; Achituv, Y.; Velasquez, X.; Morov, A. R.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549641
Tethysbaena are small peracarid crustaceans found in extreme environments such as subterranean lakes and thermal springs, represented by endemic species found around the ancient Tethys, including the Mediterranean, Arabian Sea, Mid-East Atlantic, and the Caribbean Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
