<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Buprenorphine, Methadone and Substance-Use on COVID-19 Morbidity and Mortality
Authors: CHRISTIAN, N.; ZHOU, X.; RADHAKRISHNAN, R.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.24.23298995
Objectives: Substance use disorder has been associated with increased morbidity in COVID-19 infection. However, less is known about the impact of active substance use and medications for opioid use disorder (MOUD) on COVID-19 outcomes. We conducted a retrospective cohort study to evaluate the impact of substance use, namely cannabis, cocaine, alcohol, sedative and opioid use as well as buprenorphine or methadone = on COVID-19 morbidity and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Correlation between COVID-19 vaccination and inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders
Authors: Park, Y. H.; Kim, M. H.; Choi, M. G.; Chun, E. M.
Score: 229.3, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298544
ImportanceEarlier research on COVID-19 vaccines identified a range of adverse reactions related to proinflammatory actions that can lead to an excessive immune response and sustained inflammation. However, no study has been conducted on the association between inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders and COVID-19 vaccines. ObjectiveTo investigate the incidence rates of inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders following COVID-19 vaccination and to compare them with those of unvaccinated individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Plant-like heliotropism in a photosymbiotic animal
Authors: Lintnerova, E.; Shaw, C.; Keys, M.; Brownlee, C.; Modepalli, V.
Score: 67.9, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565328
Being photosynthetic sessile organisms, plants established heliotropism to track the suns position across the sky and allow their vegetative parts to orient accordingly. Here, we report plant-like heliotropic movement in a photosymbiotic sea anemone Anemonia viridis. Like plants, photosynthesis represents a key energy source in endosymbiotic cnidarians bearing microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>CK-666 and CK-869 differentially inhibit Arp2/3 iso-complexes
Authors: Cao, L.; Huang, S.; Basant, A.; Mladenov, M.; Way, M.
Score: 23.5, Published: 2023-11-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568719
The inhibitors, CK-666 and CK-869, are widely used to probe the function of actin nucleation by the Arp2/3 complex in vitro and in cells. However, in mammals, the Arp2/3 complex consists of 8 iso-complexes, as three of its subunits (Arp3, ArpC1, ArpC5) are encoded by two different genes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Engineering mice for female-biased progeny without impacting genetic integrity and litter size
Authors: Yosef, I.; Mahata, T.; Chen, Y.; Bar-Joseph, H.; Shalgi, R.; Munitz, A.; Gerlic, M.; Qimron, U.
Score: 39.8, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568055
Generating mammalian gametes with a skewed sex ratio has thus far eluded empirical confirmation. The utilization of such genetically engineered organisms would offer the potential to curtail the necessity for culling animals of undesirable sex, mitigate resource wastage, and alleviate superfluous labor burdens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Colabfold predicts alternative protein structures from single sequences, coevolution unnecessary for AF-cluster
Authors: Porter, L. L.; Chakravarty, D.; Schafer, J. W.; Chen, E. A.
Score: 31.2, Published: 2023-11-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.567977
Though typically associated with a single folded state, globular proteins are dynamic and often assume alternative or transient structures important for their functions1,2. Wayment-Steele, et al. steered ColabFold3 to predict alternative structures of several proteins using a method they call AF-cluster4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Real-Time Structural Biology of DNA and DNA-Protein Complexes on an Optical Microscope
Authors: Szalai, A. M.; Ferrari, G.; Richter, L.; Hartmann, J.; Kesici, M.-Z.; Ji, B.; Koshic, K.; Jaeger, A.; Aksimentiev, A.; Tessmer, I.; Kaminska, I.; Vera, A. M.; Tinnefeld, P.
Score: 41.5, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.567962
The intricate interplay between DNA and proteins is key for biological functions such as DNA replication, transcription, and repair. To better understand these interactions, it is crucial to develop tools to study DNA-protein complexes with high spatial and temporal resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cancer-associated fibroblasts serve as decoys to suppress NK cell anti-cancer cytotoxicity
Authors: Ben-Shmuel, A.; Gruper, Y.; Levi-Galibov, O.; Rosenberg-Fogler, H.; Carradori, G.; Stein, Y.; Dadiani, M.; Naumova, M.; Nevo, R.; Morzaev-Sulzbach, D.; Yagel, G.; Mayer, S.; Gal-Yam, E.; Scherz-Shouval, R.
Score: 20.7, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568355
Cancer associated fibroblasts (CAFs) are among the most abundant components of the breast tumor microenvironment (TME) and major contributors to immune modulation. CAFs are well-known to regulate the activity of diverse types of immune cells including T cells, macrophages and dendritic cells, however little is known about their interaction with Natural killer (NK) cells, which constitute an important arm of anti-tumor immunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>ERBB2 R599C variant is associated with left ventricular outflow tract obstruction defects in human
Authors: Ampuja, M.; Selenius, S.; Paatero, I.; Chowdhury, I.; Villman, J.; Broberg, M.; Ranta, A.; Ojala, T.; Chong, J. X.; Bamshad, M.; Priest, J. R.; Varjosalo, M.; Kivela, R.; Helle, E.
Score: 2.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23297969
Background and aimsNon-syndromic congenital heart defects (CHD) are occasionally familial and left ventricular out flow tract obstruction (LVOTO) defects are among the subtypes with the highest hereditability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Proliferation history and transcription factor levels drive direct conversion
Authors: Wang, N. B.; Lende-Dorn, B. A.; Adewumi, H. O.; Beitz, A. M.; Han, P.; O&amp;#39;Shea, T. M.; Galloway, K. E.
Score: 51.3, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568736
The sparse and stochastic nature of reprogramming has obscured our understanding of how transcription factors drive cells to new identities. To overcome this limit, we developed a compact, portable reprogramming system that increases direct conversion of fibroblasts to motor neurons by two orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Approach to Measure Alveolar Bone Loss After COVID-19
Authors: Lee, S. W.; Huz, K.; Gorelick, K.; Bina, T.; Matsumura, S.; Yin, N.; Zhang, N.; Naa Ardua Anang, Y.; Li, J.; Servin-DeMarrais, H. I.; McMahon, D. J.; Yin, M. T.; Wadhwa, S.; Lu, H.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298788
Severity of periodontal disease may be determined by measurement of alveolar crestal height (ACH) on dental bitewing radiographs; however, the prevailing method of assessment is through visualization which is time consuming and not a direct measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathophysiological Mechanisms of the Onset, Development, and Disappearance Phases of Skin Eruptions in Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria
Authors: Seirin-Lee, S.; Takahagi, S.; Hide, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.23298424
Chronic spontaneous urticaria (CSU) is a typical example of an intractable skin disease with no clear cause and significantly affects daily life of patients. Because CSU is a human-specific disease and lacks proper animal model, there are many questions regarding its pathophysiological dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive mapping of sensory and sympathetic innervation of the developing kidney
Authors: N&amp;#39;Guetta, P.-E. Y.; McLarnon, S. R.; Tassou, A.; Geron, M.; Scherrer, G.; O&amp;#39;Brien, L. L.
Score: 101.5, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567276
The kidney functions as a finely tuned sensor to balance body fluid composition and filter out waste through complex coordinated mechanisms. This versatility requires tight neural control, with innervating efferent nerves playing a crucial role in regulating blood flow, glomerular filtration rate, water and sodium reabsorption, and renin release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Chemical cues from beetle larvae trigger proliferation and virulence of a plant pathogen
Authors: Cambon, M. C.; Thomas, G.; Caulfield, J. C.; Crampton, M.; Doonan, J. M.; Hussain, U.; Denman, S.; Vuts, J.; McDonald, J. E.
Score: 17.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568124
Pest insects and microbial pathogens threaten agricultural crop productivity and global forest biomes, and insect-microbe interactions can increase the severity of plant decline. Whilst bacterial chemicals have been shown to influence insect behaviour, the impact of insect-derived chemistries on phytopathogens is barely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning-Based Hyperglycemia Prediction: Enhancing Risk Assessment in a Cohort of Undiagnosed Individuals
Authors: Oyebola, K.; Ligali, F.; Owoloye, A.; Erinwusi, B.; Alo, Y.; Musa, A.; Aina, O.; Salako, B.
Score: 5.5, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298939
BackgroundNoncommunicable diseases (NCDs) continue to pose a significant health challenge globally, with hyperglycemia serving as a prominent indicator of potential diabetes. This study employed machine learning algorithms to predict hyperglycemia in a cohort of asymptomatic individuals and unraveled crucial predictors contributing to early risk identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Wastewater monitoring of SARS-CoV-2 gene for COVID-19 epidemiological surveillance in Tucuman Argentina
Authors: DArpino, M. C.; Sineli, P. E.; Goroso, G.; Watanabe, W.; Saavedra, L.; Hebert, E. M.; Martinez, A.; Migliavacca, J.; Gerstenfeld, S.; Chahla, R. E.; Bellomio, A.; Albarracin, V. H.
Score: 30.3, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298851
Wastewater-based epidemiology provides temporal and spatial information about the health status of a population. The objective of this study was to analyze and report the epidemiological dynamics of SARS-CoV-2 in the province of Tucuman, Argentina during the second and third surges of COVID-19 between April 2021 and March 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>New genome reveals molecular signatures of adaptation to nocturnality in moth-like butterflies (Hedylidae)
Authors: Singh, R. P.; Weng, Y.-M.; Sondhi, Y.; Plotkin, D.; Frandsen, P. B.; Kawahara, A. Y.
Score: 55.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568084
Nearly all animals have a preferred period of daily activity (diel-niche), which is strongly influenced by the light environment. Sensory systems, particularly vision, are adapted to light, and evolutionary transitions to novel light environments, especially light limited ones, can impose strong constraints on eye evolution, color, and motion vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Deep generative modeling of the human proteome reveals over a hundred novel genes involved in rare genetic disorders.
Authors: Orenbuch, R.; Kollasch, A. W.; Spinner, H. D.; Shearer, C. A.; Hopf, T. A.; Franceschi, D.; Dias, M.; Frazer, J.; Marks, D. S.
Score: 27.0, Published: 2023-11-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.27.23299062
Identifying causal mutations accelerates genetic disease diagnosis, and therapeutic development. Missense variants present a bottleneck in genetic diagnoses as their effects are less straightforward than truncations or nonsense mutations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Step Control of Homologous Recombination by Mec1/ATR Ensures Robust Suppression of Gross Chromosomal Rearrangements
Authors: Xie, B.; Sanford, E. J.; Hung, S.-H.; Wagner, M. M.; Heyer, W.-D.; Smolka, M. B.
Score: 15.5, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568146
The Mec1/ATR kinase is crucial for genome stability, yet the mechanism by which it prevents gross chromosomal rearrangements (GCRs) remains unknown. Here we find that in cells with deficient Mec1 signaling, GCRs accumulate due to the deregulation of multiple steps in homologous recombination (HR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous Profiling of Chromatin Accessibility and DNA Methylation in Complete Plant Genomes Using Long-Read Sequencing
Authors: Leduque, B.; Edera, A.; Vitte, C.; Quadrana, L.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567180
Epigenetic regulations, including chromatin accessibility, nucleosome positioning, and DNA methylation intricately shape genome function. However, current chromatin profiling techniques relying on short-read sequencing technologies fail to characterise highly repetitive genomic regions and cannot detect multiple chromatin features simultaneously. Here, we performed Simultaneous Accessibility and DNA Methylation Sequencing (SAM-seq) of purified plant nuclei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Changes in the physical behaviour of older adults during the 13 weeks GOTO intervention explain a boost in immuno-metabolic health.
Authors: Paraschiakos, S.; Bogaards, F.; Knobbe, A.; Slagboom, P. E.; Beekman, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.23299026
BackgroundThe aging population faces numerous health challenges, with sedentary behavior and decreased physical activity being paramount. We explore the physical behaviour of older adults in the GOTO combined lifestyle intervention study and its related immuno-metabolic health effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Cost-effective boosting allocations in the post-Omicron era of COVID-19 management
Authors: Le, T. P.; Conway, E.; Akpan, E.; Abell, I.; Abraham, P.; Baker, C. M.; Campbell, P. T.; Cromer, D.; Lydeamore, M. J.; McDonough, Y.; Mueller, I.; Ryan, G.; Walker, C.; Wang, Y.; Carvalho, N.; McVernon, J.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298536
BackgroundFollowing widespread exposure to Omicron variants, COVID-19 has transitioned to endemic circulation. Populations now have diverse infection and vaccination histories, resulting in heterogeneous immune landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT Influence on Medical Decision-Making, Bias, and Equity: A Randomized Study of Clinicians Evaluating Clinical Vignettes
Authors: Goh, E.; Bunning, B.; Khoong, E.; Gallo, R.; Milstein, A.; Centola, D.; Chen, J. H.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.24.23298844
In a randomized, pre-post intervention study, we evaluated the influence of a large language model (LLM) generative AI system on accuracy of physician decision-making and bias in healthcare. 50 US-licensed physicians reviewed a video clinical vignette, featuring actors representing different demographics (a White male or a Black female) with chest pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the optimal age for infant measles vaccination
Authors: Goult, E. A.; Barrero Guevara, L. A.; Briga, M.; Domenech de Celles, M.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298759
The persistence of measles in many regions demonstrates large immunity gaps, resulting from incomplete or ineffective immunization with measles-containing vaccines (MCVs). A key factor affecting MCV impact is age, with infants receiving dose 1 (MCV1) at older ages having a reduced risk of vaccine failure, but also an increased risk of contracting infection before vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Nature-based social prescribing programmes: opportunities, challenges, and facilitators for implementation
Authors: de Bell, S.; Alejandre, J. C.; Menzel, C.; Sousa-Silva, R.; Straka, T. M.; Berzborn, S.; Burck-Gemassmer, M.; Dallimer, M.; Dayson, C.; Fisher, J. C.; Haywood, A.; Herrmann, A.; Immich, G.; Kesler, C. S.; Kohler, K.; Lynch, M.; Marx, V.; Michalsen, A.; Mudu, P.; Napierala, H.; Nawrath, M.; Pfleger, S.; Quitmann, C.; Reeves, J. P.; Rozario, K.; Straff, W.; Walter, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Analytical treatment interruption: detection of an increase in the latent, inducible HIV-1 reservoir more than a decade after viral resuppression
Authors: Lungu, C.; Hossain, T.; Prins, H. A. B.; Hensley, K. S.; Crespo, R.; Rokx, C.; Rao, S.; van Kampen, J. J. A.; van de Vijver, D. A. M. C.; Mesplede, T.; Katsikis, P. D.; Mueller, Y. M.; Gruters, R. A.; Mahmoudi, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298452</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 584.3, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-Co-V-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Hematologic abnormalities after COVID-19 vaccination: A large Korean population-based cohort study
Authors: CHOI, H. S.; KIM, M.-H.; CHOI, M. G.; PARK, J. H.; CHUN, E. M.
Score: 293.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298565
Adverse hematologic events have been reported after COVID-19 vaccination. The objective of this study was to investigate whether hematologic abnormalities develop after COVID-19 vaccination. Retrospective cohort analyses of data from the Korean National Health Insurance Service (KNHIS) database were conducted from July 2022 to August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 infects neurons, astrocytes, choroid plexus epithelial cells and pericytes of the human central nervous system
Authors: Haverty, R.; McCormack, J.; Evans, C.; Purves, K.; O&amp;#39;Reilly, S.; Gautier, V. W.; Rochfort, K.; Fabre, A.; Fletcher, N.
Score: 143.6, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568132
SARS-CoV-2, the coronavirus responsible for the COVID-19 pandemic, is associated with a range of neurological manifestations including haemorrhage, thrombosis and ischaemic necrosis and encephalitits. However, the mechanism by which this occurs is unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Efficient scar-free knock-ins of several kilobases by engineered CRISPR/Cas endonucleases
Authors: Schreiber, T.; Prange, A.; Schaefer, P.; Iwen, T.; Gruetzner, R.; Marillonnet, S.; Tissier, A. F.
Score: 49.5, Published: 2023-11-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.24.568561
In plants and mammals, non-homologous end-joining is the dominant pathway to repair DNA double strand breaks, making it challenging to generate knock-in events. Using a transient assay in Nicotiana benthamiana we identified two groups of exonucleases, respectively from the Herpes Virus and from the bacteriophage T7 families, hat confer up to 38-fold increase in HDR frequencies when fused to Cas9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Small Fiber Neuropathy after COVID-19: A Key to Long COVID
Authors: McAlpine, L.; Zubair, A.; Joseph, P.; Spudich, S.
Score: 192.4, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23297764
ObjectivesReport a case series of new onset small fiber neuropathy (SFN) after COVID-19 treated with intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG). SFN is a critical objective finding in long COVID and amenable to treatment. MethodsA retrospective chart review was conducted on patients seen in the NeuroCOVID Clinic at Yale who developed new-onset SFN after a documented COVID-19 illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>XCP-D: A Robust Pipeline for the post-processing of fMRI data
Authors: Mehta, K. P.; Salo, T.; Madison, T.; Adebimpe, A.; Bassett, D. S.; Bertolero, M.; Cieslak, M.; Covitz, S.; Houghton, A.; Keller, A. S.; Luo, A.; Miranda Dominguez, O.; Nelson, S.; Shafiei, G.; Shanmugan, S.; Shinohara, R.; Sydnor, V. J.; Feczko, E.; Fair, D. A.; Satterthwaite, T. D.
Score: 47.5, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567926
Functional neuroimaging is an essential tool for neuroscience research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Exogenous ketosis attenuates acute mountain sickness and mitigates high-altitude hypoxemia
Authors: Stalmans, M.; Tominec, D.; Lauriks, W.; Robberechts, R.; Debevec, T.; Poffe, C.
Score: 7.9, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298762
BackgroundAcute mountain sickness (AMS) represents a considerable issue for individuals sojourning to high altitudes with systemic hypoxemia known to be intimately involved in its development. Based on recent evidence that ketone ester (KE) intake attenuates hypoxemia, we sought to investigate whether exogenous ketosis might mitigate AMS development and improve hypoxic tolerance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Brick kiln pollution and its impact on health: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Nicolaou, L.; Sylvies, F.; Veloso, I.; Lord, K.; Chandyo, R. K.; Sharma, A. K.; Shrestha, L. P.; Parker, D.; Thygerson, S. M.; Waugh, D.; DeCarlo, P. F.; Ramachandran, G.; Checkley, W.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298642
BackgroundBrick kiln emissions contribute to ambient air pollution and poor health in workers and individuals living near the brick kilns; however, data on the effects of brick kiln pollution on the environment and health are limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Spatial characterization and stratification of colorectal adenomas by Deep Visual Proteomics
Authors: Kabatnik, S.; Post, F.; Drici, L.; Snejbjerg Bartels, A.; Strauss, M. T.; Zheng, X.; Madsen, G. I.; Mund, A.; Rosenberger, F. A.; Moreira, J. M. A.; Mann, M.
Score: 13.4, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.25.23298987
Colorectal adenomas (CRA) are precursor lesions of the colon that may progress to adenocarcinomas, with patients currently categorized into risk groups by morphological features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Human coronavirus OC43 infection remodels Connexin 43 mediated gap junction intercellular communication in vitro
Authors: Karmakar, S.; Das Sarma, J.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567927
{beta}-coronaviruses cause acute infection in the upper respiratory tract, resulting in various symptoms and clinical manifestations. OC43 is a human {beta}-coronavirus that induces mild clinical symptoms and can be safely studied in the BSL2 laboratory. Due to its low risk, OC43 can be a valuable and accessible model for understanding {beta}-coronavirus pathogenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Increased Severity of New-onset Type 1 Diabetes in Children and Adolescents during the COVID-19 Pandemic: Experience from a Tertiary Care Center in Serbia
Authors: Jovanovic, D.; Blagojevic, J.; Stanisavljevic, D.; Jesic, M.
Score: 29.0, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298741
Background and objectivesPublic health measures, parental fear of infection, and redeployment of medical resources in response to the COVID-19 pandemic might have led to a decrease in pediatric healthcare access. As a result, a delay in type 1 diabetes diagnosis might have occurred, leading to the worsening of its clinical presentation in the pediatric population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Leukemia in Sprague-Dawley Rats Exposed Long-term from Prenatal Life to Glyphosate and Glyphosate-Based Herbicides
Authors: Panzacchi, S.; Tibaldi, E.; De Angelis, L.; Falcioni, L.; Gnudi, F.; Iuliani, M.; Manservigi, M.; Manservisi, F.; Manzoli, I.; Menghetti, I.; Montella, R.; Noferini, R.; Sgargi, D.; Strollo, V.; Antoniou, M.; Chen, J.; Dinelli, G.; Lorenzetti, S.; Mesnage, R.; Vornoli, A.; Perry, M. J.; Landrigan, P. J.; Belpoggi, F.; Mandrioli, D.
Score: 12.0, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Adherent reformed islets: a long-term primary cell-based platform for exploring mouse and human islet biology.
Authors: Haq, N.; Toczyska, K.; Wilson, M.; Jacobs, M.; Lei, Y.; Zhao, M.; Pearson, J.; Persaud, S.; Pullen, T.; Bewick, G. A.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.568245
Pancreatic islets are 3-dimensional micro-organs that maintain {beta}-cell functionality via cell-cell and cell-matrix communication. Isolated primary islets are the gold standard for in vitro models. However, native islets present experimental challenges for long-term mechanistic studies owing to their short culture life (approximately 1 week).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>AvrSr27 is a zinc-bound effector with a modular structure important for immune recognition
Authors: Outram, M. A.; Chen, J.; Broderick, S.; Li, Z.; Aditya, S.; Tasneem, N.; Arndell, T.; Blundell, C.; Ericsson, D. J.; Figueroa, M.; Sperschneider, J.; Dodds, P.; Williams, S. J.
Score: 25.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.567997
Stem rust, caused by the fungal pathogen Puccinia graminis f. sp.tritici (Pgt) is a major threat for wheat production and global food security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Comparative Effectiveness of Semaglutide and Tirzepatide for Weight Loss in Adults with Overweight and Obesity in the US: A Real-World Evidence Study
Authors: Rodriguez, P. J.; Cartwright, B.; Gratzl, S.; Baker, C.; Brar, R.; Gluckman, T. J.; Stucky, N.
Score: 388.2, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298775
BackgroundBoth tirzepatide and semaglutide have been shown to reduce weight for patients with overweight or obesity in randomized controlled trials (RCTs). While tirzepatide appears to provide greater weight loss than semaglutide in this population, head-to-head RCTs are not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Electrophysiologically-defined excitation-inhibition autism neurosubtypes
Authors: Bertelsen, N.; Vitale, A.; Bolis, D.; Mandelli, V.; Lombardo, M. V.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298729
Excitation-inhibition (E:I) imbalance has long been considered one of the primary neurobiological theories explaining autism. However, the theory has been bolstered heavily by research on high-penetrance genetic mechanisms which are only found in a small proportion of the autism population. Thus, how well does E:I imbalance explain idiopathic autism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Post-Vaccination Syndrome: A Descriptive Analysis of Reported Symptoms and Patient Experiences After Covid-19 Immunization
Authors: Krumholz, H. M.; Wu, Y.; Sawano, M.; Shah, R.; Zhou, T.; Arun, A. S.; Khosla, P.; Kaleem, S.; Vashist, A.; Bhattacharjee, B.; Ding, Q.; Lu, Y.; Caraballo, C.; Warner, F.; Huang, C.; Herrin, J.; Putrino, D.; Hertz, D.; Dressen, B.; Iwasaki, A.
Score: 915.8, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.23298266
IntroductionA chronic post-vaccination syndrome (PVS) after covid-19 vaccination has been reported but has yet to be well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Spot the Difference: Can ChatGPT4-Vision Transform Radiology Artificial Intelligence?
Authors: Kelly, B. S. S.; Duignan, S.; Mathur, P.; Dillon, H.; Lee, E.; Yeom, K. W.; Keane, P.; Killeen, R. P.; Lawlor, A.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298499
OpenAIs flagship Large Language Model ChatGPT can now accept image input (GPT4V). &amp;#34;Spot the Difference&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;Medical&amp;#34; have been suggested as emerging applications. The interpretation of medical images is a dynamic process not a static task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>GMAC: A simple measure to quantify upper limb use from wrist-worn accelerometers
Authors: Balasubramanian, S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.23299036
AO_SCPLOWBSTRACTC_SCPLOWVarious measures have been proposed to quantify upper-limb use through wrist-worn inertial measurement units. The two most popular traditional measures of upper-limb use - thresholded activity counts (TAC) and the gross movement (GM) score suffer from high sensitivity and specificity, respectively. We had previously proposed a hybrid version of these two measures - the GMAC - that showed better overall detection performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The effects of inhaled corticosteroids on healthy airways
Authors: Marchi, E.; Hinks, T. S. C.; Richardson, M.; Khalfaoui, L.; Symon, F.; Rajasekar, P.; Clifford, R.; Hagardon, B.; Austin, C. D.; MacIsaac, J.; Kobor, M. S.; Siddiqui, S.; Mar, J. S.; Arron, J. R.; Choy, D.; Bradding, P. H.
Score: 15.9, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298442
RationaleThe effects of inhaled corticosteroids (ICS) on healthy airways are poorly defined. ObjectivesTo delineate the effects of ICS on gene expression in healthy airways, without confounding caused by changes in disease-related genes and disease-related alterations in ICS-responsiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Development and Outcomes of an International Certificate Program in Science Policy and Advocacy for STEM PhD Students and Postdocs
Authors: Bankston, A.; Ralston, A.; Ly, J.; Singh, H.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568726
Scientists must play a significant role in enacting societal change by educating and advising policymakers on relevant policy topics. To fill the identified gap in science policy and advocacy training, during the pandemic years, we piloted and offered the online Science Policy &amp;amp; Advocacy for STEM Scientists Certificate Program starting in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A randomised cross-over trial to investigate the effects of a rigid cervical collar on three-dimensional angular movement and angular acceleration during emergency spinal immobilisation and extrication procedures in elite football (soccer) players: The RESTRICT study.
Authors: Callaghan, M. J.; Hughes, T.; Davin, J.; Hayes, R.; Hough, N.; Torpey, D.; Dawson, S.; Murray, E.; Perry, D.; Lancett, M.; Liu, A.; Jones, R.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298822
ObjectiveTo determine the effects of rigid collars on cervical movement and acceleration during triple spinal immobilisation and extrication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>An interdependent Metabolic and Genetic Network shows emergent properties in vitro
Authors: Giaveri, S.; Bohra, N.; Diehl, C.; Ballinger, M.; Paczia, N.; Glatter, T.; Erb, T. J.
Score: 24.4, Published: 2023-11-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568713
A hallmark of all living organisms is their ability for self-regeneration which requires a tight integration of metabolic and genetic networks. Here we constructed a metabolic and genetic linked in vitro network (MGLN) that shows life-like behavior outside of a cellular context and generates its own building blocks from non-living matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>One-Hour Phosphoproteome Analysis with the Orbitrap Astral Mass Spectrometer
Authors: Lancaster, N. M.; Sinitcyn, P.; Forny, P.; Peters-Clarke, T. M.; Fecher, C.; Smith, A. J.; Shishkova, E.; Arrey, T. N.; Pashkova, A.; Robinson, M. L.; Arp, N.; Fan, J.; Hansen, J.; Galmozzi, A.; Serrano, L. R.; Westphall, M. S.; Stewart, H.; Hock, C.; Damoc, E.; Pagliarini, D. J.; Zabrouskov, V.; Coon, J. J.
Score: 25.8, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568149</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Avian influenza viruses in wild birds in Canada following incursion of the highly pathogenic H5N1 virus from Eurasia in 2021/2022
Authors: Giacinti, J. A.; Signore, A. V.; Jones, M. E. B.; Bourque, L.; Lair, S.; Jardine, C.; Stevens, B.; Bollinger, T.; Goldsmith, D.; British Columbia Wildlife AIV Surveillance Program (BC WASP), ; Pybus, M.; Stasiak, I.; Davis, R.; Pople, N.; Nituch, L.; Brook, R. W.; Ojkic, D.; Masse, A.; Dimitri-Masson, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
