<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Correlation between COVID-19 vaccination and inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders
Authors: Park, Y. H.; Kim, M. H.; Choi, M. G.; Chun, E. M.
Score: 57.9, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298544
ImportanceEarlier research on COVID-19 vaccines identified a range of adverse reactions related to proinflammatory actions that can lead to an excessive immune response and sustained inflammation. However, no study has been conducted on the association between inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders and COVID-19 vaccines. ObjectiveTo investigate the incidence rates of inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders following COVID-19 vaccination and to compare them with those of unvaccinated individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Plant-like heliotropism in a photosymbiotic animal
Authors: Lintnerova, E.; Shaw, C.; Keys, M.; Brownlee, C.; Modepalli, V.
Score: 67.9, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565328
Being photosynthetic sessile organisms, plants established heliotropism to track the suns position across the sky and allow their vegetative parts to orient accordingly. Here, we report plant-like heliotropic movement in a photosymbiotic sea anemone Anemonia viridis. Like plants, photosynthesis represents a key energy source in endosymbiotic cnidarians bearing microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structure of the γ-tubulin ring complex-capped microtubule
Authors: Aher, A.; Urnavicius, L.; Xue, A.; Neselu, K.; Kapoor, T.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567916
Microtubules are composed of /{beta}-tubulin dimers positioned head-to-tail to form protofilaments that associate laterally in varying numbers. It is not known how cellular microtubules assemble with the canonical 13-protofilament architecture, resulting in micrometer-scale /{beta}-tubulin tracks for intracellular transport that align with, rather than spiral along, the filaments long-axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Engineering mice for female-biased progeny without impacting genetic integrity and litter size
Authors: Yosef, I.; Mahata, T.; Chen, Y.; Bar-Joseph, H.; Shalgi, R.; Munitz, A.; Gerlic, M.; Qimron, U.
Score: 36.6, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568055
Generating mammalian gametes with a skewed sex ratio has thus far eluded empirical confirmation. The utilization of such genetically engineered organisms would offer the potential to curtail the necessity for culling animals of undesirable sex, mitigate resource wastage, and alleviate superfluous labor burdens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>DL4MicEverywhere: Deep learning for microscopy made flexible, shareable, and reproducible
Authors: Hidalgo-Cenalmor, I.; Pylvänäinen, J. W.; Ferreira, M. G.; Russell, C. T.; Arganda-Carreras, I.; AI4Life Consortium, ; Jacquemet, G.; Henriques, R.; Gomez-de-Mariscal, E.
Score: 49.9, Published: 2023-11-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.19.567606
Deep learning has revolutionised the analysis of extensive microscopy datasets, yet challenges persist in the widespread adoption of these techniques. Many lack access to training data, computing resources, and expertise to develop complex models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Real-Time Structural Biology of DNA and DNA-Protein Complexes on an Optical Microscope
Authors: Szalai, A. M.; Ferrari, G.; Richter, L.; Hartmann, J.; Kesici, M.-Z.; Ji, B.; Koshic, K.; Jaeger, A.; Aksimentiev, A.; Tessmer, I.; Kaminska, I.; Vera, A. M.; Tinnefeld, P.
Score: 40.7, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.567962
The intricate interplay between DNA and proteins is key for biological functions such as DNA replication, transcription, and repair. To better understand these interactions, it is crucial to develop tools to study DNA-protein complexes with high spatial and temporal resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cancer-associated fibroblasts serve as decoys to suppress NK cell anti-cancer cytotoxicity
Authors: Ben-Shmuel, A.; Gruper, Y.; Levi-Galibov, O.; Rosenberg-Fogler, H.; Carradori, G.; Stein, Y.; Dadiani, M.; Naumova, M.; Nevo, R.; Morzaev-Sulzbach, D.; Yagel, G.; Mayer, S.; Gal-Yam, E.; Scherz-Shouval, R.
Score: 17.2, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568355
Cancer associated fibroblasts (CAFs) are among the most abundant components of the breast tumor microenvironment (TME) and major contributors to immune modulation. CAFs are well-known to regulate the activity of diverse types of immune cells including T cells, macrophages and dendritic cells, however little is known about their interaction with Natural killer (NK) cells, which constitute an important arm of anti-tumor immunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>ERBB2 R599C variant is associated with left ventricular outflow tract obstruction defects in human
Authors: Ampuja, M.; Selenius, S.; Paatero, I.; Chowdhury, I.; Villman, J.; Broberg, M.; Ranta, A.; Ojala, T.; Chong, J. X.; Bamshad, M.; Priest, J. R.; Varjosalo, M.; Kivela, R.; Helle, E.
Score: 2.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23297969
Background and aimsNon-syndromic congenital heart defects (CHD) are occasionally familial and left ventricular out flow tract obstruction (LVOTO) defects are among the subtypes with the highest hereditability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>A liquid-like coat mediates chromosome clustering during mitotic exit
Authors: Hernandez-Armendariz, A.; Sorichetti, V.; Hayashi, Y.; Brunner, A.; Ellenberg, J.; Saric, A.; Cuylen-Haering, S.
Score: 45.8, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568026
The individualization of chromosomes during early mitosis and their clustering upon exit from cell division are two key transitions that ensure efficient segregation of eukaryotic chromosomes. Both processes are regulated by the surfactant-like protein Ki-67, but how Ki-67 achieves these diametric functions has remained unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Approach to Measure Alveolar Bone Loss After COVID-19
Authors: Lee, S. W.; Huz, K.; Gorelick, K.; Bina, T.; Matsumura, S.; Yin, N.; Zhang, N.; Naa Ardua Anang, Y.; Li, J.; Servin-DeMarrais, H. I.; McMahon, D. J.; Yin, M. T.; Wadhwa, S.; Lu, H.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298788
Severity of periodontal disease may be determined by measurement of alveolar crestal height (ACH) on dental bitewing radiographs; however, the prevailing method of assessment is through visualization which is time consuming and not a direct measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathophysiological Mechanisms of the Onset, Development, and Disappearance Phases of Skin Eruptions in Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria
Authors: Seirin-Lee, S.; Takahagi, S.; Hide, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.23298424
Chronic spontaneous urticaria (CSU) is a typical example of an intractable skin disease with no clear cause and significantly affects daily life of patients. Because CSU is a human-specific disease and lacks proper animal model, there are many questions regarding its pathophysiological dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive mapping of sensory and sympathetic innervation of the developing kidney
Authors: N&amp;#39;Guetta, P.-E. Y.; McLarnon, S. R.; Tassou, A.; Geron, M.; Scherrer, G.; O&amp;#39;Brien, L. L.
Score: 98.9, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567276
The kidney functions as a finely tuned sensor to balance body fluid composition and filter out waste through complex coordinated mechanisms. This versatility requires tight neural control, with innervating efferent nerves playing a crucial role in regulating blood flow, glomerular filtration rate, water and sodium reabsorption, and renin release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Chemical cues from beetle larvae trigger proliferation and virulence of a plant pathogen
Authors: Cambon, M. C.; Thomas, G.; Caulfield, J. C.; Crampton, M.; Doonan, J. M.; Hussain, U.; Denman, S.; Vuts, J.; McDonald, J. E.
Score: 17.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568124
Pest insects and microbial pathogens threaten agricultural crop productivity and global forest biomes, and insect-microbe interactions can increase the severity of plant decline. Whilst bacterial chemicals have been shown to influence insect behaviour, the impact of insect-derived chemistries on phytopathogens is barely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning-Based Hyperglycemia Prediction: Enhancing Risk Assessment in a Cohort of Undiagnosed Individuals
Authors: Oyebola, K.; Ligali, F.; Owoloye, A.; Erinwusi, B.; Alo, Y.; Musa, A.; Aina, O.; Salako, B.
Score: 5.5, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298939
Background: Noncommunicable diseases (NCDs) continue to pose a significant health challenge globally, with hyperglycemia serving as a prominent indicator of potential diabetes. This study employed machine learning algorithms to predict hyperglycemia in a cohort of asymptomatic individuals and unraveled crucial predictors contributing to early risk identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Combining genomic data and infection estimates to characterize the complex dynamics of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variants in the United States
Authors: Lopes, R.; Pham, K.; Klaassen, F.; Chitwood, M. H.; Hahn, A.; Redmond, S.; Swartwood, N. A.; Salomon, J. A.; Menzies, N. A.; Cohen, T.; Grubaugh, N. D.
Score: 186.7, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23298178
SARS-CoV-2 Omicron surged as a variant of concern (VOC) in late 2021. Subsequently, several distinct Omicron variants have appeared and overtaken each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>New genome reveals molecular signatures of adaptation to nocturnality in moth-like butterflies (Hedylidae)
Authors: Singh, R. P.; Weng, Y.-M.; Sondhi, Y.; Plotkin, D.; Frandsen, P. B.; Kawahara, A. Y.
Score: 55.0, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568084
Nearly all animals have a preferred period of daily activity (diel-niche), which is strongly influenced by the light environment. Sensory systems, particularly vision, are adapted to light, and evolutionary transitions to novel light environments, especially light limited ones, can impose strong constraints on eye evolution, color, and motion vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of polygenic scoring methods in five biobanks reveals greater variability between biobanks than between methods and highlights benefits of ensemble learning
Authors: Monti, R.; Eick, L.; Hudjashov, G.; Läll, K.; Kanoni, S.; Wolford, B. N.; Wingfield, B.; Pain, O.; Wharrie, S.; Jermy, B.; McMahon, A.; Hartonen, T.; Heyne, H. O.; Mars, N.; Genes &amp;amp; Health Research Team, ; Hveem, K.; Inouye, M.; van Heel, D. A.; Mägi, R.; Marttinen, P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Misexpression of inactive genes in whole blood is associated with nearby rare structural variants
Authors: Vanderstichele, T.; Burnham, K. L.; de Klein, N.; Tardaguila, M.; Howell, B.; Walter, K.; Kundu, K.; Koeppel, J.; Lee, W.; Tokolyi, A.; Persyn, E.; Nath, A. P.; Marten, J.; Petrovski, S.; Roberts, D. J.; Di Angelantonio, E.; Danesh, J.; Berton, A.; Platt, A.; Butterworth, A. S.; Soranzo, N.; Parts, L.; Inouye, M.; Paul, D. S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous Profiling of Chromatin Accessibility and DNA Methylation in Complete Plant Genomes Using Long-Read Sequencing
Authors: Leduque, B.; Edera, A.; Vitte, C.; Quadrana, L.
Score: 21.6, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567180
Epigenetic regulations, including chromatin accessibility, nucleosome positioning, and DNA methylation intricately shape genome function. However, current chromatin profiling techniques relying on short-read sequencing technologies fail to characterise highly repetitive genomic regions and cannot detect multiple chromatin features simultaneously. Here, we performed Simultaneous Accessibility and DNA Methylation Sequencing (SAM-seq) of purified plant nuclei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Cost-effective boosting allocations in the post-Omicron era of COVID-19 management
Authors: Le, T. P.; Conway, E.; Akpan, E.; Abell, I.; Abraham, P.; Baker, C. M.; Campbell, P. T.; Cromer, D.; Lydeamore, M. J.; McDonough, Y.; Mueller, I.; Ryan, G.; Walker, C.; Wang, Y.; Carvalho, N.; McVernon, J.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298536
BackgroundFollowing widespread exposure to Omicron variants, COVID-19 has transitioned to endemic circulation. Populations now have diverse infection and vaccination histories, resulting in heterogeneous immune landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Development of meta-prompts for Large Language Models to screen titles and abstracts for diagnostic test accuracy reviews
Authors: KATAOKA, Y.; So, R.; Banno, M.; Kumasawa, J.; Someko, H.; Taito, S.; Terasawa, T.; Tsujimoto, Y.; Tsutsumi, Y.; Wada, Y.; Furukawa, T. A.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297818
Systematic reviews (SRs) are a critical component of evidence-based medicine, but the process of screening titles and abstracts is time-consuming. This study aimed to develop and externally validate a method using large language models to classify abstracts for diagnostic test accuracy (DTA) systematic reviews, thereby reducing the human workload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the optimal age for infant measles vaccination
Authors: Goult, E. A.; Barrero Guevara, L. A.; Briga, M.; Domenech de Celles, M.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298759
The persistence of measles in many regions demonstrates large immunity gaps, resulting from incomplete or ineffective immunization with measles-containing vaccines (MCVs). A key factor affecting MCV impact is age, with infants receiving dose 1 (MCV1) at older ages having a reduced risk of vaccine failure, but also an increased risk of contracting infection before vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Exploring virtual funding committee practices in the allocation of National Institute for Health and Care Research funding: A netnographic study
Authors: Blatch-Jones, A. J.; Boxall, C.; Asante, E.; Meadmore, K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23298707
ObjectivesFunding committees, comprising members with a range of knowledge, skills, and experience, are considered integral to the decision-making process of funding organisations for recommending or allocating research funding. However, there is limited research investigating the decision-making processes, the role of members and their social interactions during funding committee meetings conducted both virtually and face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Association between HIV/AIDS, Medical Male Circumcision and Traditional Circumcision in Mozambique, 2015
Authors: Militao, H. I. E.; Braga, J. M.; Rossetto, E. V.; Baltazar, C. S.; Kellogg, T. A.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298896
BackgroundThe WHO AFRO region continues to be severely impacted by HIV and a global public health problem. In Mozambique, as of 2015, HIV prevalence was estimated to be 12.5% among adults. Medical male circumcision (MMC) has been promoted as a national prevention strategy to reduce the risk of HIV in men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Fast evolution of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 to JN.1 under heavy immune pressure
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Xu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Wang, P.; Wang, J.; Liu, J.; Yu, L.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Wang, Y.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y.
Score: 242.9, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566860
While the BA.2.86 variant demonstrated significant antigenic drift and enhanced ACE2 binding affinity, its ability to evade humoral immunity was relatively moderate compared to dominant strains like EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Hematologic abnormalities after COVID-19 vaccination: A large Korean population-based cohort study
Authors: CHOI, H. S.; KIM, M.-H.; CHOI, M. G.; PARK, J. H.; CHUN, E. M.
Score: 276.9, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298565
Adverse hematologic events have been reported after COVID-19 vaccination. The objective of this study was to investigate whether hematologic abnormalities develop after COVID-19 vaccination. Retrospective cohort analyses of data from the Korean National Health Insurance Service (KNHIS) database were conducted from July 2022 to August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>MedEdMENTOR AI: Can artificial intelligence help medical education researchers select theoretical constructs?
Authors: Ow, G.; Rodman, A.; Stetson, G. V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298661
INTRODUCTIONMedical education scholarship often lacks a strong theoretical underpinning, with this gap most often affecting early-career researchers and researchers in the Global South. Large language models (LLMs) have shown considerable promise to augment human writing and creativity in a variety of settings. In this study, we describe the development of MedEdMENTOR -- an online platform for medical education research with a library of over 250 theories -- and the development and evaluation of MedEdMENTOR AI, an LLM containing knowledge from MedEdMENTOR and the first AI mentor for medical education research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 infects neurons, astrocytes, choroid plexus epithelial cells and pericytes of the human central nervous system
Authors: Haverty, R.; McCormack, J.; Evans, C.; Purves, K.; O&amp;#39;Reilly, S.; Gautier, V. W.; Rochfort, K.; Fabre, A.; Fletcher, N.
Score: 140.7, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568132
SARS-CoV-2, the coronavirus responsible for the COVID-19 pandemic, is associated with a range of neurological manifestations including haemorrhage, thrombosis and ischaemic necrosis and encephalitits. However, the mechanism by which this occurs is unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Antagonistic conflict between transposon-encoded introns and guide RNAs
Authors: Zedaveinyte, R.; Meers, C.; Le, H. C.; Mortman, E. E.; Tang, S.; Lampe, G. D.; Pesari, S. R.; Gelsinger, D. R.; Wiegand, T.; Sternberg, S. H.
Score: 20.1, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567912
TnpB nucleases represent the evolutionary precursors to CRISPR-Cas12 and are widespread in all domains of life, presumably due to the critical roles they play in transposon proliferation. IS605-family TnpB homologs function in bacteria as programmable homing endonucleases by exploiting transposon-encoded guide RNAs to cleave vacant genomic sites, thereby driving transposon maintenance through DSB-stimulated homologous recombination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Small Fiber Neuropathy after COVID-19: A Key to Long COVID
Authors: McAlpine, L.; Zubair, A.; Joseph, P.; Spudich, S.
Score: 177.8, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23297764
ObjectivesReport a case series of new onset small fiber neuropathy (SFN) after COVID-19 treated with intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG). SFN is a critical objective finding in long COVID and amenable to treatment. MethodsA retrospective chart review was conducted on patients seen in the NeuroCOVID Clinic at Yale who developed new-onset SFN after a documented COVID-19 illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>XCP-D: A Robust Pipeline for the post-processing of fMRI data
Authors: Mehta, K. P.; Salo, T.; Madison, T.; Adebimpe, A.; Bassett, D. S.; Bertolero, M.; Cieslak, M.; Covitz, S.; Houghton, A.; Keller, A. S.; Luo, A.; Miranda Dominguez, O.; Nelson, S.; Shafiei, G.; Shanmugan, S.; Shinohara, R.; Sydnor, V. J.; Feczko, E.; Fair, D. A.; Satterthwaite, T. D.
Score: 45.7, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567926
Functional neuroimaging is an essential tool for neuroscience research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Exogenous ketosis attenuates acute mountain sickness and mitigates high-altitude hypoxemia
Authors: Stalmans, M.; Tominec, D.; Lauriks, W.; Robberechts, R.; Debevec, T.; Poffe, C.
Score: 7.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298762
BackgroundAcute mountain sickness (AMS) represents a considerable issue for individuals sojourning to high altitudes with systemic hypoxemia known to be intimately involved in its development. Based on recent evidence that ketone ester (KE) intake attenuates hypoxemia, we sought to investigate whether exogenous ketosis might mitigate AMS development and improve hypoxic tolerance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Brick kiln pollution and its impact on health: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Nicolaou, L.; Sylvies, F.; Veloso, I.; Lord, K.; Chandyo, R. K.; Sharma, A. K.; Shrestha, L. P.; Parker, D.; Thygerson, S. M.; Waugh, D.; DeCarlo, P. F.; Ramachandran, G.; Checkley, W.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298642
BackgroundBrick kiln emissions contribute to ambient air pollution and poor health in workers and individuals living near the brick kilns; however, data on the effects of brick kiln pollution on the environment and health are limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>An elevated rate of whole-genome duplication events in cancers from Black patients
Authors: Brown, L. M.; Hagenson, R. A.; Sheltzer, J. M.
Score: 35.0, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298349
In the United States, Black individuals have higher rates of cancer mortality than any other racial or ethnic group. The sources of these significant racial disparities are not fully understood, and may include social, environmental, and genetic factors that influence cancer onset, diagnosis, and treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Unsupervised subgrouping of chronic low back pain patients treated in a specialty clinic
Authors: Torres Espin, A.; Keller, A.; Ewing, S.; Bishara, A.; Takegami, N.; Ferguson, A. R.; Scheffler, A.; Hue, T.; Lotzs, J.; Peterson, T.; Zheng, P.; O&amp;#39;Neill, C.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.23298104
BackgroundChronic low back pain (cLBP) is the leading cause of disability worldwide. Current treatments have minor or moderate effects, partly because of the idiopathic nature of most cLBP cases, the complexity of its presentation, and heterogeneity in the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Human coronavirus OC43 infection remodels Connexin 43 mediated gap junction intercellular communication in vitro
Authors: Karmakar, S.; Das Sarma, J.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.567927
{beta}-coronaviruses cause acute infection in the upper respiratory tract, resulting in various symptoms and clinical manifestations. OC43 is a human {beta}-coronavirus that induces mild clinical symptoms and can be safely studied in the BSL2 laboratory. Due to its low risk, OC43 can be a valuable and accessible model for understanding {beta}-coronavirus pathogenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Increased Severity of New-onset Type 1 Diabetes in Children and Adolescents during the COVID-19 Pandemic: Experience from a Tertiary Care Center in Serbia
Authors: Jovanovic, D.; Blagojevic, J.; Stanisavljevic, D.; Jesic, M.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298741
Background and objectivesPublic health measures, parental fear of infection, and redeployment of medical resources in response to the COVID-19 pandemic might have led to a decrease in pediatric healthcare access. As a result, a delay in type 1 diabetes diagnosis might have occurred, leading to the worsening of its clinical presentation in the pediatric population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Effects of testosterone and metformin on the GlycanAge index of biological age and the composition of the IgG glycome
Authors: Vinicki, M.; Pribic, T.; Vuckovic, F.; Frkatovic-Hodzic|, A.; Plaza-Andrade, I.; Tinahones, F.; Raffaele, J.; Fernandez-Garcia, J. C.; Lauc, G.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298497
With aging, there is a correlation between a decline in the bodys ability to maintain regular functioning and greater susceptibility to age-related diseases. Therapeutic interventions targeting the underlying biological changes of aging hold promise for preventing or delaying multiple age-related diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>RAG-17: A Novel siRNA Conjugate Demonstrating Efficacy in Late-Stage Treatment of SOD1G93A ALS mice
Authors: Duan, C.; Kang, M.; Liu, K.; Gan, Z.; Li, G.; Chen, J.; Schacht, I.; Place, R. F.; Li, L.-C.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568255
Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a devastating neurodegenerative disease characterized by rapid progression and high mortality. With genetic mutations, particularly in the SOD1 gene, playing a significant role in ALS pathogenesis, targeted therapies have become a primary focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Fibre-specific mitochondrial protein abundance is linked to resting and post-training mitochondrial content in human muscle.
Authors: Reisman, E.; Botella Ruiz, J.; Huang, C.; Schittenhelm, R. B.; Stroud, D. A.; Granata, C.; Chandrasiri, S.; Ramm, G.; Oorschot, V.; Caruana, N. J.; Bishop, D. J.
Score: 37.2, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2022.10.23.512956
Analyses of mitochondrial adaptations in human skeletal muscle have mostly used whole-muscle samples, where results may be confounded by the presence of a mixture of type I and II muscle fibres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>AvrSr27 is a zinc-bound effector with a modular structure important for immune recognition
Authors: Outram, M. A.; Chen, J.; Broderick, S.; Li, Z.; Aditya, S.; Tasneem, N.; Arndell, T.; Blundell, C.; Ericsson, D. J.; Figueroa, M.; Sperschneider, J.; Dodds, P.; Williams, S. J.
Score: 25.9, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.567997
Stem rust, caused by the fungal pathogen Puccinia graminis f. sp.tritici (Pgt) is a major threat for wheat production and global food security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Electrophysiologically-defined excitation-inhibition autism neurosubtypes
Authors: Bertelsen, N.; Vitale, A.; Bolis, D.; Mandelli, V.; Lombardo, M. V.
Score: 7.5, Published: 2023-11-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298729
Excitation-inhibition (E:I) imbalance has long been considered one of the primary neurobiological theories explaining autism. However, the theory has been bolstered heavily by research on high-penetrance genetic mechanisms which are only found in a small proportion of the autism population. Thus, how well does E:I imbalance explain idiopathic autism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Post-Vaccination Syndrome: A Descriptive Analysis of Reported Symptoms and Patient Experiences After Covid-19 Immunization
Authors: Krumholz, H. M.; Wu, Y.; Sawano, M.; Shah, R.; Zhou, T.; Arun, A. S.; Khosla, P.; Kaleem, S.; Vashist, A.; Bhattacharjee, B.; Ding, Q.; Lu, Y.; Caraballo, C.; Warner, F.; Huang, C.; Herrin, J.; Putrino, D.; Hertz, D.; Dressen, B.; Iwasaki, A.
Score: 881.8, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.23298266
IntroductionA chronic post-vaccination syndrome (PVS) after covid-19 vaccination has been reported but has yet to be well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Spot the Difference: Can ChatGPT4-Vision Transform Radiology Artificial Intelligence?
Authors: Kelly, B. S. S.; Duignan, S.; Mathur, P.; Dillon, H.; Lee, E.; Yeom, K. W.; Keane, P.; Killeen, R. P.; Lawlor, A.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298499
OpenAIs flagship Large Language Model ChatGPT can now accept image input (GPT4V). &amp;#34;Spot the Difference&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;Medical&amp;#34; have been suggested as emerging applications. The interpretation of medical images is a dynamic process not a static task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The effects of inhaled corticosteroids on healthy airways
Authors: Marchi, E.; Hinks, T. S. C.; Richardson, M.; Khalfaoui, L.; Symon, F.; Rajasekar, P.; Clifford, R.; Hagardon, B.; Austin, C. D.; MacIsaac, J.; Kobor, M. S.; Siddiqui, S.; Mar, J. S.; Arron, J. R.; Choy, D.; Bradding, P. H.
Score: 15.9, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298442
RationaleThe effects of inhaled corticosteroids (ICS) on healthy airways are poorly defined. ObjectivesTo delineate the effects of ICS on gene expression in healthy airways, without confounding caused by changes in disease-related genes and disease-related alterations in ICS-responsiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A randomised cross-over trial to investigate the effects of a rigid cervical collar on three-dimensional angular movement and angular acceleration during emergency spinal immobilisation and extrication procedures in elite football (soccer) players: The RESTRICT study.
Authors: Callaghan, M. J.; Hughes, T.; Davin, J.; Hayes, R.; Hough, N.; Torpey, D.; Dawson, S.; Murray, E.; Perry, D.; Lancett, M.; Liu, A.; Jones, R.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298822
ObjectiveTo determine the effects of rigid collars on cervical movement and acceleration during triple spinal immobilisation and extrication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Engineering orthogonal ribosomes for real-time monitoring using fluorescence
Authors: Csibra, E.; Klopprogge, B.; Hau Sorensen, G.; Gorochowski, T. E.
Score: 22.2, Published: 2023-11-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.19.567736
A promising route to tackle the trade-off in cellular resources between synthetic protein production and cellular growth is to use a separate dedicated pool of orthogonal ribosomes to produce synthetic proteins. However, the optimisation of strains containing two ribosomal pools - native for the host cells proteome and orthogonal for synthetic proteins - has yet to be thoroughly explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>One-Hour Phosphoproteome Analysis with the Orbitrap Astral Mass Spectrometer
Authors: Lancaster, N. M.; Sinitcyn, P.; Forny, P.; Peters-Clarke, T. M.; Fecher, C.; Smith, A. J.; Shishkova, E.; Arrey, T. N.; Pashkova, A.; Robinson, M. L.; Arp, N.; Fan, J.; Hansen, J.; Galmozzi, A.; Serrano, L. R.; Westphall, M. S.; Stewart, H.; Hock, C.; Damoc, E.; Pagliarini, D. J.; Zabrouskov, V.; Coon, J. J.
Score: 25.8, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.568149</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging whole genome sequencing to promote genetic diversity and population health in zoo-housed western lowland gorillas
Authors: Gorzynski, J.; Danforth, M. D.; Strong, V.; Kutinsky, I.; Murphy, H.; Lowenstine, L.; Priest, J. R.; Ashley, E. A.
Score: 6.4, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.565567
The sustainability of zoo populations is dependent on maintaining genetic diversity and controlling heritable disease. Here, we explore the integration of whole genome sequencing data in the management of the international zoological population of western lowland gorillas, focusing on genetic diversity and heritable diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
