<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Behavioural changes in aposematic Heliconius melpomene butterflies in response to their predatory bird calls
Authors: Potdar, S.; Dinakar, M.; Westerman, E. L.
Score: 9.9, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563859
Prey-predator interactions have resulted in the evolution of many anti-predatory traits. One of them is the ability for prey to listen to predators and avoid them. Although prey anti-predatory behavioural responses to predator auditory cues are well described in a wide range of taxa, studies on whether butterflies change their behaviours in response to their predatory calls are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structure of the yeast ceramide synthase
Authors: Schäfer, J.-H.; Clausmeyer, L.; Körner, C.; Esch, B. M.; Wolf, V. N.; Walter, S.; Januliene, D.; Moeller, A.; Fröhlich, F.
Score: 17.4, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563787
Ceramides play a pivotal role as essential lipids, serving as foundational components for complex sphingolipids and potent signaling molecules. Ceramides are the products of the N-acylation of a sphingoid base and a CoA-activated fatty acid. This reaction is catalyzed by the enzymes of the evolutionarily conserved ceramide synthase (CerS) family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>EV-Elute: a universal platform for enrichment of functional surface marker-defined extracellular vesicle subpopulations
Authors: de Voogt, W. S.; Frunt, R.; Leandro, R. M.; Triesscheijn, C. S.; Monica, B.; Paspali, I.; Tielemans, M.; Francois, J. J.; Seinen, C. W.; de Jong, O. G.; Kooijmans, S. A.
Score: 11.6, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.563755
Intercellular communication via extracellular vesicles (EVs) has been identified as a vital component of a steadily expanding number of physiological and pathological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>OMICmAge: An integrative multi-omics approach to quantify biological age with electronic medical records
Authors: Chen, Q.; Dwaraka, V. B.; Carreras-Gallo, N.; Mendez, K.; Chen, Y.; Kachroo, P.; Prince, N.; Went, H.; Mendez, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Moqri, M.; Chu, S. H.; Kelly, R. S.; Weiss, S. T.; Rattray, N. J.; Gladyshev, V. N.; Karlson, E.; Wheelock, C.; Mathe, E. A.; Dahlin, A.; McGeachie, M. J.; Smith, R.; Lasky-Su, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Data-driven regularisation lowers the size barrier of cryo-EM structure determination
Authors: Kimanius, D.; Jamali, K.; Wilkinson, M. E.; Lövestam, S.; Velazhahan, V.; Nakane, T.; Scheres, S. H.
Score: 105.8, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563586
Macromolecular structure determination by electron cryo-microscopy (cryo-EM) is limited by the alignment of noisy images of individual particles. Because smaller particles have weaker signals, alignment errors impose size limitations on its applicability. Here, we explore how image alignment is improved by the application of deep-learning to exploit prior knowledge about biological macromolecular structures that would otherwise be difficult to express mathematically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Ataxia-telangiectasia mutated (Atm) disruption sensitizes spatially-directed H3.3K27M/TP53 diffuse midline gliomas to radiation therapy
Authors: Mangoli, A.; Wu, S.; Liu, H. Q.; Aksu, M.; Jain, V. J.; Foreman, B. E.; Regal, J. A.; Weidenhammer, L. B.; Stewart, C. E.; Guerra Garcia, M. E.; Hocke, E.; Abramson, K.; Williams, N. T.; Luo, L.; Deland, K.; Attardi, L.; Abe, K.; Hashizume, R.; Ashley, D. M.; Becher, O. J.; Kirsch, D. G.; Gregory, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>ChineseCVD: first-in-world, web-based, Chinese-specific Cardiovascular Risk Calculator incorporating long COVID, COVID-19 vaccination, SGLT2i and PCSK9i treatment effects
Authors: Chang, C.; Tse, G.; Lee, Q.; Chou, O. H. I.; Lee, T. T. L.; Leung, B. K.-h.; Ngai, A. L.; Khan, A.; Wong, W. T.; Wai, A. K. C.; Chen, K. Y.; Liu, T.; Zhou, J.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-10-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.23297656
Background: Web-based risk prediction tools for cardiovascular diseases are crucial for providing rapid risk estimates for busy clinicians, but there is none available specifically for Chinese subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Diatom pyrenoids are encased in a protein shell that enables efficient CO2 fixation
Authors: Shimakawa, G.; Demulder, M.; Flori, S.; Kawamoto, A.; Tsuji, Y.; Nawaly, H.; Tanaka, A.; Tohda, R.; Ota, T.; Matsui, H.; Morishima, N.; Okubo, R.; Wietrzynski, W.; Lamm, L.; Righetto, R. D.; Uwizeye, C.; Gallet, B.; Jouneau, P.-H.; Gerle, C.; Kurisu, G.; Finazzi, G.; Engel, B. D.; Matsuda, Y.
Score: 55.4, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.564039
Pyrenoids are subcompartments of algal chloroplasts that concentrate Rubisco enzymes and their CO2 substrate, thereby increasing the efficiency of carbon fixation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular basis for positional memory and its reprogrammability in limb regeneration
Authors: Otsuki, L.; Plattner, S. A.; Taniguchi-Sugiura, Y.; Tanaka, E. M.
Score: 60.7, Published: 2023-10-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.564423
Upon limb amputation in salamanders, anterior and posterior connective tissue cells form distinct signalling centres that together fuel successful regeneration. The molecular properties that distinguish anterior and posterior cells prior to injury, which enable them to initiate different signalling centres after amputation, are not known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Drab and distant birds are studied less than their fancy-feathered friends
Authors: Fischer, S. E.; Lindsay, A. M.; Otten, J. G.; Miles, D. B.; Streby, H. M.
Score: 96.2, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.560707
Human decisions are influenced by implicit biases, and scientists do not exist in an objectivity vacuum. Subconscious biases in scientists choices about which species to study may beget distorted knowledge bases and stagnant paradigms. Disparities in biological knowledge can result from bias in study species selection within a cycle of policymaking, funding, and publication, all subject to implicit biases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Threat awareness and counter-terrorism preparedness of Dutch hospitals: a cross-sectional survey
Authors: Barten, D.; Janssen, M.; De Cauwer, H.; Keereweer, D.; Tan, E.; van Osch, F.; Mortelmans, L.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2023-10-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.14.23297038
BackgroundWorkplace violence, including violent extremism, is a growing concern in the healthcare environment. Furthermore, there has been a disproportionate rise in the rate of terrorist attacks on hospitals during the past two decades. Hospitals are vulnerable targets due to their easy accessibility and their high density of patients, staff and visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of Stroke Risk Following COVID-19 mRNA Bivalent Vaccines Among U.S. Adults Aged &amp;gt;=65 Years
Authors: Lu, Y.; Matuska, K.; Nadimpalli, G.; Ma, Y.; Duma, N.; Zhang, H.; Chiang, Y.; Lyu, H.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R. A.; Anderson, S. A.
Score: 1098.5, Published: 2023-10-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296624
In January 2023, the United States Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention noted a safety concern for ischemic stroke in adults [&amp;amp;ge;]65 years receiving the BNT162b2; WT/OMI BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A systematic screen for co-option of transposable elements across the fungal kingdom
Authors: Oggenfuss, U.; Badet, T.; Croll, D.
Score: 39.9, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.563377
How novel protein functions are acquired is a central question in molecular biology. Key paths to novelty include gene duplications, recombination or horizontal acquisition. Transposable elements (TEs) are increasingly recognized as a major source of novel domain-encoding sequences. However, the impact of TE coding sequences on the evolution of the proteome remains understudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Microbiome-based risk prediction in incident heart failure: a community challenge
Authors: Erawijantari, P. P.; Kartal, E.; Linares-Blanco, J.; Laajala, T. D.; Feldman, L. E.; The FINRISK Microbiome DREAM Challenge and ML4Microbiome Communities, ; Carmona-Saez, P.; Shigdel, R.; Claesson, M. J.; Bertelsen, R. J.; Gomez-Cabrero, D.; Minot, S.; Albrecht, J.; Chung, V.; Inouye, M.; Jousilahti, P.; Schultz, J.-H.; Friederich, H.-C.; Knight, R.; Salomaa, V.; Niiranen, T.; Havulinna, A. S.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Prospective analysis of incident disease among individuals of diverse ancestries using genetic and conventional risk factors
Authors: Wang, W.; Eriksson, N.; McIntyre, M.; Bagur Quetglas, R.; Koelsch, B. L.; Hinds, D. A.; Aslibekyan, S.; Auton, A.; Holmes, M. V.; Shringarpure, S. S.
Score: 35.3, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.23297414
BackgroundHuman genetics provides opportunities for enhancing disease prediction through polygenic risk scores (PRS). MethodWe used a dataset from 23andMe (6.77M European, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Transcription factor stoichiometry, motif affinity and syntax regulate single-cell chromatin dynamics during fibroblast reprogramming to pluripotency
Authors: Nair, S.; Ameen, M.; Sundaram, L.; Pampari, A.; Schreiber, J.; Balsubramani, A.; Wang, Y. X.; Burns, D.; Blau, H. M.; Karakikes, I.; Wang, K. C.; Kundaje, A.
Score: 37.7, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.560808
Ectopic expression of OCT4, SOX2, KLF4 and MYC (OSKM) transforms differentiated cells into induced pluripotent stem cells. To refine our mechanistic understanding of reprogramming, especially during the early stages, we profiled chromatin accessibility and gene expression at single-cell resolution across a densely sampled time course of human fibroblast reprogramming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Systematic identification of cargo-carrying genetic elements reveals new dimensions of eukaryotic diversity
Authors: Gluck-Thaler, E.; Vogan, A. A.
Score: 33.4, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563810
Cargo-carrying mobile elements (CCEs) are genetic entities that transpose diverse protein coding sequences. Although common in bacteria, we know little about the biology of eukaryotic CCEs because no appropriate tools exist for their annotation. For example, Starships are fungal CCEs whose functions are largely unknown because they require time-intensive manual curation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Toward AI-Guided Smoking Cessation: Individualized Nicotine Addiction Modeling Using Gaussian Processes
Authors: Chari, A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.23297563
Cigarette smoking remains the leading cause of preventable disease and death in the United States, accounting for nearly half a million deaths annually. Given the recent rise of artificial intelligence in healthcare applications, computational assessment of smoking behaviors is a promising direction. In this study, we aim to recognize and classify addiction patterns in individual smokers daily usage based on time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Who would be affected by a ban on disposable vapes? A population study in Great Britain
Authors: Jackson, S. E.; Tattan-Birch, H. O.; Shahab, L.; Oldham, M.; Kale, D.; Brose, L.; Brown, J.
Score: 22.4, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.23297396
ObjectivesThe UK government is consulting on banning disposable e-cigarettes. This study aimed to describe trends in disposable e-cigarette use among adults in Great Britain since 2021 and establish who would currently be affected by a ban on disposables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the landscape: A protocol for a jurisdictional scan of self-identified learning health systems
Authors: Vanderhout, S.; Bird, M.; Giannarakos, A.; Whitmore, C.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.23297605
BackgroundThere is a growing movement to implement learning health systems (LHS), in which real-time evidence, informatics, patient-provider partnerships and experiences, and organizational culture are aligned to support improvements in care. However, what constitutes a LHS varies based on context and capacity, hindering standardization, scale-up, and knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Heterotypic responses against nsp12/nsp13 from prior SARS-CoV-2 infection associates with lower subsequent endemic coronavirus incidence
Authors: Bean, D. J.; Monroe, J.; Liang, Y. M.; Borberg, E.; Senussi, Y.; Swank, Z.; Chalise, S.; Walt, D.; Weinberg, J.; Sagar, M.
Score: 143.7, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563621
Immune responses from prior SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 vaccination do not prevent re-infections and may not protect against future novel coronaviruses (CoVs). We examined the incidence of and immune differences against human endemic CoVs (eCoV) as a proxy for response against future emerging CoVs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Swank, Z. N.; Goldberg, S. A.; Lu, S.; Dalhuisen, T.; Borberg, E.; Senussi, Y.; Luna, M. A.; Chang Song, C.; Clark, A.; Zamora, A.; Lew, M.; Viswanathan, B.; Huang, B.; Anglin, K.; Hoh, R.; Hsue, P. Y.; Durstenfeld, M. S.; Spinelli, M. A.; Glidden, D. V.; Henrich, T. J.; Kelly, J. D.; Deeks, S. G.; Walt, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Lifecycle of a predatory bacterium vampirizing its prey through the cell envelope and S-layer
Authors: Santin, Y. G.; Sogues, A.; Bourigault, Y.; Remaut, H. K.; Laloux, G.
Score: 61.1, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.563945
Predatory bacteria feed upon and kill other bacteria in various natural environments. Obligate epibiotic predators like Bdellovibrio exovorus consume their prey whilst remaining attached to the outside of the prey. How these predators achieve epibiotic feeding through the prey cell envelope has not been explored previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>ATAC and SAGA histone acetyltransferase modules facilitate transcription factor binding to nucleosomes in an acetylation independent manner
Authors: Chesnutt, K.; Yayli, G.; Toelzer, C.; Cox, K.; Gautam, G.; Berger, I.; Tora, L.; Poirier, M. G.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.564358
Transcription initiation involves the coordination of multiple events, starting with activators binding specific DNA target sequences, which recruits transcription co-activators to open chromatin and enable binding of general transcription factors and RNA polymerase II to promoters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Peripheral Transcriptomics in Acute and Long-Term Kidney Dysfunction in SARS-CoV2 Infection
Authors: Jayaraman, P.; Rajagopal, M.; Paranjpe, I.; Liharska, L.; Suarez-Farinas, M.; Thompson, R.; Del Valle, D. M.; Beckmann, N.; Oh, W.; Gulamali, F. F.; Kauffman, J.; Gonzalez-Kozlova, E.; Dellepiane, S.; Vasquez-Rios, G.; Vaid, A.; Jiang, J.; Chen, A.; Sakhuja, A.; Chen, S.; Kenigsberg, E.; He, J. C.; Coca, S. G.; Chan, L.; Schadt, E.; Merad, M.; Kim-Schulze, S.; Gnjatic, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>An efficient design for whole genome trio sequencing identifies key variants in rare neurological disorder cases
Authors: Ramsey, K.; Kruglyak, S.; Naymik, M.; Lajoie, B. R.; Wiseman, K. N.; Sanchez-Castillo, M.; Billings, S.; Jepsen, W.; Huentelman, M.; Narayanan, V.
Score: 522.2, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23296768
We sequenced nine trios in which the probands in an underserved population were affected by a rare and undiagnosed disorder with neurological features. Sequencing was performed with one trio per flowcell on a benchtop sequencing instrument, leveraging the design of sequencing the proband at twice the coverage of the parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuroinflammation in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) as assessed by PBR28 PET correlates with vascular disease measures
Authors: VanElzakker, M. B.; Bues, H. F.; Brusaferri, L.; Kim, M.; Saadi, D.; Ratai, E.-M.; Dougherty, D. D.; Loggia, M. L.
Score: 1054.7, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563117
The COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has triggered a consequential public health crisis of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC), sometimes referred to as long COVID. The mechanisms of the heterogeneous persistent symptoms and signs that comprise PASC are under investigation, and several studies have pointed to the central nervous and vascular systems as being potential sites of dysfunction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Low Booster uptake in cancer patients despite health benefits
Authors: Figueiredo, J. C.; Levy, J. A.; Choi, S. Y.; Xu, A. M.; Merin, N. M.; Hamid, O.; Lemos, T.; Nguyen, N.; Nadri, M.; Gonzalez, A.; Mahov, S.; Darrah, J. M.; Gong, J.; Paquette, R. L.; Mita, A. C.; Vescio, R. A.; Salvy, S. J.; Mehmi, I.; Hendifar, A. E.; Natale, R. B.; Tourtellotte, W. G.; Ramanujan, V. K.; Huynh, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Regular Non-steroidal Anti-inflammatory Drug Use Increases Stress Fracture Risk in the General Population: A Retrospective Case-Control Study
Authors: Ciuciu, A.; Mulholland, C.; Bozzi, M. A.; Frymoyer, C. C.; Cavinatto, L.; Yaron, D.; Harwood, M. I.; Close, J. D.; Mehallo, C. J.; Tomlinson, R. E.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-10-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.23297788
Previous studies have shown that the use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) is associated with increased stress fracture risk, potentially due to diminished skeletal adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Platelet proteo-transcriptomic profiling validates mediators of thrombosis and proteostasis in patients with myeloproliferative neoplasms
Authors: Kelliher, S.; Gamba, S.; Weiss, L.; Shen, Z.; Marchetti, M.; Schieppati, F.; Scaife, C.; Madden, S.; Bennett, K.; Fortune, A.; Maung, S.; Fay, M.; Ni Ainle, F.; Maguire, P.; Falanga, A.; Kevane, B.; Krishnan, A.
Score: 3.7, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563619
Patients with chronic Myeloproliferative Neoplasms (MPN) including polycythemia vera (PV) and essential thrombocythemia (ET) exhibit unique clinical features, such as a tendency toward thrombosis and hemorrhage, and risk of disease progression to secondary bone marrow fibrosis and/or acute leukemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Targeting cancer with small molecule pan-KRAS degraders
Authors: Popow, J.; Farnaby, W.; Gollner, A.; Kofink, C.; Fischer, G.; Wurm, M.; Zollman, D.; Wijaya, A.; Mischerikow, N.; Hasenoehrl, C.; Prokofeva, P.; Arnhof, H.; Arce-Solano, S.; Bell, S.; Boeck, G.; Diers, E.; Frost, A. B.; Goodwin-Tindall, J.; Karolyi-Oezguer, J.; Khan, S.; Klawatsch, T.; Koegl, M.; Kousek, R.; Kratochvil, B.; Kropatsch, K.; Lauber, A. A.; McLennan, R.; Olt, S.; Peter, D.; Petermann, O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Intrinsic properties of spinal motoneurons degrade ankle torque control in humans
Authors: Beauchamp, J. A.; Pearcey, G. E. P.; Khurram, O. U.; Negro, F.; Dewald, J. P. A.; Heckman, C.
Score: 7.6, Published: 2023-10-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563670
Motoneurons are the final common pathway for all motor commands and possess intrinsic electrical properties that must be tuned to control muscle across the full range of motor behaviors. Neuromodulatory input from the brainstem is likely essential for adapting motoneuron properties to match this diversity of motor tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The Marchantia pangenome reveals ancient mechanisms of plant adaptation to the environment
Authors: Beaulieu, C.; Libourel, C.; Mbadinga Zamar, D.-L.; El Mahboubi, K.; Hoey, D. J.; Keller, J.; Girou, C.; San Clemente, H.; Diop, I.; Amblard, E.; Theron, A.; Cauet, S.; Rodde, N.; Sabine, Z.; Halpape, W.; Meierhenrich, A.; Laker, B.; Braeutigam, A.; Greiff, G. R. L.; The SLCU Outreach Consortium, ; Szovenyi, P.; Cheng, S.; Tanizawa, Y.; Leebens-Mack, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Rumination Induction Task in fMRI: Test-Retest Reliability in Youth and Potential Mechanisms of Change with Intervention
Authors: Westlund Schreiner, M.; Miller, R. H.; Jacobsen, A. M.; Crowell, S. E.; Kaufman, E. A.; Farstead, B.; Feldman, D. A.; Thomas, L.; Bessette, K. L.; Welsh, R. C.; Watkins, E. R.; Langenecker, S. A.
Score: 23.2, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296759
BackgroundRumination is a transdiagnostic problem that is common in major depressive disorder (MDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Reduced risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection among household contacts with recent vaccination and past COVID-19 infection: results from two multi-site case-ascertained household transmission studies
Authors: Rolfes, M. A.; Talbot, H. K.; Morrissey, K. G.; Stockwell, M. S.; Maldonado, Y.; McLean, H. Q.; Lutrick, K.; Bowman, N. M.; Rao, S.; Izurieta, H. S.; Zhu, Y.; Chappell, J.; Battan-Wraith, S.; Merrill, L. S.; McLaren, S. H.; Sano, E.; Biddle, J. E.; Johnson, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Parental education and income are linked to offspring cortical brain structure and psychopathology at 9-11 years
Authors: Norbom, L. B.; Rokicki, J.; Eilertsen, E. M.; Wiker, T.; Hanson, J.; Dahl, A.; Alnaes, D.; Fernandez-Cabello, S.; Beck, D.; Agartz, I.; Andreassen, O. A.; Westlye, L. T.; Tamnes, C. K.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.02.16.23286027
BackgroundA childs socioeconomic environment can shape central aspects of their life, including vulnerability to mental disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Performance of next-generation molecular methods in the diagnosis of pleural space infections and their aetiology
Authors: Bell, P. T.; Baird, T.; Goddard, J.; Olagoke, O. S.; Burke, A.; Subedi, S.; Davey, T. R.; Anderson, J.; Sarovich, D. S.; Price, E. P.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.23297281
Pleural space infections (PSIs) are common and associated with substantial healthcare cost, morbidity, and mortality. Accurate PSI diagnosis remains challenging due to low culture positivity rates, frequent polymicrobial involvement, and non-specific diagnostic biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Women&amp;#39;s representation in Indian academia and conferences
Authors: Muralidhar, S.; Ananthanarayanan, V.
Score: 60.5, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564078
Abstract/IntroductionIndian science academia has a dearth of women researchers at all levels. Not only are they under-represented, but they are also under-highlighted, under-mentored and overlooked for awards, grants and other career-advancing steps. To effectively address this problem and devise a solution for the inequity, we need data on the proportion of women faculty across multiple STEM institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Tuning and minimizing lipidome composition in Mycoplasma mycoides and the Minimal Cell JCVI-Syn3A
Authors: Justice, I. G.; Saenz, J. P.
Score: 28.9, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563757
All cells are encapsulated by a lipid membrane which facilitates the interaction between life and its environment. The property and function of the cell membrane is critically dependent on its lipidome composition which can range from 10s to 100s of unique lipid structures. How life has evolved to exploit such diverse mixtures of lipids has been experimentally challenging to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>DrugMap: A quantitative pan-cancer analysis of cysteine ligandability
Authors: Takahashi, M.; Chong, H. B.; Zhang, S.; Lazarov, M.; Harry, S.; Maynard, M.; White, R.; Hilbert, B.; Gohar, M.; Ge, M.; Zhang, J.; Durr, B. R.; Kryukov, G.; Tsou, C.-C.; Brooijmans, N.; Alghali, A.; Rubio, K.; Vilanueva, A.; Harrison, D.; Koglin, A.-S.; Ojeda, S.; Karakyriakou, B.; Healy, A.; Assaad, J.; Makram, F.; Rachimin, I.; Khandelwal, N.; Tien, P.-C.; Popoola, G.; Chen, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Ticks without borders: Microbial communities of immature Neotropical tick species parasitizing migratory landbirds along northern Gulf of Mexico
Authors: Karim, S.; Zenzal, T. J.; Beati, L.; Sen, R.; Adegoke, A.; Kumar, D.; Downs, L.; Keko, M.; Nussbaum, A.; Becker, D.; Moore, F.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.563347
The long-distance, seasonal migrations of birds make them an effective ecological bridge for the movement of ticks. The introduction of exotic tick species to new geographical regions can lead to the emergence of novel tick-borne pathogens or the re-emergence of previously eradicated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
