<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Identifying novel gene dysregulation associated with opioid overdose death: A meta-analysis of differential gene expression in human prefrontal cortex
Authors: Carter, J. K.; Quach, B. C.; Willis, C.; Minto, M. S.; PGC SUD Epigenetics Working Group, ; Hancock, D. B.; Montalvo-Ortiz, J. L.; Corradin, O.; Logan, R. W.; Walss Bass, C.; Maher, B.; Johnson, E. O.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301153
Only recently have human postmortem brain studies of differential gene expression (DGE) associated with opioid overdose death (OOD) been published; sample sizes from these studies have been modest (N = 40-153).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the autoreactome: Proteome-wide immunological fingerprints reveal the promise of plasma cell depleting therapy
Authors: Bodansky, A.; Yu, D. J.; Rallistan, A.; Kalaycioglu, M.; Boonyaratanakornkit, J.; Green, D. J.; Gauthier, J.; Turtle, C. J.; Zorn, K.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, B.; Mandel-Brehm, C.; Asaki, J.; Kortbawi, H.; Kung, A. F.; Rackaityte, E.; Wang, C.-Y.; Saxena, A.; de Dios, K.; Masi, G.; Nowak, R. J.; O&amp;#39;Connor, K. C.; Li, H.; Diaz, V. E.; Casaletto, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Rapid body colouration change in Oryzias celebensisas a social signal for intraspecific competition
Authors: Ueda, R.; Ansai, S.; Takeuchi, H.
Score: 26.8, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.23.573172
In some species, such as chameleon and cichlid fish, rapid body colouration changes (within seconds or minutes) serve as visual social signals in male-male competition. This study investigated the relationship between aggressive behaviour and body colouration changes in Oryzias celebensis, an Indonesian medaka fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Human coronavirus HKU1 recognition of the TMPRSS2 host receptor
Authors: McCallum, M.; Park, Y.-J.; Stewart, C.; Sprouse, K. R.; Brown, J.; Tortorici, M. A.; Gibson, C.; Wong, E.; Ieven, M.; Telenti, A.; Veesler, D.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.574565
The human coronavirus HKU1 spike (S) glycoprotein engages host cell surface sialoglycans and transmembrane protease serine 2 (TMPRSS2) to initiate infection. The molecular basis of HKU1 binding to TMPRSS2 and determinants of host receptor tropism remain elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Saponin Nanoparticle Adjuvants Incorporating Toll-Like Receptor Agonists Improve Vaccine Immunomodulation
Authors: Ou, B. S.; Baillet, J.; Filsinger Interrante, M. V.; Adamska, J. Z.; Zhou, X.; Saouaf, O.; Yan, J.; Klich, J.; Jons, C. K.; Meany, E.; Valdez, A. S.; Carter, L.; Pulendran, B.; King, N. P.; Appel, E.
Score: 147.8, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.16.549249
Over the past few decades, the development of potent and safe immune-activating adjuvant technologies has become the heart of intensive research in the constant fight against highly mutative and immune evasive viruses such as influenza, SARS-CoV-2, and HIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>The Scalable Variant Call Representation: Enabling Genetic Analysis Beyond One Million Genomes
Authors: Poterba, T.; Vittal, C.; King, D.; Goldstein, D.; Goldstein, J.; Schultz, P.; Karczewski, K.; Seed, C.; Neale, B.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2024-01-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.574205
The Variant Call Format (VCF) is widely used in genome sequencing but scales poorly. For instance, we estimate a 150,000 genome VCF would occupy 900 TiB, making it both costly and complicated to produce and analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>High-throughput analysis of membrane fluidity unveils a hidden dimension in immune cell states
Authors: Andronico, L. A.; Jiang, Y.; Carannante, V.; Iskrak, S.; Sandoz, P. A.; Mikes, J.; Klymchenko, A. S.; Buggert, M.; Osterborg, A.; Onfelt, B.; Brodin, P.; Sezgin, E.
Score: 27.1, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575649
Cell membranes undergo biophysical remodelling as an adaptation to the surroundings and to perform specific biological functions. However, the extent and relevance of such changes in human immune systems remain unknown, largely due to the lack of high throughput and multidimensional methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Direct excitatory synapses between neurons and tumor cells drive brain metastatic seeding of breast cancer and melanoma
Authors: Venkataramani, V.; Karreman, M. A.; Nguyen, L. C.; Tehranian, C.; Hebach, N.; Mayer, C.; Meyer, L.; Mughal, S.; Reifenberger, G.; Felsberg, J.; Koehrer, K.; Schubert, M. C.; Westphal, D.; Breckwolt, M.; Brors, B.; Wick, W.; Kuner, T.; Winkler, F.
Score: 145.5, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574608
Interactions between neurons and cancer cells are found in many malignancies, but their relevance for metastatic organ colonization remain largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Interpretable Machine Learning Leverages Proteomics to Improve Cardiovascular Disease Risk Prediction and Biomarker Identification
Authors: Climente-Gonzalez, H.; Oh, M.; Chajewska, U.; Hosseini, R.; Mukherjee, S.; Gan, W.; Traylor, M.; Hu, S.; Fatemifar, G.; Del Villar, P. P.; Vernet, E.; Koelling, N.; Du, L.; Abraham, R.; Li, C.; Howson, J. M. M.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301213
Cardiovascular diseases (CVD), primarily coronary heart disease and stroke, rank amongst the leading causes of long-term disability and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Measuring and modeling the dynamics of mitotic error correction
Authors: Ha, G.; Dieterle, P.; Shen, H.; Amir, A.; Needleman, D. J.
Score: 13.0, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.574250
When functioning properly, the mitotic spindle segregates an equal number of chromosomes to daughter cells with high fidelity. Over the course of spindle assembly, many initially erroneous attachments between kinetochores and microtubules are fixed through a process called error correction. Despite the importance of chromosome segregation errors in cancer and other diseases, there is a lack of methods to characterize the dynamics of error correction and how it can go wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic priming of embryonic lineages in the mammalian epiblast
Authors: Sendra, M.; McDole, K.; Jimenez-Carretero, D.; de Dios-Hourcade, J.; Temino Valbuena, S.; Raiola, M.; Guignard, L.; Keller, P. J.; Sanchez-Cabo, F.; Dominguez, J. N.; Torres, M.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575188
Understanding the diversification of mammalian cell lineages is an essential to embryonic development, organ regeneration and tissue engineering. Shortly after implantation in the uterus, the pluripotent cells of the mammalian epiblast generate the three germ layers: ectoderm, mesoderm and endoderm1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Pervasive sublethal effects of agrochemicals as contributing factors to insect decline
Authors: Gandara, L.; Jacoby, R.; Laurent, F.; Spatuzzi, M.; Vlachopoulos, N.; Borst, N. O.; Ekmen, G.; Potel, C. M.; Garrido-Rodriguez, M.; Boehmert, A. L.; Misunou, N.; Bartmanski, B. J.; Li, X. C.; Kutra, D.; Heriche, J.-K.; Tischer, C.; Zimmermann-Kogadeeva, M.; Ingham, V. A.; Savitski, M.; Masson, J.-B.; Zimmermann, M.; Crocker, J.
Score: 28.3, Published: 2024-01-14 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575373
Insect biomass is declining across the globe at an alarming rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 74.6, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Estimated number of lives directly saved by COVID-19 vaccination programs in the WHO European Region, December 2020 to March 2023
Authors: Mesle, M. M.; Brown, J.; Mook, P.; Katz, M. A.; Hagan, J.; Pastore, R.; Nitzan, D.; Benka, B.; Redlberger-Fritz, M.; Bossuyt, N.; Stouten, V.; Vernemmen, C.; Constantinou, E.; Kyncl, J.; Maly, M.; Sanca, O.; Grove Krause, T.; Skafte Vestergaard, L.; Leino, T.; Poukka, E.; Gkolfinopoulou, K.; Mellou, K.; Maria Tsintziloni, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reproductive innovation enabled radiation in the deep sea during an ecological crisis
Authors: Brownstein, C.; Zapfe, K.; Lott, S.; Harrington, R. C.; Ghezelayagh, A.; Dornburg, A.; Near, T. J.
Score: 96.3, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575380
Major ecological transitions are thought to fuel evolutionary radiations, but whether they are contingent on the evolution of certain traits is unclear. We show that the rapid ecological transition of anglerfishes into pelagic habitats during a period of major global warming coincided with the origins of sexual parasitism, in which male anglerfishes temporarily attach or permanently fuse to females to mate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Impact of genome build on RNA-seq interpretation and diagnostics
Authors: Ungar, R. A.; Goddard, P. C.; Jensen, T. D.; Degalez, F.; Smith, K. S.; Jin, C. A.; Undiagnosed Diseases Network, ; Bonner, D. E.; Bernstein, J. A.; Wheeler, M. T.; Montgomery, S. B.
Score: 33.4, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.24301165
Transcriptomics is a powerful tool for unraveling the molecular effects of genetic variants and disease diagnosis. Prior studies have demonstrated that choice of genome build impacts variant interpretation and diagnostic yield for genomic analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Associations between common genetic variants and income provide insights about the socioeconomic health gradient
Authors: Kweon, H.; Burik, C. A. P.; Ning, Y.; Ahlskog, R.; Xia, C.; Abner, E.; Bao, Y.; Bhatta, L.; Faquih, T.; Feijter, M.; Fisher, P.; Gelemanovic, A.; Giannelis, A.; Hottenga, J.-J.; Khalili, B.; Lee, Y.; Li-Gao, R.; Masso, J.; Myhre, R.; Palviainen, T.; Rietveld, C. A. P.; Teumer, A.; Verweij, R. M.; Willoughby, E. A.; Agerbo, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Comparative analysis of multiplexed in situ gene expression profiling technologies
Authors: Hartman, A.; Satija, R.
Score: 104.1, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575135
The burgeoning interest in in situ multiplexed gene expression profiling technologies has opened new avenues for understanding cellular behavior and interactions. In this study, we present a comparative benchmark analysis of six in situ gene expression profiling methods, including both commercially available and academically developed methods, using publicly accessible mouse brain datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Development and Validation of an Intrinsic Capacity Score in the UK Biobank Study
Authors: Beyene, M. B.; Visvanathan, R.; Ahmed, M.; Benyamin, B.; Beard, J. R.; Amare, A. T.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2024-01-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.24301076
BackgroundIn 2015, the World Health Organization introduced the concept of intrinsic capacity (IC) to define the individual-level characteristics that enable an older person to be and do the things they value. This study developed an IC score for UK Biobank (UKB) study participants and validated its use as a tool for health outcome prediction, understanding healthy aging trajectories, and genetic research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>The molecular landscape of premature aging diseases defined by multilayer network exploration
Authors: Beust, C.; Valdeolivas, A.; Baptista, A.; Briere, G.; Levy, N.; Ozisik, O.; Baudot, A.
Score: 8.6, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.23300210
Premature Aging (PA) diseases are rare genetic disorders that mimic some aspects of physiological aging at an early age. Various causative genes of PA diseases have been identified in recent years, providing insights into some dysfunctional cellular functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Network Modelling for the Clinical Diagnosis of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Bate St Cliere, A.-R.; Fenton, N.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300452
Alzheimers disease (AD) is a progressively debilitating disease commonly affecting the elderly. Correct diagnosis is important for patients to access suitable therapies and support that can help improve or manage symptoms of the condition. Reports of misdiagnosis and difficulty diagnosing AD highlight existing clinical challenges. Here we propose a Bayesian network as a preliminary model for a complementary clinical diagnostic tool for dementia due to AD and mild cognitive impairment due to AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Calling for diversity: improving transfusion safety through high-throughput blood group microarray genotyping
Authors: Wittig, M.; Steiert, T. A.; ElAbd, H.; Degenhardt, F.; Valenti, L.; Prati, D.; Ronzoni, L.; Bujanda, L.; Banales, J. M.; Blay, N.; Invernizzi, P.; Buti, M.; Albillos, A.; Fernandez, J.; Sacchi, N.; Julia, A.; Latiano, A.; de Cid, R.; D&amp;#39;Amato, M.; Asselta, R.; Laudes, M.; Lieb, W.; Juhl, D.; Gassner, C.; Franke, A.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Emergent Dolutegravir Resistance Mutations In People Living With HIV: A Rapid Scoping Review
Authors: Chu, C.; Tao, K.; Kouamou, V.; Avalos, A.; Scott, J.; Grant, P. M.; Rhee, S.-Y.; McCluskey, S. M.; Jordan, M. R.; Morgan, R. L.; Shafer, R. W.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2024-01-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.24300911
BackgroundDolutegravir (DTG) is a cornerstone of global antiretroviral (ARV) therapy (ART) due to its high efficacy and favorable tolerability. However, limited data exist regarding the risk of virological failure (VF) with emergent integrase strand transfer inhibitor (INSTI) drug-resistance mutations (DRMs) in individuals receiving DTG-containing ART.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Humoral immune responses to the monovalent XBB.1.5-adapted BNT162b2 mRNA booster
Authors: Marking, U.; Bladh, O.; Aguilera, K.; Yang, Y.; Greilert-Norin, N.; Blom, K.; Hober, S.; Klingstrom, J.; Havervall, S.; Aberg, M.; Sheward, D. J.; Thalin, C.
Score: 99.4, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.572575
Continued SARS-CoV-2 evolution and immune escape necessitated the development of updated vaccines, and a monovalent vaccine incorporating the XBB.1.5 variant spike protein is currently being rolled out. Amidst the emergence of the highly mutated BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Immunological imprinting shapes the specificity of human antibody responses against SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Johnston, T. S.; Li, S. H.; Painter, M. M.; Atkinson, R. K.; Douek, N. R.; Reeg, D. B.; Doueck, D. C.; Wherry, E. J.; Hensley, S. E.
Score: 84.2, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24301002
The spike glycoprotein of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) continues to accumulate substitutions, leading to breakthrough infections of vaccinated individuals and prompting the development of updated booster vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Self-perceived competence and its determinants among pre-intern (PRINT) doctors in Uganda
Authors: Ssewante, N.; Wekha, G.; Nalunkuma, R.; Sentongo, L. K.; Sanyu, B.; Namusoke, M.; Nkwanga, A.; Ahabwe, R.; Nantagya, V. N.; Kalembe, S. E.; Nampeera, C.; Musoke, P.; Kibwika, P. B.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301259
Introduction: Uganda still survives way below the recommended doctor-patient ratio. This problem could be solved by increasing the number of doctors produced in the country annually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Lethal Infection of Human ACE2-Transgenic Mice Caused by SARS-CoV-2-related Pangolin Coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 2492.3, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) can cause 100% mortality in human ACE2-transgenic mice, potentially attributable to late-stage brain infection. This underscores a spillover risk of GX_P2V into humans and provides a unique model for understanding the pathogenic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2-related viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Brain and cancer associated binding domain mutations provide insight into CTCF&amp;#39;s relationship with chromatin and its ability to act as a chromatin organizer
Authors: Do, C.; Jiang, G.; Katsifis, C. C.; Narducci, D. N.; Yang, J.; Cova, G.; Sakellaropoulos, T.; Vidal, R.; Lhoumaud, P.; Fara Regis, F.; Kakabadze, N.; Nora, E. P.; Noyes, M.; Chen, X.; Hansen, A. S.; Skok, J. A.
Score: 17.4, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575070
Although only a fraction of CTCF motifs are bound in any cell type, and few occupied sites overlap cohesin, the mechanisms underlying cell-type specific attachment and ability to function as a chromatin organizer remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease biological PET staging using plasma p217&amp;#43;tau
Authors: Feizpour, A.; Dore, V.; Krishnadas, N.; Bourgeat, P.; Doecke, J. D.; Saad, Z.; Triana-Baltzer, G.; Laws, S. M.; Shishegar, R.; Huang, K.; Fowler, C.; Ward, L.; Masters, C. L.; Mejan-Fripp, J.; Kolb, H. C.; Villemagne, V. L.; Rowe, C. C.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.24301180
BackgroundPlasma phospho-tau biomarkers, such as p217&amp;#43;tau, excel at identifying Alzheimers Disease (AD) neuropathology. However, questions remain regarding their capacity to inform AD biological PET stages at group level and maintain the same precision at individual patient level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 papain-like protease activates nociceptors to drive sneeze and pain
Authors: Mali, S. S.; Silva, R.; Gong, Z.; Cronce, M.; Vo, U.; Vuong, C.; Moayedi, Y.; Cox, J. S.; Bautista, D. M.
Score: 51.7, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.575114
SARS-CoV-2, the virus responsible for COVID-19, triggers symptoms such as sneezing, aches and pain.1 These symptoms are mediated by a subset of sensory neurons, known as nociceptors, that detect noxious stimuli, densely innervate the airway epithelium, and interact with airway resident epithelial and immune cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 163.9, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Obesity shapes selection for driver mutations in cancer
Authors: Tang, C.; Castillon, V. J.; Waters, M.; Fong, C.; Park, T.; Boscenco, S.; Kim, S.; Schultz, N.; Ostrovnaya, I.; Gusev, A.; Jee, J.; Reznik, E.
Score: 11.2, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.24301114
Obesity is a leading risk factor for cancer, but whether obesity is linked to specific genomic subtypes of cancer is unknown. Here, we examined the relationship between obesity and tumor genotype in two large clinicogenomic corpora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Innate Immune Activation and Mitochondrial ROS Invoke Persistent Cardiac Conduction System Dysfunction after COVID-19
Authors: Ashok, D.; Liu, T.; Criscione, J.; Prakash, M.; Kim, B.; Chow, J.; Craney, M.; Papanicolaou, K.; Sidor, A.; Foster, D. B.; Pekosz, A.; Villano, J.; Kim, D.-H.; O&amp;#39;Rourke, B.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574280
BackgroundCardiac risk rises during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and in long COVID syndrome in humans, but the mechanisms behind COVID-19-linked arrhythmias are unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Limited Research Investigating the Added Value of MRI in Predicting Future Cognitive Morbidity in Survivors of Paediatric Brain Tumours: A Call to Action for Clinical Neuroimaging Researchers
Authors: Griffiths-King, D. J.; Delivett, C.; Peet, A.; Waite, J.; Novak, J.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301212
Survivors of pediatric brain tumour patients are at high risk of cognitive morbidity. There is clinical benefit in being able to reliably predict, at the individual patient level, whether a patient will experience these difficulties or not, the degree of impairment, and the domains affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>AlphaFold2 structures template ligand discovery
Authors: Lyu, J.; Kapolka, N.; Gumpper, R.; Alon, A.; Wang, L.; Jain, M.; Alvarez, X.; Sakamoto, K.; Kim, Y.; DiBerto, J.; Kim, K.; Tummino, T.; Huang, S.; Irwin, J.; Tarkhanova, O.; Moroz, Y.; Skiniotis, G.; Kruse, A.; Shoichet, B.; Roth, B.
Score: 84.6, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572662
AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RosettaFold have greatly expanded the number of structures available for structure-based ligand discovery, even though retrospective studies have cast doubt on their direct usefulness for that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>TRPV4 is expressed by enteric glia and muscularis macrophages of the colon but does not play a prominent role in colonic motility
Authors: Rajasekhar, P.; Carbone, S. E.; Johnston, S. T.; Nowell, C. J.; Wiklendt, L.; Crampin, E. J.; She, Y.; DiCello, J. J.; Saito, A.; Sorensen, L.; Nguyen, T.; Lee, K. M.; Hamilton, J. A.; King, S. K.; Eriksson, E. M.; Spencer, N. J.; Gulbransen, B. D.; Veldhuis, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>An oomycete effector co-opts a host RabGAP protein to remodel pathogen interface and subvert defense-related secretion
Authors: Yuen, E. L. H.; Tumtas, Y.; Chan, L. I.; Ibrahim, T.; Evangelisti, E.; Tulin, F.; Sklenar, J.; Menke, F.; Kamoun, S.; Bubeck, D.; Schornack, S.; Bozkurt, T. O.
Score: 22.5, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575225
Pathogens have evolved sophisticated mechanisms to manipulate host cell membrane dynamics, a crucial adaptation to survive in hostile environments shaped by innate immune responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>The antidepressant effects of vaporized N,N-Dimethyltryptamine: a preliminary report in treatment-resistant depression
Authors: Falchi-Carvalho, M.; Barros, H.; Bolcont, R.; Laborde, S.; Wiessner, I.; Silva, S. R. B.; Montanini, D.; Barbosa, D.; Teixeira, E.; Florence-Vilela, R.; Almeida, R.; Macedo, R. K. A.; Arichelle, F.; J. Pantrigo, E.; Arcoverde, E.; Galvao-Coelho, N.; Araujo, D. B.; Palhano-Fontes, F.
Score: 11.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.23300610
IntroductionN,N-Dimethyltryptamine (DMT), a naturally occurring psychedelic tryptamine contained in the indigenous ayahuasca brew has shown antidepressant effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Barriers to healthcare access: findings from a co-produced Long Covid case-finding study
Authors: Clutterbuck, D.; Ramasawmy, M.; Pantelic, M.; Hayer, J.; Begum, F.; Faghy, M.; Nasir, N.; Causer, B.; Heightman, M.; Allsopp, G.; Wootton, D.; Khan, M. A.; Hastie, C.; Jackson, M.; Rayner, C.; Brown, D.; Parrett, E.; Jones, G.; Clarke, R.; Mcfarland, S.; Gabbay, M.; Banerjee, A.; Alwan, N. A.; STIMULATE-ICP Consortium, Score: 101.8, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300767</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Performance of Multimodal ChatGPT-4 on an image based Radiology Board-style Examination: An exploratory study
Authors: Bera, K.; Gupta, A.; Jiang, S.; Berlin, S.; Faraji, N.; Tippareddy, C.; Chiong, I.; Jones, R.; Nemer, O.; Nayate, A.; Tirumani, S. H.; Ramaiya, N.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301222
ObjectiveTo evaluate the performance of multimodal ChatGPT 4 on a radiology board-style examination containing text and radiologic images.s Materials and MethodsIn this prospective exploratory study from October 30 to December 10, 2023, 110 multiple-choice questions containing images designed to match the style and content of radiology board examination like the American Board of Radiology Core or Canadian Board of Radiology examination were prompted to multimodal ChatGPT 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Financial Cost Analysis Associated with a Locomotor Exercise Randomized Controlled Trial in Chronic Stroke
Authors: Hazen, E. M.; Bartsch, B. L.; Billinger, S. A.
Score: 14.1, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.23300342
BackgroundPost-stroke recovery trials pose distinct recruitment and retention challenges, and understanding the financial requirements of conducting randomized controlled trials is crucial to ensure sufficient resources for successful study execution. The purpose of this analysis was to quantify the costs at a single site with a large catchment area of the Moderate-Intensity Exercise Versus High-Intensity Interval Training to Recover Walking Post-Stroke, HIT Stroke Trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Studentsourcing - aggregating and re-using data from a practical cell biology course
Authors: Goedhart, J.
Score: 24.9, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561479
Data that is generated by students during a course is often lost as there is no centrally organized collection and storage of the data. The loss of data prevents its re-use. To provide access to these data, I present an approach that I call studentsourcing. It collects, aggregates and re-uses data that is generated by students in a practical course on cell biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>De novo-designed minibinders expand the synthetic biology sensing repertoire
Authors: Weinberg, Z. Y.; Soliman, S. S.; Kim, M. S.; Chen, I. P.; Ott, M.; El-Samad, H.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575267
Synthetic and chimeric receptors capable of recognizing and responding to user-defined antigens have enabled &amp;#34;smart&amp;#34; therapeutics based on engineered cells. These cell engineering tools depend on antigen sensors which are most often derived from antibodies. Advances in the de novo design of proteins have enabled the design of protein binders with the potential to target epitopes with unique properties and faster production timelines compared to antibodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open-ST: High-resolution spatial transcriptomics in 3D
Authors: Schott, M.; Leon-Perinan, D.; Splendiani, E.; Strenger, L.; Licha, J. R.; Pentimalli, T. M.; Schallenberg, S.; Alles, J.; Samut Tagliaferro, S.; Boltengagen, A.; Ehrig, S.; Abbiati, S.; Dommerich, S.; Pagani, M.; Ferretti, E.; Macino, G.; Karaiskos, N.; Rajewsky, N.
Score: 87.2, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572554
Spatial transcriptomics (ST) methods have been developed to unlock molecular mechanisms underlying tissue development, homeostasis, or disease. However, there is a need for easy-to-use, high-resolution, cost-efficient, and 3D-scalable methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>MRI-Targeted Prostate Biopsy Introduces Grade Inflation and Overtreatment
Authors: Batouche, A. O.; Czeizler, E.; Lehto, T.-P.; Erickson, A.; Shadbahr, T.; Laajala, T. D.; Pohjonen, J.; Vickers, A. J.; Mirtti, T.; Rannikko, A. S.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.24300922
PurposeThe use of MRI-targeted biopsies has led to lower detection of Gleason Grade Group 1 (GG1) prostate cancer and increased detection of GG2 disease. Although this finding is generally attributed to improved sensitivity and specificity of MRI for aggressive cancers, it might also be explained by grade inflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 10:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>How smart was T. rex? Testing claims of exceptional cognition in dinosaurs and the application of neuron count estimates in palaeontological research
Authors: Caspar, K. R.; Gutierrez-Ibanez, C.; Bertrand, O. C.; Carr, T.; Colbourne, J.; Erb, A.; George, H.; Holtz, T. R.; Naish, D.; Wylie, D. R.; Hurlburt, G. R.
Score: 63.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.575006
Recent years have seen increasing scientific interest in whether neuron counts can act as correlates of diverse biological phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
