<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the autoreactome: Proteome-wide immunological fingerprints reveal the promise of plasma cell depleting therapy
Authors: Bodansky, A.; Yu, D. J.; Rallistan, A.; Kalaycioglu, M.; Boonyaratanakornkit, J.; Green, D. J.; Gauthier, J.; Turtle, C. J.; Zorn, K.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, B.; Mandel-Brehm, C.; Asaki, J.; Kortbawi, H.; Kung, A. F.; Rackaityte, E.; Wang, C.-Y.; Saxena, A.; de Dios, K.; Masi, G.; Nowak, R. J.; O&amp;#39;Connor, K. C.; Li, H.; Diaz, V. E.; Casaletto, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Cryptic female choice in response to male pheromones in Drosophila melanogaster
Authors: Doubovetzky, N.; Kohlmeier, P.; Bal, S.; Billeter, J.-C.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572608
Females control the paternity of their offspring by selectively mating with males they perceive to be of high quality. In species where females mate with multiple males in succession, females may bias offspring paternity by favoring the sperm of one male over another, a process known as cryptic female choice (CFC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>De novo design of diverse small molecule binders and sensors using Shape Complementary Pseudocycles
Authors: An, L.; Said, M.; Tran, L.; Majumder, S.; Goreshnik, I.; Lee, G. R.; Juergens, D.; Dauparas, J.; Anishchenko, I.; Coventry, B.; Bera, A. K.; Kang, A.; Levine, P. M.; Alvarez, V.; Pillai, A.; Norn, C.; Feldman, D.; Zorine, D.; Hicks, D. R.; Li, X.; Sanchez, M. G.; Vafeados, D. K.; Salveson, P. J.; Vorobieva, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Human neuron subtype programming through combinatorial patterning with scRNA-seq readouts
Authors: Lin, H.-C.; Janssens, J.; Kroell, A.-S.; Hornauer, P.; Santel, M.; Okamoto, R.; Karava, K.; Priouret, M.; Garcia, M. P.; Schroeter, M.; Camp, J. G.; Treutlein, B.
Score: 47.2, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.12.571318
Human neurons programmed through transcription factor (TF) overexpression model neuronal differentiation and neurological diseases. However, programming specific neuron types remains challenging. Here, we modulate developmental signaling pathways combined with TF overexpression to explore the spectrum of neuron subtypes generated from pluripotent stem cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>BioLLMBench: A Comprehensive Benchmarking of Large Language Models in Bioinformatics
Authors: Sarwal, V.; Munteanu, V.; Suhodolschi, T.; Ciorba, D.; Eskin, E.; Wang, W.; Mangul, S.
Score: 40.0, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572483
Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown great promise in their knowledge integration and problem-solving capabilities, but their ability to assist in bioinformatics research has not been systematically evaluated. To bridge this gap, we present BioLLMBench, a novel benchmarking framework coupled with a scoring metric scheme for comprehensively evaluating LLMs in solving bioinformatics tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>High-throughput computational discovery of inhibitory protein fragments with AlphaFold
Authors: Savinov, A.; Swanson, S.; Keating, A. E.; Li, G.-W.
Score: 81.6, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572389
Peptides can bind to specific sites on larger proteins and thereby function as inhibitors and regulatory elements. Peptide fragments of larger proteins are particularly attractive for achieving these functions due to their inherent potential to form native-like binding interactions. Recently developed experimental approaches allow for high-throughput measurement of protein fragment inhibitory activity in living cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>A compendium of Amplification-Related Gain Of Sensitivity (ARGOS) genes in human cancer
Authors: Rendo, V.; Schubert, M.; Khuu, N.; Suarez Peredo Rodriguez, M. F.; Huang, K.; Swift, M.; He, Y.; Zerbib, J.; Smith, R.; Raaijmakers, J.; Bandopadhayay, P.; Guenther, L. M.; Hwang, J. H.; Iniguez, A.; Moody, S.; Seo, J.-H.; Stover, E.; Garraway, L.; Hahn, W. C.; Stegmaier, K.; Medema, R. H.; Chowdhury, D.; Colome-Tatche, M.; Ben-David, U.; Beroukhim, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Integrative proteomic analyses across common cardiac diseases yield new mechanistic insights and enhanced prediction
Authors: Schuermans, A.; Pournamdari, A. B.; Lee, J.; Bhukar, R.; Ganesh, S.; Darosa, N.; Small, A. M.; Yu, Z.; Hornsby, W.; Koyama, S.; Januzzi, J. L.; Honigberg, M. C.; Natarajan, P.
Score: 26.9, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.23300218
Cardiac diseases represent common highly morbid conditions for which underlying molecular mechanisms remain incompletely understood. Here, we leveraged 1,459 protein measurements in 44,313 UK Biobank participants to characterize the circulating proteome associated with incident coronary artery disease, heart failure, atrial fibrillation, and aortic stenosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Global organelle profiling reveals subcellular localization and remodeling at proteome scale
Authors: Hein, M. Y.; Peng, D.; Todorova, V.; McCarthy, F.; Kim, K.; Liu, C.; Savy, L.; Januel, C.; Baltazar-Nunez, R.; Bax, S.; Vaid, S.; Vangipuram, M.; Ivanov, I. E.; Byrum, J. R.; Pradeep, S.; Gonzalez, C. G.; Aniseia, Y.; Wang, E.; Creery, J. S.; McMorrow, A. H.; Burgess, J.; Sunshine, S.; Yeung-Levy, S.; DeFelice, B. C.; Mehta, S. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Persistence of the primary somatosensory system in zebrafish
Authors: Navajas Acedo, J.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572352
The somatosensory system detects peripheral stimuli that are translated into behaviors necessary for survival. Fishes and amphibians possess two somatosensory systems in the trunk: the primary somatosensory system, formed by the Rohon-Beard neurons, and the secondary somatosensory system, formed by the neural crest cell-derived neurons of the Dorsal Root Ganglia. Rohon-Beard neurons have been characterized as a transient population that mostly disappears during the first days of life and is functionally replaced by the Dorsal Root Ganglia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>DNA barcoding reveals an increased diversity within the genus Culex (Diptera: Culicidae) in Ireland
Authors: Curran, T. G.; O&amp;#39;Hanlon, A.; Gallagher, F.; Pedersen, R. S.; Zintl, A.; Isiye, E.; Olmeda, A. V.; O&amp;#39;Neill, D.; McDevitt, A.; O&amp;#39;Reilly, C.; O&amp;#39;Meara, D. B.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572570
Arthropod populations are changing globally due to the combined impacts of climate change, land-use transformation, globalisation and trade. Changes in arthropod populations can potentially result in the decline and extinction of some native and/or endemic species, while other species that potentially pose threats may increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Endogenous glucagon-like peptide 1 diminishes prandial glucose counterregulatory response to hypoglycemia after gastric bypass surgery
Authors: Honka, H.; Gastaldelli, A.; Pezzica, S.; Peterson, R.; DeFronzo, R.; Salehi, M.
Score: 8.6, Published: 2023-12-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295840
We have previously shown that prandial endogenous glucose production (EGP) during insulin-induced hypoglycemia is smaller in non-diabetic subjects with gastric bypass (GB), where prandial glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1) concentrations are 5-10 times higher than those in non-operated controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Early COVID-19 vaccine effectiveness of XBB.1.5 vaccine against hospitalization and ICU admission, the Netherlands, 9 October - 5 December 2023
Authors: van Werkhoven, H.; Valk, A.-W.; Smagge, B.; de Melker, H. E.; Knol, M. J.; Hahne, S.; van den Hof, S.; de Gier, B.
Score: 875.1, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.12.23299855
We present early vaccine effectiveness (VE) estimates of the 2023 seasonal COVID-19 vaccination campaign using XBB.1.5 vaccine against COVID-19 hospitalization and ICU admission in previously vaccinated adults [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years old in the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Phylogenomics recovers multiple origins of portable case-making in caddisflies (Insecta: Trichoptera), the world&amp;#39;s most common underwater architects
Authors: Frandsen, P. B.; Holzenthal, R. W.; Espeland, M.; Breinholt, J.; Thomas, J. A.; Simon, S.; Kawahara, A. Y.; Plotkin, D.; Hotaling, S.; Li, Y.; Nelson, C. R.; Niehuis, O.; Mayer, C.; Podsiadlowski, L.; Donath, A.; Misof, B.; Lemmon, E.; Lemmon, A. R.; Morse, J. C.; Pauls, S. U.; Zhou, X.
Score: 73.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Imputation of structural variants using a multi-ancestry long-read sequencing panel enables identification of disease associations
Authors: Noyvert, B.; Erzurumluoglu, A. M.; Drichel, D.; Omland, S.; Andlauer, T. F. M.; Mueller, S.; Sennels, L.; Becker, C.; Kantorovich, A.; Bartholdy, B. A.; Braenne, I.; Bolivar-Lopez, J. C.; Mistrellides, C.; Belbin, G. M.; Li, J. H.; Pickrell, J. K.; de Jong, J.; Arora, J.; Hu, Y.; Boehringer Ingelheim - Global Computational Biology and Digital Sciences, ; Wood, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Rewriting regulatory DNA to dissect and reprogram gene expression
Authors: Martyn, G. E.; Montgomery, M. T.; Jones, H.; Guo, K.; Doughty, B. R.; Linder, J.; Chen, Z.; Cochran, K.; Lawrence, K. A.; Munson, G.; Pampari, A.; Fulco, C. P.; Kelley, D. R.; Lander, E. S.; Kundaje, A.; Engreitz, J. M.
Score: 50.7, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572268
Regulatory DNA sequences within enhancers and promoters bind transcription factors to encode cell type-specific patterns of gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Genomic analysis of Staphylococcus aureus isolates from bacteremia reveals genetic features associated with the COVID-19 pandemic
Authors: Sanchez-Osuna, M.; Pedrosa, M.; Bierge, P.; Gomez-Sanchez, I.; Alguacil-Guillen, M.; Espasa, M.; Erill, I.; Gasch, O.; Pich, O. Q.
Score: 261.4, Published: 2023-12-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572975
Genomic analyses of bacterial isolates are necessary to monitor the prevalence of antibiotic resistance genes and virulence determinants. Herein, we provide a comprehensive genomic description of a collection of 339 Staphylococcus aureus strains isolated from patients with bacteremia between 2014 and 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare utilisation in people with long COVID: an OpenSAFELY cohort study
Authors: Lin, L.-Y.; Henderson, A. D.; Carlile, O.; Dillingham, I.; Butler-Cole, B. F.; Marks, M.; Briggs, A.; Jit, M.; Tomlinson, L. A.; Bates, C.; Parry, J.; Bacon, S. C.; Goldacre, B.; Mehrkar, A.; MacKenna, B.; The OpenSAFELY Collaborative, ; Eggo, R. M.; Herrett, E.
Score: 16.0, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300305
Background: Long COVID, characterised by various symptoms and complications, potentially increases healthcare utilisation and costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory electronic health record analysis with ehrapy
Authors: Heumos, L.; Ehmele, P.; Treis, T.; Upmeier zu Belzen, J.; Namsaraeva, A.; Horlava, N.; Shitov, V. A.; Zhang, X.; Zappia, L.; Knoll, R.; Lang, N. J.; Hetzel, L.; Virshup, I.; Sikkema, L.; Roellin, E.; Curion, F.; Eils, R.; Schiller, H. B.; Hilgendorff, A.; Theis, F.
Score: 52.8, Published: 2023-12-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299816
With progressive digitalization of healthcare systems worldwide, large-scale collection of electronic health records (EHRs) has become commonplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>The global burden of HIV among Long-distance truck drivers: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: MUTIE, C.; Otieno, B.; Mwangi, E.; Kawira, R.; Mutisya, A.; Gachohi, J.; Mbuthia, G.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23300177
Long-distance truck drivers (LDTDs) endure a disproportionately high burden of HIV in various global settings. However, unlike other most at-risk populations, the global burden of HIV among LDTDs has not been documented so far. The result has been poor allocation and distribution of the limited HIV preventive resources for LDTDs in most parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 1300.7, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 serosurvey across multiple waves of the COVID-19 pandemic in New York City between 2020-2023
Authors: Carreno Quiroz, J. M.; Wagner, A.; Monahan, B.; Floda, D.; Gonzalez-Reiche, A. S.; Tcheou, J.; Raskin, A.; Bielak, D.; Singh, G.; Morris, S.; Fried, M.; Yellin, T.; Sullivan, L.; Study Group, P.; Sordillo, E. M.; Gordon, A.; van Bakel, H.; Simon, V.; Krammer, F.
Score: 45.6, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23300131
Sero-monitoring provides context to the epidemiology of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infections and changes in population immunity following vaccine introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical students&amp;#39; perceptions towards artificial intelligence in education and practice: A multinational, multicenter cross-sectional study
Authors: Busch, F.; Hoffmann, L.; Truhn, D.; Ortiz-Prado, E.; Makowski, M. R.; Bressem, K. K.; Adams, L. C.; COMFORT Consortium, Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.23299744
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) is anticipated to fundamentally change the educational and professional landscape for the next generation of physicians, but its successful integration depends on the global perspectives of all stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Interferon signaling in the nasal epithelium distinguishes among lethal and common cold respiratory viruses and is critical for viral clearance
Authors: Otter, C. J.; Renner, D. M.; Fausto, A.; Tan, L. H.; Cohen, N. A.; Weiss, S. R.
Score: 70.4, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.571720
All respiratory viruses establish primary infections in the nasal epithelium, where efficient innate immune induction may prevent dissemination to the lower airway and thus minimize pathogenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Air monitoring by nanopore sequencing
Authors: Reska, T.; Pozdniakova, S.; Borras, S.; Schloter, M.; Canas, L.; Fenn, A.; Rodo, X.; Winkler, B.; Schnitzler, J.-P.; Urban, L.
Score: 33.8, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572325
While the air microbiome and its diversity are known to be essential for human health and ecosystem resilience, the current lack of holistic air microbial diversity monitoring means that little is known about the air microbiomes composition, distribution, or functional effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence of orthostatic intolerance in Long Covid clinic patients - A multicentre observational study
Authors: Lee, C.; Greenwood, D.; Master, H.; Balasundaram, K.; Williams, P.; Scott, J.; Wood, C.; Cooper, R.; Darbyshire, J.; Espinosa Gonzalez, A.; Davies, H.; Osborne, T.; Corrado, J.; Iftekhar, N.; Rogers, N.; Delaney, B. C.; Greenhalgh, T.; Sivan, M.; LOCOMOTION Consortium, Score: 32.7, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23299958
PurposeOrthostatic intolerance (OI), including postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (PoTS) and orthostatic hypotension (OH), are often reported in long covid, but published studies are small with inconsistent results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A subcortical switchboard for exploratory, exploitatory, and disengaged states
Authors: Ahmadlou, M.; Yasamin Shirazi, M.; Zhang, P.; Rogers, I. L. M.; Dziubek, J.; Hofer, S. B.
Score: 76.6, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572654
To survive in evolving environments with uncertain resources, animals need to dynamically adapt their behavior and exhibit flexibility in choosing appropriate behavioral strategies, for example, to exploit familiar choices, to explore and acquire novel information, or to disengage altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Consuming less ultra-processed food is associated with inadequate protein intake among vegan dieters
Authors: Leitao, A. E.; Esteves, G. P.; Mazzolani, B. C.; Smaira, F. I.; Santini, M. H.; Santo Andre, H. C.; Gualano, B.; Roschel, H.
Score: 11.4, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299823
ImportanceMajor concerns regarding vegan dieters are whether they meet protein and essential amino acids (EAA) recommendations, and how reliant they are on ultra-processed foods (UPF). ObjectivesTo investigate whether vegan dieters meet protein and EAA recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>HIPTox. Hazard Identification Platform to Assess the Health Impacts from Indoor and Outdoor Air Pollutant Exposures, through Mechanistic Toxicology: A single-centre double-blind human exposure trial protocol
Authors: Faherty, T.; Badri, H.; Hu, D.; Voliotis, A.; Pope, F. D.; Mudway, I.; Smith, J.; McFiggans, G.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-12-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.23299801
Over the past decade, our understanding of the impact of air pollution on short- and long-term population health has advanced considerably, focusing on adverse effects on cardiovascular and respiratory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A Video Intervention to Improve Patient Understanding of Tumor Genomic Testing in Patients with Cancer
Authors: Veney, D.; Wei, L.; Toland, A. E.; Presley, C. J.; Hampel, H.; Padamsee, T. J.; Lee, C. N.; Irvin, W. J.; Bishop, M.; Kim, J.; Hovick, S. R.; Senter, L.; Stover, D.
Score: 7.6, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299443
BackgroundTumor genomic testing (TGT) has become standard-of-care for most patients with advanced/metastatic cancer. Despite established guidelines, patient education prior to TGT is variable or frequently omitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Neuropathological assessment of the olfactory bulb and tract in individuals with COVID-19
Authors: Lengacher, N. A.; Tomlinson, J. J.; Jochum, A.-K.; Franz, J.; Hasan Ali, O.; Flatz, L.; Jochum, W.; Penninger, J.; aSCENT-PD Investigators, ; Stadelmann-Nessler, C.; Woulfe, J. M.; Schlossmacher, M. G.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.572180
The majority of patients with Parkinson disease (PD) experience a loss in their sense of smell and accumulate insoluble -synuclein aggregates in their olfactory bulbs (OB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety and efficacy of orally administered full-spectrum medicinal cannabis plant extract 0.08% THC (NTI-164) in children with autism spectrum disorder: An open-label study.
Authors: El-Sukkari, D.; Sharma, K. G.; Fleiss, B.; Bragazna, D.; Crichton, A.; Fahey, M.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299505
Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is commonly associated with debilitating comorbidities impacting the well-being of affected children and their families. Some children with ASD experience behavioural difficulties that do not respond well to current medications and may also experience unwanted side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>AlphaFold2 structures template ligand discovery
Authors: Lyu, J.; Kapolka, N.; Gumpper, R.; Alon, A.; Wang, L.; Jain, M.; Alvarez, X.; Sakamoto, K.; Kim, Y.; DiBerto, J.; Kim, K.; Tummino, T.; Huang, S.; Irwin, J.; Tarkhanova, O.; Moroz, Y.; Skiniotis, G.; Kruse, A.; Shoichet, B.; Roth, B.
Score: 52.1, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572662
AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RosettaFold have greatly expanded the number of structures available for structure-based ligand discovery, even though retrospective studies have cast doubt on their direct usefulness for that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Exogenous mitochondrial transfer increases energy expenditure and attenuates adiposity gains in mice with diet-induced obesity
Authors: Namwanje, M.; Mazumdar, S.; Stayton, A.; Patel, P. S.; Watkins, C.; White, C.; Brown, C.; Eason, J. D.; Mozhui, K.; Kuscu, C.; Pabla, N.; Stephenson, E. J.; Bajwa, A.
Score: 6.0, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.23.573206
Obesity is associated with chronic multi-system bioenergetic stress that may be improved by increasing the number of healthy mitochondria available across organ systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Plasmodesmata act as unconventional membrane contact sites regulating inter-cellular molecular exchange in plants
Authors: Smokvarska, M.; Perez-Sancho, J.; Glavier, M.; Sritharan, S.; Dubois, G.; Dietrich, V.; Platre, M. P.; Li, Z. P.; Paterlini, A.; Moreau, H.; Fouillen, L.; GRISON, M. S.; Cana-Quijada, P.; Moraes, T. S.; Immel, F.; Wattelet, V.; Ducros, M.; Brocard, L.; Chambaud, C.; Zabrady, M.; Luo, Y.; Busch, W.; Tilsner, J.; Helariutta, Y.; Russinova, J.; Taly, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Ghrelin is associated with an elevated mood after an overnight fast in depression
Authors: Fahed, R.; Schulz, C.; Klaus, J.; Ellinger, S.; Walter, M.; Kroemer, N. B.
Score: 12.3, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23300133
BackgroundMajor depressive disorder (MDD) comprises subtypes with distinct symptom profiles. For example, patients with melancholic and atypical MDD differ in the direction of appetite and body weight changes as well as mood reactivity. Despite reported links to altered energy metabolism, the role of circulating neuropeptides from the gut in modulating such symptoms remains largely elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1311.3, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
ImportancePhase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects which are not assessed within the current regulatory framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Blood-Brain Barrier Opening in Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease Patients Using Portable Focused Ultrasound System
Authors: Bae, S.; Liu, K.; Pouliopoulos, A. N.; Ji, R.; Jimenez-Gambin, S.; Yousefian, O.; Kline-Schoder, A. R.; Batts, A.; Kokossis, D.; Mintz, A.; Honig, L. S.; Konofagou, E. E.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300222
Focused ultrasound (FUS) has recently shown great promise in facilitating blood-brain barrier opening (BBBO) for drug delivery and immunotherapy in Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease. However, FUS-mediated BBBO treatment is currently limited to systems integrated with MRI or post-surgical implants, thus restricting its widespread clinical adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Financial Cost Analysis Associated with a Locomotor Exercise Randomized Controlled Trial in Chronic Stroke
Authors: Hazen, E. M.; Bartsch, B. L.; Billinger, S. A.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.23300342
Background: Post-stroke recovery trials pose distinct recruitment and retention challenges, and understanding the financial requirements of conducting randomized controlled trials is crucial to ensure sufficient resources for successful study execution. The purpose of this analysis was to quantify the costs at a single site with a large catchment area of the Moderate-Intensity Exercise Versus High-Intensity Interval Training to Recover Walking Post-Stroke, HIT Stroke Trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Evolving patterns of extremely productive publishing behavior across science
Authors: Ioannidis, J.; Collins, T. A.; Baas, J.
Score: 44.7, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568476
We aimed to evaluate how many authors are extremely productive and how their presence across countries and scientific fields has changed during 2000-2022. Extremely productive (EP) authors were defined as those with &amp;gt;60 full papers (articles, reviews, conference papers) published in a single calendar year and indexed in Scopus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Fractal correlation properties of heart rate variability as a marker of exercise intensity during incremental and constant-speed treadmill running
Authors: van Rassel, C. R.; Ajayi, O. O.; Sales, K. M.; Clermont, A. C.; Rummel, M.; MacInnis, M. J.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.23300234
The short-term scaling exponent of detrended fluctuation analysis (DFA1) applied to interbeat intervals may provide a method to identify ventilatory thresholds and indicate systemic perturbation during prolonged exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Sculpting conducting nanopore size and shape through de novo protein design
Authors: Berhanu, S.; Majumder, S.; Muntener, T.; Whitehouse, J.; Berner, C.; Bera, A. K.; Kang, A.; Liang, B.; Khan, G. N.; Sankaran, B.; Tamm, L.; Brockwel, D. J.; Hiller, S.; Radford, S.; Baker, D.; Vorobieva, A. A.
Score: 30.6, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572500
Transmembrane {beta}-barrels (TMBs) are widely used for single molecule DNA and RNA sequencing and have considerable potential for a broad range of sensing and sequencing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open-ST: High-resolution spatial transcriptomics in 3D
Authors: Schott, M.; Leon-Perinan, D.; Splendiani, E.; Strenger, L.; Licha, J. R.; Pentimalli, T. M.; Schallenberg, S.; Alles, J.; Samut Tagliaferro, S.; Boltengagen, A.; Ehrig, S.; Abbiati, S.; Dommerich, S.; Pagani, M.; Ferretti, E.; Macino, G.; Karaiskos, N.; Rajewsky, N.
Score: 58.9, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572554
Spatial transcriptomics (ST) methods have been developed to unlock molecular mechanisms underlying tissue development, homeostasis, or disease. However, there is a need for easy-to-use, high-resolution, cost-efficient, and 3D-scalable methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 10:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) - a new record of butterfly for Saudi Arabia
Authors: ALFAKIH, A.; AL FAIFY, E. A.
Score: 35.8, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572884
The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) was recorded for the first time in Saudi Arabia. At this stage, we confirmed the presence of this species in the southernmost part of Saudi Arabia based on photographs taken in 2020-2023 from Fayfa and the adjacent mountains in Jazan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
