<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Extracellular Matrix Abnormalities in the Hippocampus of Subjects with Substance Use Disorder
Authors: Valeri, J.; Stiplosek, C.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, S. M.; Sinclair, D.; Grant, K. A.; Bollavarapu, R.; Platt, D. M.; Stockmeier, C. A.; Gisabella, B.; Pantazopoulos, H.
Score: 4.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295222
Contextual triggers are significant factors contributing to relapse in substance use disorders (SUD). Emerging evidence points to a critical role of extracellular matrix (ECM) molecules as mediators of reward memories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 406.1, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>African elephants address one another with individually specific calls
Authors: Pardo, M. A.; Fristrup, K.; Lolchuragi, D. S.; Poole, J.; Granli, P.; Moss, C.; Douglas-Hamilton, I.; Wittemyer, G.
Score: 131.8, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554872
Personal names are a universal feature of human language, yet few analogs exist in other species. While dolphins and parrots address conspecifics by imitating the calls of the addressee 1,2, human names are not imitations of the sounds typically made by the names owner 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Broad receptor tropism and immunogenicity of a clade 3 sarbecovirus
Authors: Lee, J.; Zepeda, S.; Park, Y.-J.; Taylor, A. L.; Quispe, J.; Stewart, C.; Leaf, E. M.; Treichel, C.; Corti, D.; King, N. P.; Starr, T. N.; Veesler, D.
Score: 102.9, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.557371
Although Rhinolophus bats harbor diverse clade 3 sarbecoviruses, the structural determinants of receptor tropism along with the antigenicity of their spike (S) glycoproteins remain uncharacterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Protein generation with evolutionary diffusion: sequence is all you need
Authors: Alamdari, S.; Thakkar, N.; van den Berg, R.; Lu, A. X.; Fusi, N.; Amini, A. P.; Yang, K. K.
Score: 172.6, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.556673
Deep generative models are increasingly powerful tools for the in silico design of novel proteins. Recently, a family of generative models called diffusion models has demonstrated the ability to generate biologically plausible proteins that are dissimilar to any actual proteins seen in nature, enabling unprecedented capability and control in de novo protein design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>The tidyomics ecosystem: Enhancing omic data analyses
Authors: Hutchison, W. J.; Keyes, T. J.; Crowell, H. L.; Soneson, C.; Mu, W.; Park, J.-E.; Davis, E. S.; Nahid, A. A.; Tang, M.; Yuan, V.; Axisa, P.-P.; Kitt, J. W.; Poon, C.-L.; Sato, N.; Gottardo, R.; Morgan, M.; Lee, S.; Lawrence, M.; Hicks, S. C.; Nolan, G. P.; Davis, K. L.; Papenfuss, A. T.; Love, M. I.; Mangiola, S.
Score: 118.1, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of Parkinsons Disease-related LRRK2 by type-I and type-II kinase inhibitors: activity and structures
Authors: Leschziner, A. E.; Sanz Murillo, M.; Suarez, A. V.; Dederer, V.; Chatterjee, D.; Louro, J. A.; Knapp, S.; Mathea, S.
Score: 36.1, Published: 2023-09-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556689
Mutations in Leucine Rich Repeat Kinase 2 (LRRK2) are a common cause of familial Parkinsons Disease (PD), and a risk factor for the sporadic form. Increased kinase activity has been shown in both familial and sporadic PD patients, making LRRK2 kinase inhibitors a major focus of drug development efforts in PD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mutually exclusive teams-like patterns of gene regulation characterize phenotypic heterogeneity along the noradrenergic-mesenchymal axis in neuroblastoma
Authors: Sehgal, M.; Nayak, S. P.; Sahoo, S.; Somarelli, J.; Jolly, M. K.
Score: 10.4, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.03.556132
Neuroblastoma is the most frequent extracranial pediatric tumor and leads to 15% of all cancer-related deaths in children. Tumor relapse and therapy resistance in neuroblastoma are driven by phenotypic plasticity and heterogeneity between noradrenergic (NOR) and mesenchymal (MES) cell states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Leukocyte Telomere Length and Cardiac Structure and Function: A Mendelian Randomization Study
Authors: Salih, A. M. A.; Boscolo Galazzo, I.; Menegaz, G.; Altmann, A.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295516
Existing research demonstrates association of shorter telomere length (TL) with increased risk of agerelated health outcomes including cardiovascular diseases. However, the direct causality of these relationships is not definitively established. Cardiovascular aging at an organ-level may be captured using image derived phenotypes (IDPs) of cardiac anatomy and function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>The anti-SARS-CoV-2 BNT162b2 vaccine suppresses mithramycin-induced erythroid differentiation and expression of embryo-fetal globin genes in human erythroleukemia K562 cells
Authors: Zurlo, M.; Gasparello, J.; Verona, M.; Papi, C.; Cosenza, L. C.; Finotti, A.; Marzaro, G.; Gambari, R.
Score: 973.5, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556634
The COVID-19 severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) the ongoing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic. The SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein (S-protein) plays an important role in the early phase of SARS-CoV2 infection through efficient interaction with ACE2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Testing the Limits of Language Models: A Conversational Framework for Medical AI Assessment
Authors: Johri, S.; Jeong, J.; Tran, B. A.; Schlessinger, D. I.; Wongvibulsin, S.; Cai, Z. R.; Daneshjou, R.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 33.7, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295399
Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise for medical diagnosis, but traditional evaluations using static exam questions overlook the complexity of real-world clinical dialogues. We introduce a multi-agent conversational framework where doctor-AI and patient-AI agents interact to diagnose medical conditions, evaluated by a grader-AI agent and medical experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Meta-Atlas of the Developing Human Cortex Identifies Modules Driving Cell Subtype Specification
Authors: Nano, P. R.; Fazzari, E.; Azizad, D.; Nguyen, C. V.; Wang, S.; Kan, R. L.; Wick, B.; Haeussler, M.; Bhaduri, A.
Score: 26.0, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.557406
Human brain development requires the generation of hundreds of diverse cell types, a process targeted by recent single-cell transcriptomic profiling efforts. Through a meta-analysis of seven of these published datasets, we have generated 225 meta-modules - gene co-expression networks that can describe mechanisms underlying cortical development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the ecology, taxonomy and metabolic capabilities of MBA03, a potential key player in anaerobic digestion
Authors: Puchol-Royo, R.; Pascual, J.; Ortega-Legarreta, A.; Otto, P.; Tideman, J.; de Vries, S.-J.; Abendroth, C.; Tanner, K.; Porcar, M.; Latorre-Perez, A.
Score: 89.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.556800
Biogas, a mix of CO2, CH4 and small proportions of other gases, is a biofuel obtained by anaerobic digestion (AD). Biogas production is often considered a black box process, as the role and dynamics of some of the microorganisms involved remain undisclosed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Attacks on Ukrainian healthcare facilities during the first year of the full-scale Russian invasion of Ukraine
Authors: Barten, D.; Tin, D.; Granholm, F.; Rusnak, D.; van Osch, F.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294763
BackgroundAlthough the Geneva Conventions and Rome Statute demand protections for healthcare facilities during war, breaches of these protections are frequently reported. The ongoing war in Ukraine is no exception, with several healthcare attacks eliciting widespread condemnation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Morning exercise and pre-breakfast metformin interact to reduce glycaemia in people with Type 2 Diabetes: a randomized crossover trial
Authors: Pena Carrillo, B. J.; Cope, E.; Gurel, S.; Traslosheros, A.; Kenny, A.; Mody, N.; Delibegovic, M.; Philip, S.; Thies, F.; Blana, D.; Gabriel, B. M.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295059
Exercise is recommended in the treatment of Type 2 Diabetes and can improve insulin sensitivity [1]. However, previous evidence suggests that exercise at different times of the day in people with type 2 diabetes may have opposing outcomes on glycaemia [2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Serological outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection by vaccination status and variant in England
Authors: Quinot, C.; Lunt, R.; Kirsebom, F.; Andrews, N.; Whitaker, H.; Skarnes, C.; Letley, L.; Haskins, D.; Angel, C.; Firminger, S.; Ratcliffe, K.; Sheridan, A.; Rajan, S.; Akindele, L.; Ijaz, S.; Zambon, M.; Brown, K.; Ramsay, M.; Lopez Bernal, J.
Score: 137.0, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295073
BackgroundThroughout the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, several vaccines have been rolled out and distinct variants with different severity and immune profiles emerged in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Deep mutational scans of XBB.1.5 and BQ.1.1 reveal ongoing epistatic drift during SARS-CoV-2 evolution
Authors: Taylor, A. L.; Starr, T. N.
Score: 81.1, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.557279
Substitutions that fix between SARS-CoV-2 variants can transform the mutational landscape of future evolution via epistasis. For example, large epistatic shifts in mutational effects caused by N501Y underlied the original emergence of Omicron variants, but whether such large epistatic saltations continue to define ongoing SARS-CoV-2 evolution remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Genetic Variations in TrkB.T1 Isoform and Their Association with Somatic and Psychological Symptoms in Individuals with IBS
Authors: Hong, H.; Mocci, E.; Kamp, K.; Zhu, S.; Cain, K. C.; Burr, R. L.; Perry, J. A.; Heitkemper, M. M.; Weaver-Toedtman, K.; Dorsey, S. G.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.23295434
Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), a disorder of gut-brain interaction, is often comorbid with somatic pain and psychological disorders. Dysregulated signaling of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) and its receptor, tropomyosin-related kinase B (TrkB), has been implicated in somatic-psychological symptoms in individuals with IBS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell RNA sequencing reveals dysregulated cellular programmes in the inflamed epithelium of Crohn&amp;#39;s disease patients.
Authors: Krzak, M.; Alegbe, T.; Taylor, D. L.; Ghouraba, M. H.; Strickland, M.; Satti, R.; Thompson, T.; Arestang, K.; Przybilla, M. J.; Ramirez-Navarro, L.; Harris, B. T.; Cheam, K. A. X.; Noell, G.; Leonard, S.; Petrova, V.; Jones-Bell, C.; James, K. R.; Wana, N.; Hu, M. X.; Skelton, J.; Ostermayer, J.; Gu, Y.; Dawson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Expression Level Analysis of ACE2 Receptor Gene in African-American and Non-African-American COVID-19 Patients
Authors: Nyamari, M. N.; Omar, K. M.; Fayehun, A. F.; Dachi, O.; Bwana, B. K.; Awe, O. I.
Score: 19.5, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.557129
BackgroundThe COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has spread rapidly across the continents. While the incidence of COVID-19 has been reported to be higher among African-American individuals, the rate of mortality has been lower compared to that of non-African-Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Regulatory Transposable Elements in the Encyclopedia of DNA Elements
Authors: Du, A. Y.; Chobirko, J. D.; Zhuo, X.; Feschotte, C.; Wang, T.
Score: 54.4, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.556380
Transposable elements (TEs) make up about half of the human genome and many have the biochemical hallmarks of tissue- or cell type-specific cis-regulatory elements. While some TEs have been rigorously documented to contribute directly to host gene regulation, we still have a very partial view of their regulatory landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic aging clock predicts mortality and risk of common age-related diseases in diverse populations
Authors: Argentieri, M. A.; Xiao, S.; Bennett, D.; Winchester, L.; Nevado-Holgado, A. J.; Albukhari, A.; Yao, P.; Mazidi, M.; Lv, J.; Li, L.; Adams, C. J.; Clarke, R.; Amin, N.; Chen, Z.; van Duijn, C. M.
Score: 17.7, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295486
Circulating plasma proteins play key roles in human health and could be used to measure biological aging to predict risk of mortality, disease, and multimorbidity beyond chronological age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>A Literature Review and Meta-Analysis of the Effects of Lockdowns on COVID-19 Mortality - II
Authors: Herby, J.; Jonung, L.; Hanke, S.
Score: 225.6, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294845
The purpose of this systematic review and meta-analysis is to determine the effect of lockdowns on COVID-19 mortality based on available empirical evidence. Lockdowns are defined as the imposition of at least one compulsory, non-pharmaceutical intervention (NPI). We employ a systematic search and screening procedure in which 19,646 studies are identified that could potentially address the purpose of our study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating AI in Clinical Practice: A Scoping Evaluation
Authors: Han, R.; Acosta, J. N.; Shakeri, Z.; Ioannidis, J.; Topol, E.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 70.0, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295381
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a promising tool in healthcare, with numerous studies indicating its potential to perform as well or better than clinicians. However, a considerable portion of these AI models have only been tested retrospectively, raising concerns about their true effectiveness and potential risks in real-world clinical settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Ischemic Stroke after COVID-19 Bivalent Booster Vaccination in an Integrated Health System
Authors: Sharff, K.; Tandy, T. K.; Lewis, P. F.; Johnson, E. S.
Score: 6.4, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295368
PurposeWhat is the absolute occurrence of ischemic stroke and transient ischemic attack after a COVID-19 bivalent vaccination? MethodsWe conducted a retrospective cohort study of Kaiser Permanente Northwest (KPNW) patients 18 years and older who were vaccinated with either the Pfizer or Moderna formulation of the COVID-19 bivalent vaccine between September 1, 2022 and March 1st 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Cellular aging is accelerated in the malignant clone of myeloproliferative neoplasms
Authors: Vieri, M.; Tharmapalan, V.; Kalmer, M.; Baumeister, J.; Nikolic, M.; Schnitker, M.; Kirschner, M.; Flosdorf, N.; Szymanski de Toledo, M. A.; Zenke, M.; Koschmieder, S.; Brummendorf, T. H.; Beier, F.; Wagner, W.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295349
Myeloproliferative neoplasms (MPNs) are caused by somatic driver mutations, such as JAK2V617F, which might also affect cellular aging and senescence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the potential population-level impacts of HIV self-testing distribution among key populations in Cote d&amp;#39;Ivoire, Mali, and Senegal: a mathematical modelling analysis
Authors: Silhol, R.; Maheu-Giroux, M.; Soni, N.; Simo Fotso, A.; Rouveau, N.; Vautier, A.; Doumenc-Aidara, C.; Geoffroy, O.; N&amp;#39;Guessan, K. N.; Sidibe, Y.; Kabemba, O. K.; Gueye, P. A.; Mukandavire, C.; Vickerman, P.; Keita, A.; Ndour, C. T.; Ehui, E.; Larmarange, J.; Boily, M.-C.; The ATLAS Team, Score: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Antigenicity and infectivity characterization of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Chen, X.; Xu, Y.; Wang, P.; Yu, L.; Wang, J.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Xiao, T.; An, R.; Wang, Y.; Gu, Q.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Shen, Z.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y. R.
Score: 621.9, Published: 2023-09-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555815
The recently identified SARS-CoV-2 variant, BA.2.86, which carries a substantial number of Spike mutations, has raised a global alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Wu, K.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 2838.4, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Conventional and unconventional T cell responses contribute to the prediction of clinical outcome and causative bacterial pathogen in sepsis patients
Authors: Burton, R. J.; Raffray, L.; Moet, L. M.; Cuff, S. M.; White, D. A.; Baker, S. E.; Moser, B.; O&amp;#39;Donnell, V. B.; Ghazal, P.; Morgan, M. P.; Artemiou, A.; Eberl, M.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295490
Sepsis is characterised by a dysfunctional host response to infection culminating in life-threatening organ failure that requires complex patient management and rapid intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Comparing the Performance of ChatGPT and GPT-4 versus a Cohort of Medical Students on an Official University of Toronto Undergraduate Medical Education Progress Test
Authors: Meaney, C.; Huang, R. S.; Lu, K.; Fischer, A. W.; Leung, F.-H.; Kulasegaram, K.; Tzanetos, K.; Punnett, A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.23295571
Background: Large language model (LLM) based chatbots have recently received broad social uptake; demonstrating remarkable abilities in natural language understanding, natural language generation, dialogue, and logic/reasoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Neutralization Escape by SARS-CoV-2 Omicron Subvariant BA.2.86
Authors: Lasrado, N.; Collier, A.-r.; Hachmann, N.; Miller, J.; Rowe, M.; Schonberg, E.; Rodrigues, S.; LaPiana, A.; Patio, R.; Anand, T.; Fisher, J.; Mazurek, C.; Guan, R.; Wagh, K.; Theiler, J.; Korber, B.; Barouch, D. H.
Score: 796.9, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.556272
The continued evolution of SARS-CoV-2 may lead to evasion of vaccine immunity and natural immunity. A highly mutated Omicron variant BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA methylation shapes the Polycomb landscape during the exit from naïve pluripotency
Authors: Albert, J. R.; Urli, T.; Monteagudo-Sanchez, A.; Le Breton, A.; Sultanova, A.; David, A.; Schulz, M.; Greenberg, M. V. C.
Score: 53.8, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.557729
In mammals, 5 methyl-cytosine (5mC) and Polycomb Repressive Complex 2 (PRC2)- deposited histone 3 lysine 27 trimethylation (H3K27me3) are generally mutually exclusive at CpG-rich regions. As mouse embryonic stem cells exit the naive pluripotent state, there is a massive gain of 5mC coincident with a restriction of broad H3K27me3 to 5mC-free, CpG-rich regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The citrate transporter SLC13A5 as a therapeutic target for kidney disease: evidence from Mendelian randomization to inform drug development
Authors: Gill, D.; Zagkos, L.; Gill, R.; Benzing, T.; Jordan, J.; Birkenfeld, A.; Burgess, S.; Zahn, G.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294760
BackgroundSolute carrier family 13 member 5 (SLC13A5) is a Na -coupled citrate co-transporter that mediates the entry of extracellular citrate into the cytosol. SLC13A5 inhibition has been proposed as a therapeutic target for reducing progression of kidney disease via its effects on citrate metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Navigating the Neurological Aftermath of COVID-19: An In-Depth Exploration
Authors: Butt, M.; Nagpal, S.; Phillips, E.; Shah, S. Q.; Dogar, Z.; Loh, H.; Mishra, S.; Vijayan, R.; Jeyakumar, R.; Makkar, S. S.; Jahan, S.; Diaz, G. M.; Franca, H.; Javed, S.; Belizaire, M.-P.; Reddy Somagutta, M.
Score: 138.9, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.10.23295343
BackgroundThe COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has affected millions of people and can result in both immediate and prolonged neurological effects, including severe complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Spike amyloid fibrils specifically and selectively accelerates amyloid fibril formation of human prion protein and the amyloid β peptide
Authors: Larsson, J. N.; Hellstrand, E.; Hammarström, P.; Nyström, S.
Score: 2152.6, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555834
An increasing number of reports suggest an association between COVID-19 infection and initiation or acceleration of neurodegenerative diseases (NDs) including Alzheimers disease (AD) and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease (CJD). Both these diseases and several other NDs are caused by conversion of human proteins into a misfolded, aggregated amyloid fibril state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Dietary sulfur amino acid restriction in humans with overweight and obesity: a translational randomized controlled trial
Authors: Olsen, T.; Stolt, E.; Ovrebo, B.; Elshorbagy, A.; Tore, E. C.; Lee-Oedegard, S.; Troensegaard, H.; Johannessen, H.; Doeland, B.; Vo, A. A. D.; Dahl, A. F.; Svendsen, K.; Thoresen, M.; Refsum, H.; Rising, R.; Barvikova, K.; Greevenbroek, M. v.; Kozich, V.; Retterstol, K.; Vinknes, K. J.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295155</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Strategies for optimising early detection and first response management of postpartum haemorrhage at caesarean birth: A modified Delphi-based international expert consensus
Authors: Pingray, V.; Williams, C. R.; Alwy Al-beity, F.; Abalos, E.; Arulkumaran, S.; Blumenfeld, A.; Carvalho, B.; Deneux-Tharaux, C.; Downe, S.; Dumont, A.; Escobar Vidarte, M. F.; Evans, C.; Fawcus, S.; Galadanci, H.; Hoang, T. D. T.; Hofmeyr, G. J.; Homer, C. S.; Lewis, A. G.; Liabsuetrakul, T.; Lumbiganon, P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Model for Tumor Type Prediction using Targeted Clinical Genomic Sequencing Data
Authors: Darmofal, M.; Suman, S.; Atwal, G.; Chen, J.-F.; Chang, J. C.; Toomey, M.; Vakiani, E.; Varghese, A. M.; Balakrishnan Rema, A.; Syed, A.; Schultz, N.; Berger, M.; Morris, Q.
Score: 16.1, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295131
Tumor type guides clinical treatment decisions in cancer, but histology-based diagnosis remains challenging. Genomic alterations are highly diagnostic of tumor type, and tumor type classifiers trained on genomic features have been explored, but the most accurate methods are not clinically feasible, relying on features derived from whole genome sequencing (WGS), or predicting across limited cancer types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Performance of ChatGPT in Diagnosis of Corneal Eye Diseases
Authors: Delsoz, M.; Madadi, Y.; M Munir, W.; Tamm, B.; Mehravaran, S.; Soleimani, M.; Djalilian, A.; Yousefi, S.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.23294635
IntroductionAssessing the capabilities of ChatGPT-4.0 and ChatGPT-3.5 for diagnosing corneal eye diseases based on case reports and compare with human experts. MethodsWe randomly selected 20 cases of corneal diseases including corneal infections, dystrophies, degenerations, and injuries from a publicly accessible online database from the University of Iowa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>palliative medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/palliative-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/palliative-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A rapid systematic review of the effectiveness of out-of-hours palliative care telephone advice lines for people living at home and their carers
Authors: Johansson, T.; Chambers, R.; Curtis, T. C.; Pask, S.; Greenley, S.; Brittain, M.; Bone, A. E.; Laidlaw, L.; Okamoto, I.; Barclay, S.; Higginson, I. J.; Murtagh, F. E. M.; Sleeman, K. E.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294814
BackgroundPeople with palliative and end-of-life care needs in the community and their carers often rely on out-of-hours services to remain at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Digital holo-tomographic 3D maps of COVID-19 microclots in blood to assess disease severity
Authors: Bergaglio, T.; Synhaivska, O.; Nirmalraj, P.
Score: 5.7, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.557318
The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has impacted health globally. Cumulative evidence points to long-term effects of COVID-19 such as cardiovascular and cognitive disorders diagnosed in patients even after the recovery period. In particular, micrometer-sized blood clots and hyperactivated platelets have been identified as potential indicators of long COVID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>The neonatal gut microbiota: a role in the encephalopathy of prematurity
Authors: Vaher, K.; Blesa Cabez, M.; Lusarreta Parga, P.; Binkowska, J.; van Beveren, G. J.; Odendaal, M.-L.; Sullivan, G. P.; Stoye, D. Q.; Corrigan, A.; Quigley, A. J.; Thrippleton, M. J.; Bastin, M. E.; Bogaert, D.; Boardman, J. P.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295409
Preterm birth is associated with atypical brain development and alterations in the gut microbiome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Association between Haloperidol use and Risk of Rheumatoid Arthritis
Authors: Ambati, V.; Cummings, T.; Yerramothu, P.; Nguyen, J.; Sutton, S. S.; Werner, B.; Magagnoli, J.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295367
Haloperidol is an anti-psychotic used for the treatment of schizophrenia or Tourette disorder. Here we report, by studying three large administrative health insurance databases, that haloperidol use is associated with a reduced risk of developing rheumatoid arthritis. A meta-analysis revealed a 31% reduced hazard of incident rheumatoid arthritis among individuals with schizophrenia or Tourette disorder treated with haloperidol compared to those treated with other anti-psychotic drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning connects structure, bitterness &amp;amp; mechanism to antimalarial activity
Authors: Sambu, S.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.556833
Machine learning allows us to identify patterns we might otherwise have missed in the data. It therefore provides an ample solution to the age-old problem of lossless research. When the pattern is robust and the signal is durable, it is possible to use relatively modest amounts of data to build powerful well-learned models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Myosin Heavy Chains: Ribosomal Specialization Drives Human Skeletal Muscle Fiber Heterogeneity
Authors: Moreno-Justicia, R.; Van der Stede, T.; Stocks, B.; Laitila, J.; Seaborne, R. A.; Van de Loock, A.; Lievens, E.; Marin-Arraiza, L.; Van Vossel, K.; Yigit, N.; Anckaert, J.; Weyns, A.; Van Thienen, R.; Sahl, R. E.; Zanoteli, E.; Lawlor, M. W.; Mestdagh, P.; Vandesompele, J.; Ochala, J.; Hostrup, M.; Derave, W.; Deshmukh, A. S.
Score: 48.5, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cellular gibberellin dynamics govern indeterminate nodule development, morphologyand function
Authors: Drapek, C.; Radzman-Mohd, N. A.; Rizza, A.; Schiessl, K.; Dos Santos Barbosa, F.; Wen, J.; Oldroyd, G. E. D.; Jones, A. M.
Score: 34.0, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.556959
During nutrient scarcity, plants can adapt their developmental strategy to maximize their chance of survival. Such plasticity in development is underpinned by hormonal regulation, which mediates the relationship between environmental cues and developmental outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>The Sensation and Pain Rating Scale: easy to use, clear to interpret, and responsive to clinical change
Authors: Madden, V. J.; Kamerman, P.; Leake, H. B.; Catley, M. J.; Heathcote, L. C.; Moseley, L. G.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-09-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295128
The Sensation and Pain Rating Scale (SPARS) allows rating of non-painful as well as painful percepts. Although it performs well in the experimental context, its clinical utility has not been tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Social media use and internalising symptoms in clinical and community adolescent samples: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Fassi, L.; Thomas, K.; Parry, D. A.; Leyland-Craggs, A.; Ford, T.; Orben, A.
Score: 16.1, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295355
ImportanceThere are many concerns about the link between social media use and adolescent mental health. However, most research has studied adolescents from the general population, overlooking clinical groups. To address this gap, we synthesize, quantify and compare evidence on the relationship between social media use and internalising symptoms in adolescent clinical and community samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Genomic epidemiology of the cholera outbreak in Malawi 2022-2023
Authors: Chabuka, L.; Choga, W. T.; Mavian, C. N.; Moir, M.; Tegally, H.; Wilkinson, E.; Naidoo, Y.; Inward, R.; Morgenstern, C.; Bhatt, S.; Wint, W. G. R.; Khan, K.; Bogoch, I. I.; Kraemer, M. U. G.; Baxter, C.; Tagliamonte, M.; Salemi, M.; Lessells, R.; Mitambo, C.; Chitatanga, R.; Bango, J. B.; Chiwaula, M.; Chavula, Y.; Bukhu, M.; Manda, H.; Chitenje, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Charting Aging Trajectories of Knee Cartilage Thickness for Early Osteoarthritis Risk Prediction: An MRI Study from the Osteoarthritis Initiative Cohort
Authors: Li, T.; Luo, T.; Chen, B.; Huang, C.; Shen, Z.; Xu, Z.; Nissman, D.; Golightly, Y.; Nelson, A.; Niethammer, M.; Zhu, H.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295398
Knee osteoarthritis (OA), a prevalent joint disease in the U.S., poses challenges in terms of predicting of its early progression. Although high-resolution knee magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) facilitates more precise OA diagnosis, the heterogeneous and multifactorial aspects of OA pathology remain significant obstacles for prognosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>HEART rate variability biofeedback breathing programme for LOng Covid dysautonomia (HEARTLOC): results of a feasibility study
Authors: Corrado, J.; Iftekhar, N.; Halpin, S.; Li, M.; Tarrant, R.; Grimaldi, J.; Simms, A.; O&amp;#39;Connor, R. J.; Casson, A.; Sivan, M.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295208
IntroductionPost-covid-19 syndrome, or Long covid (LC) refers to symptoms persisting 12 weeks after Covid-19 infection. LC comprises a wide range of dysautonomia symptoms, including fatigue, breathlessness, palpitations, dizziness, pain and brain fog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>You do not receive enough recognition for your influential science
Authors: Arabi, S.; Ni, C.; Hutchins, B. I.
Score: 38.9, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556750
During career advancement and funding allocation decisions in biomedicine, reviewers have traditionally depended on journal-level measures of scientific influence like the impact factor. Prestigious journals are thought to pursue a reputation of exclusivity by rejecting large quantities of papers, many of which may be meritorious. It is possible that this process could create a system whereby some influential articles are prospectively identified and recognized by journal brands but most influential articles are overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Factors associated with teenage pregnancies during the Covid-19 period in Pakwach district, Northern Uganda: a case-control study
Authors: Alunyo, J. P.; Mukunya, D.; Napyo, A.; Matovu, J. K.; Okia, D.; Wanume, B.; Okello, F.; Tuwa, A. H.; Wenani, D.; Okibure, A.; Omara, G.; Olupot Olupot, P.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295521
Abstract Background: Teenage pregnancy rates have globally decreased over the years, but remain high, especially in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review on the Effects of Exercise on Gut Microbial Diversity, Taxonomic Composition, and Microbial Metabolites: Identifying Research Gaps and Future Directions
Authors: Cullen, J.; Shahzad, S.; Dhillon, J.
Score: 39.6, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23294991
The gut microbiome, hosting a diverse microbial community, plays a pivotal role in metabolism, immunity, and digestion. While the potential of exercise to influence this microbiome has been increasingly recognized, findings remain incongruous. This systematic review examined the effects of exercise on the gut microbiome of human and animal models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>IMPROVING ANTIBODY AFFINITY USING LABORATORYDATA WITH LANGUAGE MODEL GUIDED DESIGN
Authors: Krause, B.; Subramanian, S.; Yuan, T.; Yang, M.; Sato, A.; Naik, N.
Score: 17.4, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557505
AO_SCPLOWBSTRACTC_SCPLOWProtein design requires searching exponentially large spaces of possible sequences to find candidates with desired properties. Language models (LMs) pretrained on universal protein datasets have shown potential to help make this search space tractable. However, LMs trained on natural sequences alone have limitations in designing proteins with novel functions, which is especially important for many pharmaceutical applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Escalating High-dimensional Imaging using Combinatorial Channel Multiplexing and Deep Learning
Authors: Ben-Uri, R.; Ben Shabat, L.; Bar-Tal, O.; Bussi, Y.; Maimon, N.; Keidar Haran, T.; Milo, I.; Elhanani, O.; Rochwarger, A.; Schürch, C. M.; Bagon, S.; Keren, L.
Score: 22.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.556962
Understanding tissue structure and function requires tools that quantify the expression of multiple proteins at single-cell resolution while preserving spatial information. Current imaging technologies use a separate channel for each individual protein, inherently limiting their throughput and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Dark taxonomy&amp;#34;: a new protocol for overcoming the taxonomic impediments for dark taxa and broadening the taxon base for biodiversity assessment
Authors: Meier, R.; Srivathsan, A.; Oliveira, S. S.; Balbi, M. I. P. A.; Ang, Y.; Yeo, D.; Amorim, D. d. S.
Score: 30.2, Published: 2023-09-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555664
We are entering the 6th mass extinction event on the planet with scarcely any data for &amp;#34;dark taxa&amp;#34; that comprise most animal species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
