<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Polymerized type I collagen down-regulates STAT-1 phosphorylation through engagement to LAIR-1 in M1-macrophages avoiding long COVID
Authors: Olivares Martinez, E.; Hernandez-Ramirez, D. F.; Nunez-Alvarez, C. A.; Chapa-Ibarguengoitia, M.; Mendez-Flores, S.; Priego-Ranero, A.; Azamar-Llamas, D.; Olvera-Prado, H.; Rivas-Redonda, K. I.; Ochoa-Hein, E.; Lopez-Mosqueda, L. G.; Rojas-Castaneda, E.; Urbina-Teran, S.; Septien-Stute, L.; Hernandez-Gilsoul, T.; Aguilar-Leon, D.; Torres-Villalobos, G.; Furuzawa-Carballeda, J.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-07-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292108
BackgroundThe polymerized type I collagen (PTIC) is a {gamma}-irradiated mixture of pepsinized porcine type I collagen and polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous helping in pigs is mediated by helper&amp;#39;s social attention and distress signals of individuals in need
Authors: Moscovice, L. R.; Eggert, A.; Manteuffel, C.; Rault, J.-L.
Score: 104.5, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.17.533160
Helping behaviour is of special interest for prosociality because it appears to be motivated by the needs of others. We developed a novel paradigm to investigate helping in pigs (Sus scrofa domesticus) and tested 75 individuals in eight groups in their home pens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structure of the human Duffy antigen receptor
Authors: Saha, S.; Khanppnavar, B.; Maharana, J.; Kim, H.; Carino, C. M. C.; Daly, C.; Houston, S.; Kumari, P.; Yadav, P. N.; Plouffe, B.; Inoue, A.; Chung, K. Y.; Banerjee, R.; Korkhov, V. M.; Shukla, A. K.
Score: 28.9, Published: 2023-07-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.09.548245
The Duffy antigen receptor, also known as FY glycoprotein or CD234, is a seven transmembrane protein expressed primarily at the surface of red blood cells, which displays promiscuous binding to multiple chemokines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Single cell susceptibility to SARS-CoV-2 infection is driven by variable cell states
Authors: Reffsin, S.; Miller, J.; Ayyanathan, K.; Dunagin, M. C.; Jain, N.; Schultz, D. C.; Cherry, S.; Raj, A.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.06.547955
The ability of a virus to infect a cell type is at least in part determined by the presence of host factors required for the viral life cycle. However, even within cell types that express known factors needed for infection, not every cell is equally susceptible, suggesting that our knowledge of the full spectrum of factors that promote infection is incomplete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Petascale Homology Search for Structure Prediction
Authors: Lee, S.; Kim, G.; Levy Karin, E.; Mirdita, M.; Park, S.; Chikhi, R.; Babaian, A.; Kryshtafovych, A.; Steinegger, M.
Score: 70.8, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548308
The recent CASP15 competition highlighted the critical role of multiple sequence alignments (MSAs) in protein structure prediction, as demonstrated by the success of the top AlphaFold2-based prediction methods. To push the boundaries of MSA utilization, we conducted a petabase-scale search of the Sequence Read Archive (SRA), resulting in gigabytes of aligned homologs for CASP15 targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Direct optical measurement of intra-molecular distances down to the Angstrom scale
Authors: Sahl, S. J.; Matthias, J.; Inamdar, K.; Khan, T. A.; Weber, M.; Becker, S.; Griesinger, C.; Broichhagen, J.; Hell, S. W.
Score: 81.1, Published: 2023-07-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548133
Optical investigations of nanometer distances between proteins, their subunits, or other biomolecules have been the exclusive prerogative of Forster Resonance Energy Transfer (FRET) microscopy for decades. Here we show that MINFLUX fluorescence nanoscopy measures intra-molecular distances down to 1 nm - and in planar projections down to 1 Angstrom - directly, linearly, and with Angstrom precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Integrative spatial analysis reveals a multi-layered organization of glioblastoma
Authors: Greenwald, A. C.; Darnell, N. G.; Hoefflin, R.; Simkin, D.; Gonzalez-Castro, L. N.; Mount, C.; Hirsch, D.; Nomura, M.; Talpir, T.; Kedmi, M.; Goliand, I.; Medici, G.; Li, B.; Keren-Shaul, H.; Weller, M.; Addadi, Y.; Neidert, M. C.; Suva, M. L.; Tirosh, I.
Score: 78.3, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.06.547924
Glioma contains malignant cells in diverse states. Hypoxic regions are associated with a unique histology of pseudopalisading cells, while other regions appear to have limited histological organization, reflecting the diffuse nature of glioma cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Appropriateness of ChatGPT in answering heart failure related questions
Authors: King, R.; Samaan, J. S.; Yeo, Y. H.; Mody, B.; Lombardo, D. M.; Ghashghaei, R.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292385
BackgroundHeart failure requires complex management with increased patient knowledge shown to improve outcomes. The large language model (LLM), Chat Generative Pre-Trained Transformer (ChatGPT), may be a useful supplemental resource of information for patients with heart failure. MethodsResponses produced by GPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Filter-aided extracellular vesicle enrichment (FAEVEr)
Authors: Pauwels, J.; Van de Steene, T.; Van de Velde, J.; Eyckerman, S.; Gevaert, K.
Score: 31.5, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.06.547926
A.Extracellular vesicles (EVs), membrane-delimited nanovesicles that are secreted by cells into the extracellular environment, are gaining substantial interest due to their involvement in cellular homeostasis and their contribution to disease pathology. The latter in particular has led to an exponential increase in interest in EVs as they are considered to be circulating packages containing potential biomarkers and are also a possible biological means to deliver drugs in a cell-specific manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>GPT-4, an artificial intelligence large language model,exhibits high levels of accuracy on dermatology specialty certificate exam questions.
Authors: Shetty, M.; Ettlinger, M.; Lynch, M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292418
Artificial Intelligence (AI) has shown considerable potential within medical fields including dermatology. In recent years a new form of AI, large language models, have shown impressive performance in complex textual reasoning across a wide range of domains including standardised medical licensing exam questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Tgfbr1 controls developmental plasticity between the hindlimb and external genitalia by remodeling their regulatory landscape
Authors: Lozovska, A.; Korovesi, A. G.; Dias, A.; Lopes, A.; Fowler, D. A.; Martins, G. G.; Novoa, A.; Mallo, M.
Score: 61.3, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548120
The hindlimb and external genitalia of present-day tetrapods are thought to derive from an ancestral common primordium that evolved to generate a wide diversity of structures adapted for efficient locomotion and mating in the ecological niche conquered by the species 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>The architecture of multifunctional ecological networks
Authors: Hervias-Parejo, S.; Cuevas-Blanco, M.; Lacasa, L.; Traveset, A.; Donoso, I.; Heleno, R.; Nogales, M.; Rodriguez-Echeverria, S.; Melian, C.; Eguiluz, V. M.
Score: 16.2, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.02.547400
Understanding how biotic interactions affect ecosystem functioning has been a research priority in natural sciences due to their critical role in bolstering ecological resilience1-3. Yet, traditional assessment of ecological complexity typically focus on species-species effective interactions that mediate a particular function (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Very Low Lipoprotein(a) Levels Are Associated With Higher Risks Of New-Onset Diabetes And Non-Alcoholic Liver Disease
Authors: Yeung, M. W.; Said, M. A.; van de Vegte, Y. J.; Verweij, N.; Dullaart, R. P.; van der Harst, P.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292471
AimWe aimed to study the association of very low serum Lipoprotein(a) [Lp(a)] concentrations with new-onset type 2 diabetes (T2D) and non-alcoholic liver disease (NAFLD) in the context of lipid-lowering medication usage in the UK Biobank, a large prospective population cohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Marburg Virus Disease outbreaks, mathematical models, and disease parameters: a Systematic Review
Authors: Cuomo-Dannenburg, G.; McCain, K.; McCabe, R.; Unwin, H. J. T.; Doohan, P.; Nash, R. K.; Hicks, J. T.; Charniga, K.; Geismar, C.; Lambert, B.; Nikitin, D.; Skarp, J. E.; Wardle, J.; Pathogen Epidemiology Review Group, ; Kont, M.; Bhatia, S.; Imai, N.; van Elsland, S. L.; Cori, A.; Morgenstern, C.
Score: 15.8, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292424</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Enamel proteins reveal biological sex and genetic variability within southern African Paranthropus
Authors: Madupe, P. P.; Koenig, C.; Patramanis, I.; Rüther, P. L.; Hlazo, N.; Mackie, M.; Tawane, M.; Krueger, J.; Taurozzi, A. J.; Troche, G. B.; Kibii, J.; Pickering, R.; Dickinson, M. R.; Sahle, Y.; Kgotleng, D.; Musiba, C.; Manthi, F.; Bell, L.; du Plessis, M.; Gilbert, C.; Zipfel, B.; Kuderna, L.; Lizano, E.; Welker, F.; Kyriakidou, P.; Cox, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Novel autoantibody targets identified in patients with autoimmune hepatitis (AIH) by PhIP-Seq reveal pathogenic insights
Authors: Klepper, A.; Kung, A.; Vazquez, S. E.; Mitchell, A.; Mann, S.; Avila-Vargas, I.; Kari, S.; Tekeste, M.; Castro, J.; Lee, B.; Duarte, M.; Khalili, M.; Wilson, M. R.; Yang, M.; Wolters, P.; Price, J.; Perito, E.; Feng, S.; Maher, J. J.; Lai, J. C.; Weiler-Normann, C.; Lohse, A.; DeRisi, J.; Tana, M.
Score: 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Estimation of indirect genetic effects and heritability under assortative mating
Authors: Young, A. S.
Score: 34.5, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548458
Both direct genetic effects (effects of alleles in an individual on that individual) and indirect genetic effects -- effects of alleles in an individual (e.g. parents) on another individual (e.g. offspring) -- can contribute to phenotypic variation and genotype-phenotype associations. Here, we consider a phenotype affected by direct and parental indirect genetic effects under assortative mating at equilibrium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Three-dimensional genome architecture persists in a 52,000-year-old woolly mammoth skin sample
Authors: Sandoval-Velasco, M.; Dudchenko, O.; Antonio Rodriguez, J.; Perez Estrada, C.; Dehasque, M.; Fontsere, C.; Mak, S. S. T.; Plotnikov, V.; Khan, R.; Weisz, D.; Contessoto, V. G.; Oliveira Junior, A. B.; Kalluchi, A.; Omer, A. D.; Batra, S. S.; Shamim, M. S.; Durand, N. C.; O&amp;#39;Connell, B.; Roca, A. L.; Gnirke, A.; Garcia-Trevino, I.; Coke, R.; Flanagan, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the hype: large language models propagate race-based medicine
Authors: Omiye, J. A.; Lester, J.; Spichak, S.; Rotemberg, V.; Daneshjou, R.
Score: 63.0, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292192
ImportanceLarge language models (LLMs) are being integrated into healthcare systems; but these models recapitulate harmful, race-based medicine. ObjectiveThe objective of this study is to assess whether four commercially available large language models (LLMs) propagate harmful, inaccurate, race-based content when responding to eight different scenarios that historically included race-based medicine or widespread misconceptions around race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics and quality of studies pertaining to masks published in the Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report
Authors: Hoeg, T. B.; Haslam, A.; Prasad, V.
Score: 454.0, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292338
ImportanceBecause the MMWR has substantial influence on United States public health policy and is not externally peer-reviewed, it is critical to understand the scientific process within the journal. Mask policies during COVID is one topic that has been highly influenced by data published in the MMWR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell transcriptomic analysis of NK cell dynamics in myeloma patients reveal persistent reduction of cytotoxic NK cells from diagnosis to relapse
Authors: Tahri, S.; de Jong, M. M. E.; Fokkema, C.; Papazian, N.; Kellermayer, Z.; Vermeulen, M.; Van Duin, M.; Van Beek, G.; Hoogenboezem, R.; Van De Woestijne, P.; Nasserinejad, K.; Saraci, E.; D&amp;#39;Agostino, M.; Gay, F.; Van Der Velden, V.; Sanders, M.; Zweegman, S.; Van De Donk, N.; Broijl, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Risk of SARS-CoV-2 reinfection during multiple Omicron variant waves in the UK general population
Authors: Wei, J.; Stoesser, N.; Matthews, P.; Khera, T.; Gethings, O.; Diamond, I.; Studley, R.; Taylor, N.; peto, t. E.; Walker, A. S.; Pouwels, K.; Eyre, D. W.
Score: 78.2, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.23292043
SARS-CoV-2 reinfections increased substantially after Omicron variants emerged. Large-scale community-based comparisons across multiple Omicron waves of reinfection characteristics, risk factors, and protection afforded by previous infection and vaccination, are limited, especially after widespread national testing stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>ORBIT for E. coli: Kilobase-scale oligonucleotide recombineering at high throughput and high efficiency
Authors: Saunders, S. H.; Ahmed, A. M.
Score: 40.5, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.546561
Microbiology and synthetic biology depend on reverse genetic approaches to manipulate bacterial genomes; however, existing methods require molecular biology to generate genomic homology, suffer from low efficiency, and are not easily scaled to high throughput applications. To overcome these limitations, we developed a system for creating kilobase-scale genomic modifications that uses DNA oligonucleotides to direct the integration of a non-replicating plasmid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Chromatin remodeling of histone H3 variants underlies epigenetic inheritance of DNA methylation
Authors: Lee, S. C.; Adams, D. W.; Ipsaro, J. J.; Cahn, J.; Lynn, J.; Kim, H.-S.; Berube, B.; Major, V.; Calarco, J. P.; LeBlanc, C.; Bhattacharjee, S.; Ramu, U.; Grimanelli, D.; Jacob, Y.; Voigt, P.; Joshua-Tor, L.; Martienssen, R. A.
Score: 20.5, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.11.548598
Epigenetic inheritance refers to the faithful replication of DNA methylation and histone modification independent of DNA sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of commensal gut microbiota signatures as predictors of clinical severity and disease progression in multiple sclerosis
Authors: Montgomery, T. L.; Wang, Q.; Mirza, A.; Dwyer, D.; Wu, Q.; Dowling, C. A.; Martens, J. W.; Yang, J.; Krementsov, D. N.; Mao-Draayer, Y.
Score: 10.3, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291875
BackgroundMultiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic autoimmune disease of the central nervous system and a leading cause of neurological disability in young adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>What can 1.8 billion regressions tell us about the pressures shaping high-level visual representation in brains and machines?
Authors: Conwell, C.; Prince, J. S.; Kay, K. N.; Alvarez, G. A.; Konkle, T.
Score: 104.8, Published: 2023-07-01 DOI: 10.1101/2022.03.28.485868
The rapid development and open-source release of highly performant computer vision models offers new potential for examining how different inductive biases impact representation learning and emergent alignment with the high-level human ventral visual system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Childhood growth trajectory patterns are associated with the pubertal gut microbiota
Authors: Lopez-Dominguez, L.; Bourdon, C.; Hamilton, J.; Taibi, A.; Bassani, D.; Vaz, J. d. S.; Buffarini, R.; Rodrigues, L. T.; dos Santos, I. d. S.; Matijasevich, A.; Borges, M. C.; Hanley, A.; Barros, A. J.; Bandsma, R. H. J.; Comelli, E.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291663
The relationship between growth and gut microbiota establishment is critical but under-investigated during late childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>The ADNEX risk prediction model for ovarian cancer diagnosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of external validation studies
Authors: Barrenada, L.; Ledger, A.; Dhiman, P.; Collins, G. S.; Wynants, L.; Verbakel, J. Y.; Timmerman, D.; Valentin, L.; Van Calster, B.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23291935
Objectives: To conduct a systematic review of studies externally validating the ADNEX model for ovarian cancer diagnosis and perform a meta-analysis of its performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Association of Genetic Ancestry with Molecular Tumor Profiles in Colorectal Cancer
Authors: Rhead, B.; Hein, D.; Pouliot, Y.; Guinney, J.; De La Vega, F. M.; Sanford, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292571
PurposePrior research in the molecular correlates of disparities in incidence and outcomes of colorectal cancer (CRC) by race and ethnicity have typically used self-reported or observed categories, which can be missing or inaccurate. Furthermore, race and ethnicity do not always capture genetic similarity well, particularly in admixed populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Diagnostic test accuracy of artificial intelligence in screening for referable diabetic retinopathy in real-world settings: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Uy, H.; Fielding, C.; Hohlfeld, A.; Ochodo, E.; Opare, A.; Mukonda, E.; Minnies, D.; Engel, M. E.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291687
Studies on artificial intelligence (AI) in screening for diabetic retinopathy (DR) have shown promising results in addressing the mismatch between the capacity to implement DR screening and the increasing DR incidence; however, most of these studies were done retrospectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning approaches to the phylogenetic placement of extinct pollen morphotypes
Authors: Adaïme, M.-E.; Kong, S.; Punyasena, S. W.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.09.545296
The phylogenetic interpretation of pollen morphology is limited by our inability to recognize the evolutionary history embedded in pollen features. Deep learning offers tools for connecting morphology to phylogeny. Using neural networks, we developed an explicitly phylogenetic toolkit for analyzing the overall shape, internal structure, and texture of a pollen grain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Lung injury shifts pulmonary capillary endothelial cells towards regeneration-associated Lrg1&amp;#43; subpopulations with delayed dynamics in aged mice
Authors: Truchi, M.; Savary, G.; Cadis, H.; Lebrigand, K.; Baeri, A.; Lingampally, A.; Girard-Riboulleau, C.; Scribe, C.; Magnone, V.; Arguel, M.-J.; de Schutter, C.; Gautier-Isola, M.; Fassy, J.; Rezzonico, R.; Larrue, R.; Pluquet, O.; Perrais, M.; Hofman, V.; Marquette, C.-H.; Hofman, P.; Günther, A.; Ricard, N.; BARBRY, P.; Leroy, S.; Cauffiez, C.; Bellusci, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Refining the impact of genetic evidence on clinical success
Authors: Minikel, E. V.; Painter, J. L.; Dong, C. C.; Nelson, M. R.
Score: 51.0, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23291765
The cost of drug discovery and development is driven primarily by failure, with just [~]10% of clinical programs eventually receiving approval. We previously estimated that human genetic evidence doubles the success rate from clinical development to approval. In this study we leverage the growth in genetic evidence over the past decade to better understand the characteristics that distinguish clinical success and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Multidrug Efflux in Gram-Negative Bacteria: Rationally Modifying Compounds to Avoid Efflux Pumps
Authors: Gurvic, D.; Zachariae, U.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548850
Gram-negative bacteria cause the majority of critically drug-resistant infections, necessitating the rapid development of new drugs with Gram-negative activity. However, drug design is hampered by the low permeability of the Gram-negative cell envelope and the function of drug efflux pumps, which extrude foreign molecules from the cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Hip thrust and back squat training elicit similar gluteus muscle hypertrophy and transfer similarly to the deadlift
Authors: Plotkin, D. L.; Rodas, M. A.; Vigotsky, A.; McIntosh, M. C.; Breeze, E.; Ubrik, R.; Robitzsch, C.; Agyin-Birikorang, A.; Mattingly, M. L.; Michel, J. M.; Kontos, N. J.; Fruge, A. D.; Wilburn, C. M.; Weimar, W. H.; Bashir, A.; Beyers, R. J.; Henselmans, M.; Contreras, B. M.; Roberts, M. D.
Score: 78.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Teosinte Pollen Drive guides maize domestication and evolution by RNAi
Authors: Berube, B.; Ernst, E.; Cahn, J.; Roche, B.; de Santis Alves, C.; Lynn, J.; Scheben, A.; Siepel, A.; Ross-Ibarra, J.; Kermicle, J.; Martienssen, R. A.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548689
Meiotic drivers subvert Mendelian expectations by manipulating reproductive development to bias their own transmission. Chromosomal drive typically functions in asymmetric female meiosis, while gene drive is normally postmeiotic and typically found in males.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>LSD increases sleep duration the night after microdosing
Authors: Allen, N.; Jeremiah, A.; Murphy, R.; Sumner, R.; Forsyth, A.; Hoeh, N.; Menkes, D.; Evans, W.; Muthukumaraswamy, S.; Sundram, F.; Roop, P.
Score: 25.2, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.23291970
Microdosing psychedelic drugs, at a level below the threshold to induce hallucinations, is an increasingly common lifestyle practise. However, the effects of microdosing on sleep have not been previously reported. Here we report results from a Phase 1 randomised controlled trial in which 80 healthy adult male volunteers received a six week course of either LSD (10 {micro}g) or placebo with doses self-administered every third day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Risk of COVID-19 death in adults who received booster COVID-19 vaccinations: national retrospective cohort study on 14.6 million people in England
Authors: Ward, I. L.; Robertson, C.; Agrawal, U.; Patterson, L.; Bradley, D. T.; Shi, T.; de Lusignan, S.; Hobbs, R.; Sheikh, A.; Nafilyan, V.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23291596
ImportanceThe emergence of the COVID-19 vaccination has been critical in changing the course of the COVID-19 pandemic, with estimates suggesting vaccinations have prevented millions of deaths worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Characterizing personalized neuropathology in dementia and mild cognitive impairment with explainable artificial intelligence
Authors: Leonardsen, E. H.; Persson, K.; Grodem, E.; Dinsdale, N.; Schellhorn, T.; Roe, J. M.; Vidal-Pineiro, D.; Sorensen, O.; Kaufmann, T.; Marquand, A.; Selbaek, G.; Andreassen, O. A.; Wolfers, T.; Westlye, L. T.; Wang, Y.
Score: 5.5, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291592
Deep learning applied to magnetic resonance imaging data have shown great promise as a translational technology for diagnosis and prognosis in dementia, but its impact clinically has thus far been limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Unreviewed science in the news: The evolution of preprint media coverage from 2014-2021
Authors: Fleerackers, A.; Shores, K.; Chtena, N.; Alperin, J. P.
Score: 13.7, Published: 2023-07-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548392
It has been argued that preprint coverage during the COVID-19 pandemic constituted a paradigm shift in journalism norms and practices. This study examines whether, in what ways, and to what extent this is the case using a sample of 11,538 preprints posted on four preprint servers--bioRxiv, medRxiv, arXiv, and SSRN--that received coverage in 94 English-language media outlets between 2014-2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Late reproduction is associated with extended female survival but not with familial longevity
Authors: Kat, A. d.; Roelofs, F.; Slagboom, E.; Broekmans, F.; Beekman, M.; Berg, N. v. d.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291896
ObjectiveFemale reproductive health comprises adequate oocyte quality and quantity, normal fecundability, a normal course of pregnancy, and the delivery of healthy offspring. General aging patterns and the maintenance of somatic health have been associated with female reproductive health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alterations of the gut microbiome are associated with epigenetic age acceleration and physical fitness
Authors: Torma, F.; Kerepesi, C.; Jokai, M.; Bakonyi, P.; Koltai, E.; Babszki, G.; Ligeti, B.; Kalcsevszki, R.; McGreevy, K. M.; Horvath, S.; Radak, Z.
Score: 21.7, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292191
Epigenetic clocks can measure aging and predict the incidence of diseases and mortality. Higher levels of physical fitness are associated with a slower aging process and a healthier lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Emergent digital bio-computation through spatial diffusion and engineered bacteria
Authors: Fedorec, A. J. H.; Treloar, N. J.; Wen, K. Y.; Dekker, L.; Ong, Q. H.; Jurkeviciute, G.; Lyu, E.; Rutter, J.; Rosa, L.; Zaikin, A.; Barnes, C. P.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548081
Building computationally capable biological systems has long been an aim of synthetic biology. The potential utility of biocomputing devices ranges from biosafety and environmental applications to diagnosis and personalised medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Does ribosome composition maximize growth rate? The role of RNA instability
Authors: Szeliova, D.; Müller, S.; Zanghellini, J.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548114
Ribosomes are protein synthesis machines that are central to cellular self-fabrication, and the synthesis time of a ribosome places an upper bound on growth rate. While most cellular enzymes are proteins, ribosomes consist of 1/3 protein and 2/3 RNA (in E. coli). Recent research suggests that ribosome composition arises from a trade-off between two &amp;#34;autocatalytic loops&amp;#34;, ribosomal protein and RNA polymerase synthesis, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Meta-analysis of gonadal transcriptomes in protogynous fishes provides novel perspective into sex change machinery
Authors: Nozu, R.; Kadota, M.; Nakamura, M.; Kuraku, S.; Bono, H.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.09.545663
Protogynous fishes can change sex from female to male; concomitantly, their ovarian tissue is completely replaced by testicular tissue. The high functional conservation of gonads across organisms suggests the existence of as-yet-undefined common and essential factors in the regulation of such gonadal transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
