<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence of Substance Use and related Behaviors among Tertiary Students: A Cross-sectional Survey in Yaounde, Cameroon
Authors: Edzamba, M. F.; Lekeumo Cheuyem, F. Z.; Amani, A.; Mossus, T.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.24301042
BackgroundThe use of psychoactive substances is a major global public health problem. People aged 15-24 years are more likely to abuse psychoactive substances than the general population. Substances use among youth, especially students in higher education is increasing rapidly worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the autoreactome: Proteome-wide immunological fingerprints reveal the promise of plasma cell depleting therapy
Authors: Bodansky, A.; Yu, D. J.; Rallistan, A.; Kalaycioglu, M.; Boonyaratanakornkit, J.; Green, D. J.; Gauthier, J.; Turtle, C. J.; Zorn, K.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, B.; Mandel-Brehm, C.; Asaki, J.; Kortbawi, H.; Kung, A. F.; Rackaityte, E.; Wang, C.-Y.; Saxena, A.; de Dios, K.; Masi, G.; Nowak, R. J.; O&amp;#39;Connor, K. C.; Li, H.; Diaz, V. E.; Casaletto, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Sound-seeking before and after hearing loss in mice
Authors: Mai, J.; Gargiullo, R.; Zheng, M.; Esho, V.; Hussein, O. E.; Pollay, E.; Bowe, C.; Williamson, L. M.; McElroy, A. F.; Goolsby, W. N.; Brooks, K. A.; Rodgers, C. C.
Score: 21.6, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574475
How we move our bodies affects how we perceive sound. For instance, we can explore an environment to seek out the source of a sound and we can use head movements to compensate for hearing loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Human coronavirus HKU1 recognition of the TMPRSS2 host receptor
Authors: McCallum, M.; Park, Y.-J.; Stewart, C.; Sprouse, K. R.; Brown, J.; Tortorici, M. A.; Gibson, C.; Wong, E.; Ieven, M.; Telenti, A.; Veesler, D.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.574565
The human coronavirus HKU1 spike (S) glycoprotein engages host cell surface sialoglycans and transmembrane protease serine 2 (TMPRSS2) to initiate infection. The molecular basis of HKU1 binding to TMPRSS2 and determinants of host receptor tropism remain elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Saponin Nanoparticle Adjuvants Incorporating Toll-Like Receptor Agonists Improve Vaccine Immunomodulation
Authors: Ou, B. S.; Baillet, J.; Filsinger Interrante, M. V.; Adamska, J. Z.; Zhou, X.; Saouaf, O.; Yan, J.; Klich, J.; Jons, C. K.; Meany, E.; Valdez, A. S.; Carter, L.; Pulendran, B.; King, N. P.; Appel, E.
Score: 141.8, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.16.549249
Over the past few decades, the development of potent and safe immune-activating adjuvant technologies has become the heart of intensive research in the constant fight against highly mutative and immune evasive viruses such as influenza, SARS-CoV-2, and HIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Sequence clustering confounds AlphaFold2
Authors: Schafer, J. W.; Chakravarty, D.; Chen, E. A.; Porter, L. L.
Score: 23.3, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574434
Though typically associated with a single folded state, some globular proteins remodel their secondary and/or tertiary structures in response to cellular stimuli. AlphaFold21 (AF2) readily generates one dominant protein structure for these fold-switching (a.k.a. metamorphic) proteins2, but it often fails to predict their alternative experimentally observed structures3,4. Wayment-Steele, et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Single molecule delivery into living cells
Authors: Chau, C.; Maffeo, C.; Aksimentiev, A.; Radford, S.; Hewitt, E.; Actis, P.
Score: 12.6, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.574652
Controlled manipulation of cultured cells by delivery of exogenous macromolecules is a cornerstone of experimental biology. Here we describe a platform which uses nanopipettes to deliver defined numbers of macromolecules into cultured cell lines and primary cells at single molecule resolution. In the nanoinjection platform the nanopipette is used as both a scanning ion conductance microscope (SICM) scanning probe and as an injection probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Direct excitatory synapses between neurons and tumor cells drive brain metastatic seeding of breast cancer and melanoma
Authors: Venkataramani, V.; Karreman, M. A.; Nguyen, L. C.; Tehranian, C.; Hebach, N.; Mayer, C.; Meyer, L.; Mughal, S.; Reifenberger, G.; Felsberg, J.; Koehrer, K.; Schubert, M. C.; Westphal, D.; Breckwolt, M.; Brors, B.; Wick, W.; Kuner, T.; Winkler, F.
Score: 135.0, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574608
Interactions between neurons and cancer cells are found in many malignancies, but their relevance for metastatic organ colonization remain largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Interpretable Machine Learning Leverages Proteomics to Improve Cardiovascular Disease Risk Prediction and Biomarker Identification
Authors: Climente-Gonzalez, H.; Oh, M.; Chajewska, U.; Hosseini, R.; Mukherjee, S.; Gan, W.; Traylor, M.; Hu, S.; Fatemifar, G.; Del Villar, P. P.; Vernet, E.; Koelling, N.; Du, L.; Abraham, R.; Li, C.; Howson, J. M. M.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301213
Cardiovascular diseases (CVD), primarily coronary heart disease and stroke, rank amongst the leading causes of long-term disability and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Human cytomegalovirus deploys molecular mimicry to recruit VPS4A to sites of virus assembly
Authors: Butt, B. G.; Fischer, D.; Rep, A. R.; Schauflinger, M.; Read, C.; Bock, T.; Hirner, M.; Graham, S. C.; von Einem, J.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.572781
The AAA-type ATPase VPS4 is recruited by proteins of the endosomal sorting complex required for transport III (ESCRT-III) to catalyse membrane constriction and membrane fission. VPS4A accumulates at the cytoplasmic viral assembly complex (cVAC) of cells infected with human cytomegalovirus (HCMV), the site where nascent virus particles obtain their membrane envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell transcriptional dynamics in a living vertebrate
Authors: Eck, E.; Moretti, B.; Schlomann, B. H.; Bragantini, J.; Lange, M.; Zhao, X.; VijayKumar, S.; Valentin, G.; Loureiro, C.; Soroldoni, D.; Royer, L. A.; Oates, A. C.; Garcia, H. H.
Score: 27.3, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574108
The ability to quantify transcriptional dynamics in individual cells via live imaging has revolutionized our understanding of gene regulation. However, such measurements are lacking in the context of vertebrate embryos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Step selection analysis with non-linear and random effects in mgcv
Authors: Klappstein, N. J.; Michelot, T.; Fieberg, J.; Pedersen, E. J.; Field, C.; Mills Flemming, J.
Score: 21.8, Published: 2024-01-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574363
Step selection analysis is used to jointly describe animal movement patterns and habitat preferences. Recent work has extended this framework to model inter-individual differences, account for unexplained structure in animals space use, and capture temporally-varying patterns of movement and habitat selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 73.0, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Adverse Events Following SARS-CoV-2 mRNA Vaccination in Adolescents: A Norwegian Nationwide Register-Based Study
Authors: Bergstad Larsen, V.; Gunnes, N.; Gran, J. M.; Boas, H.; Dahl, J.; Viksmoen Watle, S.; Berild, J. D.; Greve-Isdahl, M.; Stoerdal, K.; Gulseth, H.; Karlstad, O.; Lopez-Doriga Ruiz, P.; Tapia, G.
Score: 809.1, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.23299926
BackgroundVaccination of older adolescents against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) started in the spring of 2021 and continued with younger adolescents throughout the summer and fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA methylation enables recurrent endogenization of giant viruses in an animal relative
Authors: Sarre, L. A.; Kim, I. V.; Ovchinnikov, V.; Olivetta, M.; Suga, H.; Dudin, O.; Sebe-Pedros, A.; de Mendoza, A.
Score: 55.0, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574619
5-methylcytosine (5mC) is a widespread silencing mechanism that controls genomic parasites. However, in many eukaryotes 5mC has gained complex roles in gene regulation beyond parasite control. Animals are a quintessential case for 5mC evolution, as they show widespread variability across lineages, ranging from gene regulation and transposable element control to loss of this base modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Impact of genome build on RNA-seq interpretation and diagnostics
Authors: Ungar, R. A.; Goddard, P. C.; Jensen, T. D.; Degalez, F.; Smith, K. S.; Jin, C. A.; Undiagnosed Diseases Network, ; Bonner, D. E.; Bernstein, J. A.; Wheeler, M. T.; Montgomery, S. B.
Score: 15.9, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.24301165
Transcriptomics is a powerful tool for unraveling the molecular effects of genetic variants and disease diagnosis. Prior studies have demonstrated that choice of genome build impacts variant interpretation and diagnostic yield for genomic analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Associations between common genetic variants and income provide insights about the socioeconomic health gradient
Authors: Kweon, H.; Burik, C. A. P.; Ning, Y.; Ahlskog, R.; Xia, C.; Abner, E.; Bao, Y.; Bhatta, L.; Faquih, T.; Feijter, M.; Fisher, P.; Gelemanovic, A.; Giannelis, A.; Hottenga, J.-J.; Khalili, B.; Lee, Y.; Li-Gao, R.; Masso, J.; Myhre, R.; Palviainen, T.; Rietveld, C. A. P.; Teumer, A.; Verweij, R. M.; Willoughby, E. A.; Agerbo, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>mRNA initiation and termination are spatially coordinated
Authors: Calvo-Roitberg, E.; Carroll, C. L.; Venev, S. V.; Kim, G.; Mick, S. T.; Dekker, J.; Fiszbein, A.; Pai, A. A.
Score: 30.9, Published: 2024-01-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574404
The expression of a precise mRNA transcriptome is crucial for establishing cell identity and function, with dozens of alternative isoforms produced for a single gene sequence. The regulation of mRNA isoform usage occurs by the coordination of co-transcriptional mRNA processing mechanisms across a gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Development and Validation of an Intrinsic Capacity Score in the UK Biobank Study
Authors: Beyene, M. B.; Visvanathan, R.; Ahmed, M.; Benyamin, B.; Beard, J. R.; Amare, A. T.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2024-01-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.09.24301076
BackgroundIn 2015, the World Health Organization introduced the concept of intrinsic capacity (IC) to define the individual-level characteristics that enable an older person to be and do the things they value. This study developed an IC score for UK Biobank (UKB) study participants and validated its use as a tool for health outcome prediction, understanding healthy aging trajectories, and genetic research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of higher uptake of plant-based diets in England: model-based estimates of health care resource use and health-related quality of life
Authors: Henderson, N.; Sampson, C. J.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300536
Plant-based diets have grown in popularity in recent years, in part because of the perceived health benefits; higher consumption of vegetables and other healthy foods is associated with better nutrition and reduced risk of disease. In this study, we estimate the potential impact of higher uptake of a 100% plant-based (vegan) diet in England from the perspective of the National Health Service (NHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory electronic health record analysis with ehrapy
Authors: Heumos, L.; Ehmele, P.; Treis, T.; Upmeier zu Belzen, J.; Namsaraeva, A.; Horlava, N.; Shitov, V. A.; Zhang, X.; Zappia, L.; Knoll, R.; Lang, N. J.; Hetzel, L.; Virshup, I.; Sikkema, L.; Roellin, E.; Curion, F.; Eils, R.; Schiller, H. B.; Hilgendorff, A.; Theis, F.
Score: 55.8, Published: 2023-12-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299816
With progressive digitalization of healthcare systems worldwide, large-scale collection of electronic health records (EHRs) has become commonplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Network Modelling for the Clinical Diagnosis of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Bate St Cliere, A.-R.; Fenton, N.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300452
Alzheimers disease (AD) is a progressively debilitating disease commonly affecting the elderly. Correct diagnosis is important for patients to access suitable therapies and support that can help improve or manage symptoms of the condition. Reports of misdiagnosis and difficulty diagnosing AD highlight existing clinical challenges. Here we propose a Bayesian network as a preliminary model for a complementary clinical diagnostic tool for dementia due to AD and mild cognitive impairment due to AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Gene dysregulation among virally suppressed people living with HIV links to non-AIDS defining cancer pathways
Authors: Quach, B. C.; Earley, E.; Zhou, L.; Willis, C.; Marks, J. A.; Stratford, J. K.; Fang, F.; Bierut, L. J.; Milloy, M.-J. S.; Hayashi, K.; DeBeck, K.; Hancock, D. B.; Xu, K.; Aouizerat, B. E.; Johnson, E. O.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300792
Combination antiretroviral therapy (ART) has changed the landscape of the HIV epidemic by providing an effective means for viral suppression to people living with HIV (PLWH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Humoral immune responses to the monovalent XBB.1.5-adapted BNT162b2 mRNA booster
Authors: Marking, U.; Bladh, O.; Aguilera, K.; Yang, Y.; Greilert-Norin, N.; Blom, K.; Hober, S.; Klingstrom, J.; Havervall, S.; Aberg, M.; Sheward, D. J.; Thalin, C.
Score: 99.8, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.572575
Continued SARS-CoV-2 evolution and immune escape necessitated the development of updated vaccines, and a monovalent vaccine incorporating the XBB.1.5 variant spike protein is currently being rolled out. Amidst the emergence of the highly mutated BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Immunological imprinting shapes the specificity of human antibody responses against SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Johnston, T. S.; Li, S. H.; Painter, M. M.; Atkinson, R. K.; Douek, N. R.; Reeg, D. B.; Doueck, D. C.; Wherry, E. J.; Hensley, S. E.
Score: 83.9, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24301002
The spike glycoprotein of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) continues to accumulate substitutions, leading to breakthrough infections of vaccinated individuals and prompting the development of updated booster vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>UK medical students&amp;#39; self-reported knowledge and harm assessment of psychedelics and their application in clinical research: a cross-sectional study
Authors: Song-Smith, C.; Jacobs, E.; Rucker, J.; Saint, M.; Cooke, J.; Schlosser, M.
Score: 11.1, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300364
ObjectiveTo capture UK medical students self-reported knowledge and harm assessment of psychedelics and to explore the factors associated with support for changing the legal status of psychedelics to facilitate further research. DesignCross-sectional, anonymous online survey of UK medical students using a non-random sampling method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Lethal Infection of Human ACE2-Transgenic Mice Caused by SARS-CoV-2-related Pangolin Coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 1787.1, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) can cause 100% mortality in human ACE2-transgenic mice, potentially attributable to late-stage brain infection. This underscores a spillover risk of GX_P2V into humans and provides a unique model for understanding the pathogenic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2-related viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>A universal molecular mechanism driving aging
Authors: Jin, W.; Zheng, J.; Xiao, Y.; Ju, L.; Chen, F.; Fu, J.; Jiang, H.; Zhang, Y.
Score: 43.3, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.06.574476
How cell replication ultimately results in aging and the Hayflick limit are not fully understood. Here we show that clock-like accumulation of DNA G-quadruplexes (G4s) throughout cell replication drives conserved aging mechanisms. G4 stimulates transcription-replication interactions to delay genome replication and impairs DNA re-methylation and histone modification recovery, leading to loss of heterochromatin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Effects of changes in calculating GFR using KDIGO standards: Discordance in the Staging and Timing of Diagnosis of Chronic Kidney Disease
Authors: Baker, C.; Gratzl, S.; Rodriguez, P. J.; simonov, m.; Cartwright, B.; brar, r.; Stucky, N.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300415
IntroductionChronic kidney disease (CKD) is a highly prevalent disease with disparities in diagnosis and treatment. Until recently, primary diagnosis for CKD was based on equations that incorporated race and have demonstrated racial bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The use of continuous brain parenchymal impedance dispersion to measure glymphatic function in humans
Authors: Dagum, P.; Giovangrandi, L.; Levendovszky, S. R.; Winebaum, J. J.; Singh, T.; Cho, Y.; Kaplan, R. M.; Jaffe, M. S.; Lim, M. M.; Vandeweerd, C.; Iliff, J. J.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.06.24300933
Glymphatic function in animal models supports the clearance of brain proteins whose mis-aggregation is implicated in neurodegenerative conditions including Alzheimers and Parkinsons disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A choroid plexus apocrine secretion mechanism shapes CSF proteome and embryonic brain development
Authors: Courtney, Y.; Head, J. P.; Yimer, E. D.; Dani, N.; Shipley, F. B.; Libermann, T. A.; Lehtinen, M. K.
Score: 47.0, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574486
We discovered that apocrine secretion by embryonic choroid plexus (ChP) epithelial cells contributes to the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) proteome and influences brain development in mice. The apocrine response relies on sustained intracellular calcium signaling and calpain-mediated cytoskeletal remodeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>Long-term disgust habituation with limited generalisation in care home workers
Authors: Edgar, C.; Chan, F.; Armstrong, T.; Dalmaijer, E. S.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295198
Countless workers handle bodily effluvia and body envelope violations every working day, and consequentially face deeply unpleasant levels of disgust. Understanding if and how they adapt can help inform policies to improve worker satisfaction and reduce staff turnover. So far, limited evidence exist that self-reported disgust is reduced (or lower to begin with) among those employed in high-disgust environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 61.0, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 158.2, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omics profiling with untargeted proteomics for blood-based early detection of lung cancer
Authors: Koh, B.; Liu, M.; Almonte, R.; Ariad, D.; Bundalian, G.; Chan, J.; Choi, J.; Chou, W.-F.; Cuaresma, R.; Hoedt, E.; Hopper, L.; Hu, Y.; Jain, A.; Khaledian, E.; Khin, T.; Kokate, A.; Lee, J.-Y.; Leung, S.; Lin, C.-H.; Marispini, M.; Malekpour, H.; Mora, M.; Mudaliar, N.; Nouri Golmaei, S.; Ramaiah, M.; Ramaswamy, S.; Ranjan, P.; Shu, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Innate Immune Activation and Mitochondrial ROS Invoke Persistent Cardiac Conduction System Dysfunction after COVID-19
Authors: Ashok, D.; Liu, T.; Criscione, J.; Prakash, M.; Kim, B.; Chow, J.; Craney, M.; Papanicolaou, K.; Sidor, A.; Foster, D. B.; Pekosz, A.; Villano, J.; Kim, D.-H.; O&amp;#39;Rourke, B.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574280
BackgroundCardiac risk rises during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and in long COVID syndrome in humans, but the mechanisms behind COVID-19-linked arrhythmias are unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>AlphaFold2 structures template ligand discovery
Authors: Lyu, J.; Kapolka, N.; Gumpper, R.; Alon, A.; Wang, L.; Jain, M.; Alvarez, X.; Sakamoto, K.; Kim, Y.; DiBerto, J.; Kim, K.; Tummino, T.; Huang, S.; Irwin, J.; Tarkhanova, O.; Moroz, Y.; Skiniotis, G.; Kruse, A.; Shoichet, B.; Roth, B.
Score: 79.5, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572662
AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RosettaFold have greatly expanded the number of structures available for structure-based ligand discovery, even though retrospective studies have cast doubt on their direct usefulness for that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and fatty symbionts: photosynthetic productivity and carbon storage boosted in microalgae within a host
Authors: Catacora Grundy, A.; Chevalier, F.; Yee, D.; LeKieffre, C.; Schieber, N.; Schwab, Y.; Gallet, B.; Jouneau, P.-H.; Curien, G.; Decelle, J.
Score: 27.5, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572971
Symbiosis between a host and intracellular eukaryotic microalgae is a widespread life strategy in aquatic ecosystems. This partnership is considered to be mainly energized by the photosynthetically-derived carbon energy of microalgal symbionts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The origin, deployment, and evolution of a plant-parasitic nematode effectorome
Authors: Molloy, B.; Shin, D. S.; Long, J.; Pellegrin, C.; Senatori, B.; Vieira, P.; Thorpe, P. J.; Damm, A.; Ahmad, M.; Vermeulen, K.; Derevnina, L.; Wei, S.; Sperling, A.; Reyes Estevez, E.; Bruty, S.; de Souza, V. H. M.; Kranse, O. P.; Maier, T.; Baum, T.; Eves-van den Akker, S.
Score: 40.8, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574317
Plant-parasitic nematodes constrain global food security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Risk and early signs of PTSD in people indirectly exposed to October 7 events
Authors: Yamin, D.; Lev-Ari, S.; Mofaz, M.; Elias, R.; Spiegel, D.; Yechezkel, M.; L. Brandeau, M.; Shmueli, E.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300048
The coordinated terrorist attacks on October 7, 2023, resulted in catastrophic atrocities, and marked the beginning of the 2023 Israel-Hamas war. The overwhelming coverage by mainstream and social media, characterized by extreme details and graphic images, vividly transported viewers to the horrifying scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Barriers to healthcare access: findings from a co-produced Long Covid case-finding study
Authors: Clutterbuck, D.; Ramasawmy, M.; Pantelic, M.; Hayer, J.; Begum, F.; Faghy, M.; Nasir, N.; Causer, B.; Heightman, M.; Allsopp, G.; Wootton, D.; Khan, M. A.; Hastie, C.; Jackson, M.; Rayner, C.; Brown, D.; Parrett, E.; Jones, G.; Clarke, R.; Mcfarland, S.; Gabbay, M.; Banerjee, A.; Alwan, N. A.; STIMULATE-ICP Consortium, Score: 102.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300767</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 16.1, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Immersive Virtual Reality Games in Neuromotor Rehabilitation with Brain-Computer Interfaces: A Scoping Review
Authors: Gaafer, M. N.; Ahmed, Z. M.; El-Husseiny, A. S.; Youssef, A. R.; Al-Kabbany, A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24300991
The use of immersive virtual reality (VR) is gaining traction among the scientific community as it opens great opportunities in the field of rehabilitation. By making use of video game mechanics and Brain computer interface (BCI) that is based on electroencephalography (EEG) signals, patients undergoing neurorehabilitation can be more engaged in rehabilitation training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Studentsourcing - aggregating and re-using data from a practical cell biology course
Authors: Goedhart, J.
Score: 24.9, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561479
Data that is generated by students during a course is often lost as there is no centrally organized collection and storage of the data. The loss of data prevents its re-use. To provide access to these data, I present an approach that I call studentsourcing. It collects, aggregates and re-uses data that is generated by students in a practical course on cell biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Unlocking de novo antibody design with generative artificial intelligence
Authors: Shanehsazzadeh, A.; McPartlon, M.; Kasun, G.; Steiger, A. K.; Sutton, J. M.; Yassine, E.; McCloskey, C.; Haile, R.; Shuai, R.; Alverio, J.; Rakocevic, G.; Levine, S.; Cejovic, J.; Gutierrez, J. M.; Morehead, A.; Dubrovskyi, O.; Chung, C.; Luton, B. K.; Diaz, N.; Kohnert, C.; Consbruck, R.; Carter, H.; LaCombe, C.; Bist, I.; Vilaychack, P.; Anderson, Z.; Xiu, L.; Bringas, P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open-ST: High-resolution spatial transcriptomics in 3D
Authors: Schott, M.; Leon-Perinan, D.; Splendiani, E.; Strenger, L.; Licha, J. R.; Pentimalli, T. M.; Schallenberg, S.; Alles, J.; Samut Tagliaferro, S.; Boltengagen, A.; Ehrig, S.; Abbiati, S.; Dommerich, S.; Pagani, M.; Ferretti, E.; Macino, G.; Karaiskos, N.; Rajewsky, N.
Score: 86.7, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572554
Spatial transcriptomics (ST) methods have been developed to unlock molecular mechanisms underlying tissue development, homeostasis, or disease. However, there is a need for easy-to-use, high-resolution, cost-efficient, and 3D-scalable methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 10:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>How smart was T. rex? Testing claims of exceptional cognition in dinosaurs and the application of neuron count estimates in palaeontological research
Authors: Caspar, K. R.; Gutierrez-Ibanez, C.; Bertrand, O. C.; Carr, T.; Colbourne, J.; Erb, A.; George, H.; Holtz, T. R.; Naish, D.; Wylie, D. R.; Hurlburt, G. R.
Score: 58.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.575006
Recent years have seen increasing scientific interest in whether neuron counts can act as correlates of diverse biological phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
