<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends and Adverse Outcomes of Xylazine Misuse: A Digital Surveillance Study
Authors: Bhagavathula, A. S.; Aldhaleei, W. A.; Kim, S.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302075
Background: Xylazine is an animal tranquilizer without approved medical use in humans that is increasingly being misused as an adulterant in illicit drugs. This study aimed to characterize national trends and adverse outcomes associated with the emerging misuse of xylazine using digital surveillance data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Repeated Hand Grip Strength is an Objective Marker for Disability and Severity of Key Symptoms in Post-COVID ME/CFS
Authors: Paffrath, A.; Kim, L.; Kedor, C.; Stein, E.; Rust, R.; Freitag, H.; Hoppmann, U.; Hanitsch, L. G.; Bellmann-Strobl, J.; Wittke, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Sotzny, F.
Score: 91.5, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301776
Post-COVID Syndrome (PCS) refers to a diverse array of symptoms that persist beyond 3 months of the acute phase of a SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Noxious stimulation induces self-protective behaviour in bumblebees
Authors: Gibbons, M.; Pasquini, E.; Kowalewska, A.; Read, E.; Gibson, S.; Crump, A.; Solvi, C.; Versace, E.; Chittka, L.
Score: 136.3, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575734
Self-grooming directed towards a noxiously-stimulated body part is one indicator that an animal may feel pain. In insects, the lack of evidence for such behaviour has been widely argued to reflect the absence of pain experiences. Here, we tested whether bumblebees (Bombus terrestris) selectively groom one of their antennae that was touched with a noxiously-heated (65 {square}C) probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Highly specific intracellular ubiquitination of a small molecule
Authors: Li, W.; Garcia-Rivera, E. M.; Mitchell, D. C.; Chick, J. M.; Maetani, M.; Knapp, J. M.; Matthews, G. M.; Shirasaki, R.; de Matos Simoes, R.; Viswanathan, V.; Pulice, J. L.; Rees, M. G.; Roth, J. A.; Gygi, S. P.; Mitsiades, C. S.; Kadoch, C.; Schreiber, S. L.; Ostrem, J. M. L.
Score: 75.3, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577493
Ubiquitin is a small, highly conserved protein that acts as a posttranslational modification in eukaryotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>A general platform for targeting MHC-II antigens via a single loop
Authors: Du, H.; Liu, J.; Jude, K. M.; Yang, X.; Li, Y.; Bell, B.; Yang, H.; Kassardjian, A.; Mobedi, A.; Parekh, U.; Sperberg, A.; Julien, J.-P.; Mellins, E.; Garcia, K. C.; Huang, P.
Score: 37.5, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577489
Class-II major histocompatibility complexes (MHC-IIs) are central to the communications between CD4&amp;#43; T cells and antigen presenting cells (APCs), but intrinsic structural features associated with MHC-II make it difficult to develop a general targeting system with high affinity and antigen specificity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>LazyAF, a pipeline for accessible medium-scale in silico prediction of protein-protein interactions
Authors: McLean, T. C.
Score: 94.7, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.577767
Artificial intelligence has revolutionized the field of protein structure prediction. However, with more powerful and complex software being developed, it is accessibility and ease of use rather than capability that is quickly becoming a limiting factor to end users. Here, I present a Google Colaboratory-based pipeline, named LazyAF, which integrates the existing ColabFold BATCH to streamline the process of medium-scale protein-protein interaction prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Cryo-EM structures of human cone visual pigments
Authors: Peng, Q.; Li, J.; Jiang, H.; Cheng, X.; Lu, Q.; Zhou, S.; Zhang, Y.; Lv, S.; Wan, S.; Yang, T.; Chen, Y.; Zhang, W.; Nan, W.; Che, T.; Li, Y.; Liao, H.; Zhang, J.
Score: 9.0, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.577689
Trichromatic color vision in humans constitutes a pivotal evolutionary adaptation, endowing individuals with the capacity to discern and discriminate a diverse spectrum of colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Therapeutic targeting of KRAS mutation-driven tumorigenesis by extracellular vesicles loaded with small interfering RNA
Authors: Zhai, Y.; Niu, S.; Qiu, T.; Yi, Y.; Yan, Y.; Hu, R.; He, X.; Xu, K.
Score: 51.5, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576015
RAS is a well-known oncogene contributing to significant proportion of cancer incidences, yet it remains as an undruggable target to majority of therapeutic modalities. Here, we explored the potential of extracellular vesicles (EVs) for therapeutic targeting of KRAS mutation-driven tumorigenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists modestly reduced blood pressure among patients with and without diabetes mellitus: A meta-analysis and meta-regression
Authors: RIVERA, F. B.; Lumbang, G. N.; Gaid, D. R. M.; Cruz, L. L.; Magalong, J. V.; Bantayan, N. R.; Lara-Breitinger, K. M.; Gulati, M.; Bakris, G. L.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.24301971
BackgroundThe cardiovascular benefits provided by glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists (GLP-1RAs) extend beyond weight reduction and glycemic control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Full-length direct RNA sequencing uncovers stress-granule dependent RNA decay upon cellular stress
Authors: Dar, S. A.; Malla, S.; Martinek, V.; Payea, M. J.; Lee, C. T.-Y.; Martin, J.; Khandeshi, A. J.; Martindale, J. L.; Belair, C.; Maragkakis, M.
Score: 22.6, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555629
Cells react to stress by triggering response pathways, leading to extensive alterations in the transcriptome to restore cellular homeostasis. The role of RNA metabolism in shaping the cellular response to stress is vital, yet the global changes in RNA stability under these conditions remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A new genetically tractable non-vertebrate system to study complete camera-type eye regeneration
Authors: Accorsi, A.; Pardo, B.; Ross, E.; Corbin, T. J.; McClain, M.; Weaver, K.; Delventhal, K.; Morrison, J. A.; McKinney, M. C.; McKinney, S. A.; Sanchez Alvarado, A.
Score: 75.0, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577494
Camera-type eyes are complex sensory organs susceptible to irreversible damage. Their repair is difficult to study due to the paucity of camera-type eye regeneration models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Sonic restoration: Acoustic stimulation enhances soil fungal biomass and activity of plant growth-promoting fungi
Authors: Robinson, J. M.; Cando-Dumancela, C.; Breed, M. F.
Score: 103.2, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575298
Ecosystem restoration interventions often utilise visible elements to restore an ecosystem (e.g., replanting native plant communities and reintroducing lost species). However, using acoustic stimulation to restore ecosystems has received little attention. Our study aimed to (a) investigate the potential effects of acoustic stimulation on fungal biomass and organic matter decomposition, which are both crucial components of ecosystem functioning and (b) assess the effect of acoustic stimulation on the growth rate and sporulation of the plant growth-promoting fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The CoLab-score rapidly and efficiently excludes COVID-19 at the emergency department without need for SARS-CoV-2 testing: a multicenter case-control study
Authors: Boer, A.-K.; Deneer, R.; Maas, M.; Ammerlaan, H.; van Balkom, R. H. H.; Leers, M. P.; Martens, R. J. H.; Buijs, M. M.; Kerremans, J. J.; Messchaert, M.; van Suijlen, J. D. E.; van Riel, N. A. W.; Scharnhorst, V.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301996
BackgroundRapid identification of emergency department (ED) patients with a possible COVID-19 infection is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>New Reference Values for Thyroid Volume by Ultrasound in German Children and Adolescents Under Iodine-Sufficient Conditions from a Population-Based Study
Authors: Hirtz, R.; Thamm, R.; Kuhnert, R.; Liesenkoetter, K.-P.; Thamm, M.; Grasemann, C.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24301932
ContextReliable reference values for thyroid ultrasound measurements are essential to effectively guide individual diagnostics and direct health care measures at the population level, such as iodine fortification programs. However, the latest reference values for total thyroid volume (Tvol) provided by the WHO in 2004 only apply to the 6 to 12-year-old age group and are limited to countries with a long history of iodine sufficiency, which does not reflect the situation in most European countries, including Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Effect of Paxlovid Treatment on Long COVID Onset: An EHR-Based Target Trial Emulation from N3C
Authors: Preiss, A.; Bhatia, A.; Zang, C.; Aragon, L. V.; Baratta, J. M.; Baskaran, M.; Blancero, F.; Brannock, M. D.; Chew, R. F.; Diaz, I.; Fitzgerald, M.; Kelly, E. P.; Zhou, A. G.; Weiner, M. G.; Carton, T. W.; Wang, F.; Kaushal, R.; Chute, C. G.; Haendel, M.; Moffitt, R.; Pfaff, E.; N3C, ; RECOVER, Score: 72.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Variation in Neural Crest Development and Functional Divergence of sox10 Paralogs Contribute to Morphological Diversification in Cichlid Fishes
Authors: Marconi, A.; Vernaz, G.; Karunaratna, A.; Ngochera, M. J.; Durbin, R.; Santos, M. E.
Score: 28.5, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.578004
Neural crest (NC) is a vertebrate-specific embryonic progenitor cell population at the basis of important vertebrate features such as the craniofacial skeleton and pigmentation patterns. Despite the wide-ranging variation of NC-derived traits across vertebrates, the contribution of NC to species diversification remains largely unexplored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Impact of extended Elexacaftor/Tezacaftor/Ivacaftor therapy on the gut microbiome in cystic fibrosis
Authors: Marsh, R.; Dos Santos, C.; Yule, A.; Dellschaft, N. S.; Hoad, C. L.; Ng, C.; Major, G.; Smyth, A. R.; Rivett, D.; van der Gast, C.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.24301982
BackgroundThere is a paucity of knowledge on the longer-term effects of CF transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) modulator therapies upon the gut microbiome and associated outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Evidence-based recommendations for gene-specific ACMG/AMP variant classification from the ClinGen ENIGMA BRCA1 and BRCA2 Variant Curation Expert Panel
Authors: Parsons, M. T.; de la Hoya, M.; Richardson, M. E.; Tudini, E.; Anderson, M.; Berkofsky-Fessler, W.; Caputo, S.; Chan, R. C.; Cline, M. C.; Feng, B.-J.; Fortuno, C.; Gomez-Garcia, E.; Hadler, J.; Hiraki, S.; Holdren, M.; Houdayer, C.; Hruska, K.; James, P.; Karam, R.; Leong, H. S.; Martins, A.; Mensenkamp, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Helicase-assisted continuous editing for programmable mutagenesis of endogenous genomes
Authors: Chen, X. D.; Chen, Z.; Wythes, G.; Zhang, Y.; Orr, B. C.; Sun, G.; Thao, K.; Vallurupalli, M.; Sun, J.; Borji, M.; Tkacik, E.; Chen, H.; Bernstein, B. E.; Chen, F.
Score: 27.8, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.577593
A major challenge in human genomics is to decipher the context specific relationship of sequence to function. However, existing tools for locus specific hypermutation and evolution in the native genome context are limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Systematic reconstruction of molecular pathway signatures using scalable single-cell perturbation screens
Authors: Jiang, L.; Dalgarno, C.; Papalexi, E.; Mascio, I.; Wessels, H.-H.; Yun, H.; Iremadze, N.; Lithwick-Yanai, G.; Lipson, D.; Satija, R.
Score: 48.9, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.576933
Recent advancements in functional genomics have provided an unprecedented ability to measure diverse molecular modalities, but learning causal regulatory relationships from observational data remains challenging. Here, we leverage pooled genetic screens and single cell sequencing (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Unequal access to diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis in England
Authors: Ponting, C. P.; Samms, G. L.
Score: 8.0, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302070
People with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS; sometimes referred to as chronic fatigue syndrome) experience very poor health-related quality of life and only rarely recover. ME/CFS has no curative treatment and no single diagnostic test. Public health and policy decisions relevant to ME/CFS require knowledge of its prevalence and barriers to diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The policy formulation process, and the role of actors in the policy formulation and implementation process: A policy analysis of the Kenyan free maternity policy
Authors: Oyugi, B.; Audi-Poquillon, Z.; Kendall, S.; Peckham, S.; Barasa, E.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.23300268
Kenya is one of the many African countries committed to advancing its health system reforms by providing affordable and equitable access to essential health services. In 2016, the Government of Kenya unveiled an expanded free maternity care policy called Linda Mama to provide essential health services for pregnant women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Prescribing pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) for HIV prevention: A cross-sectional survey of General Practitioners in Australia
Authors: Wu, J.; Fairley, C. K.; Grace, D.; Bavinton, B. R.; Fraser, D.; Chan, C.; Chow, E. P. F.; Ong, J. J.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301757
BackgroundPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is a safe and effective medication for preventing HIV acquisition. We examined Australian general practitioners (GP) knowledge of PrEP efficacy, characteristics associated with ever prescribing PrEP, and barriers to prescribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Cytotoxic CD4&amp;#43; T cells in the bone marrow compromise healthy ageing by enhancing granulopoiesis
Authors: Gabande-Rodriguez, E.; Soto-Heredero, G.; Carrasco, E.; Anerillas, C.; Escrig-Larena, J. I.; Delgado-Pulido, S.; Francos-Quijorna, I.; Gomez de las Heras, M. M.; Fernandez-Almeida, A.; Blanco, E. M.; Winand-Osete, E.; Zorita, V.; Martinez-Cano, J.; Garrido, A.; de Cabo, R.; Manes, S.; Gorospe, M.; Mittelbrunn, M.
Score: 50.1, Published: 2024-01-29 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577360
Neutrophils are the most abundant leukocytes in the blood, with numbers further increasing with age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Possible roles of phytochemicals with bioactive properties in the prevention of and recovery from COVID-19
Authors: Koyama, S.; Shields, V. D.; Heinbockel, T.; Joseph, P. V.; Adhikari, P.; Kaur, R.; Kumar, R.; Alizadeh, R.; Bhutani, S.; Calcinoni, O.; Mucignat-Caretta, C.; Chen, J.; Cooper, K. W.; Das, S.; Dominguez, P. R.; Guardia, M. D.; Klyuchnikova, M. A.; Laktionova, T. K.; MOri, E.; Namjoo, Z.; Nguyen, H.; Ozdener, M. H.; Parsa, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive ML-based Respiratory Monitoring System for Physiological Monitoring &amp;amp; Resource Planning in the ICU
Authors: Hüser, M.; Lyu, X.; Faltys, M.; Pace, A.; Hoche, M.; Hyland, S. L.; Yeche, H.; Burger, M.; Merz, T. M.; Rätsch, G.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301516
Respiratory failure (RF) is a frequent occurrence in critically ill patients and is associated with significant morbidity and mortality as well as resource use. To improve the monitoring and management of RF in intensive care unit (ICU) patients, we used machine learning to develop a monitoring system covering the entire management cycle of RF, from early detection and monitoring, to assessment of readiness for extubation and prediction of extubation failure risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Viroid-like colonists of human microbiomes
Authors: Zheludev, I. N.; Edgar, R. C.; Galiano, M. J. L.; De la Pena, M.; Babaian, A.; Bhatt, A. S.; Fire, A. Z.
Score: 592.1, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576352
Here, we describe the &amp;#34;Obelisks,&amp;#34; a previously unrecognised class of viroid-like elements that we first identified in human gut metatranscriptomic data. &amp;#34;Obelisks&amp;#34; share several properties: (i) apparently circular RNA [~]1kb genome assemblies, (ii) predicted rod-like secondary structures encompassing the entire genome, and (iii) open reading frames coding for a novel protein superfamily, which we call the &amp;#34;Oblins&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Programmable RNA writing with trans-splicing
Authors: Schmitt-Ulms, C.; Kayabolen, A.; Manero-Carranza, M.; Zhou, N.; Donnelly, K.; Nuccio, S. P.; Kato, K.; Nishimasu, H.; Gootenberg, J. S.; Abudayyeh, O. O.
Score: 112.7, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.578223
RNA editing offers the opportunity to introduce either stable or transient modifications to nucleic acid sequence without permanent off-target effects, but installation of arbitrary edits into the transcriptome is currently infeasible. Here, we describe Programmable RNA Editing &amp;amp; Cleavage for Insertion, Substitution, and Erasure (PRECISE), a versatile RNA editing method for writing RNA of arbitrary length and sequence into existing pre-mRNAs via 5&amp;#39; or 3&amp;#39; trans-splicing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating GPT-4 as a Clinical Decision Support Tool in Ischemic Stroke Management
Authors: Haim, A.; Katson, M.; Cohen-Shelly, M.; Peretz, S.; Aran, D.; Shelly, S.
Score: 55.0, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301409
Cerebrovascular diseases are the second most common cause of death worldwide and one of the major causes of disability burden. Advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) have the potential to revolutionize healthcare delivery, particularly in critical decision-making scenarios such as ischemic stroke management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Planar, Spiral, and Concentric Traveling Waves Distinguish Cognitive States in Human Memory
Authors: Das, A.; Zabeh, E.; Ermentrout, B.; Jacobs, J.
Score: 43.1, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577456
A fundamental challenge in neuroscience is explaining how widespread brain regions flexibly interact to support behaviors. We hypothesize that a mechanism of neural coordination is brain oscillations that propagate as traveling waves across the cortex in distinctive patterns that control when and where different regions interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of cancer incidence among Marines and Navy personnel and civilian workers exposed to contaminated drinking water at USMC Base Camp Lejeune
Authors: Bove, F. J.
Score: 89.2, Published: 2024-01-29 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.27.24301873
BackgroundDrinking water at U.S. Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, North Carolina was contaminated with trichloroethylene and other industrial solvents from 1953 to 1985. MethodsA cohort cancer incidence study was conducted of Marines/Navy personnel who, between 1975 and 1985, began service and were stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina (N=154,821) or Camp Pendleton, California (N=163,484), and civilian workers employed at Camp Lejeune (N=6,494) or Camp Pendleton (N=5,797) between October 1972 and December 1985.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Convergence for Inactivation of TGFβ Signaling Is a Common Feature of Advanced Pancreatic Cancer
Authors: Hong, J.; Kohutek, Z.; Zhang, H.; Karnoub, E.-R.; Kappagantula, R.; Wood, L. D.; Iacobuzio-Donahue, C.
Score: 5.7, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301554
We performed WES of 250 unique tumor tissues from 30 multiregion sampled pancreatic cancer research autopsies from patients diagnosed with advanced stage disease. We find that most genetic alterations in PDAC occur in a subclonal manner, and some genes occurred in a subclonal manner exclusively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Ophthalmic Manifestations of NAA10-Related and NAA15-Related Neurodevelopmental Syndrome: Analysis of Cortical Visual Impairment and Refractive Errors
Authors: Patel, R.; Park, A.; Marchi, E.; Gropman, A.; Whitehead, M.; Lyon, G. J.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.24302161
NAA10-related and NAA15-related neurodevelopmental syndrome, otherwise known as Ogden Syndrome, is known to present with varying degrees of intellectual disability, hypotonia, congenital cardiac abnormalities, seizures, and delayed speech and motor development. However, the ophthalmic manifestations of NAA10 and NAA15 mutations are not yet fully characterized or understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Adequacy of Morphological Models used in Palaeobiology
Authors: Mulvey, L. P. A.; May, M. R.; Brown, J. M.; Hoehna, S.; Wright, A. M.; Warnock, R. C. M.
Score: 31.7, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577179
Reconstructing the evolutionary history of different groups of organisms provides insight into how life originated and diversified on Earth. Phylogenetic trees are commonly used to estimate this evolutionary history, providing a hypothesis of the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>A drug cocktail of rapamycin, acarbose, and phenylbutyrate enhances resilience to features of early-stage Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease in aging mice
Authors: Wezeman, J.; Darvas, M.; Postupna, N.; Klug, J.; Mangalindan, R. S.; Keely, A.; Nguyen, K.; Johnson, C.; Rosenfeld, M.; Ladiges, W.
Score: 9.6, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577437
The process of aging is defined by the breakdown of critical maintenance pathways leading to an accumulation of damage and its associated phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Highly comparative time series analysis of oxygen saturation and heart rate to predict respiratory outcomes in extremely preterm infants
Authors: Qiu, J.; Di Fiore, J. M.; Krishnamurthi, N.; Indic, P.; Carroll, J. L.; Claure, N.; Kemp, J. S.; Dennery, P. A. A.; Ambalavanan, N.; Weese-Mayer, D.; Hibbs, A. M.; Martin, R. J.; Bancalari, E.; Hamvas, A.; Moorman, R.; Lake, D. E.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301724
ObjectiveHighly comparative time series analysis (HCTSA) is a novel approach involving massive feature extraction using publicly available code from many disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Selective degradation of multimeric proteins via chemically induced proximity to TRIM21
Authors: Lu, P.; Cheng, Y.; Xue, L.; Ren, X.; Chen, C.; Li, J.; Wu, Q.; Sun, S.; Hou, J.; Jia, W.; Li, C.; Qi, X.; Huang, N.; Han, T.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.578122
Targeted protein degradation (TPD) has emerged as an effective strategy to eliminate disease-causing proteins by inducing their interactions with the protein degradation machinery. First-generation TPD agents exploit a limited set of broadly expressed E3 ubiquitin ligases with constitutive activity, forbidding their application to proteins requiring higher levels of targeting selectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin protects the heart against chronic intermittent hypoxia through AMPK-dependent phosphorylation of HIF-1α
Authors: Moulin, S.; Blachot-Minassian, B.; Kneppers, A.; Thomas, A.; Paradis, S.; Bultot, L.; Arnaud, C.; Pepin, J.-L.; Bertrand, L.; Mounier, R.; Belaidi, E.
Score: 15.8, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575152
Chronic intermittent hypoxia (IH), a major feature of obstructive sleep apnea syndrome (OSA), is associated with a more severe myocardial infarction. In this study, we performed RNA sequencing of cardiac samples from mice exposed to IH, which reveals a specific transcriptomic signature of the disease, relative to mitochondrial remodeling and cell death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 114.2, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Development, validation, and clinical utility of Short-term AdVerse-effects of Electroconvulsive therapy (SAVE) Checklist
Authors: Uppinkudru, C.; Pathak, H.; K, R. K.; S, B.; Bagali, K.; Pantoji, M.; Ezhumalai, N.; Parlikar, R.; Shah, V.; Balachander, S.; Sreeraj, V. S.; Mehta, U. M.; Sinha, P.; Arumugham, S. S.; Venkatasubramanian, G.; Thirthalli, J.
Score: 7.3, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301691
Electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) is one of the most effective treatments in psychiatry. However, it has many cognitive and non-cognitive adverse effects (AEs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Safety Monitoring of Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA Vaccines Among Recipients 6 months and Older in the United States
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Smith, E. R.; Gruber, J. F.; Ondari, M.; Wong, H. L.; Hu, M.; Clarke, T. C.; McEvoy, R.; Amend, K. L.; Bleacher, D. C.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Seeger, J. D.; Secora, A.; Djibo, D. A.; Song, J.; Selvam, N.; DeShazo, J. P.; Clifford, R.; Abente, E.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Automated Deep Learning Segmentation of Cardiac Inflammatory FDG PET
Authors: Poitrasson-Riviere, A.; Vanderver, M.; Hagio, T.; Arida-Moody, L.; Moody, J. B.; Renaud, J. M.; Ficaro, E. P.; Murthy, V. L.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302113
Background: Fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography (FDG PET) with glycolytic metabolism suppression plays a pivotal role in diagnosing cardiac sarcoidosis. Reorientation of images to match perfusion datasets is critical and myocardial segmentation enables consistent image scaling and quantification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>The effect of post-acute rehabilitation setting on 90-day mobility after stroke: A difference-in-difference analysis
Authors: French, M. A.; Hayes, H. A.; Johnson, J. K.; Young, D. L.; Roemmich, R. T.; Raghavan, P.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24301026
BackgroundAfter discharged from the hospital for acute stroke, individuals typically receive rehabilitation in one of three settings: inpatient rehabilitation facilities (IRFs), skilled nursing facilities (SNFs), or home with community services (i.e., home health or outpatient clinics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathogenic autoantibody internalization in myositis
Authors: Pinal-Fernandez, I.; Munoz-Braceras, S.; Casal-Dominguez, M.; Pak, K.; Torres-Ruiz, J.; Musai, J.; Dell&amp;#39;Orso, S.; Naz, F.; Islam, S.; Gutierrez-Cruz, G.; Dolores Cano, M.; Matas-Garcia, A.; Padrosa, J.; Tobias-Baraja, E.; Garrabou, G.; Aldecoa, I.; Espinosa, G.; Simeon-Aznar, C. P.; Guillen-Del-Castillo, A.; Gil-Vila, A.; Trallero-Araguas, E.; Christopher-Stine, L.; Lloyd, T. E.; Liewluck, T.; Naddaf, E.; Stenzel, W.; Greenberg, S. A.; Maria Grau, J.; Selva-O&amp;#39;Callaghan, A.; Milisenda, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Undergraduate Research in the Department of Biology at Western University: Effect on project types, learning outcomes, and student perceptions.
Authors: Chaplin, A.; Kohalmi, S. E.; Simon, A. F.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.577125
Undergraduate research is a high impact practice that offers numerous benefits to students, academic institutions, and the wider scientific community. Unfortunately, undergraduate research has faced restrictions due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA-Diffusion: Leveraging Generative Models for Controlling Chromatin Accessibility and Gene Expression via Synthetic Regulatory Elements
Authors: Ferreira DaSilva, L.; Senan, S.; Patel, Z. M.; Reddy, A. J.; Gabbita, S.; Nussbaum, Z.; Cordova, C. M. V.; Wenteler, A.; Weber, N.; Tunjic, T. M.; Khan, T. A.; Li, Z.; Smith, C. R.; Bejan, M.; Louis, L. K.; Cornejo, P.; Connell, W.; Wong, E. S.; Meuleman, W.; Pinello, L.
Score: 54.8, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic mapping of antibiotic cross-resistance and collateral sensitivity with chemical genetics
Authors: Sakenova, N.; Cacace, E.; Orakov, A.; Huber, F.; Varik, V.; Kritikos, G.; Michiels, J.; Bork, P.; Cossart, P.; Goemans, C.; Typas, A.
Score: 45.7, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.576750
By acquiring or evolving resistance to one antibiotic, bacteria can become resistant to a second one, due to shared underlying mechanisms. This is called cross-resistance (XR) and further limits therapeutic choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>MRI-Targeted Prostate Biopsy Introduces Grade Inflation and Overtreatment
Authors: Batouche, A. O.; Czeizler, E.; Lehto, T.-P.; Erickson, A.; Shadbahr, T.; Laajala, T. D.; Pohjonen, J.; Vickers, A. J.; Mirtti, T.; Rannikko, A. S.
Score: 8.4, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.24300922
PurposeThe use of MRI-targeted biopsies has led to lower detection of Gleason Grade Group 1 (GG1) prostate cancer and increased detection of GG2 disease. Although this finding is generally attributed to improved sensitivity and specificity of MRI for aggressive cancers, it might also be explained by grade inflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 10:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Microalgal biofilm induces larval settlement in the model marine worm Platynereis dumerilii
Authors: Hird, C.; Jekely, G.; Williams, E. A.
Score: 7.0, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576855
A free-swimming larval stage features in many marine invertebrate life cycles. To transition to a seafloor-dwelling juvenile stage, larvae need to settle out of the plankton, guided by specific environmental cues that lead them to an ideal habitat for their future life on the seafloor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
