<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 58.9, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Protein Ensemble Generation through VariationalAutoencoder Latent Space Sampling
Authors: Mansoor, S.; Baek, M.; Park, H.; Lee, G. R.; Baker, D.
Score: 28.9, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.551540
Mapping the ensemble of protein conformations that contribute to function and can be targeted by small molecule drugs remains an outstanding challenge. Here we explore the use of soft-introspective variational autoencoders for reducing the challenge of dimensionality in the protein structure ensemble generation problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell precision nanotechnology in vivo
Authors: MOLBAY, M.; Kick, B.; Zhao, S.; Todorov, M. I.; Ohn, T.-L.; Roth, S.; Simats, A.; Singh, V.; Khalin, I.; Pan, C.; Singh Bhatia, H.; Hellal, F.; Zeidler, R.; Liesz, A.; Plesnila, N.; Dietz, H.; Erturk, A.
Score: 143.8, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550304
Targeting nanoparticle therapeutics with cellular accuracy in whole organisms could open breakthrough opportunities in precision medicine. However, evaluating and fine-tuning the biodistribution of such systems in the whole organism at the cellular level remains a major obstacle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>phytools 2.0: An updated R ecosystem for phylogenetic comparative methods (and other things)
Authors: Revell, L. J.
Score: 205.4, Published: 2023-08-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.08.531791
Phylogenetic comparative methods comprise the general endeavor of using an estimated phylogenetic tree (or set of trees) to make secondary inferences: about trait evolution, diversification dynamics, biogeography, community ecology, and a wide range of other phenomena or processes. Over the past ten years or so, the phytools R package (Revell 2012) has grown to become an important research tools for phylogenetic comparative analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Cell Membranes Sustain Phospholipid Imbalance Via Cholesterol Asymmetry
Authors: Doktorova, M.; Symons, J. L.; Zhang, X.; Wang, H.-Y.; Schlegel, J.; Lorent, J. H.; Heberle, F. A.; Sezgin, E.; Lyman, E.; Levental, K. R.; Levental, I.
Score: 112.7, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.30.551157
Membranes are molecular interfaces that insulate cells from external stresses, compartmentalize the cytoplasm, and control the flow of nutrients and information1. These functions are facilitated by diverse collections of lipids, nearly all of which are distributed asymmetrically between the two leaflets of living bilayers2,3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 625.9, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Influenza Vaccination and Major Cardiovascular Risk: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Clinical Trials Studies
Authors: Omidi, F.; Zangiabadian, M.; Shahidi Bonjar, A. H.; Nasiri, M. J.; Sarmastzadeh, T.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.23293585
Background: Cardiovascular events remain a substantial global health concern, necessitating innovative strategies for prevention. This study aims to assess the potential impact of influenza vaccination on major cardiovascular events. Methods: A search of the medical English literature was conducted using PubMed/MEDLINE, EMBASE, and the Cochrane CENTRAL up to 1 August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Sulfolobus acidocaldarius adhesion pili power twitching motility in the absence of a dedicated retraction ATPase
Authors: Charles-Orszag, A.; van Wolferen, M.; Lord, S. J.; Albers, S.-V.; Mullins, D.
Score: 30.4, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.552066
Type IV pili are ancient and widespread filamentous organelles found in most bacterial and archaeal phyla where they support a wide range of functions, including substrate adhesion, DNA uptake, self aggregation, and cell motility. In most bacteria, PilT-family ATPases disassemble adhesion pili, causing them to rapidly retract and produce twitching motility, important for surface colonization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Loss of PAX6 alters the excitatory/inhibitory neuronal ratio in human cerebral organoids
Authors: Chan, W. K.; Negro, D.; Munro, V. M.; Marshall, H. L.; Kozic, Z.; Brown, M.; Beltran, M.; Henderson, N.; Price, D. J.; Mason, J. O.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.551262
The transcription factor PAX6 is a crucial regulator of multiple aspects of embryonic forebrain development. Its well-known roles in mice include regulating differentiation of excitatory and inhibitory neurons in the embryonic cortex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Global meta-analysis reveals overall benefits of silvopastoral systems for biodiversity
Authors: Perez-Alvarez, R.; Chara, J.; Snyder, L. D.; Bonatti, M.; Sieber, S.; Martin, E. A.
Score: 16.0, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.30.551160
Domestic livestock grazing accounts for roughly one quarter of the worlds terrestrial surface and is a leading driver of biodiversity loss. Yet, it also provides a critical livelihood for nearly one billion smallholder farmers, creating a paradox that highlights the need for conservation strategies to balance human and ecological needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Spatial Transcriptomic Analysis of Pituitary Corticotroph Tumors Unveils Intratumor Heterogeneity
Authors: Pina, J. O.; Faucz, F. R.; Padilla, C.; Floudas, C. S.; Chittiboina, P.; Quezado, M.; Tatsi, C.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.23293576
Spatial transcriptomic (ST) analysis of tumors provides a novel approach on studying gene expression along with the localization of tumor cells in their environment to uncover spatial interactions. Herein, we present ST analysis of corticotroph pituitary neuroendocrine tumors (PitNETs) from formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tissues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Influence of Prior SARS-CoV-2 Infection on COVID-19 Severity: Evidence from the National COVID Cohort Collaborative
Authors: Hendrix, N.; Sidky, H.; Sahner, D.; N3C Consortium, Score: 363.7, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293612
BackgroundAs SARS-CoV-2 has transitioned from a pandemic to endemic disease, the majority of new infections have been among previously infected individuals. To manage the risks and benefits of ongoing COVID-19 policies, it is important to understand whether prior infection modifies the severity of subsequent infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Functional Adaptations of Endogenous Retroviruses to the Drosophila Host Underlie their Evolutionary Diversification
Authors: Senti, K.-A.; Handler, D.; Rafanel, B.; Kosiol, C.; Schloetterer, C.; Brennecke, J.
Score: 50.6, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551782
Transposable elements profoundly affect the biology and evolution of their hosts, yet their own evolutionary dynamics remain poorly understood. Here, we investigate insect endogenous retroviruses (iERVs), a monophyletic group of LTR retrotransposons that have acquired the trait of infectivity, likely through capture of a Baculovirus envelope gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Copy-number variants as modulators of common disease susceptibility
Authors: Auwerx, C.; Joeloo, M.; Sadler, M. C.; Tesio, N.; Ojavee, S. E.; Clark, C. J.; Mägi, R.; Estonian Biobank Research Team, ; Reymond, A.; Kutalik, Z.
Score: 15.9, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293408
BackgroundCopy-number variations (CNVs) have been associated with rare and debilitating genomic syndromes but their impact on health later in life in the general population remains poorly described. MethodsAssessing four modes of CNV action, we performed genome-wide association scans (GWASs) between the copy-number of CNV-proxy probes and 60 curated ICD-10 based clinical diagnoses in 331,522 unrelated white UK Biobank participants with replication in the Estonian Biobank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Broad functional profiling of fission yeast proteins using phenomics and machine learning
Authors: Rodriguez-Lopez, M.; Bordin, N.; Lees, J.; Scholes, H.; Hassan, S.; Saintain, Q.; Kamrad, S.; Orengo, C.; Bähler, J.
Score: 60.5, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.05.535764
Many proteins remain poorly characterized even in well-studied organisms, presenting a bottleneck for research. We applied phenomics and machine-learning approaches with Schizosaccharomyces pombe for broad cues on protein functions. We assayed colony-growth phenotypes to measure the fitness of deletion mutants for 3509 non-essential genes in 131 conditions with different nutrients, drugs, and stresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>A computational pipeline for spatial mechano-transcriptomics
Authors: Hallou, A.; He, R.; Simons, B. D.; Dumitrascu, B.
Score: 21.3, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551894
Advances in spatial profiling technologies are providing insights into how molecular programs are influenced by local signaling and environmental cues. However, cell fate specification and tissue patterning involve the interplay of biochemical and mechanical feedback. Here, we develop a computational framework that enables the joint statistical analysis of transcriptional and mechanical signals in the context of spatial transcriptomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The principal component-based clinical aging clock (PCAge) identifies signatures of healthy aging and provides normative targets for clinical intervention
Authors: Fong, S.; Pabis, K.; Latumalea, D.; Dugersuren, N.; Unfried, M.; Tolwinski, N.; Kennedy, B.; Gruber, J.
Score: 25.3, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292604
Clinical healthy aging recommendations are disease-centric and reactive rather than focusing on holistic, organismal aging. In contrast, biological age (BA) estimation informs risk stratification by predicting all-cause mortality, however current BA clocks do not pinpoint aging mechanisms making it difficult to intervene clinically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Coding Inequity: Assessing GPT-4&amp;#39;s Potential for Perpetuating Racial and Gender Biases in Healthcare
Authors: Zack, T.; Lehman, E.; Suzgun, M.; Rodriguez, J. A.; Celi, L. A.; Gichoya, J.; Jurafsky, D.; Szolovits, P.; Bates, D. W.; Abdulnour, R.-E. E.; Butte, A. J.; Alsentzer, E.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292577
BackgroundLarge language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 hold great promise as transformative tools in healthcare, ranging from automating administrative tasks to augmenting clinical decision- making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Recommended distances for physical distancing during COVID-19 pandemics reveal cultural connections between countries
Authors: Chai, D.; El Mossadeq, L.; Raymond, M.; Orgogozo, V.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293497
During COVID-19 pandemic several public health measures were implemented by diverse countries to reduce the risk of COVID-19, including social distancing. Here we collected the minimal distance recommended by each country for physical distancing at the onset of the pandemic and aimed to examine whether it had an impact on the outbreak dynamics and how this specific value was chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Vascular injury markers associated with cognitive impairment in people with HIV on suppressive antiretroviral therapy
Authors: Guha, D.; Misra, V.; Yin, J.; Horiguchi, M.; Uno, H.; Gabuzda, D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23293053
ObjectiveHuman immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-associated neurocognitive disorders (HAND) remain prevalent despite viral suppression on antiretroviral therapy (ART). Vascular disease contributes to HAND, but peripheral markers that distinguish vascular cognitive impairment (VCI) from HIV-related etiologies remain unclear. DesignCross-sectional study of vascular injury, inflammation, and central nervous system (CNS) injury markers in relation to HAND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>The T cell receptor sequence influences the likelihood of T cell memory formation
Authors: Lagattuta, K. A.; Nathan, A.; Rumker, L.; Birnbaum, M. E.; Raychaudhuri, S.
Score: 55.3, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549939
T cell differentiation depends on activation through the T cell receptor (TCR), whose amino acid sequence varies cell to cell. Particular TCR amino acid sequences nearly guarantee Mucosal-Associated Invariant T (MAIT) and Natural Killer T (NKT) cell fates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Phenotyping the virulence of SARS-CoV-2 variants in hamsters by digital pathology and machine learning
Authors: Meehan, G. R.; Herder, V.; Allan, J.; Huang, X.; Kerr, K.; Mendonca, D. C.; Ilia, G.; Wright, D.; Nomikou, K.; Gu, Q.; Arias, S. M.; De Lorenzo, G.; Cowton, V.; Upfold, N.; Palmalux, N.; Brown, J. C.; Barclay, W.; Filipe, A. D. S.; Furnon, W.; Patel, A.; Palmarini, M.
Score: 916.1, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Intra-host variation in the spike S1/S2 region of a feline coronavirus type-1 in a cat with persistent infection
Authors: Olarte-Castillo, X. A.; Licitra, B. N.; Andre, N. M.; Sierra, M. A.; Mason, C. E.; Goodman, L. B.; Whittaker, G.
Score: 44.5, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.551356
Feline coronavirus type 1 (FCoV-1) is widely known for causing feline infectious peritonitis (FIP), a systemic infection that is often fatal, with the virus known as the FIPV biotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The use of machine learning methods in neurodegenerative disease research: A scoping review
Authors: Ciampi, A.; Rouette, J.; Pellegrini, F.; Simoneau, G.; Caba, B.; Gafson, A.; de Moor, C.; Belachew, S.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293414
Machine learning (ML) methods are increasingly used in clinical research, but their extent is complex and largely unknown in the field of neurodegenerative diseases (ND). This scoping review describes state-of-the-art ML in ND research using MEDLINE (PubMed), Embase (Ovid), Central (Cochrane), and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Xplore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Learning produces a hippocampal cognitive map in the form of an orthogonalized state machine
Authors: Sun, W.; Winnubst, J.; Natrajan, M.; Lai, C.; Kajikawa, K.; Michaelos, M.; Gattoni, R.; Fitzgerald, J. E.; Spruston, N.
Score: 64.7, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551900
Cognitive maps confer animals with flexible intelligence by representing spatial, temporal, and abstract relationships that can be used to shape thought, planning, and behavior. Cognitive maps have been observed in the hippocampus, but their algorithmic form and the processes by which they are learned remain obscure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Evidence-Based Practice Competencies among Nutrition Professionals and Students: A Systematic Review
Authors: Ghosh, N. R.; Esmaeilinezhad, Z.; Zajac, J.; Creasy, R. A.; Lorenz, S. G.; Crews, M.; Beathard, K. M.; Bala, M. M.; Klatt, K. C.; Johnston, B. C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293580
Background: Evidence-based practice (EBP) promotes shared decision-making between clinicians and patients and has been widely adopted by various health professions including nutrition &amp;amp; dietetics, medicine and nursing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Mistletoe as a Therapeutic Option in Cancer Patients: a scoping review protocol
Authors: Cordeiro, M. M.; Malta, F. A. P. S.; Goncalves, D. C.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.23293280
ObjectiveThis scoping review aims to identify, map and provide an overview of the studies investigating the therapeutic use of Viscum Album L. (mistletoe) in cancer patients. By identifying pivotal patterns and research gaps in the existing literature on Viscum therapy, this review intends to offer valuable insights and supportive information to better inform future research efforts in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omic spatial effects on high-resolution AI-derived retinal thickness
Authors: Jackson, V. E.; Wu, Y.; Bonelli, R.; Owen, J.; Farashi, S.; Kihara, Y.; Gantner, M. L.; Egan, C.; Williams, K. M.; Ansell, B. R.; Tufail, A.; Lee, A. Y.; Bahlo, M.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293176
Retinal thickness is a marker of retinal health and more broadly, is seen as a promising biomarker for many systemic diseases. Retinal thickness measurements are procured from optical coherence tomography (OCT) as part of routine clinical eyecare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Lack of early animal fossils: insights from taphonomic experiments on placozoans and their traces
Authors: Naimark, E.; Lyupina, Y. V.; Nikitin, M. A.; Finoshin, A. D.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551688
Placozoa are simple two-layered multicellular animals. Can such a simple animal preserve in the fossil record? The results of our taphonomic experiments showed that it is chemically possible; however, the chances of the presevation are negligible for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>An end-to-end workflow for non-destructive 3D pathology
Authors: Bishop, K. W.; Barner, L. A. E.; Han, Q.; Baraznenok, E.; Lan, L.; Poudel, C.; Gao, G.; Serafin, R. B.; Chow, S. S. L.; Glaser, A. K.; Janowczyk, A.; Brenes, D.; Huang, H.; Miyasato, D.; True, L. D.; Kang, S.; Vaughan, J. C.; Liu, J. T. C.
Score: 119.3, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551845
Recent advances in 3D pathology offer the ability to image orders-of-magnitude more tissue than conventional pathology while providing a volumetric context that is lacking with 2D tissue sections, all without requiring destructive tissue sectioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Plasma protein biomarkers distinguish Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome in Children (MIS-C) from other pediatric infectious and inflammatory diseases
Authors: Yeoh, S.; Estrada-Rivadeneyra, D.; Jackson, H.; Keren, I.; Galassini, R.; Cooray, S.; Shah, P.; Agyeman, P.; Basmaci, R.; Carrol, E.; Emonts, M.; Fink, C.; Kuijpers, T.; Martinon-Torres, F.; Mommert-Tripon, M.; Paulus, S.; Pokorn, M.; Rojo, P.; Romani, L.; Schlapbach, L.; Schweintzger, N.; Shen, C.-F.; Tsolia, M.; Usuf, E.; van der Flier, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>RNA splicing modulator induces peripheral neuropathy with increased neurofilament light chain levels via p53 signaling
Authors: Krach, F.; Boerstler, T.; Reischl, S.; Krumm, L.; Regensburger, M.; Winkler, J.; Winner, B.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551640
RNA splicing modulators are a new class of small molecules with the potential to modify the expression levels of proteins. A recent clinical trial investigating the splicing modulator branaplam for Huntingtons disease to lower huntingtin levels was terminated due to the development of peripheral neuropathy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of RyR2 distribution in HEK293 cells and mouse cardiac myocytes using 3D MINFLUX microscopy
Authors: Clowsley, A. H.; Meletiou, A.; Lucinskaite, E.; Jansen, I.; Jones, P. P.; Louch, W. E.; Soeller, C.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550636
The cardiac type 2 ryanodine receptor (RyR2) is a large homotetramer of a [~]560 kD subunit and is the molecular pathway through which the majority of Ca2&amp;#43; enters the cytosol during cardiac activation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mucilage produced by sorghum (Sorghum bicolor) aerial roots supports a nitrogen-fixing community
Authors: Venado, R. E.; Wilker, J.; Pankievicz, V.; Infante, V.; MacIntyre, A.; Wolf, E.; Vela, S.; Robbins, F. A.; Fernandes-Junior, P. I.; Vermerris, W.; Ane, J.-M.
Score: 68.9, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.05.552127
Sorghum (Sorghum bicolor) is gaining popularity as a sustainable energy crop due to its high biomass and potential for biofuel production. Some rare sorghum accessions develop many aerial roots that produce viscous carbohydrate-rich mucilage after rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Familial risk of postpartum psychosis
Authors: Kepinska, A. P.; Robakis, T.; Humphreys, K.; Liu, X.; Kahn, R. S.; Munk-Olsen, T.; Bergink, V.; Mahjani, B.
Score: 20.4, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23292910
BackgroundPostpartum psychosis, a mood disorder triggered by childbirth, is one of the most severe psychiatric conditions, with high risks of suicide and infanticide if untreated. While it is evident that genetic factors play a crucial role in disorder risk, the exact extent of their importance is yet to be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 892.6, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Frequency of Atypical Pulmonary Manifestations of COVID-19 Patients on Chest CTscan: A cross-sectional study
Authors: Borji, S.; Isavand, P.; Azami, M.; Ghafouri, E.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.23293261
BackgroundChest CT examination is significant in COVID-19 diagnosis due to its high sensitivity. Although typical chest CT findings have been discussed thoroughly in the literature throughout the pandemic, we aimed to investigate the prevalence of the atypical conclusions during the start of the Omicron variant insurgency and compare the results to studies conducted before its outbreak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Purchases dominate the carbon footprint of research laboratories
Authors: De Paepe, M.; Jeanneau, L.; Mariette, J.; Aumont, O.; Estevez-Torres, A.
Score: 33.7, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.04.535626
Despite increasing interest for the carbon footprint of higher education institutions, little is known about the carbon footprint associated to research activities. Air travel and attendance to conferences concentrate recent data and debates but purchases have attracted little attention. Here we develop a hybrid method to estimate the greenhouse gas emissions (GHG) associated to research purchases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The MidPIC study: Midwives knowledge, perspectives and learning needs regarding preconception and interconception care
Authors: Bradfield, Z.; Leefhelm, E.; Soh, S.-E.; Black, K.; Boyle, J.; Kuliukas, L.; Harrison, C.; Homer, C. S.; Smith, R. M.; Skouteris, H.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293432
BackgroundPreconception and interconception care improves the health outcomes of women and communities. ProblemLittle is known about how prepared and willing Australian midwives are to provide preconception and interconception care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Scoping Review of One-Dimension Statistical Parametric Mapping in Lower Limb Biomechanical Analysis
Authors: Yona, T.; Kamel, N.; Cohen-Eick, G.; Ovadia, I.; Fischer, A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293709
Background: Biomechanics is crucial in enhancing sports performance and preventing injury. Traditionally, discrete point analysis is used to analyze important kinetic and kinematic data points, reducing continuous data to a single point. One-dimensional Statistical Parametric Mapping (spm1d) offers a more comprehensive approach by assessing entire movement curves instead of isolated peak values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Engineering the highly productive cyanobacterium Synechococcus sp. PCC 11901
Authors: Victoria, A. J.; Selao, T. T.; Moreno-Cabezuelo, J. A.; Mills, L. A.; Gale, G. A.; Lea-Smith, D. J.; McCormick, A. J.
Score: 11.0, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.552009
Synechococcus sp. PCC 11901 (PCC 11901) is a fast-growing marine cyanobacterial strain that has a capacity for sustained biomass accumulation to very high cell densities, comparable to that achieved by commercially relevant heterotrophic organisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic exploration of prokaryotic form I rubisco maximal carboxylation rates
Authors: de Pins, B.; Greenspoon, L.; Bar-On, Y. M.; Shamshoum, M.; Ben-Nissan, R.; Milshtein, E.; Davidi, D.; Sharon, I.; Mueller-Cajar, O.; Noor, E.; Milo, R.
Score: 19.3, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550689
Autotrophy is the basis for complex life on Earth. Its physiological limits are largely constrained by rubisco - the enzyme that catalyzes almost all carbon fixation on the planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Welding fume exposure is associated with medial temporal lobe microstructural features resembling early Alzheimer disease
Authors: Lee, E.; Kim, J.; Prado-Rico, J. M.; Du, G.; Lewis, M. M.; Kong, L.; Yanosky, J. D.; Eslinger, P. J.; Kim, B.-G.; Hong, Y.-S.; Mailman, R. B.; Huang, X.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292828
IntroductionWelding fumes contain a mixture of metals and are an epitype for environmental metal-related neurotoxicity. Past studies of welders focused largely on basal ganglia regions and their association with parkinsonism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Routine surveillance of kidney allograft rejection using a fully automated urinary CXCL9 and CXCL10 immunoassay
Authors: Tinel, C.; Sauvaget, V.; Aouni, L.; Lamarthee, B.; Leclaire, C.; Legendre, C.; Marquet, P.; Normand, C.; Rabant, M.; Terzi, F.; Anglicheau, D.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293106
BackgroundFor kidney transplant recipients, assessing non-invasively the individualized risk of acute rejection is one of the most unmet need. Urinary chemokines are one of the short-term most promising biomarkers, because of their simple and low-cost analytical method in easily accessible samples, and their high diagnostic performance consistently assessed over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms in a prospective cohort of COVID-19 survivors
Authors: Gomes, C. M.; Hisano, M.; Souza, J. D.; Henriques, J. V. T.; De Bessa, J.; Moromizato, J.; Bosi, T.; Mazoni, R.; Gismondi, J.; Camargo, B.; Sammour, Z. M.; Bruschini, H.; Battistella, L. R.; Nahas, W. C.
Score: 28.6, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293500
PurposeTo analyze the prevalence of lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in patients who survived moderate and severe forms of COVID-19 and the risk factors for LUTS six months after hospital discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Primed and ready: Nanopore metabarcoding can now recover highly accurate consensus barcodes that are generally indel-free
Authors: Chang, J. J. M.; Ip, Y. C. A.; Neo, W. L.; Mowe, M. A. D.; Jaafar, Z.; Huang, D.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.552069
DNA metabarcoding applies high-throughput sequencing approaches to generate numerous DNA barcodes from mixed sample pools for mass species identification and community characterisation. To date, however, most metabarcoding studies employ second-generation sequencing platforms like Illumina, which are limited by short read lengths and longer turnaround times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
