<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Diverse prey capture strategies in teleost larvae
Authors: Mearns, D. S.; Hunt, S. A.; Schneider, M. W.; Parker, A. V.; Stemmer, M.; Baier, H.
Score: 21.2, Published: 2023-10-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.560453
Animal behavior is adapted to the sensory environment in which it evolved, while also being constrained by physical limits, evolutionary history, and developmental trajectories. The hunting behavior of larval zebrafish (Danio rerio), a cyprinid native to streams in Eastern India, has been well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Improving protein expression, stability, and function with ProteinMPNN
Authors: Sumida, K. H.; Nunez Franco, R.; Kalvet, I.; Pellock, S. J.; Wicky, B. I. M.; Milles, L. F.; Dauparas, J.; Wang, J.; Kipnis, Y.; Jameson, N.; Kang, A.; De La Cruz, J.; Sankaran, B.; Bera, A. K.; Jimenez Oses, G.; Baker, D.
Score: 85.5, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.560713
Natural proteins are highly optimized for function, but are often difficult to produce at a scale suitable for biotechnological applications due to poor expression in heterologous systems, limited solubility, and sensitivity to temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Molecular de-extinction of antibiotics enabled by deep learning
Authors: Wan, F.; Torres, M. D. T.; Peng, J.; de la Fuente, C.
Score: 87.3, Published: 2023-10-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.560353
Molecular de-extinction is an emerging field that aims to resurrect molecules to solve present-day problems such as antibiotic resistance. Here, we introduce a deep learning approach called Antibiotic Peptide de-Extinction (APEX) to mine the proteomes of all available extinct organisms (the &amp;#34;extinctome&amp;#34;) searching for encrypted peptide (EP) antibiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>SaProt: Protein Language Modeling with Structure-aware Vocabulary
Authors: Su, J.; Han, C.; Zhou, Y.; Shan, J.; Zhou, X.; Yuan, F.
Score: 42.4, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.560349
Large-scale protein language models (PLMs), such as the ESM family, have achieved remarkable performance in various downstream tasks related to protein structure and function by undergoing unsupervised training on residue sequences. They have become essential tools for researchers and practitioners in biology. However, a limitation of vanilla PLMs is their lack of explicit consideration for protein structure information, which suggests the potential for further improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Structural and quantum chemical basis for OCP-mediated quenching of phycobilisomes
Authors: Sauer, P. V.; Cupellini, L.; Sutter, M.; Bondanza, M.; Dominguez Martin, M. A.; Kirst, H.; Bina, D.; Koh, A. F.; Kotecha, A.; Greber, B. J.; Nogales, E.; Polivka, T.; Mennucci, B.; Kerfeld, C. A.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-09-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.30.560311
Cyanobacteria employ large antenna complexes called phycobilisomes (PBS) for light harvesting. However, intense light triggers non-photochemical quenching, where the Orange Carotenoid Protein (OCP) binds to PBS, dissipating excess energy as heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Alveolar differentiation drives resistance to KRAS inhibition in lung adenocarcinoma
Authors: Li, Z.; Zhuang, X.; Pan, C.-H.; Yan, Y.; Thummalapalli, R.; Hallin, J.; Torborg, S.; Singhal, A.; Chang, J. C.; Manchado, E.; Dow, L. E.; Yaeger, R.; Christensen, J. G.; Lowe, S. W.; Rudin, C. M.; Joost, S.; Tammela, T.
Score: 34.8, Published: 2023-10-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560194
Lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD), commonly driven by KRAS mutations, is responsible for 7% of all cancer mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Repurposing of Glatiramer Acetate to Treat Heart Diseases
Authors: Aviel, G.; Elkahal, J.; Umansky, K. B.; Bueno-Levy, H.; Miyara, S.; Lendengolts, D.; Zhang, L.; Petrover, Z.; Kain, D.; Shalit, T.; Aharoni, R.; Arnon, R.; Mishaly, D.; Katz, U.; Nachman, D.; Ammar, M.; Asleh, R.; Amir, O.; Tzahor, E.; Sarig, R.
Score: 5.7, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.30.23295943
Myocardial injury may ultimately lead to adverse ventricular remodeling and development of heart failure (HF), which is a major cause of morbidity and mortality worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Spatially and Functionally Distinct mTORC1 Entities Orchestrate the Cellular Response to Amino Acid Availability
Authors: Fernandes, S. A.; Angelidaki, D.-D.; Nuechel, J.; Pan, J.; Gollwitzer, P.; Elkis, Y.; Artoni, F.; Wilhelm, S.; Kovacevic-Sarmiento, M.; Demetriades, C.
Score: 51.4, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.559930
Amino acid (AA) availability is a robust determinant of cell growth, through controlling mTORC1 activity 1. According to the predominant model in the field, AA sufficiency drives the recruitment and activation of mTORC1 on the lysosomal surface by the heterodimeric Rag GTPases, from where it coordinates the majority of cellular processes (reviewed in 2,3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open top multi sample dual view light sheet microscope for live imaging of large multicellular systems
Authors: Moos, F.; Suppinger, S.; de Medeiros, G.; Oost, K.; Boni, A.; Remy, C.; Weevers, S.; Tsiairis, C. D.; Strnad, P.; Liberali, P.
Score: 95.9, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.559925
Multicellular systems grow over the course of weeks from single cells to tissues or even full organisms composed of several thousands of cells, making live imaging of such samples challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Bringing circuit theory into spatial occupancy models to assess landscape connectivity
Authors: Kervellec, M.; Couturier, T.; Bauduin, S.; Chenesseau, D.; Defos du Rau, P.; Drouet-Hoguet, N.; Duchamp, C.; Steinmetz, J.; Vandel, J.-M.; Gimenez, O.
Score: 21.0, Published: 2023-09-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.559320
Connectivity shapes species distribution across fragmented landscapes. Assessing landscape resistance to dispersal is challenging because dispersal events are rare and difficult to detect especially for elusive species. To address these issues, spatial occupancy models have been developed to integrate the resistance surface concept of landscape ecology and model patch occupancy dynamics through colonization and extinction while accounting for imperfect species detection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic Review of Treatment of Beta-Cell Monogenic Diabetes
Authors: Naylor, R. N.; Patel, K. A.; Kettunen, J. L. T.; Männistö, J. M. E.; Stoy, J.; Beltrand, J.; Polak, M.; ADA/EASD PMDI, ; Vilsobll, T.; Greeley, S. A. W.; Hattersley, A. T.; Tuomi, T.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.12.23289807
BackgroundBeta-cell monogenic forms of diabetes are the area of diabetes care with the strongest support for precision medicine. We reviewed treatment of hyperglycemia in GCK-related hyperglycemia, HNF1A- HNF4A- and HNF1B-diabetes, Mitochondrial diabetes (MD) due to m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Drug Overdose Mortality Rates by Educational Attainment and Sex for Adults Aged 25-64 in the United States Before and During the COVID-19 Pandemic, 2015-2021
Authors: Xu, J. J.; Seamans, M. J.; Friedman, J. R.
Score: 45.2, Published: 2023-10-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.19.23290239
Introduction: Dramatic increases in U.S. drug overdose deaths involving synthetic opioids, especially fentanyl, beginning around 2014 have driven a marked progression in overall drug overdose deaths in the U.S., sharply rising after the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single-fly assemblies fill major phylogenomic gaps across the Drosophilidae Tree of Life
Authors: Kim, B. Y.; Gellert, H. R.; Church, S. H.; Suvorov, A.; Anderson, S. S.; Barmina, O.; Beskid, S. G.; Comeault, A. A.; Crown, K. N.; Diamond, S. E.; Dorus, S.; Fujichika, T.; Hemker, J. A.; Hrcek, J.; Kankare, M.; Katoh, T.; Magnacca, K. N.; Martin, R. A.; Matsunaga, T.; Medeiros, M. J.; Miller, D. E.; Pitnick, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Spinocerebellar ataxia type 4 is caused by a GGC expansion in the ZFHX3 gene and is associated with prominent dysautonomia and motor neuron signs
Authors: Paucar, M.; Nilsson, D.; Engvall, M.; Laffita-Mesa, J.; Soderhall, C.; Skorpil, M.; Halldin, C.; Fazio, P.; Lagerstedt-Robinson, K.; Solders, G.; Angeria, M.; Risling, M.; Jiao, H.; Nennesmo, I.; Wedell, A.; Svenningsson, P.
Score: 18.4, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296230
BackgroundSpinocerebellar ataxias (SCAs) are a group of heterogeneous autosomal dominant disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Extensive co-regulation of neighbouring genes complicates the use of eQTLs in target gene prioritisation
Authors: Tambets, R.; Kolde, A.; Kolberg, P.; Love, M. I.; Alasoo, K.
Score: 21.0, Published: 2023-09-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560109
Identifying causal genes underlying genome-wide association studies (GWAS) is a fundamental problem in human genetics. Although colocalisation with gene expression quantitative trait loci (eQTLs) is often used to prioritise GWAS target genes, systematic benchmarking has been limited due to unavailability of large ground truth datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Ancient genomes illuminate Eastern Arabian population history and adaptation against malaria
Authors: Martiniano, R.; Haber, M.; Almarri, M. A.; Mattiangeli, V.; Kuijpers, M. C. M.; Chamel, B.; Breslin, E. M.; Littleton, J.; Almahari, S.; Aloraifi, F.; Bradley, D. G.; Lombard, P.; Durbin, R.
Score: 120.3, Published: 2023-10-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.559299
The harsh climate of Arabia has posed challenges in generating ancient DNA from the region, hindering the direct examination of ancient genomes for understanding the demographic processes that shaped Arabian populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating the life-extending potential and safety profile of rapamycin: a Mendelian Randomization study of the mTOR pathway
Authors: Sobczyk, M. K.; Gaunt, T. R.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.23296427
ObjectiveThe mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway plays an integral role in cellular metabolism, growth, and aging. While rapamycin and its analogs inhibit the mTOR pathway, extending lifespan in various organisms, the long-term safety and efficacy of these compounds in humans remain understudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Automated Extraction and Classification of Drug Prescriptions in Electronic Health Records: Introducing the PRESNER Pipeline
Authors: Colon-Ruiz, C.; Fitzgerald, T. W.; Segura-Bedmar, I.; Birney, E.; Herrero-Zazo, M.
Score: 7.0, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296481
Electronic health record (EHR) systems with prescription data offer vast potential in pharmacoepidemiology and pharmacogenomics. The large amount of clinical data recorded in these systems requires automatic processing to extract relevant information. This paper introduces PRESNER, a name entity recognition (NER) and classification pipeline for EHR prescription data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare and long-term care for people with cognitive impairment in the US: A latent transition analysis
Authors: Hu, B.; Wang, P.; Chen, X.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.23296615
IMPORTANCE People with cognitive impairment often have complex care needs. Both healthcare and long-term care are crucial to the well-being of people with mild cognitive impairment (MCI) or dementia. OBJECTIVE To understand the clustering patterns of healthcare and long-term care use in people with MCI or dementia and the relationships between changes in cognitive functioning and transitions of care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Ischemic Stroke after COVID-19 Bivalent Booster Vaccination in an Integrated Health System
Authors: Sharff, K.; Tandy, T. K.; Lewis, P. F.; Johnson, E. S.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295368
PurposeWhat is the absolute occurrence of ischemic stroke and transient ischemic attack after a COVID-19 bivalent vaccination? MethodsWe conducted a retrospective cohort study of Kaiser Permanente Northwest (KPNW) patients 18 years and older who were vaccinated with either the Pfizer or Moderna formulation of the COVID-19 bivalent vaccine between September 1, 2022 and March 1st 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>HIV-HBV Co-infections in Central India: Prevalence, Clearance Rates, and Long-term Outcomes from a Decade of Experience at a Tertiary Care Center.
Authors: Kunkal, U. R.; Mishra, N.; Tiwari, J.; Saad, T.; Vyas, A. K.; Rai, A.; Rawat, S. K.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.05.23296399
from a Decade of Experience at a Tertiary Care Center. Abstract: Two of the most infamous viruses, the Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and hepatitis B virus (HBV) have similar transmission routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>HERV activation segregates ME/CFS from fibromyalgia and defines a novel nosological entity for patients fulfilling both clinical criteria
Authors: Gimenez-Orenga, K.; Martin-Martinez, E.; Nathanson, L.; Oltra, E.
Score: 107.5, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.05.561025
Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS) and fibromyalgia (FM) are chronic diseases with poorly understood pathophysiology and diagnosis based on clinical assessment of unspecific symptoms. The recent post-COVID-19 condition, which shares similarities with ME/CFS and FM, has raised concerns about viral-induced transcriptome changes in post-viral syndromes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Humoral and cellular immune responses following BNT162b2 XBB.1.5 vaccination
Authors: Stankov, M. V.; Hoffmann, M.; Gutierrez, R.; Cossmann, A.; Morillas Ramos, G.; Graalmann, T.; Friedrichsen, M.; Ravens, I.; Tamara, I.; Ristenpart, J.; Schimrock, A.; Willenzon, S.; Ahrenstorff, G.; Witte, T.; Foerster, R.; Kempf, A.; Poehlmann, S.; Hammerschmidt, S. I.; Dopfer-Jablonka, A.; Behrens, G. M.
Score: 78.2, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296545
SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB subvariants efficiently evade immunity from prior infection or vaccination, requiring vaccine adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Conventional and unconventional T cell responses contribute to the prediction of clinical outcome and causative bacterial pathogen in sepsis patients
Authors: Burton, R. J.; Raffray, L.; Moet, L. M.; Cuff, S. M.; White, D. A.; Baker, S. E.; Moser, B.; O&amp;#39;Donnell, V. B.; Ghazal, P.; Morgan, M. P.; Artemiou, A.; Eberl, M.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295490
Sepsis is characterised by a dysfunctional host response to infection culminating in life-threatening organ failure that requires complex patient management and rapid intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Phospholipid transport to the bacterial outer membrane through an envelope-spanning bridge
Authors: Isom, G.; Cooper, B. F.; Clark, R.; Kudhail, A.; Ekiert, D. C.; Bhabha, G.; Khalid, S.
Score: 52.9, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.05.561070
The outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria provides a formidable barrier, essential for both pathogenesis and antimicrobial resistance. Biogenesis of the outer membrane requires the transport of phospholipids across the cell envelope. Recently, YhdP was implicated as a major protagonist in the transport of phospholipids from the inner membrane to the outer membrane however the molecular mechanism of YhdP mediated transport remains elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Non-canonical activation of IRE1α during Candida albicans infection enhances macrophage fungicidal activity
Authors: McFadden, M. J.; Reynolds, M. B.; Michmerhuizen, B. C.; Anderson, F. M.; O&amp;#39;Riordan, M. X. D.; O&amp;#39;Meara, T. R.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.560560
Infection by intracellular pathogens can trigger activation of the IRE1 branch of the unfolded protein response (UPR), which then modulates innate immunity and infection outcomes during bacterial or viral infection. However, the mechanisms by which infection activates IRE1 have not been fully elucidated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Striatal dopamine tone is positively associated with body mass index in humans as determined by PET using dual dopamine type-2 receptor antagonist tracers
Authors: Darcey, V. L.; Guo, J.; Chi, M.; Chung, S. T.; Courville, A. B.; Gallagher, I.; Herscovitch, P.; Howard, R.; La Noire, M.; Milley, L.; Schick, A.; Stagliano, M.; Turner, S.; Urbanski, N.; Yang, S.; Yim, E.; Zhai, N.; Zhou, M. S.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 neurotropism-induced anxiety and depression-like behaviors require Microglia activation
Authors: Ge, Q.; Zhou, S.; Porras, J.; Fu, P.; Wang, T.; Du, J.; Li, K.
Score: 166.8, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.560570
The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), has been associated with a wide range of long COVID neurological symptoms. However, the mechanisms governing SARS-CoV-2 neurotropism and its effects on long-term behavioral changes remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Diet order affects energy balance in randomized crossover feeding studies that vary in macronutrients but not ultra-processing
Authors: Sciarrillo, C. M.; Guo, J.; Darcey, V. L.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 13.3, Published: 2023-10-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296501
BACKGROUND: Crossover studies can induce order effects, especially when they lack a wash-out period. OBJECTIVE: To explore diet order effects on energy balance and food intake between randomized diet order groups in two inpatient crossover studies originally designed to compare within-subject differences in ad libitum energy intake between either minimally processed low carbohydrate (LC) versus low fat (LF) diets or macronutrient-matched diets composed of mostly minimally processed food (MPF) or ultra-processed food (UPF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Methylomic, proteomic, and metabolomic correlates of traffic-related air pollution: A systematic review, pathway analysis, and network analysis relating traffic-related air pollution to subclinical and clinical cardiorespiratory outcomes
Authors: Casella, C.; Kiles, F.; Urquhart, C.; Michaud, D. S.; Kirwa, K.; Corlin, L.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.30.23296386
A growing body of literature has attempted to characterize how traffic-related air pollution (TRAP) affects molecular and subclinical biological processes in ways that could lead to cardiorespiratory disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>DNA mismatch repair gene variant classification: evaluating the utility of somatic mutations and mismatch repair deficient colonic crypts and endometrial glands
Authors: Walker, R.; Mahmood, K.; Como, J.; Clendenning, M.; Joo, J. E.; Georgeson, P.; Joseland, S.; Preston, S. G.; Pope, B. J.; Austin, R.; Bojadzieva, J.; Campbell, A.; Chan, J. M.; Edwards, E.; Gleeson, M.; Goodwin, A.; Harris, M. T.; Ip, E.; Kirk, J.; Mansour, J.; Marfan, H.; Nichols, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Potential Structural Biomarkers in 3D Images Validated by the First Functional Biomarker for Early Age-Related Macular Degeneration - ALSTAR2 Baseline
Authors: Fasih-Ahmad, S.; Wang, Z. C.; Mishra, Z.; Vatanatham, C.; Clark, M. E.; Swain, T. A.; Curcio, C. A.; Owsley, C.; Sadda, S. R.; Hu, Z.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.10.23295309
PurposeWhile intermediate and late age-Related Macular Degeneration (AMD) have been widely investigated, rare studies were focused on the pathophysiologic mechanism of early AMD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Macroevolutionary drivers of morphological disparity in the avian quadrate
Authors: Kuo, P.-C.; Navalon, G.; Benson, R.; Field, D. J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.05.561045
In birds, the quadrate bone acts as a hinge between the lower jaw and the skull, playing an important role in cranial kinesis. As such, the evolution of avian quadrate morphology may plausibly be assumed to have been influenced by selective pressures related to feeding ecology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Pathology Knowledge using Board-Style Questions
Authors: Geetha, S. D.; Khan, A.; Khan, A.; Kannadath, B. S.; Vitkovski, T.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.23296400
ObjectivesChatGPT is an artificial intelligence (AI) chatbot developed by OpenAI. Its extensive knowledge and unique interactive capabilities enable it to be utilized in various innovative ways in the medical field such as writing clinical notes, simplifying radiology reports. Through this study we aim to analyze its pathology knowledge to advocate its role in transforming pathology education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Investigating markers of pulmonary aspiration in bronchoalveolar lavage from children with severe neurodisability
Authors: Maher, R. E.; Trinick, R. E.; Dalzell, M.; Beynon, R. J.; McNamara, P. S.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23295956
Respiratory exacerbations are a frequent cause of hospitalisation in children with severe neurodisability (ND). Direct aspiration of food/saliva, reflux aspiration of gastric contents or a combination of both is thought to be a common cause of respiratory symptoms and disease, particularly when this occurs silently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the effects of Dasatinib, Quercetin, and Fisetin on DNA methylation clocks: a longitudinal study on senolytic interventions
Authors: Lee, E.; Carreras-Gallo, N.; Lopez, L.; Turner, L.; Lin, A.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Tomusiak, A.; Verdin, E.; Corley, M.; Ndhlovu, L.; Smith, R.; Dwaraka, V. B.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295961
Senolytics, small molecules targeting cellular senescence, have emerged as potential therapeutics to enhance health span. However, their impact on epigenetic age remains unstudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Plastic food packaging from five countries contains endocrine and metabolism disrupting chemicals
Authors: Stevens, S.; Mcpartland, M.; Bartosova, Z.; Skaland, H. S.; Voelker, J.; Wagner, M.
Score: 34.3, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.559713
Plastics are complex chemical mixtures of polymers and various intentionally and non-intentionally added substances. Despite the well-established links between certain plastic chemicals (bisphenols, phthalates) and adverse health effects, the composition and toxicity of real-world mixtures of plastic chemicals is not well understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Nicotinic Acetylcholine Receptors on Osteocytes Impact Bone Mechanoadaptation in a Sexually Dimorphic Manner
Authors: Mora-Antoinette, M.; Obaji, M.; Saffari, A. W.; Lewis, K. J.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.556129
Bone&amp;#39;s ability to adapt to mechanical loads is attributed the osteocyte. Osteocytes reside embedded in calcified bone matrix, where they function as the resident tissue mechanosensor. Ca2&amp;#43; signaling is a key second messenger in mechanotransduction in osteocytes. It is used to encode mechanical load magnitude and has been linked to downstream signaling pathways which regulate bone resorbing and bone formation cell activity, however the details regarding Ca2&amp;#43; signaling regulation in osteocytes in vivo are not well stratified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of research topics and paradigms in plant sciences
Authors: Shiu, S.-H.; Lehti-Shiu, M. D.
Score: 38.1, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.560457
Scientific advances due to conceptual or technological innovations can be revealed by examining how research topics have evolved. But such topical evolution is difficult to uncover and quantify because of the large body of literature and the needs of expert knowledge from a wide range of areas in any field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Brain-targeted autoimmunity is strongly associated with Long COVID and its chronic fatigue syndrome as well as its affective symptoms.
Authors: Almulla, A. F.; Maes, M.; Zhou, B.; Al-Hakeim, H.; Vojdani, A.
Score: 187.5, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296554
Background: Autoimmune responses contribute to the pathophysiology of Long COVID, affective symptoms and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). Objectives: To examine whether Long COVID, and its accompanying affective symptoms and CFS are associated with immunoglobulin (Ig)A/IgM/IgG directed at neuronal proteins including myelin basic protein (MBP), myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein (MOG), synapsin, &amp;#43;{beta}-tubulin, neurofilament protein (NFP), cerebellar protein-2 (CP2), and the blood-brain-barrier-brain-damage (BBD) proteins claudin-5 and S100B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Mapping geographic and demographic shifts in container breeding mosquito-borne disease transmission suitability in Central and South America in a warming world
Authors: Ryan, S. J.; Lippi, C. A.; Stewart-Ibarra, A. M.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-10-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296495
The recent Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Sixth Assessment Report (IPCC-AR6) report brought into sharp relief the potential health impacts of a changing climate across large geographic regions. It also highlighted the gaps in available evidence to support detailed quantitative assessments of health impacts for many regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Exploration of the potential of high resolution and contrast 7 Tesla MR brain imaging in neonates
Authors: Bridgen, P.; Tomi-Tricot, R.; Uus, A.; Cromb, D.; Quirke, M.; Almalbis, J.; Bonse, B.; De La Fuente Botella, M.; Maggioni, A.; Di Cio, P.; Cawley, P.; Casella, C.; Dokumaci, A. S.; Thomson, A. R.; Willers Moore, J.; Bridglal, D.; Saravia, J.; Finck, T.; Price, A. N.; Pickles, E.; Cordero-Grande, L.; Egloff, A.; O&amp;#39;Muircheartaigh, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>A Quantitative Study of Inappropriate Image Duplication in the Journal Toxicology Reports
Authors: David, S.
Score: 58.0, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.03.556099
Inappropriate image duplication is a type of scientific error that can be detected by examining published literature. Few estimates of the frequency of this problem have been published. This study aimed to quantify the rate of image duplication in the journal Toxicology Reports. In total 1540 unique articles (identified by DOI) were checked for the presence of research related images (microscopy, photography, western blot scans, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The Zipime-Weka-Schista study protocol: a longitudinal cohort study and economic evaluation of an integrated home-based approach for genital multi-pathogen screening in women, including female genital schistosomiasis, HPV, Trichomonas and HIV in Zambia
Authors: Shanaube, K.; Ndubani, R.; Kelly, H.; Webb, E.; Mayaud, P.; Lamberti, O.; Fitzpatrick, J.; Kasese, N.; Sturt, A.; Van Lieshout, L.; Van Dam, G.; Corstjens, P. L. A. M.; Kosloff, B.; Bond, V.; Hayes, R.; Terris-Prestholt, F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Burden and risk factors for Achilles tendon rupture in the military population from 2006 to 2015: A retrospective cohort study.
Authors: Fraser, J. J.; Zellers, J. A.; Sullivan, C. K.; Janney, C. F.
Score: 2.9, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.23296425
BackgroundAchilles tendon rupture (ATR) is a serious musculoskeletal injury that results in substantial functional decline, especially in highly physically demanding occupations such as service in the military PurposeThe objective of this study was to evaluate the burden and associated factors of ATR in US military service members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Modular RNA motifs for orthogonal phase separated compartments
Authors: Stewart, J. M.; Li, S.; Tang, A.; Klocke, M. A. K. A.; Gobry, M. V.; Fabrini, G.; Di Michele, L.; Rothemund, P. W. K.; Franco, E.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561123
Recent discoveries in biology have highlighted the importance of protein and RNA-based condensates as an alternative to classical membrane-bound organelles for the task of compartmentalizing molecules and biochemical reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>APOLLO: A genome-scale metabolic reconstruction resource of 247,092 diverse human microbes spanning multiple continents, age groups, and body sites
Authors: Heinken, A.; Hulshof, T.; Nap, B.; Martinelli, F.; Basile, A.; O&amp;#39;Brolchain, A.; O&amp;#39;Sullivan, N. F.; Gallagher, C.; Magee, E.; McDonagh, F.; Lalor, I.; Bergin, M.; Evans, P.; Daly, R.; Farrell, R.; Delaney, R. M.; Hill, S.; McAuliffe, S. R.; Kilgannon, T.; Fleming, R. M.; Thinnes, C. C.; Thiele, I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Diminishing growth of zoological natural history collections threatens future research in the life sciences and beyond
Authors: Card, D. C.
Score: 31.9, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560208
Natural history museums comprise a unique and important component of biological infrastructure worldwide, and underlie diverse research, education, and outreach in the natural sciences. Each museum is built around one or more biological collections that serve as a repository of important materials for study, which have contributed to scientific research in increasingly important areas ranging from understanding global climate change to developing new biotechnological applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
