<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omic network analysis identifies dysregulated neurobiological pathways in opioid addiction
Authors: Sullivan, K. A.; Kainer, D.; Lane, M.; Cashman, M.; Miller, J. I.; Garvin, M. R.; Townsend, A.; Quach, B. C.; Willis, C.; Kruse, P.; Gaddis, N. C.; Mathur, R.; Corradin, O.; Maher, B. S.; Scacheri, P. C.; Sanchez-Roige, S.; Palmer, A. A.; Troiani, V.; Chesler, E. J.; Kember, R. L.; Kranzler, H. R.; Justice, A. C.; Xu, K.; Aouizerat, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Human ASXL1 Deficiency Causes Epigenetic Dysfunction, Combined Immunodeficiency and EBV-Associated Hodgkin Lymphoma
Authors: Fu, M. P.; Sharma, M.; Merrill, S. M.; Yousefi, P.; Tan, R.; Modi, B. P.; Del Bel, K.; Deyell, R. J.; Rozmus, J.; Rehmus, W.; Hildebrand, K. J.; James, E.; Blanchard-Rohner, G.; Lin, S.; Shopsowitz, K. E.; Setiadi, A.; Terry, J.; Lee, A. F.; Drogemoller, B. I.; Matthews, A.; Tarailo-Graovac, M.; Sauve, L.; Mitchell, H.; Prendiville, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Sex- and strain-dependent effects of ageing on sleep and activity patterns in Drosophila
Authors: Woodling, N.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.573701
The fruit fly Drosophila is a major discovery platform in the biology of ageing due to its balance of relatively short lifespan and relatively complex physiology and behaviour. Previous studies have suggested that some important phenotypes of ageing, for instance increasingly fragmented sleep, are shared from humans to Drosophila and can be useful measures of behavioural change with age: these phenotypes therefore hold potential as readouts of healthy ageing for genetic or pharmacological interventions aimed at the underpinning biology of ageing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Viral proteins activate PARIS-mediated tRNA degradation and viral tRNAs rescue infection
Authors: Burman, N.; Belukhina, S.; Depardieu, F.; Wilkinson, R. A.; Skutel, M.; Santiago-Frangos, A.; Graham, A. B.; Livenskyi, A.; Chechenina, A.; Morozova, N.; Zahl, T.; Henriques, W. S.; Buyukyoruk, M.; Rouillon, C.; Shyrokova, L.; Kurata, T.; Hauryliuk, V.; Severinov, K.; Groseille, J.; Thierry, A.; Koszul, R.; Tesson, F.; Bernheim, A.; Bikard, D.; Wiedenheft, B.; Isaev, A.
Score: 60.0, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Antigen-display exosomes provide adjuvant-free protection against SARS-CoV-2 disease at nanogram levels of spike protein
Authors: Guo, C.; Sachithanandham, J.; Zhong, W.; Craney, M.; Villano, J.; Pekosz, A.; Gould, S.
Score: 11.4, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.574272
As the only bionormal nanovesicle, exosomes have high potential as a nanovesicle for delivering vaccines and therapeutics. We show here that the loading of type-1 membrane proteins into the exosome membrane is induced by exosome membrane anchor domains, EMADs, that maximize protein delivery to the plasma membrane, minimize protein sorting to other compartments, and direct proteins into exosome membranes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>PCA-Plus: Enhanced principal component analysis with illustrative applications to batch effects and their quantitation
Authors: Zhang, N.; Casasent, T. D.; Casasent, A. K.; Kumar, S. V.; Wakefield, C.; Broom, B. M.; Weinstein, J. N.; Akbani, R.
Score: 36.5, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.573793
BackgroundPrincipal component analysis (PCA), a standard approach to analysis and visualization of large datasets, is commonly used in biomedical research for detecting similarities and differences among groups of samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Quantification of cell phenotype transition manifolds with information geometry
Authors: Huang, M.; Ying, J.; Wang, Y.; Zhou, H.; Zhang, L.; Wang, W.
Score: 18.5, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.573500
Cell phenotype transition (CPT) is a common occurrence in many biological processes, such as development, and the precise control of CPT is critical in these processes. Recent advancements in single-cell sequencing techniques have revealed that cell transition dynamics in development are confined to low-dimensional manifolds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mechanisms underpinning osteosarcoma genome complexity and evolution
Authors: Espejo Valle-Inclan, J.; De Noon, S.; Trevers, K.; Elrick, H.; Tanguy, M.; Butters, T.; Muyas, F.; Amary, F.; Tirabosco, R.; Giess, A.; Sosinky, A.; Elgar, G.; Flanagan, A. M.; Cortes-Ciriano, I.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573403
Osteosarcoma is the most common primary cancer of bone with a peak incidence in children and young adults. Despite progress, the genomic aberrations underpinning osteosarcoma evolution remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Association between Cardiovascular Disease Risk and long COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis
Authors: Huang, Y.; Wen, Z.; Luo, H.; Liao, Y.; Chen, Z.
Score: 36.4, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300656
ObjectivateTo assess demographic characteristics and investigate the correlation between cardiovascular diseases and long COVID-19 patients. MethodsComprehensive details, encompassing the first authors name, publication year, sample inclusion criteria, sample size, and demographic characteristics, including age and gender of participants, were systematically extracted from all incorporated studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Constitutive Endolysosomal Perforation in Neurons allows Induction of alpha-Synuclein Aggregation by Internalized Pre-Formed Fibrils
Authors: Sanyal, A.; Scanavachi, G.; Somerville, E.; Saminathan, A.; Nair, A.; Oikonomou, A.; Hatzakis, N. S.; Kirchhausen, T.
Score: 25.0, Published: 2024-01-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.573738
The endocytic pathway is both an essential route of molecular uptake in cells and a potential entry point for pathology-inducing cargo. The cell-to-cell spread of cytotoxic aggregates, such as those of -synuclein (-syn) in Parkinsons Disease (PD), exemplifies this duality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>DMSO derives Trophectoderm and Clonal Blastoid from Single Human Pluripotent Stem Cell
Authors: Alsolami, S.; Chandrasekaran, A. P.; Jin, Y.; Shakir, I. M.; Zhang, Y.; Ramos-Mandujano, G.; Yuan, B.; Saera-Vila, A.; Izpisua Belm, J. C. o.; Li, M.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2024-01-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.31.573770
Human naive pluripotent stem cells (nPSCs) can differentiate into extra-embryonic trophectoderm (TE), a critical step in the generation of the integrated embryo model termed blastoid. The current paradigm of blastoid generation necessitates the aggregation of dozens of nPSCs treated with multiple small molecule inhibitors, growth factors, or genetic modifications to initiate TE differentiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating key evidence and formulating regulatory alternatives regarding the UK Hunting Trophies (Import Prohibition) Bill
Authors: Challender, D.; &amp;#39;t Sas-Rolfes, M.; Dickman, A.; Hare, D.; Hart, A.; Hoffmann, M.; Mallon, D.; Mandisodza-Chikerema, R.; Roe, D.
Score: 119.5, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.13.544826
Public policy addressing biodiversity loss is most likely to be effective when it is informed by appropriate evidence and considers potential unintended consequences. We evaluate key evidence relating to the UKs Hunting Trophies (Import Prohibition) Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 51.9, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>BNT162b2 XBB1.5-adapted Vaccine and COVID-19 Hospital Admissions and Ambulatory Visits in US Adults
Authors: Tartof, S. Y.; Slezak, J. M.; Frankland, T. B.; Puzniak, L.; Hong, V.; Ackerson, B. K.; Stern, J. A.; Simmons, S.; Jodar, L.; McLaughlin, J. M.
Score: 2122.7, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.24.23300512
ImportanceData describing the early additional protection afforded by recently recommended XBB1.5- adapted COVID-19 vaccines are limited. ObjectiveWe estimated the association between receipt of BNT162b2 XBB1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Consistent accumulation of transposable elements in species of the Hawaiian Tetragnatha spiny-leg adaptive radiation across the archipelago chronosequence
Authors: Yang, H.; Goubert, C.; Cotoras, D.; Graham, N.; Cerca, J.; Gillespie, R. G.
Score: 10.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574070
The ecological and phenotypic diversity observed in oceanic island radiations presents an evolutionary paradox: a high level of genetic variation is typically required for diversification, but species colonizing a new island typically suffer from founder effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Valid inference for machine learning-assisted GWAS
Authors: Miao, J.; Wu, Y.; Sun, Z.; Miao, X.; Lu, T.; Zhao, J.; Lu, Q.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300779
Machine learning (ML) has revolutionized analytical strategies in almost all scientific disciplines including human genetics and genomics. Due to challenges in sample collection and precise phenotyping, ML-assisted genome-wide association study (GWAS) which uses sophisticated ML to impute phenotypes and then performs GWAS on imputed outcomes has quickly gained popularity in complex trait genetics research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>pIGLET: Safe harbor landing sites for reproducible and efficient transgenesis in zebrafish
Authors: Lalonde, R. L.; Wells, H. H.; Kemmler, C. L.; Nieuwenhuize, S.; Lerma, R.; Burger, A.; Mosimann, C.
Score: 58.7, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570868
Standard methods for transgenesis in zebrafish depend on random transgene integration into the genome followed by resource-intensive screening and validation. Targeted vector integration into validated genomic loci using phiC31 integrase-based attP/attB recombination has transformed mouse and Drosophila transgenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive and accurate genome analysis at scale using DRAGEN accelerated algorithms
Authors: Behera, S.; Catreux, S.; Rossi, M.; Truong, S.; Huang, Z.; Ruehle, M.; Visvanath, A.; Parnaby, G.; Roddey, C.; Onuchic, V.; Cameron, D. L.; English, A.; Mehtalia, S.; Han, J.; Mehio, R.; Sedlazeck, F. J.
Score: 51.3, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.573821
Research and medical genomics require comprehensive and scalable solutions to drive the discovery of novel disease targets, evolutionary drivers, and genetic markers with clinical significance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare utilisation in people with long COVID: an OpenSAFELY cohort study
Authors: Lin, L.-Y.; Henderson, A. D.; Carlile, O.; Dillingham, I.; Butler-Cole, B. F.; Marks, M.; Briggs, A.; Jit, M.; Tomlinson, L. A.; Bates, C.; Parry, J.; Bacon, S. C.; Goldacre, B.; Mehrkar, A.; MacKenna, B.; The OpenSAFELY Collaborative, ; Eggo, R. M.; Herrett, E.
Score: 344.7, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300305
BackgroundLong COVID, characterised by various symptoms and complications, potentially increases healthcare utilisation and costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Robodoc: a conversational-AI based app for medical conversations
Authors: Pires, J. G.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.31.23300681
Artificial Intelligence (AI) evolved in trends. Currently, the trend is Conversational Artificial Intelligence (CAI). Those models of AI are focused on text-related tasks, and their commonest applications are chatbots. On this paper, we explore a smart chatbot using the Large Language Models (LLMs) from openAI. I have used a tool called Teachable Machine (TM) from Google to apply transfer learning and create image-based models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>A Healthcare Service Delivery and Epidemiological Model for Investigating Resource Allocation for Health: The Thanzi La Onse Model
Authors: Hallett, T. B.; Mangal, T. D.; Tamuri, A. U.; Arinaminpathy, N.; Cambiano, V.; Chalkley, M.; Collins, J. H.; Cooper, J.; Gillman, M. S.; Giordano, M.; Graham, M. M.; Graham, W.; Janouskova, E.; Jewell, B. L.; Lin, I. L.; Smith, R. M.; Manthalu, G.; Mnjowe, E.; Mohan, S.; Molaro, M.; Ngambi, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell analysis of bone marrow CD8&amp;#43; T cells in Myeloid Neoplasms predicts response to treatment with Azacitidine
Authors: Tasis, A.; Papaioannou, N.; Grigoriou, M.; Paschalidis, N.; Loukogiannaki, K.; Filia, A.; Katsiki, K.; Lamprianidou, E.; Papadopoulos, V.; Rimpa, C. M.; Chatzigeorgiou, A.; Kourtzelis, I.; Gerasimou, P.; Kyprianou, I.; Kosteas, P.; Liakopoulos, P.; Liapis, K.; Kolovos, P.; Chavakis, T.; Alissafi, T.; Kotsianidis, I.; Mitroulis, I.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300608</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Gene dysregulation among virally suppressed people living with HIV links to non-AIDS defining cancer pathways
Authors: Quach, B. C.; Earley, E.; Zhou, L.; Willis, C.; Marks, J. A.; Stratford, J. K.; Fang, F.; Bierut, L. J.; Milloy, M.-J. S.; Hayashi, K.; DeBeck, K.; Hancock, D. B.; Xu, K.; Aouizerat, B. E.; Johnson, E. O.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300792
Combination antiretroviral therapy (ART) has changed the landscape of the HIV epidemic by providing an effective means for viral suppression to people living with HIV (PLWH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Engineering self-propelled tumor-infiltrating CAR T cells using synthetic velocity receptors
Authors: Johnston, A. C.; Alicea, G. M.; Lee, C. C.; Patel, P. V.; Hanna, E. A.; Vaz, E.; Forjaz, A.; Wan, Z.; Nair, P. R.; Lim, Y.; Chen, T.; Du, W.; Kim, D.; Nichakawade, T. D.; Rebecca, V. W.; Bonifant, C. L.; Fan, R.; Kiemen, A. L.; Wu, P.-H.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 153.2, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.571595
Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells express antigen-specific synthetic receptors, which upon binding to cancer cells, elicit T cell anti-tumor responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Reverse mutational scanning of spike BA.2.86 identifies the epitopes contributing to immune escape from polyclonal sera
Authors: Bdeir, N.; Lüddecke, T.; Maass, H.; Schmelz, S.; Jacobsen, H.; Metzdorf, K.; Cossmann, A.; Stankov, M.; Hoffmann, M.; Pöhlmann, S.; Blankenfeldt, W.; Jablonka, A.; Behrens, G. M. N.; Cicin-Sain, L.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.23300575
The recently detected Omicron BA.2.86 lineage contains more than 30 amino acid mutations relative to BA.2. Here, we identify the epitopes driving immune escape of BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Detecting Goals of Care Conversations in Clinical Notes with Active Learning
Authors: Weissenbacher, D.; Courtright, K.; Rawal, S.; Crane-Droesch, A.; O&amp;#39;COnnor, K.; Kuhl, N.; Merlino, C.; Foxwell, A.; Haines, L.; Puhl, J.; Gonzalez-Hernandez, G.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300801
ObjectiveGoals Of Care (GOC) discussions are an increasingly used quality metric in serious illness care and research. Wide variation in documentation practices within the Electronic Health Record (EHR) presents challenges for reliable measurement of GOC discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Time to publication in medical education journals: An analysis of publication timelines during COVID-19 (2019-2022)
Authors: Maggio, L. A.; Costello, J. A.; Brown, K. R.; Artino, A. R.; Durning, S. J.; Ma, T.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.24300847
Introduction COVID-19 changed scholarly publishing. Yet, its impact on medical education publishing is unstudied. Because journal articles and their corresponding publication timelines can influence academic success, the field needs updated publication timelines to set evidence-based expectations for academic productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>AMAPEC: accurate antimicrobial activity prediction for fungal effector proteins
Authors: Mesny, F.; Thomma, B. P.
Score: 46.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.574150
Fungi typically occur in environments where numerous and diverse other microbes occur as well, often resulting in fierce competition for nutrients and habitat. To support fungal fitness in these environments, they evolved various mechanisms that mediate direct antagonism towards niche competitors. Among these, the secretion of proteins with antimicrobial activities has been reported in fungi with diverse lifestyles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Genome-Wide CRISPR Screen Identifies Sortilin as the Receptor Responsible for Galectin-1 Lysosomal Trafficking
Authors: Donnelly, J.; Kamber, R. A.; Wisnovsky, S.; Roberts, D. S.; Peltan, E. L.; Bassik, M. C.; Bertozzi, C. R.
Score: 26.3, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574113
Galectins are a family of mammalian glycan-binding proteins that have been implicated as regulators of myriad cellular processes including cell migration, apoptosis, and immune modulation. Several members of this family, such as galectin-1, exhibit both cell-surface and intracellular functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Effects of changes in calculating GFR using KDIGO standards: Discordance in the Staging and Timing of Diagnosis of Chronic Kidney Disease
Authors: Baker, C.; Gratzl, S.; Rodriguez, P. J.; simonov, m.; Cartwright, B.; brar, r.; Stucky, N.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300415
IntroductionChronic kidney disease (CKD) is a highly prevalent disease with disparities in diagnosis and treatment. Until recently, primary diagnosis for CKD was based on equations that incorporated race and have demonstrated racial bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Noradrenergic modulation of saccades in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Orlando, I. F.; Hezemans, F. H.; Ye, R.; Murley, A. G.; Holland, N.; Regenthal, R.; Barker, R. A.; Williams Gray, C. H.; Passamonti, L.; Robbins, T.; Rowe, J.; O&amp;#39;Callaghan, C.
Score: 8.0, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.24300879
Noradrenaline is a powerful modulator of cognitive processes, including action-decisions underlying saccadic control. Changes in saccadic eye movements are common across neurodegenerative diseases of ageing, including Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>The brainstem&amp;#39;s red nucleus was evolutionarily upgraded to support goal-directed action
Authors: Krimmel, S. R.; Laumann, T. O.; Chauvin, R.; Hershey, T.; Roland, J. L.; Shimony, J. S.; Willie, J. T.; Norris, S. A.; Marek, S.; Van, A. N.; Monk, J.; Scheidter, K. M.; Whiting, F.; Ramirez-Perez, N.; Metoki, A.; Wang, A.; Kay, B. P.; Nahman-Averbuch, H.; Fair, D. A.; Lynch, C. J.; Raichle, M. E.; Gordon, E. M.; Dosenbach, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>LITERATURE REVIEW THE EFFECT OF MINDFULNESS INTERVENTIONS ON BLOOD PRESSURE AND STRESS IN HYPERTENSION PATIENTS
Authors: Muafiro, A.; Nursalam, N.; Pandin, M. G. R.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-12-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.23299631
BackgroundHypertension is a significant contributor to both illness and death on a global scale. One method of managing blood pressure is through adopting a healthy lifestyle and implementing blood pressure control measures, with or without the use of medication. The objective of the review paper is to elucidate the impact of mindfulness therapies on both blood pressure and stress levels in individuals diagnosed with hypertension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 58.4, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 158.2, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Exposure to Wood dust and its Respiratory Health Effects Among Wood Workers in Yaounde (Cameroon)
Authors: Takougang, I.; Bukam Guemnyem, G. W.; Edzamba, M. F.; Lekeumo Cheuyem, F. Z.; Assomo Ndemba, P. B.; Yone Pefura, W.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300613
BackgroundOccupational respiratory diseases are responsible of one-third of all documented work-related deaths. Exposure to wood dust leads to multiple respiratory manifestations including cough, chest pain, asthma and altered lung function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping inherited genetic variation with opposite effects on autoimmune disease and cancer identifies candidate drug targets associated with the anti-tumor immune response
Authors: Chen, J.; Epstein, M. P.; Schildkraut, J. M.; Kar, S. P.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2023-12-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.23.23300491
BackgroundGermline alleles near genes that encode certain immune checkpoints (CTLA4, CD200) are associated with autoimmune/autoinflammatory disease and cancer but in opposite directions. This motivates a systematic search for additional germline alleles which demonstrate this pattern with the aim of identifying potential cancer immunotherapeutic targets using human genetic evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>A Novel Fluorescent Immuno-Lectin Assay to Identify Osteoarthritis Associated Glycoforms of Lubricin
Authors: Afshari, A. R.; Thomsson, K. A.; Hoglund, J.; Ryberg, H.; Gidwani, K.; Pettersson, K.; Rolfson, O.; Bjorkman, L. I.; Eisler, T.; Schmidt, T. A.; Jay, G. D.; Karlsson, N. G.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.23300279
Lubricin or proteoglycan-4 (PRG-4) is a mucinous glycoprotein lubricating the cartilage and maintaining normal tissue function and cell-homeostasis. Altered O-glycoforms of lubricin has been found in osteoarthritis (OA) synovial fluid (SF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>STAT4 Phosphorylation of T-helper Cells predicts surgical outcomes in Refractory Chronic Rhinosinusitis
Authors: Abidin, M.; Alpan, O.; Plassmeyer, M.; Kozhaya, L.; Loizou, D.; Dogan, M.; Upchurch, Z.; Manes, N.; Nita-Lazar, A.; Unutmaz, D.; Sonder, S. U.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299743
Objective: Chronic rhinosinusitis (CRS) impacts an estimated 5% to 15% of people worldwide, incurring significant economic healthcare burden. There is a urgent need for the discovery of predictive biomarkers to improve treatment strategies and outcomes for CRS patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Distinct causes underlie double-peaked trilobite morphological disparity
Authors: Drage, H. B.; Pates, S.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574297
Trilobite cephalic morphology impacted the autecology of individuals, and is critical for high- and low-level taxonomic assignments. Disparity in trilobite cephalon shape varied through time and was integral to the occupation of a diversity of ecological niches. To fully appreciate trilobite cephalic evolution, we must understand how this disparity varies, and what factors control cephalon morphometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Integrated histopathology, spatial and single cell transcriptomics resolve cellular drivers of early and late alveolar damage in COVID-19
Authors: Lee, J. T. H.; Barnett, S. N.; Roberts, K.; Ashwin, H.; Milross, L.; Cho, J.-W.; Huseynov, A.; Woodhams, B.; Aivazidis, A.; Li, T.; Majo, J.; Guerrero, P. C.; Lee, M.; Miranda, A. M. A.; Jablonska, Z.; Arena, V.; Hanley, B.; Osborn, M.; Uhlmann, V.; Xu, X.-N.; McLean, G. R.; Teichmann, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>The Prevalence, Etiology, And Outcome Of Anemia In Children Under Five On Admission In Three Hospitals Of Dar-Es-Salaam
Authors: Msinde, P. S.
Score: 26.1, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300509
IntroductionChildhood anemia remains a persistent global challenge, emerging as the most prevalent blood disorder among children worldwide. Its enduring prevalence underscores its significance as a hematological concern of substantial public health importance, owing to its wide prevalence and potential severity. Anemias impact is particularly pronounced among children and expectant mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Drug promiscuity: problems and promises.
Authors: VanDongen, A. M.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573633
Therapeutic drugs exert their effect by binding to a specific target protein (receptor) and altering its activity. However, all drugs have undesirable side effects, which likely result from the drug binding to other protein targets. Drug promiscuity refers to the ability of small molecule compounds to bind with high affinity to multiple proteins. This drug property is responsible for the problems caused by their side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and fatty symbionts: photosynthetic productivity and carbon storage boosted in microalgae within a host
Authors: Catacora Grundy, A.; Chevalier, F.; Yee, D.; LeKieffre, C.; Schieber, N.; Schwab, Y.; Gallet, B.; Jouneau, P.-H.; Curien, G.; Decelle, J.
Score: 10.1, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572971
Symbiosis between a host and intracellular eukaryotic microalgae is a widespread life strategy in aquatic ecosystems. This partnership is considered to be mainly energized by the photosynthetically-derived carbon energy of microalgal symbionts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Next-generation mapping of the salicylic acid signaling hub and transcriptional cascade
Authors: Powers, J.; Zhang, X.; Reyes, A. V.; Zavaliev, R.; Xu, S.-L.; Dong, X.
Score: 33.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574047
For over 60 years, salicylic acid (SA) has been known as a plant immune signal required for both basal and systemic acquired resistance (SAR). SA activates these immune responses by reprogramming up to 20% of the transcriptome through the function of NPR1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>A participatory action research study to explore adolescents experiences of adverse childhood experiences through creative workshops: a protocol
Authors: Butcher, I.; Mankee Williams, A.; Hugh-Jones, S.; Cooke, P.; Teasdale, B.; Shaughnessy, N.; Pavarini, G.; Smith, L.; Bhui, K.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300349
IntroductionAdverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) are associated with poor mental health in adolescence. There are critical gaps in understanding how and why ACEs are experienced by particular groups of young people and what factors contribute to risk and resilience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Barriers to healthcare access: findings from a co-produced Long Covid case-finding study
Authors: Clutterbuck, D.; Ramasawmy, M.; Pantelic, M.; Hayer, J.; Begum, F.; Faghy, M.; Nasir, N.; Causer, B.; Heightman, M.; Allsopp, G.; Wootton, D.; Khan, M. A.; Hastie, C.; Jackson, M.; Rayner, C.; Brown, D.; Parrett, E.; Jones, G.; Clarke, R.; Mcfarland, S.; Gabbay, M.; Banerjee, A.; Alwan, N. A.; STIMULATE-ICP Consortium, Score: 85.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300767</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Identifying alterations in hand movement coordination from chronic stroke survivors using a wearable high-density EMG sleeve
Authors: Tacca, N.; Baumgart, I.; Schlink, B.; Kamath, A.; Dunlap, C.; Darrow, M.; Colachis, S.; Putnam, P.; Branch, J.; Wengerd, L.; Friedenberg, D.; Meyers, E.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.24300714
Non-invasive, high-density electromyography (HD-EMG) has emerged as a useful tool to collect a range of neurophysiological motor information. Recent studies have demonstrated changes in EMG features that occur after stroke, which correlate with functional ability, highlighting their potential use as biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Causal Relationships Between Diabetes Mellitus and Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis
Authors: Moss, S. T.; Minelli, C.; Leavy, O. C.; Allen, R. J.; Oliver, N.; Wain, L. V.; Jenkins, R. G.; Stewart, I.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.24300827
RationaleIdiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF) is a disease of progressive lung scarring. There is a known association between IPF and diabetes mellitus (DM), but it is unclear whether this association is due to causal relationships between these traits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Rendering protein structures inside cells at the atomic level with Unreal Engine
Authors: Chen, M.
Score: 135.5, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570879
While the recent development of cryogenic electron tomography (CryoET) makes it possible to identify various macromolecules inside cells and determine their structure at near-atomic resolution, it remains challenging to visualize the complex cellular environment at the atomic level. One of the main hurdles in cell visualization is to render the millions of molecules in real time computationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reconstructing cell histories in space with image-readable base editor recording
Authors: Chadly, D. M.; Frieda, K. L.; Gui, C.; Klock, L.; Tran, M.; Sui, M. Y.; Takei, Y.; Bouckaert, R.; Lois, C.; Cai, L.; Elowitz, M. B.
Score: 97.3, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.573434
Knowing the ancestral states and lineage relationships of individual cells could unravel the dynamic programs underlying development. Engineering cells to actively record information within their own genomic DNA could reveal these histories, but existing recording systems have limited information capacity or disrupt spatial context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Highly multiplexed, image-based pooled screens in primary cells and tissues with PerturbView
Authors: Kudo, T.; Meireles, A. M.; Moncada, R.; Chen, Y.; Wu, P.; Gould, J.; Hu, X.; Kornfeld, O.; Jesudason, R.; Foo, C.; Hockendorf, B.; Bravo, H. C.; Town, J. P.; Wei, R.; Rios, A.; Chandrasekar, V.; Heinlein, M.; Cai, S.; Lu, C. S.; Celen, C.; Kljavin, N.; Jiang, J.; Hleap, J. S.; Kayagaki, N.; Melo, F. d. S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 10:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) - a new record of butterfly for Saudi Arabia
Authors: ALFAKIH, A.; AL FAIFY, E. A.
Score: 38.3, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572884
The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) was recorded for the first time in Saudi Arabia. At this stage, we confirmed the presence of this species in the southernmost part of Saudi Arabia based on photographs taken in 2020-2023 from Fayfa and the adjacent mountains in Jazan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
