<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Rhinovirus infection of airway epithelial cells uncovers the non-ciliated subset as a likely driver of genetic susceptibility to childhood-onset asthma
Authors: Djeddi, S.; Fermandez-Salinas, D.; Huang, G.; Aguiar, V.; Mohanty, C.; Kendziorski, C.; Gazal, S.; Boyce, J.; Ober, C.; Gern, J.; Barrett, N.; Gutierrez-Arcelus, M.
Score: 18.3, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302068
Asthma is a complex disease caused by genetic and environmental factors. Epidemiological studies have shown that in children, wheezing during rhinovirus infection (a cause of the common cold) is associated with asthma development during childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Tap Dancing Frogs: Posterior Toe Tapping and Feeding Behavior in Dendrobates tinctorius
Authors: Parrish, T. Q.; Fischer, E. K.
Score: 36.6, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.558032
Animals have myriad adaptations to help them hunt and feed in the most efficient and effective manner. One mysterious behavior related to hunting and feeding is the posterior toe tapping behavior of some frogs. Biologists and hobbyists alike have long noticed this behavior, but there is little empirical data to explain its causes and consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Mechanism of degrader-targeted protein ubiquitinability
Authors: Crowe, C.; Nakasone, M.; Chandler, S.; Tatham, M. H.; Makukhin, N.; Hay, R. T.; Ciulli, A.
Score: 57.7, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.578957
Small molecule degraders of disease-driving proteins offer a clinically proven modality with enhanced therapeutic efficacy and the potential to tackle previously undrugged targets. Thermodynamically stable and kinetically long-lived degrader-mediated ternary complexes can drive faster, more profound and durable target degradation, however the mechanistic features by which they impact on target ubiquitination remain elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Feature Reuse and Scaling: Understanding Transfer Learning with Protein Language Models
Authors: Li, F.-Z.; Amini, A. P.; Yue, Y.; Yang, K. K.; Lu, A. X.
Score: 80.9, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.578959
Large pretrained protein language models (PLMs) have improved protein property and structure prediction from sequences via transfer learning, in which weights and representations from PLMs are repurposed for downstream tasks. Although PLMs have shown great promise, currently there is little understanding of how the features learned by pretraining relate to and are useful for downstream tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>edgeR 4.0: powerful differential analysis of sequencing data with expanded functionality and improved support for small counts and larger datasets
Authors: Chen, Y.; Chen, L.; Lun, A. T. L.; Baldoni, P. L.; Smyth, G. K.
Score: 142.8, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.576131
edgeR is an R/Bioconductor software package for differential analyses of sequencing data in the form of read counts for genes or genomic features. Over the past 15 years, edgeR has been a popular choice for statistical analysis of data from sequencing technologies such as RNA-seq or ChIP-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Small LEA proteins as an effective air-water interface protectant for fragile samples during cryo-EM grid plunge freezing
Authors: Abe, K. M.; Lim, C. J.
Score: 48.0, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579238
Sample loss due to air-water interface (AWI) interactions is a significant challenge during cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) sample grid plunge freezing. We report that small Late Embryogenesis Abundant (LEA) proteins, which naturally bind to AWI, can protect samples from AWI damage during plunge freezing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mechanical confinement governs phenotypic plasticity in melanoma
Authors: Hunter, M. V.; Montal, E.; Ma, Y.; Moncada, R.; Yanai, I.; Koche, R. P.; White, R. M.
Score: 31.9, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.577120
Phenotype switching is a form of cellular plasticity in which cancer cells reversibly move between two opposite extremes - proliferative versus invasive states. While it has long been hypothesised that such switching is triggered by external cues, the identity of these cues has remained elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Development and validation of imaging-free myocardial fibrosis prediction models, association with outcomes, and sample size estimation for phase 3 trials
Authors: Black, N.; Bradley, J.; Lewis, G.; Lagan, J.; Orsborne, C.; Soltani, F.; Farrant, J. P.; McDonagh, T.; Schmitt, M.; Cavalcante, J.; Ugander, M.; Butler, J.; Petrie, M. C.; Miller, C.; Schelbert, E.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2024-02-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.24302443
Background and AimsPhase 3 trials testing whether pharmacologic interventions targeting myocardial fibrosis (MF) improve outcomes require MF measurement that does not rely on tomographic imaging with intravenous contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dissecting reprogramming heterogeneity at single-cell resolution using scTF-seq
Authors: Liu, W.; Saelens, W.; Rainer, P.; Biocanin, M.; Gardeux, V.; Gralak, A.; van Mierlo, G.; Russeil, J.; Liu, T.; Chen, W.; Deplancke, B.
Score: 44.1, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.577921
Reprogramming approaches often produce heterogeneous cell fates and the mechanisms behind this heterogeneity are not well-understood. To address this gap, we developed scTF-seq, a technique inducing single-cell barcoded and doxycycline-inducible TF overexpression while quantifying TF dose-dependent transcriptomic changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Local and global changes in cell density induce reorganisation of 3D packing in a proliferating epithelium.
Authors: Barone, V.; Tagua, A.; Andres-San Roman, J. A.; Hamdoun, A.; Garrido-Garcia, J.; Lyons, D.; Escudero, L. M.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.579268
Tissue morphogenesis is intimately linked to the changes in shape and organisation of individual cells. In curved epithelia, cells can intercalate along their own apicobasal axes adopting a shape named &amp;#39;scutoid&amp;#39; that allows energy minimization in the tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Sonic restoration: Acoustic stimulation enhances soil fungal biomass and activity of plant growth-promoting fungi
Authors: Robinson, J. M.; Cando-Dumancela, C.; Breed, M. F.
Score: 117.2, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575298
Ecosystem restoration interventions often utilise visible elements to restore an ecosystem (e.g., replanting native plant communities and reintroducing lost species). However, using acoustic stimulation to restore ecosystems has received little attention. Our study aimed to (a) investigate the potential effects of acoustic stimulation on fungal biomass and organic matter decomposition, which are both crucial components of ecosystem functioning and (b) assess the effect of acoustic stimulation on the growth rate and sporulation of the plant growth-promoting fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2--Reactive Salivary Antibody Detection in South Carolina Emergency Healthcare Workers: September 2019 -- March 2020
Authors: Meltzer, H. C.; Goodwin, J. L.; Fowler, L. A.; Britt, T. W.; Pirrallo, R. G.; Grier, J. T.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24301668
BackgroundOn 19 January 2020, the first case of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection was identified in the US, with the first cases in South Carolina (SC) confirmed on 06 March 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the genetic contribution of cumulative behavioral factors associated with longitudinal type 2 diabetes risk highlights adiposity and the brain-metabolic axis
Authors: Carvalho, N.; He, Y.; Smadbeck, P.; Flannick, J.; Mercader, J.; Udler, M.; Manrai, A. K.; Merino, J.; Patel, C. J.
Score: 5.2, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24302019
While genetic factors, behavior, and environmental exposures form a complex web of interrelated associations in type 2 diabetes (T2D), their interaction is poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Unreliability in Simulations of COVID-19 Cases and Deaths Based on Transmission Models
Authors: Kakeya, H.; Itoh, M.; Kamijima, Y.; Nitta, T.; Umeno, Y.
Score: 401.7, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302123
Two papers authored by the same research group were published in academic journals in October 2023, both of which simulate counterfactual COVID-19 cases and deaths using transmission models. One paper estimates that the COVID-19 cases and deaths from Feb 17 to Nov 30, 2021 in Japan would have been as many as 63.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Bacterial ecology and evolution converge on seasonal and decadal scales
Authors: Rohwer, R. R.; Kirkpatrick, M.; Garcia, S. L.; Kellom, M.; McMahon, K. D.; Baker, B. J.
Score: 77.1, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579087
Ecology and evolution are distinct theories, but the short lifespans and large population sizes of microbes allow evolution to unfold along contemporary ecological time scales. To document this in a natural system, we collected a two-decade, 471-metagenome time series from a single site in a freshwater lake, which we refer to as the TYMEFLIES dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Functional variation in human Carbohydrate-Active enZYmes (hCAZymes) in relation to the efficacy of a FODMAP-reducing diet in IBS patients
Authors: Zamfir-Taranu, A.; Loescher, B.-S.; Carbone, F.; Hoter, A.; Esteban-Blanco, C.; Bozzarelli, I.; Torices, L.; Routhiaux, K.; Van den Houte, K.; Bonfiglio, F.; Mayr, G.; Corsetti, M.; Naim, H. Y.; Franke, A.; Tack, J.; D Amato, M.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302204
ObjectiveLimiting the dietary intake of carbohydrates poorly absorbed in the small intestine (FODMAPs) has therapeutic effects in some but not all irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Novel syndromic neurodevelopmental disorder caused by de novo deletion of CHASERR, a long noncoding RNA
Authors: Ganesh, V. S.; Riquin, K.; Chatron, N.; Lamar, K.-M.; Aziz, M.; Monin, P.; O&amp;#39;Leary, M.; Goodrich, J. K.; Garimella, K. V.; England, E.; Yoon, E.; Weisburd, B.; Aguet, F.; Bacino, C. A.; Murdock, D. R.; Dai, H.; Rosenfeld, J. A.; Emrick, L. T.; Ketkar, S.; Sarusi, Y.; Sanlaville, D.; Kayani, S.; Broadbent, B.; Isidor, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>DNA methylation modulates nucleosome retention in sperm and H3K4 methylation deposition in early mouse embryos.
Authors: Fanourgakis, G.; Gaspa-Toneu, L.; Komarov, P. A.; Ozonov, E. A.; Smallwood, S. A.; Peters, A. H. F. M.
Score: 18.9, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579069
DNA methylation (DNAme) serves a stable gene regulatory function in somatic cells (1). In the germ line and during early embryogenesis, however, DNAme undergoes global erasure and re-establishment to support germ cell and embryonic development (2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Natural selection exerted by historical coronavirus epidemic(s): comparative genetic analysis in China Kadoorie Biobank and UK Biobank
Authors: Morris, S. C.; Lin, K.; Millwood, I. Y.; Yu, C.; Lv, J.; Pei, P.; Li, L.; Sun, D.; Davey Smith, G.; Chen, Z.; Walters, R. G.
Score: 23.0, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579075
BackgroundPathogens have been one of the primary sources of natural selection affecting modern humans. The footprints of historical selection events - &amp;#34;selective sweeps&amp;#34; - can be detected in the genomes of present-day individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Missing the vulnerable - Inequalities in social protection among the general population, people living with HIV, and adolescent girls and young women in 13 sub-Saharan African countries: Analysis of population-based surveys
Authors: Chipanta, D.; Amo-Agyei, S.; Hertzog, L.; Hosseinpoor, A. R.; Smith, M. J.; Mahoney, C.; Jaramillo Meija, J. G.; Keiser, O.; Estill, J.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2024-02-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302524
Inequality in access to services is a global problem mainly impacting the poorest populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Unequal access to diagnosis of myalgic encephalomyelitis in England
Authors: Ponting, C. P.; Samms, G. L.
Score: 64.6, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24302070
BackgroundPeople with Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS; sometimes referred to as chronic fatigue syndrome) experience very poor health-related quality of life and only rarely recover. ME/CFS has no curative treatment and no single diagnostic test. Public health and policy decisions relevant to ME/CFS require knowledge of its prevalence and barriers to diagnosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>TP53 mutation screening for patients at risk of myeloid malignancy
Authors: Mukherjee, D.; Lawal, R. A.; Fitzhugh, C. D.; Hourigan, C. S.; Dillon, L. W.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.24302401
There is increasing recognition of the risk of developing therapy-related myeloid malignancy, including after cellular therapy. While retrospective studies have implicated pre-existing TP53 mutated hematopoietic clones as a common causative mechanism, no prospective screening to identify those patients at greatest risk is currently possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent booster improves antibody binding and neutralization against emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variants
Authors: Jain, S.; Kumar, S.; Lai, L.; Linderman, S.; Malik, A. A.; Ellis, M. L.; Godbole, S.; Solis, D.; Sahoo, M. K.; Bechnak, K.; Paredes, I.; Tanios, R.; Kazzi, B.; Dib, S. M.; Litvack, M. B.; Wimalsena, S. T.; Ciric, C.; Rostad, C.; West, R.; Teng, I.-T.; Wang, D.; Kwong, P. D.; Rouphael, N.; Pinsky, B. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Altered IgG4 Antibody Response to Repeated mRNA versus Protein COVID Vaccines
Authors: Kalkeri, R.; Zhu, M.; Cloney-Clark, S.; Plested, J. S.; Parekh, A.; Gorinson, D.; Cai, R.; Mahato, S.; Ramanathan, P.; Aurelia, L. C.; John Selva, K.; Marchese, A. M.; Fries, L.; Chung, A. W.; Dunkle, L. M.
Score: 480.8, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301374
Repeated mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination has been associated with increases in the proportion of IgG4 in spike-specific antibody responses and concurrent reductions in Fc{gamma}-mediated effector functions that may limit control of viral infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>An Empirical Study on KDIGO-Defined Acute Kidney Injury Prediction in the Intensive Care Unit
Authors: Lyu, X.; Fan, B.; Hüser, M.; Hartout, P.; Gumbsch, T.; Faltys, M.; Merz, T. M.; Rätsch, G.; Borgwardt, K.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.24302063
MotivationAcute kidney injury (AKI) is a syndrome that affects a large fraction of all critically ill patients, and early diagnosis to receive adequate treatment is as imperative as it is challenging to make early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Perceptions, attitudes, and challenges regarding continuing professional development among Ethiopian Medical Laboratory professionals: A mixed-method study
Authors: Gudeta, A. N.; Sisay, A.; Shibabaw, A.; Kebede, E.; Tesfaye, F.; Kedida, G.; Deneke, N.; Teklu, T.; Cheneke, W.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.04.24302318
BackgroundMedical laboratory professionals play vital role in healthcare. The growing demand for quality laboratory services and emerging technologies underscore the crucial need for Continuing Professional Development (CPD). However, there is limited information on CPD programs in Ethiopia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Viroid-like colonists of human microbiomes
Authors: Zheludev, I. N.; Edgar, R. C.; Galiano, M. J. L.; De la Pena, M.; Babaian, A.; Bhatt, A. S.; Fire, A. Z.
Score: 801.3, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576352
Here, we describe the &amp;#34;Obelisks,&amp;#34; a previously unrecognised class of viroid-like elements that we first identified in human gut metatranscriptomic data. &amp;#34;Obelisks&amp;#34; share several properties: (i) apparently circular RNA [~]1kb genome assemblies, (ii) predicted rod-like secondary structures encompassing the entire genome, and (iii) open reading frames coding for a novel protein superfamily, which we call the &amp;#34;Oblins&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single-molecule chromatin configurations link transcription factor binding to expression in human cells
Authors: Doughty, B. R.; Hinks, M. M.; Schaepe, J. M.; Marinov, G. K.; Thurm, A. R.; Rios-Martinez, C.; Parks, B. E.; Tan, Y.; Marklund, E.; Dubocanin, D.; Bintu, L.; Greenleaf, W. J.
Score: 74.3, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.578660
The binding of multiple transcription factors (TFs) to genomic enhancers activates gene expression in mammalian cells. However, the molecular details that link enhancer sequence to TF binding, promoter state, and gene expression levels remain opaque.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Acute kidney injury outcomes of COVID-19 confirmed patients in a Philippine tertiary hospital: A retrospective study
Authors: Sayson, J.; Kalaw, R.; Ordona, B. E.; Lim, M. E.
Score: 14.7, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302369
The novel coronavirus (COVID-19) is known to be the fifth pandemic causing massive deaths worldwide. This virus has not only been deeply associated with acute respiratory distress, but also acute kidney injury (AKI). This study describes the baseline characteristics and various outcomes of AKI based on the KDIGO 2012 Clinical Practice Guidelines in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 at a Philippine tertiary hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Lesions causing Alice in Wonderland Syndrome map to a common brain network linking body and size perception
Authors: Friedrich, M. U.; Baughan, E. C.; Kletenik, I.; Younger, E.; Zhao, C. W.; Howard, C.; Ferguson, M. A.; Chen, A.; Zeller, D.; Piervincenzi, C.; Tommasin, S.; Pantano, P.; Blanke, O.; Prasad, S.; Nielsen, J.; Fox, M. D.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301332
BackgroundIn Lewis Carrolls 1865 novel &amp;#34;Alices Adventures in Wonderland&amp;#34;, the protagonist experiences distortions in the size of her body and those of others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Generation of surrogate brain maps preserving spatial autocorrelation through random rotation of geometric eigenmodes
Authors: Koussis, N. C.; Pang, J. C.; Jeganathan, J.; Paton, B.; Fornito, A.; Robinson, P. A.; Misic, B.; Breakspear, M.
Score: 42.6, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.579070
The brain expresses activity in complex spatiotemporal patterns, reflected in the influence of spatially distributed cytoarchitectural, biochemical, and genetic properties. The correspondence between these multimodal &amp;#34;brain maps&amp;#34; may reflect underlying causal pathways and is hence a topic of substantial interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Associations between genetically predicted iron status and cardiovascular disease risk: A Mendelian randomization study
Authors: Barad, A.; Clark, A. G.; O&amp;#39;Brien, K. O.; Pressman, E. K.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302373
BackgroundMendelian randomization (MR) studies suggest a causal effect of iron (Fe) status on cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk, but it is unknown if these associations are confounded by pleiotropic effects of the instrumental variables (IV) on CVD risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of cancer incidence among Marines and Navy personnel and civilian workers exposed to contaminated drinking water at USMC Base Camp Lejeune
Authors: Bove, F. J.
Score: 93.2, Published: 2024-01-29 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.27.24301873
BackgroundDrinking water at U.S. Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, North Carolina was contaminated with trichloroethylene and other industrial solvents from 1953 to 1985. MethodsA cohort cancer incidence study was conducted of Marines/Navy personnel who, between 1975 and 1985, began service and were stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina (N=154,821) or Camp Pendleton, California (N=163,484), and civilian workers employed at Camp Lejeune (N=6,494) or Camp Pendleton (N=5,797) between October 1972 and December 1985.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Convergence for Inactivation of TGFβ Signaling Is a Common Feature of Advanced Pancreatic Cancer
Authors: Hong, J.; Kohutek, Z.; Zhang, H.; Karnoub, E.-R.; Kappagantula, R.; Wood, L. D.; Iacobuzio-Donahue, C.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301554
We performed WES of 250 unique tumor tissues from 30 multiregion sampled pancreatic cancer research autopsies from patients diagnosed with advanced stage disease. We find that most genetic alterations in PDAC occur in a subclonal manner, and some genes occurred in a subclonal manner exclusively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Digital PCR-based deep quantitative profiling delineates heterogeneity and evolution of uveal melanoma
Authors: Nell, R. J.; Versluis, M.; Menger, N. V.; Verdijk, R. M.; Kroes, W. G. M.; Kapiteijn, E. H. W.; Luyten, G. P. M.; Jager, M. J.; van der Velden, P. A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301871
Uveal melanoma is an aggressive intraocular tumour characterised by a limited number of genetic alterations. However, the evolution of this malignancy remains enigmatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>A drug cocktail of rapamycin, acarbose, and phenylbutyrate enhances resilience to features of early-stage Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease in aging mice
Authors: Wezeman, J.; Darvas, M.; Postupna, N.; Klug, J.; Mangalindan, R. S.; Keely, A.; Nguyen, K.; Johnson, C.; Rosenfeld, M.; Ladiges, W.
Score: 13.2, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577437
The process of aging is defined by the breakdown of critical maintenance pathways leading to an accumulation of damage and its associated phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Unplugging lateral fenestrations of NALCN reveals a hidden drug binding site within the pore module
Authors: Schott, K.; Usher, S. G.; Serra, O.; Carnevale, V.; Pless, S.; Chua, H. C.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.12.536537
The sodium (Na&amp;#43;) leak channel (NALCN) is a member of the four-domain voltage-gated cation channel family that includes the prototypical voltage-gated sodium and calcium channels (NaVs and CaVs, respectively). Unlike NaVs and CaVs, which have four lateral fenestrations that serve as routes for lipophilic compounds to enter the central cavity to modulate channel function, NALCN has bulky residues (W311, L588, M1145 and Y1436) that block these openings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Rejuvenation of Senescent Cells by Low Frequency Ultrasound without Senolysis
Authors: Kureel, S. K.; Maroto, R.; Powell, S.; Margadant, F.; Blair, B.; Rasmussen, B.; Sheetz, M.
Score: 42.5, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2022.12.08.519320
It is believed that senescent cells are unable to grow; however, we have treated non-growing senescent cells with low frequency ultrasound (LFU) and they are rejuvenated for growth. Further, the senescent cells are characterized by low levels of motility but LFU treatment significantly increases the level of whole cell and organelle motility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 260.9, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Report: GLP-1 RA Prescribing Trends - December 2023 Data
Authors: Gratzl, S.; Rodriguez, P. J.; Cartwright, B. M. G.; Baker, C.; Stucky, N.
Score: 14.0, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301500
BackgroundLimited recent data exist on prescribing patterns and patient characteristics for glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonists (GLP-1 RAs), an important drug class used as anti-diabetic medication (ADM) for patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2D) and/or anti-obesity medication (AOM) in patients with overweight or obesity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Distinguishing different psychiatric disorders using DDx-PRS
Authors: Peyrot, W. J.; Panagiotaropoulou, G.; Olde Loohuis, L. M.; Adams, M.; Awasthi, S.; Ge, T.; McIntosh, A. M.; Mitchell, B. L.; Mullins, N.; O&amp;#39;Connell, K. S.; Penninx, B. W. J. H.; Posthuma, D.; Ripke, S.; Ruderfer, D. M.; Uffelmann, E.; Vilhjalmsson, B. J.; Zhu, Z.; Schizophrenia Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Bipolar Disorder Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Major Depressive Disorder Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Smoller, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Comparing surveyed adults with long COVID and those with just a positive test helps put COVID into perspective
Authors: Adams, M.; Grandpre, J.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2024-02-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302216
IntroductionAmong adults who test positive for COVID-19, some develop long COVID (symptoms lasting [&amp;amp;ge;]3 months), and some do not. We compared 3 groups on selected measures to help determine strategies to reduce COVID impact. MethodsUsing Stata and data for 385,617 adults from the 2022 Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, we compared adults reporting long COVID, those with just a positive test, and those who never tested positive, on several health status and risk factor measures plus vaccination rates (data for 178,949 adults in 29 states).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>First positronium image of the human brain in vivo
Authors: Moskal, P.; Baran, J.; Bass, S.; Choinski, J.; Chug, N.; Curceanu, C.; Czerwinski, E.; Dadgar, M.; Das, M.; Dulski, K. Ł; Eliyan, K. V.; Fronczewska, K.; Gajos, A.; Kacprzak, K.; Kajetanowicz, M.; Kaplanoglu, T.; Kaplon, L.; Klimaszewski, K.; Kobylecka, M.; Korcyl, G.; Kozik, T.; Krzemien, W.; Kubat, K.; Kumar, D.; Kunikowska, J.; Maczewska, J.; Migdal, W.; Moskal, G.; Mryka, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Structured Peer Review: Pilot results from 23 Elsevier Journals
Authors: Malicki, M.; Mehmani, B.
Score: 19.1, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.578440
BackgroundReviewers rarely comment on the same aspects of a manuscript, making it difficult to properly assess manuscripts quality and the quality of the peer review process. It was the goal of this pilot study to evaluate structured peer review implementation by: 1) exploring if and how reviewers answered structured peer review questions, 2) analysing reviewer agreement, 3) comparing that agreement to agreement before implementation of structured peer review, and 4) further enhancing the piloted set of structured peer review questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Indexing Healthcare Access and Quality for Surgically Amenable Conditions: A Global Analysis of 204 Countries and Territories from 1990 to 2019
Authors: Zadey, S.; Smith, E. R.; Staton, C. A.; Fitzgerald, T. N.; Nickenig Vissoci, J. R.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.04.24302290
IntroductionBuilding on past frameworks, our aim was to systematically analyze the healthcare access and quality (HAQ) index for surgically treatable conditions, its progress over time, and the gap compared to non-surgical HAQ across 204 countries and territories from 1990 to 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA-Diffusion: Leveraging Generative Models for Controlling Chromatin Accessibility and Gene Expression via Synthetic Regulatory Elements
Authors: Ferreira DaSilva, L.; Senan, S.; Patel, Z. M.; Reddy, A. J.; Gabbita, S.; Nussbaum, Z.; Cordova, C. M. V.; Wenteler, A.; Weber, N.; Tunjic, T. M.; Khan, T. A.; Li, Z.; Smith, C. R.; Bejan, M.; Louis, L. K.; Cornejo, P.; Connell, W.; Wong, E. S.; Meuleman, W.; Pinello, L.
Score: 63.5, Published: 2024-02-01 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Spatially Exploring RNA Biology in Archival Formalin-Fixed Paraffin-Embedded Tissues
Authors: Bai, Z.; Zhang, D.; Gao, Y.; Tao, B.; Bao, S.; Enninful, A.; Zhang, D.; Su, G.; Tian, X.; Zhang, N.; Xiao, Y.; Liu, Y.; Gerstein, M.; Li, M.; Xing, Y.; Lu, J.; Xu, M. L.; Fan, R.
Score: 71.4, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579143
Spatial transcriptomics has emerged as a powerful tool for dissecting spatial cellular heterogeneity but as of today is largely limited to gene expression analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Molecular signatures of chronic antibody-mediated rejection in human liver transplants
Authors: Engel, B.; Alaswad, A.; Campos-Murguia, A.; Zoodsma, M.; Klingbeil, A.; Chihab, K.; Bosselmann, E. A.; Heinrich, S.; Hartleben, B.; Jonigk, D. D.; Verboom, M.; Hallensleben, M.; Geffers, R.; Wedemeyer, H.; Xu, C.; Jaeckel, E.; Li, Y.; Taubert, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302515
Background&amp;amp;Aims: The role of antibody-mediated rejection (ABMR) after liver transplantation (LT) remains controversial. Chronic ABMR (cABMR) is often subclinical and potentially missed without surveillance biopsies (svLbx) which are not established in most LT centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 10:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Internal Transcribed Spacers as Phylogenetic Markers Enable Species-level Metataxonomic Analysis of Ciliated Protozoa
Authors: Somasundaram, S.; Yu, Z.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-02-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.578691
BackgroundThe conventional morphology-based classification of ciliates is often inaccurate and time-consuming. To address this issue, sequencing, and analysis of the 18S rRNA gene of ciliates have been used as an alternative. However, this method has limitations because the highly conserved nature of this gene makes it challenging to achieve species-level resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
