<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Snow flies self-amputate freezing limbs to sustain behavior at sub-zero temperatures
Authors: Golding, D.; Rupp, K.; Sustar, A.; Pratt, B.; Tuthill, J.
Score: 285.7, Published: 2023-05-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.29.541388
All living things are profoundly affected by temperature. In spite of the thermodynamic constraints on biology, some animals have evolved to live and move in extremely cold environments. Here, we investigate behavioral mechanisms of cold tolerance in the snow fly (Chionea spp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Intrinsically Disordered Regions Promote Protein Refoldability and Facilitate Retrieval from Biomolecular Condensates
Authors: To, P.; Bhagwat, A. M.; Tarbox, H. E.; Ecer, A.; Wendorff, H.; Jamieson, Z.; Trcek, T.; Fried, S. D.
Score: 109.3, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.25.546465
Many eukaryotic proteins contain intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs) that intersperse globular folded domains, in contrast with bacterial proteins which are typically highly globular. Recent years have seen great progress in identifying biological functions associated with these elusive protein sequence: in specific cases, they mediate liquid-liquid phase separation, perform molecular recognition, or act as sensors to changes in the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>QuantUMS: uncertainty minimisation enables confident quantification in proteomics
Authors: Kistner, F.; Grossmann, J. L.; Sinn, L. R.; Demichev, V.
Score: 49.3, Published: 2023-06-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545604
Mass spectrometry-based proteomics has been rapidly gaining traction as a powerful analytical method both in basic research and translation. While the problem of error control in peptide and protein identification has been addressed extensively, the quality of the resulting quantities remains challenging to evaluate. Here we introduce QuantUMS (Quantification using an Uncertainty Minimising Solution), a machine learning-based method which minimises errors and eliminates bias in peptide and protein quantification by integrating multiple sources of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Adhesion energy controls lipid binding-mediated endocytosis
Authors: Groza, R.; Schmidt, K. V.; Muller, P. M.; Ronchi, P.; Schlack-Leigers, C.; Neu, U.; Puchkov, D.; Dimova, R.; Matthaus, C.; Taraska, J. W.; Weikl, T.; Ewers, H.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.546235
Several bacterial toxins and viruses can deform membranes through multivalent binding to lipids for clathrin-independent endocytosis. However, it remains unclear, how membrane deformation and endocytic internalization are mechanistically linked. Here we show that many lipid-binding virions induce membrane deformation and clathrin-independent endocytosis, suggesting a common mechanism based on multivalent lipid binding by globular particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Deep intravital brain tumor imaging enabled by tailored three-photon microscopy and analysis
Authors: Schubert, M. C.; Soyka, S. J.; Tamimi, A.; Maus, E.; Denninger, R.; Wissmann, N.; Reyhan, E.; Tetzlaff, S. K.; Beretta, C.; Drumm, M.; Schroers, J.; Steffens, A.; Walshon, J.; McCortney, K.; Heiland, S.; Golebiewska, A.; Kurz, F. T.; Wick, W.; Winkler, F.; Kreshuk, A.; Kuner, T.; Horbinski, C.; Prevedel, R.; Venkataramani, V.
Score: 44.5, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Combinatorial selective ER-phagy remodels the ER during neurogenesis
Authors: Hoyer, M. J.; Smith, I. R.; Paoli, J. C.; Jiang, Y.; Paulo, J. A.; Harper, W.
Score: 24.5, Published: 2023-06-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.546565
The endoplasmic reticulum (ER) has a vast proteomic landscape to perform many diverse functions including protein and lipid synthesis, calcium ion flux, and inter-organelle communication. The ER proteome is remodeled in part through membrane-embedded receptors linking ER to degradative autophagy machinery (selective ER-phagy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Transgene-Free Ex Utero Derivation of A Human Post-Implantation Embryo Model Solely from Genetically Unmodified Naive PSCs
Authors: Oldak, B.; Wildschutz, E.; Bondarenko, V.; Aguilera-Castrejon, A.; Zhao, C.; Tarazi, S.; Comar, M.-Y.; Ashouokhi, S.; Lokshtanov, D.; Roncato, F.; Viukov, S.; Ariel, E.; Rose, M.; Livnat, N.; Shani, T.; Joubran, C.; Cohen, R.; Addadi, Y.; Kedmi, M.; Keren-Shaul, H.; Petropoulos, S.; Lanner, F.; Novershtern, N.; Hanna, J. H.
Score: 1057.3, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Genomic and ecological factors shaping specialism and generalism across an entire subphylum
Authors: Opulente, D. A.; LaBella, A. L.; Harrison, M.-C.; Wolters, J. F.; Liu, C.; Li, Y.; Kominek, J.; Steenwyk, J. L.; Stoneman, H. R.; VanDenAvond, J.; Miller, C. R.; Langdon, Q. K.; Silva, M.; Goncalves, C.; Ubbelohde, E. J.; Li, Y.; Buh, K. V.; Jarzyna, M.; Haase, M. A. B.; Rosa, C. A.; Cadez, N.; Libkind, D.; DeVirgilio, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The relationship between genotype- and phenotype-based estimates of genetic liability to human psychiatric disorders, in practice and in theory.
Authors: Dybdahl Krebs, M.; Appadurai, V.; Georgii Hellberg, K.-L.; Ohlsson, H.; Steinbach, J.; Pedersen, E. M.; iPSYCH Study Consortium, ; Werge, T.; Sundquist, J.; Sundquist, K.; Cai, N.; Zaitlen, N.; Dahl, A. W.; Vilhjalmsson, B. J.; Flint, J.; Bacanu, S.-A.; Schork, A. J.; Kendler, K. S.
Score: 24.3, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Nucleus-Independent Transgenerational Small RNA Inheritance in C. elegans
Authors: Rieger, I.; Weintraub, G.; Lev, I.; Goldstein, K.; Bar-Zvi, D.; Anava, S.; Gingold, H.; Shaham, S.; Rechavi, O.
Score: 155.9, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545749
Studies using C. elegans nematodes demonstrated that, against the dogma, animals can transmit epigenetic information transgenerationally. While it is now clear that in these worms ancestral RNA interference (RNAi) responses continue to regulate gene expression for many generations, it is still debated whether the primary agent that perpetuates heritable silencing is RNA or chromatin, and whether the information is communicated to the next generation inside or outside of the nucleus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Identification of a novel HKU4-related coronavirus in single-cell datasets and clade viral host analysis
Authors: Jones, A.; Massey, S. E.; Nemzer, L. R.; Zhang, D.; Deigin, Y.; Quay, S. C.
Score: 49.4, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545480
HKU4-related coronaviruses (CoVs) are merbecoviruses related to Middle Eastern Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV). In 2022 and 2023, two HKU4-related CoV strains were discovered in Manis javanica (Malayan pangolin) metagenomic datasets derived from organ samples: HKU4-P251T and MjHKU4r-CoV-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Infection-induced vascular inflammation in COVID-19 links focal microglial dysfunction with neuropathologies through IL-1/IL-6-related systemic inflammatory states
Authors: Fekete, R.; Simats, A.; Biro, E.; Cserep, C.; Schwarcz, A. D.; Posfai, B.; Szabadits, E.; Kornyei, Z.; Toth, K.; Kellermayer, A.; David, C.; Acsady, L.; Kontra, L.; Silvestre-Roig, C.; Moldvay, J.; Fillinger, J.; Hortobagyi, T.; Liesz, A.; Benko, S.; Denes, A.
Score: 20.8, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.546214
COVID-19 is associated with diverse neurological abnormalities, which predict poor outcome in patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) among Those Up-to-Date and Not Up-to-Date on COVID-19 Vaccination
Authors: Shrestha, N. K.; Burke, P. C.; Nowacki, A. S.; Gordon, S. M.
Score: 5163.1, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.09.23290893
BackgroundThe CDC recently defined being &amp;#34;up-to-date&amp;#34; on COVID-19 vaccination as having received at least one dose of a COVID-19 bivalent vaccine. The purpose of this study was to compare the risk of COVID-19 among those &amp;#34;up-to-date&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;not up-to-date&amp;#34; on COVID-19 vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Type IV-A3 CRISPR-Cas systems drive inter-plasmid conflicts by acquiring spacers in trans
Authors: Benz, F.; Camara-Wilpert, S.; Russel, J.; Wandera, K. G.; Cepaite, R.; Ares-Arroyo, M.; Gomes-Filho, J. V.; Englert, F.; Kuehn, J.; Gloor, S.; Cuenod, A.; Aguila-Sans, M.; Maccario, L.; Egli, A.; Randau, L.; Pausch, P.; Rocha, E.; Beisel, C. L.; Madsen, J. S.; Bikard, D.; Hall, A. R.; Soerensen, S. J.; Pinilla-Redondo, R.
Score: 74.8, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Vagus nerve inflammation contributes to dysautonomia in COVID-19
Authors: Woo, M. S.; Shafiq, M.; Fitzek, A.; Dottermusch, M.; Altmeppen, H.; Mohammadi, B.; Mayer, C.; Bal, L. C.; Raich, L.; Matschke, J.; Krasemann, S.; Pfefferle, S.; Brehm, T. T. S.; Luetgehetmann, M.; Schaedler, J.; Addo, M. M.; Schulze Zur Wiesch, J.; Ondruschka, B.; Friese, M. A.; Glatzel, M.
Score: 94.9, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.23291320
Dysautonomia has substantially impacted acute COVID-19 severity as well as symptom burden after recovery from COVID-19 (long COVID), yet the underlying causes remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A window to the brain: ultrasound imaging of human neural activity through a permanent acoustic window
Authors: Rabut, C.; Norman, S. L.; Griggs, W. S.; Russin, J. J.; Jann, K.; Christopoulos, V.; Liu, C.; Andersen, R. A.; Shapiro, M. G.
Score: 424.1, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.544094
Recording human brain activity is crucial for understanding normal and aberrant brain function. However, available recording methods are either highly invasive or have relatively low sensitivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>More spice, less salt: how capsaicin affects liking for and perceived saltiness of foods in people with smell loss.
Authors: Hunter, S.; Beatty, C.; Dalton, P. H.
Score: 39.7, Published: 2023-06-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.05.23290966
People who lose their sense of smell self-report consuming more salt to compensate for a lack of flavor and enhance eating enjoyment. However, this can contribute to excess sodium intake and a poor diet. Capsaicin may help increase salt taste intensity and eating enjoyment in this population, but this has not been studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Evidence for deliberate burial of the dead by Homo naledi
Authors: Berger, L. R.; Makhubela, T.; Molopyane, K.; Kruger, A.; Randolph-Quinney, P.; Elliott, M.; Peixotto, B.; Fuentes, A.; Tafforeau, P.; Beyrand, V.; Dollman, K.; Jinnah, Z.; Brewer Gillham, A.; Broad, K.; Brophy, J.; Chinamatira, G.; Dirks, P.; Feuerriegel, E.; Gurtov, A.; Hlophe, N.; Hunter, L.; Hunte, R.; Jakata, K.; Jaskolski, C.; Morris, H.; Pryor, E.; Ramaphela, M.; Roberts, E.; Smilg, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Dysregulated Platelet Function and Thrombosis in Patients with Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19
Authors: Aggarwal, A.; Singh, T. K.; Pham, M.; Godwin, M.; Chen, R.; McIntyre, T. M.; Chung, M. K.; Jennings, C.; Ali, M.; Park, H.; Englund, K.; Khorana, A. A.; Svensson, L.; Kapadia, S. R.; McCrae, K. R.; Cameron, S. J.
Score: 57.7, Published: 2023-06-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545507
ObjectivePost-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC, also referred as Long-COVID) sometimes follows COVID-19, a disease caused by SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Hip thrust and back squat training elicit similar gluteus muscle hypertrophy and transfer similarly to the deadlift
Authors: Plotkin, D. L.; Rodas, M. A.; Vigotsky, A.; McIntosh, M. C.; Breeze, E.; Ubrik, R.; Robitzsch, C.; Agyin-Birikorang, A.; Mattingly, M. L.; Michel, J. M.; Kontos, N. J.; Fruge, A. D.; Wilborn, C. M.; Weimar, W. H.; Bashir, A.; Beyers, R. J.; Henselmans, M.; Contreras, B. M.; Roberts, M. D.
Score: 40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the landscape of transcription factor promoter activity during vegetative development in Marchantia
Authors: Romani, F.; Sauret-Güeto, S.; Rebmann, M.; Annese, D.; Bonter, I.; Tomaselli, M.; Dierschke, T.; Delmans, M.; Frangedakis, E.; Silvestri, L.; Rever, J.; Bowman, J. L.; Romani, I.; Haseloff, J.
Score: 46.0, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.17.545419
Transcription factors (TFs) are essential for the regulation of gene expression and cell fate determination. Characterising the transcriptional activity of TF genes in space and time is a critical step towards understanding complex biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping neurodevelopmental diversity in executive function
Authors: Mareva, S.; The CALM Team, ; Holmes, J.
Score: 22.2, Published: 2023-06-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.15.23291392
Executive functions can be conceptualised as either a set of higher-order cognitive skills that enable us to engage in flexible thinking and regulate our thoughts and behaviours, or as the ability to integrate knowledge, beliefs, and values when applying cognitive control in everyday situations. These two perspectives map onto the ways in which executive function is measured in childhood - using either structured laboratory tasks or ratings of everyday behaviours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>A unified framework for estimating country-specific cumulative incidence for 18 diseases stratified by polygenic risk
Authors: Jermy, B.; Läll, K.; Wolford, B. N.; Wang, Y.; Zguro, K.; Cheng, Y.; Kanai, M.; Kanoni, S.; Yang, Z.; Hartnonen, T.; Monti, R.; Wanner, J.; Youssef, O.; Estonian Biobank research team, ; FinnGen, ; Lippert, C.; van Heel, D. A.; Okada, Y.; McCartney, D. L.; Hayward, C.; Marioni, R.; Furini, S.; Renieri, A.; Martin, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yorks0n.github.io/TRxiv2/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
