<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Animal Emotions and Consciousness: Researchers&amp;#39; Perceptions, Biases, and Prospects for Future Progress
Authors: Zipple, M. N.; Hazelwood, C.; Webster, M. F.; Benitez, M. E.
Score: 10.3, Published: 2023-10-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.562087
Do animals have emotions? Scientists and philosophers have long struggled with this question, with debates ranging from whether animals experience an &amp;#34;internal world&amp;#34; to whether we are capable of studying it. Recently, theoretical, and methodological advances have rekindled this debate, yet, it is unclear where the scientific consensus on these topics lies today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Generalized Biomolecular Modeling and Design with RoseTTAFold All-Atom
Authors: Krishna, R.; Wang, J.; Ahern, W.; Sturmfels, P.; Venkatesh, P.; Kalvet, I.; Lee, G. R.; Morey-Burrows, F. S.; Anishchenko, I.; Humphreys, I. R.; McHugh, R.; Vafeados, D.; Li, X.; Sutherland, G. A.; Hitchcock, A.; Hunter, C. N.; Baek, M.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 288.2, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561603
Although AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RoseTTAFold (RF) have transformed structural biology by enabling high-accuracy protein structure modeling, they are unable to model covalent modifications or interactions with small molecules and other non-protein molecules that can play key roles in biological function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Regionally-Activated Drugs for Neuroscience
Authors: Huang, Z.; Mitrofan, A.; Nouraein, S.; Horak, C.; Seo, J. P.; Harb, M.; Jin, R.; Szablowski, J. O.
Score: 16.8, Published: 2023-10-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.562069
The brain is comprised of multiple regions performing distinct functions. Within each of these regions, there are multiple cell types that can affect brain physiology. Finally, within each cell there are multiple signaling pathways, that, when activated or inhibited, control the cell activity, and consequently the brain function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>GPN-MSA: an alignment-based DNA language model for genome-wide variant effect prediction
Authors: Benegas, G.; Albors, C.; Aw, A. J.; Ye, C.; Song, Y. S.
Score: 62.3, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561776
Whereas protein language models have demonstrated remarkable efficacy in predicting the effects of missense variants, DNA counterparts have not yet achieved a similar competitive edge for genome-wide variant effect predictions, especially in complex genomes such as that of humans. To address this challenge, we here introduce GPN-MSA, a novel framework for DNA language models that leverages whole-genome sequence alignments across multiple species and takes only a few hours to train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Fast, whole-cell DNA-PAINT imaging with dual-labeled self-quenched imager probes
Authors: Sauer, M.; Ghosh, A.; Meub, M.; Helmerich, D. A.; Doose, S.
Score: 17.5, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561472
In DNA-PAINT, background fluorescence emerging from unbound imager probes requires the use of low imager concentrations, reducing the imaging speed substantially. Here, we present a novel class of dual-labeled probes that show strong fluorescence quenching when unbound, enabling imaging at higher probe concentrations with an up to [~]15-fold increase in imaging speed and improved resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>ASCT2 is the primary serine transporter in cancer cells
Authors: Conger, K. O.; Chidley, C.; Ozgurses, M. E.; Zhao, H.; Kim, Y.; Semina, S. E.; Burns, P. A.; Rawat, V.; Sheldon, R.; Ben-Sahra, I.; Frasor, J.; Sorger, P. K.; DeNicola, G. M.; Coloff, J. L.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561530
The non-essential amino acid serine is a critical nutrient for cancer cells due to its diverse biosynthetic functions. While some tumors can synthesize serine de novo, others are auxotrophic for serine and therefore reliant on the uptake of exogenous serine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Phenotypes associated with genetic determinants of type I interferon regulation in the UK Biobank: a protocol
Authors: Rioux, B.; Chong, M.; Walker, R.; McGlasson, S.; Rannikmae, K.; McCartney, D. L.; McCabe, J. J.; Brown, R.; Crow, Y. J.; Hunt, D.; Whiteley, W.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.23296935
IntroductionType I interferons are cytokines involved in innate immunity against viruses. Genetic disorders of type I interferon regulation are associated with a range of autoimmune and cerebrovascular phenotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Psychosocial experiences are associated with human brain mitochondrial biology
Authors: Trumpff, C.; Monzel, A.; Sandi, C.; Menon, V.; Klein, H.-U.; Fujita, M.; Lee, A. J.; Petyuk, V. A.; Hurst, C.; Duong, D. A.; Seyfried, N.; Wingo, A.; Wingo, T. S.; Wang, Y.; Thambisetty, M.; Ferrucci, L.; Bennett, D. A.; De Jager, P.; Picard, M.
Score: 37.3, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.559575
Psychosocial experiences affect brain health and aging trajectories, but the molecular pathways underlying these associations remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Scale-independent topological interactions drive the first fate decision in the Drosophila embryo
Authors: Hur, W.; Mukherjee, A.; Hayden, L.; Lu, Z.; Chao, A.; Mitchell, N. P.; Streichan, S. J.; Vergassola, M.; Di Talia, S.
Score: 16.8, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.561879
During embryogenesis, the earliest cell fate decision is often linked to nuclear positioning, whose control arises from the integration of the cell cycle oscillator and associated cytoskeletal dynamics. Yet, the mechanisms that ensure that the correct number of nuclei move to the appropriate place remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Diet and chemical defenses of the Sonoran Desert toads
Authors: Luccioni, M. D.; Wyman, J. T.; O&amp;#39;Connell, L. A.; Espinoza, E.
Score: 27.5, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561297
The Sonoran Desert Toad (Incilius alvarius) is the only animal known to secrete the psychedelic compound 5-MeO-DMT as a chemical defense, but the source of 5-MeO-DMT in I. alvarius remains unknown. Some amphibians endogenously produce chemical defenses while others acquire them from specialized diets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Inequalities in Accident and Emergency department attendance by socio-economic characteristics: population based study.
Authors: Gethings, O.; Machuel, P.; Nafilyan, V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296793
ObjectivesTo examine the relationship between deprivation and Accident and Emergency department attendance. DesignRetrospective cohort study. SettingEngland, United Kingdom, from 21 March 2021 to March 2022 ParticipantsAll individuals in the 2021 Census, aged 0 to 95 with an Emergency Department attendance record within the Emergency Care Dataset (ECDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>A set of circulating microRNAs belonging to the 14q32 chromosomic locus identifies two clinically and phenotypically different subgroups of individuals with recent onset Stage 3 type 1 diabetes
Authors: Sebastiani, G.; Grieco, G. E.; Bruttini, M.; Auddino, S.; Mori, A.; Toniolli, M.; Fignani, D.; Licata, G.; Nigi, L.; Formichi, C.; Pugliese, A.; Evans-Molina, C.; Overbergh, L.; Tree, T.; Peakman, M.; Mathieu, C.; Dotta, F.; INNODIA, Score: 6.4, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Did long COVID increase road deaths in the U.S.?
Authors: Robertson, L. S.
Score: 51.8, Published: 2023-10-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296868
Objective To examine data on COVID-19 disease associated with a 10 percent increase in U.S. road deaths from 2020 to 2021 that raises the question of the potential effect of pandemic stress and neurological damage from COVID-19 disease. Methods Poisson regression was used to estimate the association of recent COVID-19 cases, accumulated cases, maximum temperatures, truck registrations, and gasoline prices with road deaths monthly among U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>The landscape of ancient human pathogens in Eurasia from the Stone Age to historical times
Authors: Sikora, M.; Canteri, E.; Fernandez-Guerra, A.; Oskolkov, N.; Agren, R.; Hansson, L.; Irving-Pease, E. K.; Muehlemann, B.; Holtsmark Nielsen, S.; Scorrano, G.; Allentoft, M. E.; Seersholm, F. V.; Schroeder, H.; Gaunitz, C.; Stenderup, J.; Vinner, L.; Jones, T. C.; Nystedt, B.; Parkhill, J.; Fugger, L.; Racimo, F.; Kristiansen, K.; Iversen, A. K. N.; Willerslev, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Microbiome-based risk prediction in incident heart failure: a community challenge
Authors: Erawijantari, P. P.; Kartal, E.; Linares-Blanco, J.; Laajala, T. D.; Feldman, L. E.; The FINRISK Microbiome DREAM Challenge and ML4Microbiome Communities, ; Carmona-Saez, P.; Shigdel, R.; Claesson, M. J.; Bertelsen, R. J.; Gomez-Cabrero, D.; Minot, S.; Albrecht, J.; Chung, V.; Inouye, M.; Jousilahti, P.; Schultz, J.-H.; Friederich, H.-C.; Knight, R.; Salomaa, V.; Niiranen, T.; Havulinna, A. S.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Polygenic Embryo Screening: High Approval Despite Substantial Concerns from the U.S. Public
Authors: Furrer, R. A.; Barlevy, D.; Pereira, S.; Carmi, S.; Lencz, T.; Lazaro-Munoz, G.
Score: 12.9, Published: 2023-10-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23297022
Polygenic embryo screening (PES) is a novel, yet commercially available, technology that can compute genetic likelihood estimates of polygenic conditions (e.g., diabetes, depression) and traits (e.g., height, cognitive ability) in embryos. Patients undergoing in vitro fertilization (IVF) can use these polygenic scores to select which embryos to transfer for implantation with the goal of having a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Pervasive biases in proxy GWAS based on parental history of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Wu, Y.; Sun, Z.; Zheng, Q.; Miao, J.; Dorn, S.; Mukherjee, S.; Fletcher, J.; Lu, Q.
Score: 26.9, Published: 2023-10-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.562272
Almost every recent Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease (AD) genome-wide association study (GWAS) has performed meta-analysis to combine studies with clinical diagnosis of AD with studies that use proxy phenotypes based on parental disease history. Here, we report major limitations in current GWAS-by-proxy (GWAX) practices due to uncorrected survival bias and non-random participation of parental illness survey, which cause substantial discrepancies between AD GWAS and GWAX results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>p53 rapidly restructures 3D chromatin organization to trigger a transcriptional response
Authors: Serra, F.; Nieto-Aliseda, A.; Fanlo, L.; Rovirosa, L.; Cabrera-Pasadas, M.; Lazarenkov, A.; Urmeneta, B.; Alcalde, A.; Nola, E. M.; Okorokov, A. L.; Fraser, P.; Graupera, M.; Castillo, S. D.; Sardina, J. L.; Valencia, A.; Javierre, B. M.
Score: 18.2, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561663
Activation of the p53 tumor suppressor triggers a transcriptional program to control cellular response to stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of the updated COVID-19 mRNA Autumn 2023 vaccines in Germany
Authors: Joshi, K.; Scholz, S.; Maschio, M.; Kohli, M.; Lee, A.; Fust, K.; Ultsch, B.; van de Velde, N.; Beck, E.
Score: 37.3, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296505
ObjectivesTo assess the potential clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mRNA vaccines updated for Autumn 2023 in adults aged [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years and high-risk persons aged 30-59 years in Germany over a 1-year analytic time horizon (September 2023--August 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Real World Performance of the 21st Century Cures Act Population Level Application Programming Interface
Authors: Jones, J. R.; Gottlieb, D. I.; McMurry, A. J.; Atreja, A.; Desai, P. M.; Dixon, B. E.; Payne, P. R.; Saldanha, A. J.; Shankar, P. R.; Solad, Y. V.; Wilcox, A. B.; Ali, M. S.; Kang, E.; Martin, A. M.; Sprouse, E. A.; Taylor, D.; Terry, M.; Ignatov, V.; SMART Cumulus Network, ; Mandl, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the factors affecting global political priority for controlling sexually transmitted infections: a qualitative policy analysis
Authors: Wu, D.; Low, N.; Hawkes, S. J.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296476
IntroductionSexually transmitted infections (STIs) are a significant public health challenge, but there is a perceived lack of political priority in addressing STIs as a global health issue. Our study aimed to understand the determinants of global political priority for STIs since the 1980s and to discern implications for future prioritisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>The TB vaccine clinical trial centre directory: an inventory of clinical trial centres in sub-Saharan Africa
Authors: Pelzer, P. T.; Holleman, M.; Helinski, M. E.; Weinberg, A. L.; Beattie, P.; Nyirenda, T.; van Rest, J.; Voss, G.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296539
BackgroundThere are over ten vaccine candidates for tuberculosis (TB) in the clinical pipeline that require testing in TB-prevalent populations. To accelerate the clinical development of TB vaccines, a directory of clinical trial centres was established in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) to assess capacity for conducting late-stage TB vaccine trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Longitudinal viscosity of blood plasma for rapid COVID-19 prognostics
Authors: Illibauer, J.; Clodi-Seitz, T.; Zoufaly, A.; Aberle, J. H.; Weninger, W. J.; Foedinger, M.; Elsayad, K.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23297016
Blood Plasma Viscosity (PV) is an established biomarker for numerous diseases. While PV colloquially refers to the shear viscosity, there is a second viscosity component--the bulk viscosity--that describes the irreversible fluid compressibility on short time scales. The bulk viscosity is acutely sensitive to solid-like suspensions, and obtainable via the longitudinal viscosity from acoustic attenuation measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Facilitators and barriers to community pharmacy PrEP delivery: A scoping review.
Authors: Harrison, c.; Family, H.; Kesten, J.; Denford, S.; Scott, A.; Dawson, S.; Scott, J.; Sabin, C. A.; Copping, J.; Harryman, L.; Cochrane, S.; Horwood, J.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.23296672
IntroductionPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is an effective medication to reduce the risk of acquiring HIV. PrEP is available free of charge in the United Kingdom from sexual health clinics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 antibodies cross-react and enhance dengue infection
Authors: Jakhar, K.; Sonar, S.; Singh, G.; Sarkar, T.; Tiwari, M.; Kaur, J.; Rathore, D. K.; Lal, B.; Kumar, S.; Srivastav, P.; Kumar, S.; Phagna, V.; Kumar, L.; Gupta, V.; Kshetrapal, P.; Singh, S.; Wadhwa, N.; Thiruvengadam, R.; Raghavan, S.; Gosain, M.; Shrivastava, T.; Bhattacharyya, S.; Bhattacharya, J.; Asthana, S.; Mani, S.
Score: 202.5, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.557914
Dengue disease is highly prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>The more symptoms the better? Covid-19 vaccine side effects and long-term neutralizing antibody response
Authors: Dutcher, E. G.; Epel, E. S.; Mason, A. E.; Hecht, F. M.; Robinson, J. E.; Drury, S. S.; Prather, A. A.
Score: 247.2, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296186
Protection against SARS-CoV-2 wanes over time, and booster uptake has been low, in part because of concern about side effects. We examined the relationships between local and systemic symptoms, biometric changes, and neutralizing antibodies (nAB) after mRNA vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>MagSlice - Ultra Low-cost, modular and rapid 3D printed anatomical models for preoperative planning and patient education
Authors: Tucker, H.; Pickering, E.; Fysh, C.; Chen, M. Y.; Rukin, N.; Woodruff, M. A.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23295151
3D printed, patient-specific anatomical models have been demonstrated as effective tools for preoperative training, especially in complex surgeries involving rare cases or unique anatomy. Current, state-of-the-art solutions are expensive, requiring 3D printers with large capital and operating costs, making them impractical for common usage and less likely to be adopted in healthcare settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Integration of 168,000 samples reveals global patterns of the human gut microbiome
Authors: Abdill, R. J.; Graham, S. P.; Rubinetti, V.; Albert, F. W.; Greene, C. S.; Davis, S.; Blekhman, R.
Score: 88.9, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.560955
Understanding the factors that shape variation in the human microbiome is a major goal of research in biology. While other genomics fields have used large, pre-compiled compendia to extract systematic insights requiring otherwise impractical sample sizes, there has been no comparable resource for the 16S rRNA sequencing data commonly used to quantify microbiome composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Chemi-Northern: a versatile chemiluminescent northern blot method for analysis and quantitation of RNA molecules.
Authors: McKenney, K. M.; Connacher, R. P.; Dunshee, E. B.; Goldstrohm, A. C.
Score: 22.0, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561763
This report describes a chemiluminescence-based detection method for RNAs on northern blots, designated Chemi-Northern. This approach builds on the simplicity and versatility of northern blotting, while dispensing of the need for expensive and cumbersome radioactivity. RNAs are first separated on denaturing gel electrophoresis, transferred to a nylon membrane, and then hybridized to a biotinylated RNA or DNA antisense probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the multidimensional geometric landscape of graded phenotypic variation and progression in neurodegenerative syndromes
Authors: Ramanan, S.; Akarca, D.; Henderson, S. K.; Rouse, M.; Allinson, K.; Patterson, K.; Rowe, J.; Lambon Ralph, M. A.
Score: 6.7, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296861
Clinical variants of Alzheimers disease (AD) and frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) display a spectrum of cognitive-behavioural changes varying between individuals and over time. Understanding the landscape of these graded individual-/group-level longitudinal variations is critical for precise phenotyping; however, this remains challenging to model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A neural mechanism for learning from delayed postingestive feedback
Authors: Zimmerman, C. A.; Pan-Vazquez, A.; Wu, B.; Keppler, E. F.; Guthman, E. M.; Fetcho, R. N.; Bolkan, S. S.; McMannon, B.; Lee, J.; Hoag, A. T.; Lynch, L. A.; Janarthanan, S. N.; Lopez Luna, J. F.; Bondy, A. G.; Falkner, A. L.; Wang, S. S.-H.; Witten, I. B.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561214
Animals learn the value of foods based on their postingestive effects and thereby develop aversions to foods that are toxic1-6 and preferences to those that are nutritious7-14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Diet order affects energy balance in randomized crossover feeding studies that vary in macronutrients but not ultra-processing
Authors: Sciarrillo, C. M.; Guo, J.; Darcey, V. L.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 14.5, Published: 2023-10-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296501
BACKGROUNDCrossover studies can induce order effects, especially when they lack a wash-out period. OBJECTIVETo explore diet order effects on energy balance and food intake between randomized diet order groups in two inpatient crossover studies originally designed to compare within-subject differences in ad libitum energy intake between either minimally processed low carbohydrate (LC) versus low fat (LF) diets or macronutrient-matched diets composed of mostly minimally processed food (MPF) or ultra-processed food (UPF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Prediction of individual survival and trial outcome for anti-PDL1 treatment in non-small cell lung cancer using blood markers-based kinetics-machine learning
Authors: Benzekry, S.; Karslsen, M.; Bigarre, C.; El Kaoutari, A.; Gomes, B.; Stern, M.; Neubert, A.; Bruno, R.; Mercier, F.; Vatakuti, S.; Curle, P.; Jamois, C.
Score: 7.3, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296135
Current predictive models for survival following immune-checkpoint inhibition in non-small cell lung cancer typically use baseline or tumor kinetics data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrating the Utility of Instrumented Gait Analysis in the Treatment of Children with Cerebral Palsy
Authors: Schwartz, M. H.; Ries, A. J.; Georgiadis, A. G.; Kainz, H.
Score: 5.6, Published: 2023-10-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23296949
Background: Instrumented gait analysis (IGA) has been around for a long time but has never been shown to be useful for improving patient outcomes. In this study we demonstrate the potential utility of IGA by showing that machine learning models are better able to estimate treatment outcomes when they include both IGA and clinical (CLI) features compared to when they include CLI features alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of hind limb morphology of Titanosauriformes (Dinosauria, Sauropoda) via 3D Geometric Morphometrics reveals wide-gauge posture as an exaptation for gigantism
Authors: Paramo Blazquez, A.; Mocho, P.; Escaso, F.; Ortega, F.
Score: 14.1, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.560839
AbstractThe sauropod hind limb is the main support that allowed their gigantic body masses and a wide range of dynamic stability adaptations. It is closely related with the position of the centre of masses of their multi-toned barrel-shaped bodies, and experiences one of the most noticeable posture changes along macronarian evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Highly biased agonism for GPCR ligands via nanobody tethering
Authors: Sachdev, S.; Creemer, B. A.; Gardella, T. J.; Cheloha, R.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561766
Ligand-induced activation of G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) can initiate signaling through multiple distinct pathways with differing biological and physiological outcomes. There is intense interest in understanding how variation in GPCR ligand structure can be used to promote pathway selective signaling (biased agonism) with the goal of promoting desirable responses and avoiding deleterious side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>A red-emitting carborhodamine for monitoring and measuring membrane potential
Authors: Gest, A. M. M.; Lazzari-Dean, J. R.; Ortiz, G.; Yaeger-Weiss, S. K.; Boggess, S. C.; Miller, E. W.
Score: 34.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561080
Biological membrane potentials, or voltages, are a central facet of cellular life. Optical methods to visualize cellular membrane voltages with fluorescent indicators are an attractive complement to traditional electrode-based approaches, since imaging methods can be high throughput, less invasive, and provide more spatial resolution than electrodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>A conserved ESCRT-II-like protein participates in the biogenesis and maintenance of thylakoid membranes
Authors: Yilmazer, I.; Vetrano, P.; Eicke, S.; Abt, M. R.; Traverso, E.; Morosinotto, T.; Zeeman, S. C.; Ramundo, S.; Sharma, M.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561251
Thylakoids are membrane-bound compartments located in cyanobacteria and chloroplasts of plants and algae. They play an indispensable role in the light-driven reactions that enable photosynthetic organisms to convert water and carbon dioxide into oxygen and sugars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Transdiagnostic failure to adapt interoceptive precision estimates across affective, substance use, and eating disorders: A replication study
Authors: Lavalley, C. A.; Hakimi, N.; Taylor, S.; Kuplicki, R.; Forthman, K. L.; Stewart, J. L.; Paulus, M. P.; Khalsa, S. S.; Smith, R.
Score: 16.3, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296870
Recent computational theories of interoception suggest that perception of bodily states rests upon an expected reliability- or precision-weighted integration of afferent signals and prior beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Ischemic Stroke after Bivalent COVID-19 Vaccination: A Self-Controlled Case Series Study
Authors: Xu, S.; Sy, L. S.; Hong, V.; Holmquist, K. J.; Qian, L.; Farrington, P.; Bruxvoort, K. J.; Klein, N. P.; Fireman, B.; Han, B.; Lewin, B. J.
Score: 128.6, Published: 2023-10-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.23296968
Introduction The potential association between bivalent COVID-19 vaccination and ischemic stroke remains uncertain, despite several studies conducted thus far. The purpose is to evaluate the risk of ischemic stroke following bivalent COVID-19 vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Microstructure-Informed Myelin Mapping (MIMM) from Gradient Echo MRI using Stochastic Matching Pursuit
Authors: Sisman, M.; Nguyen, T. D.; Roberts, A. G.; Romano, D. J.; Dimov, A. V.; Kovanlikaya, I.; Spincemaille, P.; Wang, Y.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295993
Quantification of the myelin content of the white matter is important for studying demyelination in neurodegenerative diseases such as Multiple Sclerosis (MS), particularly for longitudinal monitoring. A novel noninvasive MRI method, called Microstructure-Informed Myelin Mapping (MIMM), is developed to quantify the myelin volume fraction (MVF) by utilizing a multi gradient echo sequence (mGRE) and a detailed biophysical model of tissue microstructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2, influenza A/B and respiratory syncytial virus positivity and association with influenza-like illness and self-reported symptoms, over the 2022/23 winter season in the UK: a longitudinal surveillance cohort
Authors: Dietz, E.; Pritchard, E. E.; Pouwels, K.; Ehsaan, M.; Blake, J.; Gaughan, C.; Haduli, E.; Boothe, H.; Vihta, K.-D.; Peto, T.; Stoesser, N.; Matthews, P.; Taylor, N.; Diamond, I.; Studley, R.; Rourke, E.; Birrell, P.; De Angelis, D.; Fowler, T.; Watson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Functional genomics implicates natural killer cells as potential key drivers in the pathogenesis of ankylosing spondylitis
Authors: Chinas, M.; Fernandez-Salinas, D.; Aguiar, V. R.; Nieto-Caballero, V. E.; Lefton, M.; Nigrovic, P. A.; Ermann, J.; Gutierrez-Arcelus, M.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.21.23295912
ObjectiveMultiple lines of evidence indicate that ankylosing spondylitis (AS) is a lymphocyte-driven disease. However, which lymphocyte populations are critical in AS pathogenesis is not known. In this study, we aimed to identify the key cell types mediating the genetic risk in AS using an unbiased integrative functional genomics approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Keywords to success: a practical guide to maximise the visibility and impact of academic papers
Authors: Pottier, P.; Lagisz, M.; Burke, S.; Drobniak, S. M.; Downing, P. A.; Macartney, E. L.; Martinig, A. R.; Mizuno, A.; Morrison, K.; Pollo, P.; Ricolfi, L.; Tam, J.; Williams, C.; Yang, Y.; Nakagawa, S.
Score: 40.7, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.559861
In a growing digital landscape, enhancing the discoverability and resonance of scientific articles is essential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Experiences and impacts of side effects among contraceptive users in the UK: exploring individual narratives of contraceptive side effects
Authors: Stewart, C. L.; Stevens, R.; Kennedy, F.; Cecula, P.; Rueda Carrasco, E.; Hall, J.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.23296334
PurposeWhile many women worldwide use contraception, there is a paucity of research on individual experiences of side effects and their impacts. To address this gap, we analysed free-text responses of contraception experiences from 337 women aged 18 to 35, based in the UK who took part in an online survey on contraception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>A discovery platform to identify inducible synthetic circuitry from varied microbial sources
Authors: Robinson, C. M.; Carreno, D.; Weber, T.; Chen, Y.; Riglar, D. T.
Score: 15.8, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.562223
Gut-resident microbes encode a variety of systems capable of sophisticated sensing and conditional gene expression control within the mammalian gut during health and disease. Bacterial synthetic biology approaches, such as whole-cell biosensing and &amp;#39;sense-and-respond&amp;#39; therapeutics, aim to re-purpose such systems for research and clinical applications; however, the toolbox of well characterised in vivo and disease-related inducible systems remains limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>The fitness cost of spurious phosphorylation
Authors: Bradley, D.; Hogrebe, A.; Dandage, R.; Dube, A. K.; Leutert, M.; Dionne, U.; Chang, A.; Villen, J.; Landry, C. R.
Score: 17.0, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.08.561337
The fidelity of signal transduction requires the binding of regulatory molecules to their cognate targets. However, the crowded cell interior risks off-target interactions between proteins that are functionally unrelated. How such off-target interactions impact fitness is not generally known, but quantifying this is required to understand the constraints faced by cell systems as they evolve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
