<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Poor immunogenicity upon SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccinations in autoimmune SLE patients is associated with pronounced EF-mediated responses and anti-BAFF/Belimumab treatment.
Authors: Faliti, C. E.; Anam, F.; Cheedarla, N.; Woodruff, M.; Usman, S.; Runnstrom, M.; Van, T.; Kyu, S.; Ahmed, H.; Morrison-Porter, A.; Quehl, H.; Haddad, N. S.; Chen, W.; Cheedarla, S.; Neish, A.; Roback, J. D.; Antia, R.; Khosroshahi, A.; Lee, F. E.-H.; Sanz, I.
Score: 3.7, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anesthesia</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/anesthesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/anesthesia/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of ChatGPT vs. Bard to Anesthesia-related Queries
Authors: Patnaik, S. S.; Hoffmann, U.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.23292057
We investigated the ability of large language models (LLMs) to answer anesthesia related queries prior to surgery from a patients point of view. In the study, we introduced textual data evaluation metrics, investigated &amp;#34;hallucinations&amp;#34; phenomenon, and evaluated feasibility of using LLMs at the patient-clinician interface. ChatGPT was found to be lengthier, intellectual, and effective in its response as compared to Bard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A densely sampled and richly annotated acoustic dataset from a wild bird population
Authors: Merino Recalde, N.; Estandia, A.; Pichot, L.; Vansse, A.; Cole, E. F.; Sheldon, B. C.
Score: 44.6, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.547484
We present a high-resolution, densely-sampled dataset of wild bird songs collected over multiple years from a single population of Great Tits (Parus major) in the UK. The dataset includes over 1,100,000 individual acoustic units from 109,963 richly annotated songs, sung by more than 400 individual birds, and provides unprecedented detail on the vocal behaviour of wild birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Intrinsically Disordered Regions Promote Protein Refoldability and Facilitate Retrieval from Biomolecular Condensates
Authors: To, P.; Bhagwat, A. M.; Tarbox, H. E.; Ecer, A.; Wendorff, H.; Jamieson, Z.; Trcek, T.; Fried, S. D.
Score: 129.0, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.25.546465
Many eukaryotic proteins contain intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs) that intersperse globular folded domains, in contrast with bacterial proteins which are typically highly globular1, 2. Recent years have seen great progress in identifying biological functions associated with these elusive protein sequence: in specific cases, they mediate liquid liquid phase separation3, perform molecular recognition4, or act as sensors to changes in the environment5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Direct 3D-bioprinting of hiPSC-derived cardiomyocytes to generate functional cardiac tissues
Authors: Esser, T. U.; Anspach, A.; Muenzebrock, K. A.; Kah, D.; Schruefer, S.; Schenk, J.; Heinze, K. G.; Schubert, D. W.; Fabry, B.; Engel, F. B.
Score: 78.6, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.12.544557
3D-bioprinting is a promising technology to produce human tissues as drug screening tool or for organ repair. However, direct printing of living cells has proven difficult. Here, we present a method to directly 3D-bioprint human induced pluripotent stem cell (hiPSC)-derived cardiomyocytes embedded in a collagen-hyaluronic acid ink generating centimeter-sized functional ring- and ventricle-shaped cardiac tissues in an accurate and reproducible manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>DrugGPT: A GPT-based Strategy for Designing Potential Ligands Targeting Specific Proteins
Authors: Li, Y.; Gao, C.; Song, X.; Wang, X.; Xu, Y.; Han, S.
Score: 35.7, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.543848
DrugGPT presents a ligand design strategy based on the autoregressive model, GPT, focusing on chemical space exploration and the discovery of ligands for specific proteins. Deep learning language models have shown significant potential in various domains including protein design and biomedical text analysis, providing strong support for the proposition of DrugGPT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Fiber alignment in 3D collagen networks as a biophysical marker for cell contractility
Authors: Boehringer, D.; Bauer, A.; Moravec, I.; Bischof, L.; Kah, D.; Mark, C.; Grundy, T. J.; Goerlach, E.; O&amp;#39;Neill, G. M.; Budday, S.; Strissel, P.; Strick, R.; Malandrino, A.; Gerum, R.; Mak, M.; Rausch, M.; Fabry, B.
Score: 33.6, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.546896
Cells cultured in 3D fibrous biopolymer matrices exert traction forces on their environment that induce deformations and remodeling of the fiber network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Small extracellular vesicles promote stiffness-mediated metastasis
Authors: Sneider, A.; Liu, Y.; Starich, B.; Du, W.; Marar, C.; Faqih, N.; Ciotti, G. E.; Kim, J. H.; Krishnan, S.; Ibrahim, S.; Igboko, M.; Locke, A.; Lewis, D. M.; Hong, H.; Karl, M.; Vij, R.; Russo, G. C.; Nair, P. R.; Gomez-de-Mariscal, E.; Habibi, M.; Munoz-Barrutia, A.; Gu, L.; Eisinger-Mathason, T. S. K.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 28.6, Published: 2023-07-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.545937
Tissue stiffness is a critical prognostic factor in breast cancer and is associated with metastatic progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Integrative metabolomics differentiate coronary artery disease, peripheral artery disease, and venous thromboembolism risks
Authors: Lee, J.; Gilliland, T.; Koyama, S.; Nakao, T.; Dron, J.; Lannery, K.; Wong, M.; Peloso, G. M.; Hornsby, W.; Natarajan, P.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291103
RationaleArterial and venous cardiovascular conditions, such as coronary artery disease (CAD), peripheral artery disease (PAD), and venous thromboembolism (VTE), are genetically correlated. Interrogating distinct and overlapping mechanisms may shed new light on disease mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Self-extinguishing relay waves enable homeostaticcontrol of human neutrophil swarming
Authors: Strickland, J.; Pan, D.; Godfrey, C.; Kim, J. S.; Hopke, A.; Degrange, M.; Villavicencio, B.; Mansour, M. K.; Zerbe, C. S.; Irimia, D.; Amir, A.; Weiner, O. D.
Score: 542.7, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546744
Neutrophils exhibit self-amplified swarming to sites of injury and infection. How swarming is controlled to ensure the proper level of neutrophil recruitment is unknown. Using an ex vivo model of infection, we find that human neutrophils use active relay to generate multiple pulsatile waves of swarming signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Nitrate reduction capacity of the oral microbiota is impaired in periodontitis: potential implications for systemic nitric oxide availability
Authors: Rosier, B. T.; Johnston, W.; Carda-Dieguez, M.; Simpson, A.; Cabello-Yeves, E.; Piela, K.; Reilly, R.; Artacho, A.; Easton, C.; Burleigh, M.; Culshaw, S.; Mira, A.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291703
BackgroundThe reduction of nitrate to nitrite by the oral microbiota has been proposed to be important for oral health and results in nitric oxide formation that can improve cardiometabolic conditions, such as hypertension and diabetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Transgene-Free Ex Utero Derivation of A Human Post-Implantation Embryo Model Solely from Genetically Unmodified Naive PSCs
Authors: Oldak, B.; Wildschutz, E.; Bondarenko, V.; Aguilera-Castrejon, A.; Zhao, C.; Tarazi, S.; Comar, M.-Y.; Ashouokhi, S.; Lokshtanov, D.; Roncato, F.; Viukov, S.; Ariel, E.; Rose, M.; Livnat, N.; Shani, T.; Joubran, C.; Cohen, R.; Addadi, Y.; Kedmi, M.; Keren-Shaul, H.; Petropoulos, S.; Lanner, F.; Novershtern, N.; Hanna, J. H.
Score: 1263.3, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>GIFT an R package to access the Global Inventory of Floras and Traits
Authors: Denelle, P.; Weigelt, P.; Kreft, H.
Score: 178.6, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546704
O_LIAdvancing knowledge of biodiversity requires open-access global databases and workflows. This appears particularly crucial for plants, as ongoing changes pose major threats to this central group of organisms. Having large-scale information on plant distributions, functional traits and evolutionary history will enable the scientific community to improve its understanding of the patterns and drivers of plant diversity on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage substantially decrease the incidence of electric scooter injuries
Authors: Pakarinen, O.; Kobylin, A.; Harjola, V.-P.; Castren, M.; Vasara, H.
Score: 48.6, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291641
ObjectiveTo investigate the effectiveness of restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage on the incidence of e-scooter-related injuries. DesignA retrospective comparative study. We compared shared e-scooter injuries from two periods: Unrestricted period (1.1-31.8.2021), and Restricted period (1.1.-31.8.2022). SettingGeneral population of Helsinki, Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Brain Dopamine Receptor System is Not Altered in Obesity: Bayesian and Frequentist Meta-Analyses
Authors: Pak, K.; Nummenmaa, L.
Score: 8.5, Published: 2023-06-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291735
BackgroundFeeding induces dopamine release in the striatum, and a dysfunction of the dopaminergic reward system can lead to overeating, and obesity. Studies have reported inconsistent findings of dopamine receptor (DR) positron emission tomography (PET) scans in obesity. Here we investigated the association between DR availability and overweight/obesity using Bayesian and frequentist meta-analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Design and Analysis Heterogeneity in Observational Studies of COVID-19 Booster Effectiveness: A Review and Case Study
Authors: Meah, S.; Shi, X.; Fritsche, L. G.; Salvatore, M.; Wagner, A.; Martin, E. T.; Mukherjee, B.
Score: 63.0, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291692
BackgroundObservational vaccine effectiveness (VE) studies based on real-world data are a crucial supplement to initial randomized clinical trials of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccines. However, there exists substantial heterogeneity in study designs and statistical methods for estimating VE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Enamel proteins reveal biological sex and genetic variability within southern African Paranthropus
Authors: Madupe, P. P.; Koenig, C.; Patramanis, I.; Rüther, P. L.; Hlazo, N.; Mackie, M.; Tawane, M.; Krueger, J.; Taurozzi, A. J.; Troche, G. B.; Kibii, J.; Pickering, R.; Dickinson, M. R.; Sahle, Y.; Kgotleng, D.; Musiba, C.; Manthi, F.; Bell, L.; du Plessis, M.; Gilbert, C.; Zipfel, B.; Kuderna, L.; Lizano, E.; Welker, F.; Kyriakidou, P.; Cox, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive profiling of the human intestinal DNA virome and prediction of disease-associated bacterial hosts in severe Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS)
Authors: Hsieh, S.-Y.; Savva, G. M.; Telatin, A.; Tiwari, S. K.; Tariq, M. A.; Newberry, F.; Seton, K. A.; Booth, C.; Bansal, A. S.; Wileman, T.; Andriaenssens, E.; Carding, S. R.
Score: 12.8, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.23291738
Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) is a disabling disorder of unknown etiology with severely affected patients being house- and/or bedbound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Genetic similarity between relatives provides evidence on the presence and history of assortative mating
Authors: Sunde, H. F.; Eftedal, N. H.; Cheesman, R.; Corfield, E. C.; Kleppesto, T. H.; Seierstad, A. C.; Ystrom, E.; Eilertsen, E. M.; Torvik, F. A.
Score: 35.4, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546663
Assortative mating - the non-random mating of individuals with similar traits - is known to increase trait-specific genetic variance and genetic similarity between relatives1-7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Sequence basis of transcription initiation in human genome
Authors: Dudnyk, K.; Shi, C.; Zhou, J.
Score: 73.3, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546584
Transcription initiation is an essential process for ensuring proper function of any gene, however, a unified understanding of sequence patterns and rules that determine transcription initiation sites in human genome remains elusive. By explaining transcription initiation at basepair resolution from sequence with a deep learning-inspired explainable modeling approach, here we show that simple rules can explain the vast majority of human promoters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning in medicine using JavaScript: building web apps using TensorFlow.js for interpreting biomedical datasets
Authors: Pires, J. G.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291717
IntroductionContributions to medicine may come from different areas; and most areas are full of researchers wanting to support. Physists may help with theory, such as for nuclear medicine. Engineers with machineries, such as dialysis machine. Mathematicians with models, such as pharmacokinetics. And computer scientists with codes such as bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The physical and mental health benefits of touch interventions: A comparative systematic review and multivariate meta-analysis
Authors: Packheiser, J.; Hartmann, H.; Fredriksen, K.; Gazzola, V.; Keysers, C.; Michon, F.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291651
IntroductionReceiving touch is of critical importance for human well-being. A large number of studies have shown that touch promotes mental and physical health. However, effect sizes differ considerably across studies and potential moderators of touch interventions remain unknown to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Driving uptake of missed routine vaccines in adolescent and adult migrants: a prospective observational mixed-methods pilot study of catch-up vaccination in UK general practice
Authors: Crawshaw, A. F.; Goldsmith, L. P.; Deal, A.; Carter, J.; Knights, F.; Seedat, F.; Lau, K.; Hayward, S. E.; Yong, J.; Fyle, D.; Aspray, N.; Iwami, M.; Ciftci, Y.; Wurie, F.; Majeed, A.; Forster, A. S.; Hargreaves, S.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292165</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Paridiprubart inhibits TLR4-dependant NF-κB activation by multiple pathogens
Authors: Malty, R.; Hilbe, R.; Ahn, S.; Kesselman, L.; Lam, J.; Kasawara, K.; Costa, L.; Rajakulendran, N.; Gordon, B.; Brooks, M.; Mubareka, S.; Tancevski, I.; Gray-Owen, S. D.
Score: 38.0, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.545921
Respiratory pathogens such as SARS-CoV-2 and influenza can activate an exaggerated inflammatory response (cytokine storm) in the lungs that may result in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), hospitalization, and death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Increased circulating fibronectin, depletion of natural IgM and heightened EBV, HSV-1 reactivation in ME/CFS and long COVID
Authors: Liu, Z.; Hollmann, C.; Kalanidhi, S.; Grothey, A.; Keating, S.; Mena-Palomo, I.; Lamer, S.; Schlosser, A.; Kaiping, A.; Scheller, C.; Sotzny, F.; Horn, A.; Nuernberger, C.; Cejka, V.; Afshar, B.; Bahmer, T.; Schreiber, S.; Janne Vehreschild, J.; Milljukov, O.; Schaefer, C.; Kretzler, L.; Keil, T.; Reese, J.-P.; Eichner, F. A.; Schmidbauer, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Amazing structural diversity of giant virus-like particles in forest soil
Authors: Fischer, M. G.; Mersdorf, U.; Blanchard, J. L.
Score: 118.6, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.546935
Large DNA viruses of the phylum Nucleocytoviricota infect diverse eukaryotic hosts from protists to humans, with profound consequences for aquatic and terrestrial ecosystems. While nucleocytoviruses are known to be highly diverse in metagenomes, knowledge of their capsid structures is restricted to a few characterized representatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Programmable RNA-guided endonucleases are widespread in eukaryotes and their viruses
Authors: Jiang, K.; Lim, J.; Sgrizzi, S.; Trinh, M.; Kayabolen, A.; Yutin, N.; Koonin, E. V.; Abudayyeh, O. O.; Gootenberg, J. S.
Score: 243.6, Published: 2023-06-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.13.544871
TnpB proteins are RNA-guided nucleases that are broadly associated with IS200/605 family transposons in prokaryotes. TnpB homologs, named Fanzors, have been detected in genomes of some eukaryotes and large viruses, but their activity and functions in eukaryotes remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the population-level kidney benefits of improved uptake of SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with chronic kidney disease in Australian primary care
Authors: Neuen, B. L.; Jun, M.; Wick, J.; Kotwal, S.; Badve, S. V.; Jardine, M. J.; Gallagher, M.; Chalmers, J.; Nallaiah, K.; Perkovic, V.; Peiris, D.; Rodgers, A.; Woodward, M.; Ronksley, P.
Score: 7.3, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291881
BackgroundAlthough sodium glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors reduce the risk of kidney failure and death in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD), they are underused in routine clinical practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Navigating the chaos of psychedelic neuroimaging: A multi-metric evaluation of acute psilocybin effects on brain entropy
Authors: McCulloch, D. E.-W.; Olsen, A. S.; Ozenne, B.; Stenbaek, D. S.; Armand, S.; Madsen, M. K.; Knudsen, G. M.; Fisher, P. M.
Score: 11.2, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292164
Investigations into the acute effects of psychedelics on brain imaging have emphasised increased &amp;#39;brain entropy&amp;#39; as a potential neural correlate. To date, 12 previous studies have reported brain entropy effects, each reporting a single and unique metric, none of which have been examined in an independent cohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuronal wiring diagram of an adult brain
Authors: Dorkenwald, S.; Matsliah, A.; Sterling, A. R.; Schlegel, P.; Yu, S.-c.; McKellar, C. E.; Lin, A.; Costa, M.; Eichler, K.; Yin, Y.; Silversmith, W.; Schneider-Mizell, C.; Jordan, C. S.; Brittain, D.; Halageri, A.; Kuehner, K.; Ogedengbe, O.; Morey, R.; Gager, J.; Kruk, K.; Perlman, E.; Yang, R.; Deutsch, D.; Bland, D.; Sorek, M.; Lu, R.; Macrina, T.; Lee, K.; Bae, J. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Strength of Statistical Evidence for the Efficacy of Cancer Drugs: A Bayesian Re-Analysis of Trials Supporting FDA Approval.
Authors: Pittelkow, M.-M.; Linde, M.; de Vries, Y. A.; Hemkens, L. G.; Schmitt, A. M.; Meijer, R. R.; van Ravenzwaaij, D.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.23292074
ObjectiveTo quantify the strength of statistical evidence of randomised controlled trials (RCTs) for novel cancer drugs approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) in the last two decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Alternative protocols of tissue fixation dramatically reduces the impact of DNA artifacts, unraveling the interpretation of clinical Comprehensive Genomic Profiling
Authors: Berrino, E.; Bellomo, S. E.; Chesta, A.; Detillo, P.; Bragoni, A.; Gagliardi, A.; Naccarati, A.; Cereda, M.; Witel, G.; Sapino, A.; Bussolati, B.; Bussolati, G. P.; Marchio, C.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-06-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.17.23291533
Formalin-fixed-paraffin-embedded (FFPE) samples represent the cornerstone of tissue-based analysis in precision medicine. Targeted next-generation sequencing (NGS) panels are routinely used to analyze a limited number of genes to guide treatment decision making for advanced stage patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Early-life seizures and epileptic spasms in STXBP1-related disorders
Authors: Thalwitzer, K.; Xian, J.; deCampo, D.; Parthasarathy, S.; Magielski, J.; Sullivan, K. R.; Goss, J.; Son Rigby, C.; Boland, M.; Prosser, B.; Ruggiero, S. M.; Syrbe, S.; Helbig, I.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291892
Background and ObjectivesIndividuals with disease-causing variants in STXBP1 frequently have epilepsy onset in the first year of life with a variety of seizure types, including epileptic spasms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Low Dose Naltrexone use for the management of post acute sequelae of COVID 19
Authors: Bonilla, H.; Tian, L.; Marconi, V.; Shafer, R. W.; Mccomsey, G.; Miglis, M. G.; Yang, P. C.; Geng, L. N.
Score: 23.6, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.08.23291102
Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC), also known as Long COVID, is globally estimated to have affected up to 40-50% of individuals who were infected with SARS-CoV-2. The causes of PASC are being investigated, and there are no established therapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Discovery of New Broad-Spectrum Anti-Infectives for Eukaryotic Pathogens Using Bioorganometallic Chemistry
Authors: Lin, Y.; Jung, H.; Bulman, C. A.; Ng, J.; Vinck, R.; O&amp;#39;Beirne, C.; Moser, M. S.; Tricoche, N.; Peguero, R.; Li, R. W.; Urban, J. F.; Le Pape, P.; Pagniez, F.; Moretto, M.; Weil, T.; Lustigman, S.; Cariou, K.; Mitreva, M.; Sakanari, J.; Gasser, G.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.546819
Drug resistance observed with many anti-infectives clearly highlights the need for new broad-spectrum agents to treat especially neglected tropical diseases (NTDs) caused by eukaryotic parasitic pathogens including fungal infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>The MODY-associated TALK-1 L114P mutation causes islet α-cell overactivity and β-cell inactivity resulting in transient neonatal diabetes and glucose dyshomeostasis in adults
Authors: Nakhe, A. Y.; Dadi, P. K.; Kim, J.; Shrestha, S.; Cartailler, J.-P.; Sampson, L.; Magnuson, M. A.; Jacobson, D. A.
Score: 11.0, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545631
A strong association of the gain-of-function mutation in the TALK-1 K&amp;#43; channel (p.L114P) with maturity-onset diabetes of the young (MODY) was recently reported in two distinct families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>A RabGAP-Rab GTPase pair regulates plant autophagy and immunity
Authors: Yuen, E. L. H.; Leary, A. Y.; Clavel, M.; Tumtas, Y.; Mohseni, A.; Picchianti, L.; Jamshidiha, M.; Pandey, P.; Duggan, C.; Cota, E.; Dagdas, Y.; Bozkurt, T. O.
Score: 43.9, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.547386
Plants rely on autophagy and membrane trafficking to tolerate stress, combat infections, and maintain cellular homeostasis. However, the molecular interplay between autophagy and membrane trafficking is poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Dissociable effects of dopaminergic medications on depression symptom dimensions in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Costello, H.; Schrag, A.; Howard, R.; Roiser, J.
Score: 14.7, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.23292073
BackgroundDepression in Parkinsons disease (PD) is common, disabling and responds poorly to standard antidepressant medication. Motivational symptoms of depression, such as apathy and anhedonia, are particularly prevalent in depression in PD and predict poor response to antidepressant treatment. Loss of dopaminergic innervation of the striatum is associated with emergence of motivational symptoms in PD, and mood fluctuations correlate with dopamine availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>mRNA-1273 vaccine effectiveness against symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19-related hospitalization in children aged 6 months to 5 years
Authors: Aglipay, M.; Maguire, J. L.; Swayze, S.; Tuite, A.; Mamdani, M.; Keown-Stoneman, C.; Birken, C. S.; Kwong, J. C.
Score: 68.7, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.23291933
ImportanceData on mRNA-1273 (Moderna) vaccine effectiveness in children aged 6 months to 5 years are limited. ObjectiveTo assess mRNA-1273 vaccine effectiveness against symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19-related hospitalization among children aged 6 months to 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>AI-based analysis of the shunt treatment in pre- and post-surgery computed tomography brain scans of iNPH patients
Authors: Shailja, S.; Nguyen, C.; Thanigaivelan, K.; Bhagavatula, V.; Chen, J. W.; Manjunath, B. S.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.23292008
Background: This study examines whether quantifiable changes can be detected in ventricular volume in Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus (iNPH) patients that undergo ventriculo peritoneal shunt procedures. There is no known metric that characterizes the change in ventricular volume for iNPH patients after shunt placement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Insights on Poster Preparation Practices in Life Sciences
Authors: Jambor, H.
Score: 18.2, Published: 2023-06-06 DOI: 10.1101/2020.10.08.331413
Posters are intended to spark scientific dialogue and omnipresent at biological conferences. Guides and how-to articles help life scientists in preparing informative visualizations in poster format. However, those posters shown at conferences are at present often overloaded with data and text and are poorly designed, which in sum hinder, rather than spark communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Truly tiny acoustic biomolecules for ultrasound imaging and therapy
Authors: Ling, B.; Gungoren, B.; Yao, Y.; Dutka, P.; Smith, C. A. B.; Lee, J.; Swift, M. B.; Shapiro, M. G.
Score: 15.5, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546773
Nanotechnology offers significant advantages for medical imaging and therapy, including enhanced contrast and precision targeting. However, integrating these benefits into ultrasonography has been challenging due to the size and stability constraints of conventional bubble-based agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous Multi-Omics Analysis by Direct Infusion Mass Spectrometry (SMAD-MS)
Authors: Jiang, Y.; Salladay-Perez, I.; Momenzadeh, A.; Covarrubias, A. J.; Meyer, J. G.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.546628
Combined multi-omics analysis of proteomics, polar metabolomics, and lipidomics requires separate liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS) platforms for each omics layer. This requirement for different platforms limits throughput and increases costs, preventing the application of mass spectrometry-based multi-omics to large scale drug discovery or clinical cohorts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Role of renal venous oxygen pressure for renal function monitoring after related living-donor kidney transplantation: cohort study
Authors: Escarraman-Martinez, D.; Fernandez-Bravo, M.; Kammar-Garcia, A.; Guerrero-Gutierrez, M. A.; Meza-Comparan, H. D.; Mancilla-Galindo, J.; Sanchez-Diaz, J. S.; Cendejas-Rios, E.; Escorza-Molina, C. A.; Noriega-Salas, L.; Bernaldez-Gomez, G.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-06-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.15.23291421
IntroductionMonitoring of renal function after kidney transplantation (KT) is performed by measuring serum creatinine (SCr), urine volumes (UV), and glomerular filtration rate (GFR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Physiological phenotypes differ among color morphs in introduced populations of the common wall lizard, Podarcis muralis
Authors: Amer, A.; Spears, S.; Vaughn, P. L.; Colwell, C.; Livingston, E. H.; McQueen, W.; Schill, A.; Reichard, D.; Gangloff, E. J.; Brock, K. M.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-06-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.17.545449
Many species exhibit color polymorphisms which have distinct physiological and behavioral characteristics. However, the consistency of morph trait covariation patterns across species, time, and ecological contexts remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
