<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in Hallucinogen-associated Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations in California from 2016-2021
Authors: Tate, S.; Garel, N.; Nash, K.; Lembke, A.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294275
ObjectivesHallucinogens encompass a diverse range of compounds with increasing scientific and public interest. Risks associated with hallucinogen use are poorly understood. This study aims to evaluate the trends in hallucinogen-related emergency department visits and hospitalizations in California from 2016 to 2021, as compared to alcohol and cannabis visits and hospitalizations MethodsWe conducted a descriptive study on publicly available data on diagnosis codes associated with emergency department (ED) visits and hospitalizations from the California Department of Healthcare Access and Information (HCAI) to describe hallucinogen, alcohol, and cannabis associated encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 117.1, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Cryo-EM of soft-landed β-galactosidase: Gas-phase and native structures are remarkably similar
Authors: Esser, T. K.; Boehning, J.; Onur, A.; Chinthapalli, D. K.; Eriksson, L.; Grabarics, M.; Fremdling, P.; Konijnenberg, A.; Makarov, A. A.; Botman, A.; Peter, C.; Benesch, J. L. P.; Robinson, C. V.; Gault, J.; Baker, L.; Bharat, T. A. M.; Rauschenbach, S.
Score: 55.0, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553673
Native mass spectrometry (native MS) is a powerful technique that provides information on stoichiometry, interactions, homogeneity and shape of protein complexes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Volumetric imaging of an intact organism by a distributed molecular network
Authors: Weinstein, J. A.; Qian, N.
Score: 42.1, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.553025
Lymphatic, nervous, and tumoral tissues, among others, exhibit physiology that emerges from three-dimensional interactions between genetically unique cells. A technology capable of volumetrically imaging transcriptomes, genotypes, and morphologies in a single de novo measurement would therefore provide a critical view into the biological complexity of living systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Context-Dependent Design of Induced-fit Enzymes using Deep Learning Generates Well Expressed, Thermally Stable and Active Enzymes
Authors: Zimmerman, L.; Alon, N.; Levin, I.; Koganitsky, A.; Shpigel, N.; Brestel, C.; Lapidoth, G. D.
Score: 284.3, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550799
The potential of engineered enzymes in practical applications is often constrained by limitations in their expression levels, thermal stability, and the diversity and magnitude of catalytic activities. De-novo enzyme design, though exciting, is challenged by the complex nature of enzymatic catalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Deep reconstructing generative networks for visualizing dynamic biomolecules inside cells
Authors: Rangan, R.; Khavnekar, S.; Lerer, A.; Johnston, J.; Kelley, R.; Obr, M.; Kotecha, A.; Zhong, E. D.
Score: 101.5, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553799
Advances in cryo-electron tomography (cryo-ET) have produced new opportunities to visualize the structures of dynamic macromolecular machinery in native cellular environments. Here, we describe a machine learning approach that can reconstruct the structural landscape and dynamics of biomolecular complexes present in cryo-ET subtomograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Progressive plasticity during colorectal cancer metastasis
Authors: Moorman, A.; Cambuli, F.; Benitez, E.; Jiang, Q.; Xie, Y.; Mahmoud, A.; Lumish, M.; Hartner, S.; Balkaran, S.; Bermeo, J.; Asawa, S.; Firat, C.; Saxena, A.; Luthra, A.; Sgambati, V.; Luckett, K.; Wu, F.; Li, Y.; Yi, Z.; Masilionis, I.; Soares, K.; Pappou, E.; Yaeger, R.; Kingham, P.; Jarnagin, W.; Paty, P.; Weiser, M. R.; Mazutis, L.; D&amp;#39;Angelica, M.; Shia, J.; Garcia-Aguilar, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of Myocarditis Incidence at a Large Healthcare System Before and During COVID-19 Pandemic
Authors: Case, B. C.; Waksman, O.; Rappaport, H.; Zhang, C.; Waksman, R.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23294002
BackgroundMyocarditis is a recognized complication of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. Emerging studies further suggest an associated risk of myocarditis following administration of messenger RNA (mRNA) COVID-19 vaccinations. coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccinations. We investigated the incidence of myocarditis throughout the COVID-19 pandemic across a large healthcare system in the Washington, DC, metropolitan area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>BioE3 enables the identification of bona fide targets of E3 ligases
Authors: Barroso-Gomila, O.; Merino-Cacho, L.; Muratore, V.; Perez, C.; Taibi, V.; Maspero, E.; Azkargorta, M.; Iloro, I.; Trulsson, F.; Vertegaal, A. C. O.; Mayor, U.; Elortza, F.; Polo, S.; Barrio, R.; Sutherland, J. D.
Score: 59.6, Published: 2023-08-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553883
The post-translational modification of proteins by ubiquitination is a highly regulated process that involves a dynamic, three-step enzymatic cascade, where more than 600 E3 ligases play a critical role in recognizing specific substrates for modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reversal of Biological Age in Multiple Rat Organs by Young Porcine Plasma Fraction
Authors: Horvath, S.; Singh, K.; Raj, K.; Khairnar, S.; Sanghavi, A.; Shrivastava, A.; Zoller, J. A.; Li, C. Z.; Herenu, C. B.; Canatelli-Mallat, M.; Lehmann, M.; Habazin, S.; Vuckovic, F.; Solberg-Woods, L.; Garcia Martinez, A.; Wang, T.; Chiavellini, P.; Levine, A. J.; Chen, H.; Brooke, R. T.; Gordevicius, J.; Lauc, G.; Goya, R. G.; Katcher, H. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Identifying signals of memory from observations of animal movements in Plato&amp;#39;s cave
Authors: Kim, D.; Thompson, P.; Wolfson, D.; Merkle, J.; Oliveira-Santos, L. G. R.; Forester, J.; Avgar, T.; Lewis, M.; Fieberg, J.
Score: 12.9, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553411
O_LIIncorporating memory (i.e., some notion of familiarity or experience with the landscape) into models of animal movement is a rising challenge in the field of movement ecology. The recent proliferation of new methods offers new opportunities to understand how memory influences movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected during a SARS-CoV-2 Omicron wave - Australia, 2022
Authors: Woldegiorgis, M.; Cadby, G.; Ngeh, S.; Korda, R.; Armstrong, P.; Maticevic, J.; Knight, P.; Jardine, A.; Bloomfield, L.; Effler, P.
Score: 2178.5, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293706
ObjectiveTo characterise Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected by Omicron. DesignFollow-up survey of persons testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 in Western Australia, 16 July-3 August 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Opsin gene duplication in Lepidoptera: retrotransposition, sex linkage, and gene expression
Authors: Mulhair, P. O.; Crowley, L.; Boyes, D. H.; Lewis, O. T.; Holland, P. W. H.
Score: 35.3, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.552946
Colour vision in insects is determined by signalling cascades, central to which are opsin proteins, resulting in sensitivity to light at different wavelengths. In certain insect groups, lineage specific evolution of opsin genes, in terms of copy number, shifts in expression patterns, and functional amino acid substitutions, has resulted in changes in colour vision with subsequent behavioural and niche adaptations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Longitudinal Profiling of the Intestinal Microbiome in Children with Cystic Fibrosis Treated with Elexacaftor-Tezacaftor-Ivacaftor
Authors: Reasoner, S. A.; Bernard, R.; Waalkes, A.; Penewit, K.; Lewis, J.; Sokolow, A. G.; Brown, R. F.; Edwards, K. M.; Salipante, S.; Hadjifrangiskou, M.; Nicholson, M. R.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23293949
The intestinal microbiome influences growth and disease progression in children with cystic fibrosis (CF). Elexacaftor-tezacaftor-ivacaftor (ELX/TEZ/IVA), the newest pharmaceutical modulator for CF, restores function of the pathogenic mutated CFTR channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Unique Capabilities of Genome Sequencing for Rare Disease Diagnosis
Authors: Wojcik, M. H.; Lemire, G.; Zaki, M. S.; Wissmann, M.; Win, W.; White, S.; Weisburd, B.; Waddell, L. B.; Verboon, J. M.; VanNoy, G. E.; Topf, A.; Tan, T. Y.; Straub, V.; Stenton, S. L.; Snow, H.; Singer-Berk, M.; Silver, J.; Shril, S.; Seaby, E. G.; Schneider, R.; Sankaran, V. G.; Sanchis-Juan, A.; Russell, K. A.; Reinson, K.; Ravenscroft, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Deletion of Xist upstream sequences alters TAD interactions and leads to defects in Xist coating and expression
Authors: Majumdar, S.; Bammidi, L. S.; Naik, H.; M, A.; Baro, R.; Kalita, A.; Sundarraj, N.; Bariha, G.; Notani, D.; GAYEN, S.
Score: 18.7, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553118
The topological organization of the genome plays an important role in regulating gene expression. However, the connection between the two remains poorly understood. X-chromosome inactivation is a unique model system to explore the interlink between topologically associated domains (TADs) and gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Programmable multi-kilobase RNA editing using CRISPR-mediated trans-splicing
Authors: Borrajo, J.; Javanmardi, K.; Griffin, J.; St. Martin, S. J.; Yao, D.; Hill, K.; Blainey, P.; Al-Shayeb, B.
Score: 102.2, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553620
Current gene editing approaches in eukaryotic cells are limited to single base edits or small DNA insertions and deletions, and remain encumbered by unintended permanent effects and significant challenges in the delivery of large DNA cargo. Here we describe Splice Editing, a generalizable platform to correct gene transcripts in situ by programmable insertion or replacement of large RNA segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The effects of economic difficulties on social and health care costs of children: target trial emulation using complete birth cohort data in Finland
Authors: Hiilamo, A.; Keski-Santti, M.; Juutinen, A.; Makinen, L.; Ristikari, T.; Lallukka, T.
Score: 60.7, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23293974
It is unclear how much costs economic difficulties incur to the health and social care sector, which is a critical research gap to support the economic case for preventing child poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>An Interpretable Longitudinal Preeclampsia Risk Prediction Using Machine Learning
Authors: Eberhard, B. W.; Cohen, R. Y.; Rigoni, J.; Bates, D.; Gray, K. J.; Kovacheva, V.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23293946
BackgroundPreeclampsia is a pregnancy-specific disease characterized by new onset hypertension after 20 weeks of gestation that affects 2-8% of all pregnancies and contributes to up to 26% of maternal deaths. Despite extensive clinical research, current predictive tools fail to identify up to 66% of patients who will develop preeclampsia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>A Scoping Review of Interventions to De-implement Potentially Harmful Nonsteroidal Anti-inflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs) in Healthcare Settings
Authors: Rockwell, M. S.; Oyese, E. G.; Singh, E.; Vinson, M.; Yim, I.; Turner, J. K.; Epling, J. W.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.23293362
ObjectivesPotentially harmful nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) utilization persists at undesirable rates throughout the world. The purpose of this paper is to review the literature on interventions to de-implement potentially harmful NSAIDs in healthcare settings and to suggest directions for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 infection triggers pro-atherogenic inflammatory 1 responses in human coronary vessels
Authors: Eberhardt, N.; Noval, M. G.; Kaur, R.; Sajja, S.; Amadori, L.; Das, D.; Cilhoroz, B.; Stewart, O. J.; Fernandez, D. M.; Shamailova, R.; Guillen, A. V.; Jangra, S.; Schotsaert, M.; Gildea, M.; Newman, J. D.; Faries, P.; Maldonado, T.; Rockman, C.; Rapkiewicz, A.; Stapleford, K. A.; Narula, N.; Moore, K. J.; Giannarelli, C.
Score: 253.4, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Assessing ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Mastery of Bloom&amp;#39;s Taxonomy using psychosomatic medicine exam questions
Authors: Herrmann Werner, A.; Festl-Wietek, T.; Holderried, F.; Herschbach, L.; Griewatz, J.; Masters, K.; Zipfel, S.; Mahling, M.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294159
Introduction: Large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 are increasingly used in medicine and medical education. However, these models are prone to &amp;#34;hallucinations&amp;#34; - outputs that sound convincing while being factually incorrect. It is currently unknown how these errors by LLMs relate to the different cognitive levels defined in Bloom&amp;#39;s Taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Neutralizing Antibodies Following a Second BA.5 Bivalent Booster
Authors: Wang, Q.; Bowen, A.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R.; Valdez, R.; Stoneman, E.; Gordon, A.; Lihong, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 339.0, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553148
Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA vaccines expressing both the ancestral D614G and Omicron BA.5 spike proteins were introduced in August 2022 with the goal of broadening immunity to emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariants. Subsequent studies on bivalent boosters found neutralizing antibody responses similar to boosters with the original monovalent vaccine, likely the result of immunological imprinting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>The apparent loss of PRC2 chromatin occupancy as an artefact of RNA depletion
Authors: Healy, E.; Zhang, Q.; Gail, E. H.; Agius, S. C.; Sun, G.; Bullen, M.; Pandey, V.; Das, P. P.; Polo, J. M.; Davidovich, C.
Score: 60.9, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.553488
RNA has been implicated in the recruitment of chromatin modifiers, and previous studies have provided evidence in favour and against this idea. RNase treatment of chromatin is a prevalent tool for the study of RNA-mediated regulation of chromatin modifiers, but the limitations of this approach remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Use of the Selective Cytopheretic Device to Support Critically Ill Children Requiring Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy: A Probable Benefit-Risk Assessment
Authors: Goldstein, S. L.; Ollberding, N. J.; Askenazi, D. J.; Basu, R. K.; Selewski, D. T.; Krallman, K. A.; Yessayan, L.; Humes, H. D.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294378
Background: Critically ill children with acute kidney injury (AKI) requiring continuous kidney replacement therapy (CRRT) are at increased risk of death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Transcobalamin Receptor Autoantibodies in Central Vitamin B12 Deficiency
Authors: Pluvinage, J. V.; Ngo, T.; Bartley, C. M.; Bodansky, A.; Alvarenga, B. D.; Zorn, K. C.; Fouassier, C.; Zamecnik, C.; McCann, A.; Huynh, T.; Browne, W.; Tubati, A.; Kondapavulur, S.; Anderson, M. S.; Green, A. J.; Green, R.; Douglas, V.; Louine, M.; Cree, B.; Hauser, S.; Seeley, W.; Holmes, B. B.; Wells, J. A.; Spudich, S.; Farhadian, S.; Ramachandran, P.; Gillum, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Engineered 3D Immuno-Glial-Neurovascular Human Brain Model
Authors: Stanton, A. E.; Bubnys, A.; Agbas, E.; James, B.; Park, D. S.; Jiang, A.; Pinals, R. L.; Truong, N.; Loon, A.; Staab, C.; Liu, L.; Cerit, O.; Wen, H.-L.; Kellis, M.; Blanchard, J. W.; Langer, R. S.; Tsai, L.-H.
Score: 36.4, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553453
Patient-specific, human-based cellular models that integrate biomimetic BBB, immune, and myelinated neuron components are critically needed to enable translationally relevant and accelerated discovery of neurological disease mechanisms and interventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Bioactive glycans in a microbiome-directed food for malnourished children
Authors: Hibberd, M. C.; Webber, D. M.; Rodionov, D. A.; Henrissat, S.; Chen, R. Y.; Zhou, C.; Lynn, H. M.; Wang, Y.; Chang, H.-W.; Lee, E. M.; Lelwala-Guruge, J.; Kazanov, M. D.; Arzamasov, A. A.; Leyn, S. A.; Lombard, V.; Terrapon, N.; Henrissat, B.; Castillo, J. J.; Couture, G.; Bacalzo, N. P.; Chen, Y.; Lebrilla, C. B.; Mostafa, I.; Das, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>High 3-hydroxybutyrate concentrations in the placenta-produced amniotic fluid in the human uterus
Authors: Satoh, T.; Shibata, T.; Takata, E.; Takakura, M.; Han, J.; Yamada, S.
Score: 9.4, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293873
In this study, we report first high concentrations of a ketone body, 3-hydroxybutyrate (3HB) in the amniotic fluid in humans. Although 3HB concentrations in the maternal blood are approximately 0.1, those in the amniotic fluid are approximately 0.6 mM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Order-of-mutation effects on cancer progression: models for myeloproliferative neoplasm
Authors: Wang, Y.; Shtylla, B.; Chou, T.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294177
We develop a modeling framework for cancer progression that distinguishes the order of two possible mutations. Recent observations and information on myeloproliferative neoplasms are analyzed within our framework. In some patients with myeloproliferative neoplasms, two genetic mutations can be found, JAK2 V617F and TET2. Whether or not one mutation is present will influence how the other subsequent mutation affects the regulation of gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence and risk factors of self-reported audiovestibular symptoms in a population-based sample from rural northeastern Germany
Authors: Ihler, F.; Brzoska, T.; Altindal, R.; Dziemba, O.; Voelzke, H.; Busch, C.-J.; Ittermann, T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23293690
Objectives. The senses of hearing and balance are linked by a close anatomical and physiological relationship. A further pathophysiological interaction is supposed but the detailed mechanism and direction remains elusive. Further insight is required into the prevalence of the audiovestibular symptoms hearing loss, tinnitus and dizziness as only scarce information on the combined occurrence is available so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Stellate Ganglion Block to Treat Long COVID-19 Syndrome, A 41 Patient Retrospective Cohort Study
Authors: Pearson, L.; Maina, A.; Thompson, L.; Harden, S.; Aaroe, A.; Compratt, T.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.23290338
Post Covid-19 condition (PCC), long COVID-19 syndrome and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) all refer to a constellation of symptoms that are unresolved long after the acute phase of the viral infection. The severity of symptoms can vary from mild and tolerable to severe and debilitating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Longer mandible or nose? Co-evolution of feeding organs in early elephantiforms
Authors: Li, C.; Deng, T.; Wang, Y.; Sun, F.; Wolff, B.; Jiangzuo, Q.; Ma, J.; Xing, L.; Fu, J.; Zhang, J.; Wang, S.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553347
The long-trunked elephantids underwent a significant evolutionary stage characterized by an exceptionally elongated mandible. The initial elongation and subsequent regression of the long mandible, along with its co-evolution with the trunk, present an intriguing issue that remains incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>An end-to-end workflow for non-destructive 3D pathology
Authors: Bishop, K. W.; Barner, L. A. E.; Han, Q.; Baraznenok, E.; Lan, L.; Poudel, C.; Gao, G.; Serafin, R. B.; Chow, S. S. L.; Glaser, A. K.; Janowczyk, A.; Brenes, D.; Huang, H.; Miyasato, D.; True, L. D.; Kang, S.; Vaughan, J. C.; Liu, J. T. C.
Score: 130.8, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551845
Recent advances in 3D pathology offer the ability to image orders-of-magnitude more tissue than conventional pathology while providing a volumetric context that is lacking with 2D tissue sections, all without requiring destructive tissue sectioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Factors associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome-related coronavirus 2 infection in unvaccinated children and young adults
Authors: Silverberg, S. L.; Shulha, H. P.; McMillan, B.; He, G.; Lee, A.; Marquez, A. C.; Bartlett, S. R.; Gill, V.; Abu-Raya, B.; Bettinger, J. A.; Cabrera, A.; Coombs, D.; Gantt, S.; Goldfarb, D. M.; Sauve, L.; Krajden, M.; Morshed, M.; Sekirov, I.; Jassem, A. N.; Sadarangani, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Characterization and Genome Sequencing of a Novel Lytic Bacteriophage Infecting Hospital-Associated Carbapenem-Resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae Strain from Dhaka, Bangladesh
Authors: NSU Genome Research Institute (NGRI), North South University, ; Hossain, M. M.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.23294043
BackgroundMultidrug-resistant bacterial pathogens pose a grave threat to global health, with Klebsiella pneumoniae being a particular concern due to its hypervariable extracellular matrix capsule and frequent development of extended-spectrum {beta}-lactamases and other antibiotic defenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Toxicokinetic Characterization of the Inter-Species Differences in 6PPD-Quinone Toxicity Across Seven Fish Species: Metabolite Identification and Semi-Quantification
Authors: Montgomery, D. J.; Ji, X.; Cantin, J.; Philibert, D.; Foster, G.; Selinger, S.; Jain, N.; Miller, J.; McIntyre, J.; de Jourdan, B.; Wiseman, S.; Hecker, M.; Brinkmann, M.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553920
N-(1,3-Dimethylbutyl)-N-Phenyl-P-Phenylenediamine-Quinone (6PPD-Q) is a recently identified contaminant that originates from the oxidation of the tire anti-degradant 6PPD. 6PPD-Q is acutely toxic to select salmonids at environmentally relevant concentrations, while other fish species display tolerance to concentrations surpassing those measured in the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Auxin Exposure Disrupts Feeding Behavior and Fatty Acid Metabolism in Adult Drosophila
Authors: Fleck, S. A.; Knuteson, R. L.; Dewitt, E. D.; Eisman, R. C.; Nemkov, T.; D&amp;#39;Alessandro, A.; Tennessen, J. M.; Weaver, L. N.
Score: 21.4, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553385
The ease of genetic manipulation in Drosophila melanogaster using the Gal4/UAS system has been beneficial in addressing key biological questions. Current modifications of this methodology to temporally induce transgene expression require temperature changes or exposure to exogenous compounds, both of which have been shown to have detrimental effects on physiological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The phosphorylation landscape of infection-related development by the rice blast fungus
Authors: Cruz-Mireles, N.; Oses-Ruiz, M.; Derbyshire, P.; Jegousse, C.; Ryder, L. S.; Bautista, M.-J.; Eseola, A. B.; Tang, B.; Yan, X.; Ma, W.; Findlay, K. C.; Were, V.; MacLean, D.; Talbot, N. J.; Menke, F. L. H.
Score: 64.6, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553964
Many of the world&amp;#39;s most devastating crop diseases are caused by fungal pathogens which elaborate specialized infection structures to invade plant tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Functional Connectivity and Complexity Analyses of Resting-State fMRI in Pre-Adolescents with ADHD
Authors: Zhang, R.; Murray, S. B.; Duval, C. J.; Wang, D. J. J.; Jann, K.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294136
Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) has been characterized by impairments among distributed functional brain networks, e.g., the frontoparietal network (FPN), default mode network (DMN), and reward and motivation-related circuits (RMN). In the current study, we evaluated the complexity and functional connectivity (FC) of resting state fMRI (rsfMRI) in pre-adolescents with ADHD for pathology-relevant networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 899.4, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>JOINT CLINICAL AND MOLECULAR SUBTYPING OF COPD WITH VARIATIONAL AUTOENCODERS
Authors: Maiorino, E.; De Marzio, M.; Weiss, S.; Silverman, E.; Castaldi, P.; Glass, K.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.23294298
Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a complex, heterogeneous disease. Traditional subtyping methods generally focus on either the clinical manifestations or the molecular endotypes of the disease, resulting in domain-specific classifications that may not capture its full complexity. Here, we introduce an integrative approach based on variational autoencoders to integrate clinical and blood gene expression data from the COPDGene cohort study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of JAK-STAT pathway corrects salivary gland inflammation and interferon driven immune activation in Sjögren&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Warner, B. M.; Gupta, S.; Yamada, E.; Nakamura, H.; Perez, P.; Pranzatelli, T. J. F.; Dominick, K.; Jang, S.-I.; Abed, M.; Martin, D.; Burbelo, P.; Zheng, C.; French, B.; Alevizos, I.; Khavandgar, Z.; Beach, M.; Pelayo, E.; Walitt, B.; Hasni, S.; Kaplan, M.; Tandon, M.; Magone, M. T.; Kleiner, D.; Chiorini, J.; Baer, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Important enough to show the world&amp;#34;: Using Authentic Research Opportunities and Micropublications to Build Students&amp;#39; Science Identities
Authors: Rubenstein, L. D.; Woodruff, K. A.; Taylor, A. M.; Olesen, J. B.; Smaldino, P. J.; Rubenstein, E. M.
Score: 51.8, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553701
Primarily undergraduate institutions (PUIs) often struggle to provide authentic research opportunities that culminate in peer-reviewed publications due to &amp;#34;recipe-driven&amp;#34; lab courses and the comprehensive body of work necessary for traditional scientific publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Efficient Natural Plasmid Transformation of Vibrio natriegens Enables Zero-capital Molecular Biology
Authors: Specht, D. A.; Sheppard, T. J.; Kennedy, F.; Li, S.; Gadikota, G.; Barstow, B.
Score: 40.1, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.553013
The fast-growing microbe Vibrio natriegens is capable of natural transformation where it draws DNA in from media via an active process under physiological conditions. Using an engineered strain with a genomic copy of the master competence regulator tfoX from Vibrio cholera in combination with a new minimal competence media (MCM) that uses acetate as an energy source, we demonstrate naturally competent cells which are created, transformed, and recovered entirely in the same media, without exchange or addition of new media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>LIANA&amp;#43;: an all-in-one cell-cell communication framework
Authors: Dimitrov, D.; Schäfer, P. S. L.; Farr, E.; Rodriguez Mier, P.; Lobentanzer, S.; Dugourd, A.; Tanevski, J.; Ramirez Flores, R. O.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.
Score: 41.4, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553863
The growing availability of single-cell and spatially-resolved transcriptomics has led to the rapidly growing popularity of methods to infer cell-cell communication. Many approaches have emerged, each capturing only a partial view of the complex landscape of cell-cell communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 variants Omicron BA.4/5 and XBB.1.5 significantly escape T cell recognition in solid organ transplant recipients vaccinated against the ancestral strain
Authors: Halvorson, T.; Ivison, S.; Huang, Q.; Ladua, G.; Yotis, D. M.; Mannar, D.; Subramaniam, S.; Ferreira, V. H.; Kumar, D.; Belga, S.; PREVenT Study Group, ; Levings, M.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.23293991
Background: Immune-suppressed solid organ transplant recipients (SOTRs) display impaired humoral responses to COVID-19 vaccination, but T cell responses are incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of human skin microbiome odorants that manipulate mosquito landing behavior - towards engineering a repellent skin flora
Authors: Coutinho-Abreu, I. V.; Jamshidi, O.; Raban, R.; Atabakhsh, K.; Merriman, J. A.; Fischbach, M. A.; Akbari, O. S.
Score: 43.0, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553996
The resident human skin microbiome is responsible for the production of most of the human scents that are attractive to mosquitoes. Hence, engineering the human skin microbiome to synthesize less of mosquito attractants or produce repellents could potentially reduce bites and prevent the transmission of deadly mosquito-borne pathogens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
