<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A locomotion-based assay to measure prepulse inhibition in zebrafish larvae
Authors: Read, E.; Hindges, R.
Score: 15.6, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560094
Sensory gating, assessed using a prepulse inhibition assay (PPI), is a promising endophenotype of neuropsychiatric disorders that can be measured in larval zebrafish models. However, current PPI assays require high-speed cameras to capture rapid c-bend startle behaviours. In this study, we designed and employed a PPI paradigm that uses locomotion as read-out of startle responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>PROxAb Shuttle: A non-covalent plug-and-play platform for the rapid generation of tumor-targeting antibody-PROTAC conjugates
Authors: Schneider, H.; Jaeger, S.; Koenning, D.; Rasche, N.; Schroeter, C.; Elter, D.; Evers, A.; Lecomte, M.; Riccardi Sirtori, F.; Schwarz, D.; Wegener, A.; Hartung, I.; Rieker, M.
Score: 21.5, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.558399
Proteolysis-targeting chimeras (PROTACs) have evolved in recent years from an academic idea to a therapeutic modality with more than 25 active clinical programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Protein generation with evolutionary diffusion: sequence is all you need
Authors: Alamdari, S.; Thakkar, N.; van den Berg, R.; Lu, A. X.; Fusi, N.; Amini, A. P.; Yang, K. K.
Score: 199.8, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.556673
Deep generative models are increasingly powerful tools for the in silico design of novel proteins. Recently, a family of generative models called diffusion models has demonstrated the ability to generate biologically plausible proteins that are dissimilar to any actual proteins seen in nature, enabling unprecedented capability and control in de novo protein design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>An RNA foundation model enables discovery of disease mechanisms and candidate therapeutics
Authors: Celaj, A.; Gao, A. J.; Lau, T. T. Y.; Holgersen, E. M.; Lo, A.; Lodaya, V.; Cole, C. B.; Denroche, R. E.; Spickett, C.; Wagih, O.; Pinheiro, P. O.; Vora, P.; Mohammadi-Shemirani, P.; Chan, S.; Nussbaum, Z.; Zhang, X.; Zhu, H.; Ramamurthy, E.; Kanuparthi, B.; Iacocca, M.; Ly, D.; Kron, K.; Verby, M.; Cheung-Ong, K.; Shalev, Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Bacterial antiviral defense pathways encode eukaryotic-like ubiquitination systems
Authors: Chambers, L. R.; Ye, Q.; Cai, J.; Gong, M.; Ledvina, H. E.; Zhou, H.; Whiteley, A. T.; Suhandynata, R. T.; Corbett, K. D.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.559546
Ubiquitination and related pathways play crucial roles in protein homeostasis, signaling, and innate immunity1-3. In these pathways, an enzymatic cascade of E1, E2, and E3 proteins conjugates ubiquitin or a ubiquitin-like protein (Ubl) to targetprotein lysine residues4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Alveolar differentiation drives resistance to KRAS inhibition in lung adenocarcinoma
Authors: Li, Z.; Zhuang, X.; Pan, C.-H.; Yan, Y.; Thummalapalli, R.; Hallin, J.; Torborg, S.; Singhal, A.; Chang, J. C.; Manchado, E.; Dow, L. E.; Yaeger, R.; Christensen, J. G.; Lowe, S. W.; Rudin, C. M.; Joost, S.; Tammela, T.
Score: 34.3, Published: 2023-10-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560194
Lung adenocarcinoma (LUAD), commonly driven by KRAS mutations, is responsible for 7% of all cancer mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Assessing dose-response relations of lipid traits with coronary artery disease, all-cause mortality, and cause-specific mortality: a linear and non-linear Mendelian randomization study
Authors: Yang, G.; Mason, A.; Wood, A.; Schooling, C. M.; Burgess, S.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23296203
ImportanceApolipoprotein B (apoB), low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C), and possibly triglycerides (TG) play causal roles in the aetiology of coronary artery disease (CAD). However, trial evidence for effects of intensive LDL-C lowering and TG lowering on mortality is less definitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Contact-FP: a dimerization-dependent fluorescent protein toolkit for visualizing membrane contact site dynamics
Authors: Miner, G. E.; Smith, S. Y.; Showalter, W. K.; So, C. M.; Ragusa, J. V.; Powers, A. E.; Zanellati, M. C.; Hsu, C.-H.; Marchan, M. F.; Cohen, S.
Score: 54.4, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.559820
Membrane contact sites (MCSs) are sites of close apposition between two organelles used to exchange ions, lipids, and information. Cells respond to changing environmental or developmental conditions by modulating the number, extent, or duration of MCSs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open top multi sample dual view light sheet microscope for live imaging of large multicellular systems
Authors: Moos, F.; Suppinger, S.; de Medeiros, G.; Oost, K.; Boni, A.; Remy, C.; Weevers, S.; Tsiairis, C. D.; Strnad, P.; Liberali, P.
Score: 83.4, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.559925
Multicellular systems grow over the course of weeks from single cells to tissues or even full organisms composed of several thousands of cells, making live imaging of such samples challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Insect biomass of protected habitats under the impact of arable farming in Germany
Authors: Muehlethaler, R.; Koethe, S.; Hoerren, T.; Sorg, M.; Eichler, L.; Lehmann, G. U. C.
Score: 36.0, Published: 2023-09-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.559203
Five years after the well-known study on insect biomass decline in nature protected habitats in Germany over three decades, the project DINA (Diversity of Insects in Nature protected Areas) has investigated the status of insects in 21 selected nature reserves across Germany in the years 2020 and 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alternative Defibrillation Strategies for Refractory Ventricular Fibrillation: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Perna, B.; Guarino, M.; De Fazio, R.; Esposito, L.; Portoraro, A.; Rossin, F.; Remelli, F.; Trevisan, C.; Raparelli, V.; Marasco, G.; Barbara, G.; Petrini, S.; Vason, M.; Spampinato, M. D.; De Giorgio, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296188
BackgroundCardiac arrest with refractory ventricular fibrillation (rVF) represents a dramatic medical emergency. Despite recent advances, its treatment is challenging and burdened by limited evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Is influenza B/Yamagata extinct and what public health implications could this have? An updated literature review and comprehensive assessment of global surveillance databases.
Authors: Caini, S.; Meijer, A.; Nunes, M. C.; Henaff, L.; Zounon, M.; Boudewijns, B.; Del Riccio, M.; Paget, J.
Score: 44.7, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.23296068
IntroductionEarly after the start of the COVID-19 pandemic, a major drop in the number of influenza B/Yamagata detections was observed globally. Given the potential public health implications, particularly with regards to influenza vaccination, we conducted a systematic review of influenza B/Yamagata virus circulation data from multiple complementary sources of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single-fly assemblies fill major phylogenomic gaps across the Drosophilidae Tree of Life
Authors: Kim, B. Y.; Gellert, H. R.; Church, S. H.; Suvorov, A.; Anderson, S. S.; Barmina, O.; Beskid, S. G.; Comeault, A. A.; Crown, K. N.; Diamond, S. E.; Dorus, S.; Fujichika, T.; Hemker, J. A.; Hrcek, J.; Kankare, M.; Katoh, T.; Magnacca, K. N.; Martin, R. A.; Matsunaga, T.; Medeiros, M. J.; Miller, D. E.; Pitnick, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Trans-biobank Mendelian randomization analyses identify opposing pathways in plasma low-density lipoprotein-cholesterol lowering and gallstone disease
Authors: Yang, G.; Mason, A.; Gill, D.; Schooling, C. M.; Burgess, S.
Score: 5.9, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23296205
Structured abstractO_ST_ABSBackgroundC_ST_ABSPlasma low-density lipoprotein (LDL)-cholesterol is positively associated with coronary artery disease risk while biliary cholesterol promotes gallstone formation. ObjectivesWe tested the hypothesis that different plasma LDL-cholesterol lowering pathways have distinct effects on biliary cholesterol and thereby risk of gallstone disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Multi-ancestry Polygenic Mechanisms of Type 2 Diabetes Elucidate Disease Processes and Clinical Heterogeneity
Authors: Smith, K.; Deutsch, A.; McGrail, C.; Kim, H.; Hsu, S.; Mandla, R.; Schroeder, P. H.; Westerman, K. E.; Szczerbinski, L.; Majarian, T. D.; Kaur, V.; Williamson, A.; Claussnitzer, M.; Florez, J. C.; Manning, A. K.; Mercader, J. M.; Gaulton, K. J.; Udler, M. S.
Score: 16.1, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.23296294
We identified genetic subtypes of type 2 diabetes (T2D) by analyzing genetic data from diverse groups, including non-European populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Synchronized long-read genome, methylome, epigenome, and transcriptome for resolving a Mendelian condition
Authors: Vollger, M. R.; Korlach, J.; Eldred, K. C.; Swanson, E.; Underwood, J. G.; Munson, K. M.; Cheng, Y.-H. H.; Ranchalis, J.; Mao, Y.; Blue, E. E.; Schwarze, U.; Saunders, C. T.; Wenger, A. M.; Allworth, A.; Chanprasert, S.; Duerden, B. L.; Glass, I.; Horike-Pyne, M.; Kim, M.; Leppig, K. A.; McLaughlin, I. J.; Ogawa, J.; Rosenthal, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Ancient genomes illuminate Eastern Arabian population history and adaptation against malaria
Authors: Martiniano, R.; Haber, M.; Almarri, M. A.; Mattiangeli, V.; Kuijpers, M. C. M.; Chamel, B.; Breslin, E. M.; Littleton, J.; Almahari, S.; Aloraifi, F.; Bradley, D. G.; Lombard, P.; Durbin, R.
Score: 110.7, Published: 2023-10-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.559299
The harsh climate of Arabia has posed challenges in generating ancient DNA from the region, hindering the direct examination of ancient genomes for understanding the demographic processes that shaped Arabian populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating the life-extending potential and safety profile of rapamycin: a Mendelian Randomization study of the mTOR pathway
Authors: Sobczyk, M. K.; Gaunt, T. R.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.23296427
Objective: The mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway plays an integral role in cellular metabolism, growth, and aging. While rapamycin and its analogs inhibit the mTOR pathway, extending lifespan in various organisms, the long-term safety and efficacy of these compounds in humans remain understudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating AI in Clinical Practice: A Scoping Evaluation
Authors: Han, R.; Acosta, J. N.; Shakeri, Z.; Ioannidis, J.; Topol, E.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 93.2, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295381
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a promising tool in healthcare, with numerous studies indicating its potential to perform as well or better than clinicians. However, a considerable portion of these AI models have only been tested retrospectively, raising concerns about their true effectiveness and potential risks in real-world clinical settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare system barriers impacting the care of Canadians with myalgic encephalomyelitis: a scoping review
Authors: Hussein, S.; Eiriksson, L.; MacQuarrie, M.; Merriam, S.; Dalton, M.; Stein, E.; Twomey, R.
Score: 42.1, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295809
BackgroundMyalgic encephalomyelitis (ME, also known as chronic fatigue syndrome or ME/CFS) is a debilitating, complex, multi-system illness. Developing a comprehensive understanding of the multiple and interconnected barriers to optimal care will help advance strategies and care models to improve quality of life for people living with ME in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>HIV-DRIVES: HIV Drug Resistance Identification, Variant Evaluation, &amp;amp; Surveillance Pipeline
Authors: Kanyerezi, S.; Sserwadda, I.; Ssemaganda, A.; Sseruyange, J.; Ayitewala, A.; Oundo, H.; Tenywa, W.; Kagurusi, B.; Tusabe, G.; Were, S.; Ssewanyana, I.; Nabadda, S.; Namaganda, M. M.; Mboowa, G.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.30.23296350
The global prevalence of resistance to the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) combined antiretroviral therapy (cART) emphasizes the need to continuous monitoring to better understand the dynamics of drug-resistant mutations to guide treatment optimization and patient management as well as check the spread of resistant viral strains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Neutralisation of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariants BA.2.86 and EG.5.1 by antibodies induced by earlier infection or vaccination
Authors: Lassauniere, R.; Polacek, C.; Baig, S.; Ellegaard, K.; Escobar-Herrera, L. A.; Fomsgaard, A.; Spiess, K.; Schwartz, O.; Planas, D.; Simon-Loriere, E.; Schneider, U. V.; Sieber, R. N.; Stegger, M.; Krause, T. G.; Ullum, H.; Jokelainen, P.; Rasmussen, M.
Score: 71.0, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.560365
Highly mutated SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariant BA.2.86 emerged in July 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Vaccine Effectiveness Against Long COVID in Children: A Report from the RECOVER EHR Cohort
Authors: Razzaghi, H.; Forrest, C.; Hirabayshi, K.; Wu, Q.; Allen, A.; Rao, S.; Chen, Y.; Bunnell, T.; Chrischilles, E. A.; Cowell, L. G.; Cummins, M. R.; Hanauer, D. A.; Higginbotham, M. J.; Horne, B.; Horowitz, C. R.; Jhaveri, R.; Kim, S.; Mishkin, A.; Muszynski, J.; Naggie, S.; Pajor, N. M.; Paranjape, A.; Schwenk, H. T.; Sills, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A Phase 2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multi-center trial sub-study for the clinical effects of paridiprubart treatment in hospitalized critically ill patients with COVID-19 ARDS
Authors: Gordon, B.; Allum, F.; Brooks, M.; Rajakulendran, N.; Rampakakis, E.; Sampalis, J.; EB05 Study Investigators, Score: 248.6, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.21.23295853
BackgroundCoronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mortality is predominantly due to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). There are currently limited treatment options for ARDS, a life-threatening condition with different etiologies, secondary to inflammation-induced lung injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Antigenicity and receptor affinity of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 spike
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Liu, L.; Schwanz, L. T.; Li, Z.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R. M.; Iketani, S.; Yu, J.; Huang, Y.; Qu, Y.; Valdez, R.; Lauring, A. S.; Gordon, A.; Wang, H. H.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 200.1, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.559214
Although the COVID-19 pandemic has officially ended1, SARS-CoV-2 continues to spread and evolve. Recent infections have been dominated by XBB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibiting Glutamine Metabolism Blocks Coronavirus Replication in Mammalian Cells
Authors: Greene, K. S.; Choi, A.; Chen, M.; Yang, N.; Li, R.; Qiu, Y.; Lukey, M. J.; Rojas, K. S.; Shen, J.; Wilson, K. F.; Katt, W. P.; Whittaker, G. R.; Cerione, R. A.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-09-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.559756
Developing therapeutic strategies against COVID-19 has gained widespread interest given the likelihood that new viral variants will continue to emerge. Here we describe one potential therapeutic strategy which involves targeting members of the glutaminase family of mitochondrial metabolic enzymes (GLS and GLS2), which catalyze the first step in glutamine metabolism, the hydrolysis of glutamine to glutamate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Striatal dopamine tone is positively associated with body mass index in humans as determined by PET using dual dopamine type-2 receptor antagonist tracers
Authors: Darcey, V. L.; Guo, J.; Chi, M.; Chung, S. T.; Courville, A. B.; Gallagher, I.; Herscovitch, P.; Howard, R.; La Noire, M.; Milley, L.; Schick, A.; Stagliano, M.; Turner, S.; Urbanski, N.; Yang, S.; Yim, E.; Zhai, N.; Zhou, M. S.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A suite of engineered mice for interrogating psychedelic drug actions
Authors: Chiu, Y.-t.; Deutch, A.; Wang, W.; Schmitz, G. P.; Huang, K.; Kocak, D.; Lorach, P.; Bowye, K.; Liu, B.; Sciaky, N.; Hua, K.; Chen, C.; Mott, S.; Niehaus, J.; DiBerto, J.; English, J.; Walsh, J.; Scherrer, G.; Herman, M.; Wu, Z.; Wetsel, W. C.; Roth, B. L.
Score: 79.1, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.559347
Psychedelic drugs like lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) and psilocybin have emerged as potentially transformative therapeutics for many neuropsychiatric diseases, including depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder, migraine, and cluster headaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Are children with disabilities more likely to be malnourished than children without disabilities? Evidence from the Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys in 30 countries
Authors: Rotenberg, S.; Chen, S.; Hunt, X.; Smythe, T.; Kuper, H.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.23296066
IntroductionA key Sustainable Development Goal target is to eliminate all forms of malnutrition. Existing evidence suggests children with disabilities are at greater risks of malnutrition, exclusion from nutrition programmes, and mortality from severe acute malnutrition than children without disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Methylomic, proteomic, and metabolomic correlates of traffic-related air pollution: A systematic review, pathway analysis, and network analysis relating traffic-related air pollution to subclinical and clinical cardiorespiratory outcomes
Authors: Casella, C.; Kiles, F.; Urquhart, C.; Michaud, D. S.; Kirwa, K.; Corlin, L.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.30.23296386
A growing body of literature has attempted to characterize how traffic-related air pollution (TRAP) affects molecular and subclinical biological processes in ways that could lead to cardiorespiratory disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Comparative analysis of the spatial distribution of brain metastases across several primary cancers using machine learning and deep learning models
Authors: Mahmoodifar, S.; Pangal, D. J.; Mason, J.; Salhia, B.; Neman, J.; Zada, G.; Newton, P. K.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.23295748
ObjectiveBrain metastases (BM) are associated with poor prognosis and increased mortality rates, making them a significant clinical challenge. Therefore, studying BMs can aid in developing better diagnostic tools for their early detection and monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Cost-Benefit Analysis for Universal Cataract Coverage in India for 2018
Authors: Arora, A.; Zadey, S.; Vuddemarry, M.; Iyer, H.; Nimkar, P.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.23296031
ImportanceCataract is the leading cause of curable blindness in India needing scale-up of coverage. However, the costs and benefits of such scale-up remain unknown. ObjectiveTo calculate the annual scale-up costs, economic benefits of disease burden averted, and the net benefits of covering cataract needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Pathology Knowledge using Board-Style Questions
Authors: Geetha, S. D.; Khan, A.; Khan, A.; Kannadath, B. S.; Vitkovski, T.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.23296400
Objectives: ChatGPT is an artificial intelligence (AI) chatbot developed by OpenAI. Its extensive knowledge and unique interactive capabilities enable it to be utilized in various innovative ways in the medical field such as writing clinical notes, simplifying radiology reports. Through this study we aim to analyze its pathology knowledge to advocate its role in transforming pathology education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Investigating markers of pulmonary aspiration in bronchoalveolar lavage from children with severe neurodisability
Authors: Maher, R. E.; Trinick, R. E.; Dalzell, M.; Beynon, R. J.; McNamara, P. S.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23295956
Respiratory exacerbations are a frequent cause of hospitalisation in children with severe neurodisability (ND). Direct aspiration of food/saliva, reflux aspiration of gastric contents or a combination of both is thought to be a common cause of respiratory symptoms and disease, particularly when this occurs silently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the effects of Dasatinib, Quercetin, and Fisetin on DNA methylation clocks: a longitudinal study on senolytic interventions
Authors: Lee, E.; Carreras-Gallo, N.; Lopez, L.; Turner, L.; Lin, A.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Tomusiak, A.; Verdin, E.; Corley, M.; Ndhlovu, L.; Smith, R.; Dwaraka, V. B.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295961
Senolytics, small molecules targeting cellular senescence, have emerged as potential therapeutics to enhance health span. However, their impact on epigenetic age remains unstudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Plastic food packaging from five countries contains endocrine and metabolism disrupting chemicals
Authors: Stevens, S.; Mcpartland, M.; Bartosova, Z.; Skaland, H. S.; Voelker, J.; Wagner, M.
Score: 34.3, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.559713
Plastics are complex chemical mixtures of polymers and various intentionally and non-intentionally added substances. Despite the well-established links between certain plastic chemicals (bisphenols, phthalates) and adverse health effects, the composition and toxicity of real-world mixtures of plastic chemicals is not well understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong dietary protein restriction accelerates skeletal muscle loss and reduces muscle fibre size by impairing proteostasis and mitochondrial homeostasis
Authors: Ersoy, U.; Kanakis, I.; Alameddine, M.; Pedraza Vazquez, G.; E. Ozanne, S.; Peffers, M. J.; Jackson, M. J.; Goljanek-Whysall, K.; Vasilaki, A.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.559536
The early life environment significantly affects the development of age-related skeletal muscle disorders. However, the long-term effects of lactational protein restriction on skeletal muscle are still poorly defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Near-infrared imaging of phytochrome-derived autofluorescence in plant nuclei
Authors: Yoshinari, A.; Isoda, R.; Yagi, N.; Sato, Y.; Lindeboom, J. J.; Ehrhardt, D. W.; Frommer, W. B.; Nakamura, M.
Score: 26.7, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558255
Capturing images of the nuclear dynamics within live cells is an essential technique for comprehending the intricate biological processes inherent to plant cell nuclei. While various methods exist for imaging nuclei, including combining fluorescent proteins and dyes with microscopy, there is a dearth of commercially available dyes for live-cell imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Development and validation of the Japanese version of the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Development of Clinical Skills Scale
Authors: Kanakubo, Y.; Sugiyama, Y.; Yoshida, E.; Aoki, T.; Mutai, R.; Matsushima, M.; Okada, T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296058
IntroductionThe Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Development of Clinical Skills Scale (LGBT-DOCSS) is a validated self-assessment tool for health and mental health professionals who provide care for sexual and gender minority patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation conditions increased invigoration and wanting in depression
Authors: Ferstl, M. S.; Kuehnel, A.; Klaus, J.; Lin, W. M.; Kroemer, N. B.
Score: 18.0, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.23296284
BackgroundMajor depressive disorder (MDD) is often marked by impaired motivation and reward processing, known as anhedonia. Many patients do not respond to first-line treatments, and improvements in motivation can be slow, creating an urgent need for rapid interventions. Recently, we demonstrated that transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) acutely boosts effort invigoration in healthy participants, but its effects on depression remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Association of Cognitive Deficits with Sociodemographic Characteristics among Adults with Post-COVID Conditions: Findings from the United States Household Pulse Survey
Authors: Wu, D. J.; Liu, N.
Score: 61.8, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295981
BackgroundPeople infected with COVID-19 may continue to experience symptoms for several weeks or even months after acute infection, a condition known as long COVID. Cognitive problems such as memory loss are among the most commonly reported symptoms of long COVID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Exploration of the potential of high resolution and contrast 7 Tesla MR brain imaging in neonates
Authors: Bridgen, P.; Tomi-Tricot, R.; Uus, A.; Cromb, D.; Quirke, M.; Almalbis, J.; Bonse, B.; De La Fuente Botella, M.; Maggioni, A.; Di Cio, P.; Cawley, P.; Casella, C.; Dokumaci, A. S.; Thomson, A. R.; Willers Moore, J.; Bridglal, D.; Saravia, J.; Finck, T.; Price, A. N.; Pickles, E.; Cordero-Grande, L.; Egloff, A.; O&amp;#39;Muircheartaigh, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Six Weeks of Supervised Telerehabilitation on Pulmonary Function, Functional Capacity, and Dyspnoea among individuals with Long COVID
Authors: Al Mheiri, A.; Girish, S.; Amaravadi, S. K.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23296254
BackgroundLong COVID, characterized by persistent symptoms post-COVID-19, presents challenges like reduced functional capacity, pulmonary function, and dyspnea. Telerehabilitation, a remote healthcare approach, is gaining attention for its potential to address these issues ObjectivesThe study aims to determine the effect of telerehabilitation on functional capacity by six-minute walk test (MWT), pulmonary function by pulmonary function test (PFT), dyspnea by modified medical research council (mMRC) and level of physical activity by Global physical activity questionnaire (GPAQ) in individuals with long COVID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Controlled experiment finds no detectable citation bump from Twitter promotion
Authors: Branch, T.; C?te, I. M.; David, S. R.; Drew, J. A.; LaRue, M.; Marquez, M. C.; Parsons, E. C. M.; Rabaiotti, D.; Shiffman, D.; Steen, D. A.; Wild, A. L.
Score: 227.5, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558161
Multiple studies across a variety of scientific disciplines have shown that the number of times that a paper is shared on Twitter (now called X) is correlated with the number of citations that paper receives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The Zipime-Weka-Schista study protocol: a longitudinal cohort study and economic evaluation of an integrated home-based approach for genital multi-pathogen screening in women, including female genital schistosomiasis, HPV, Trichomonas and HIV in Zambia
Authors: Shanaube, K.; Ndubani, R.; Kelly, H.; Webb, E.; Mayaud, P.; Lamberti, O.; Fitzpatrick, J.; Kasese, N.; Sturt, A.; Van Lieshout, L.; Van Dam, G.; Corstjens, P. L. A. M.; Kosloff, B.; Bond, V.; Hayes, R.; Terris-Prestholt, F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Probiotic neoantigen delivery vectors for precision cancer immunotherapy
Authors: Redenti, A.; Im, J.; Redenti, B.; Li, F.; Rouanne, M.; Sheng, Z.; Sun, W.; Gurbatri, C. R.; Huang, S.; Komaranchath, M.; Jang, Y.; Hahn, J.; Ballister, E. R.; Vincent, R. L.; Vardoshivilli, A.; Danino, T.; Arpaia, N.
Score: 17.4, Published: 2023-09-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560228
Microbial systems have been synthetically engineered to deploy therapeutic payloads in vivo1-4. With emerging evidence that bacteria naturally home to tumors5-7 and modulate anti-tumor immunity8,9, one promising application is the development of bacterial vectors as precision cancer vaccines10-12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Digitize your Biology! Modeling multicellular systems through interpretable cell behavior
Authors: Johnson, J. A. I.; Stein-O&amp;#39;Brien, G. L.; Booth, M.; Heiland, R.; Kurtoglu, F.; Bergman, D.; Bucher, E.; Deshpande, A.; Forjaz, A.; Getz, M.; Godet, I.; Lyman, M.; Metzcar, J.; Mitchell, J.; Raddatz, A.; Rocha, H. L.; Solorzano, J.; Sundus, A.; Wang, Y.; Gilkes, D. M.; Kagohara, L. T.; Kiemen, A. L.; Thompson, E. D.; Wirtz, D.; Wu, P.-H.; Zaidi, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Diminishing growth of zoological natural history collections threatens future research in the life sciences and beyond
Authors: Card, D. C.
Score: 17.0, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560208
Natural history museums comprise a unique and important component of biological infrastructure worldwide, and underlie diverse research, education, and outreach in the natural sciences. Each museum is built around one or more biological collections that serve as a repository of important materials for study, which have contributed to scientific research in increasingly important areas ranging from understanding global climate change to developing new biotechnological applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
