<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Neutrophils cultured ex vivo from CD34&amp;#43; stem cells are immature and genetically tractable
Authors: Naveh, C. A.; Roberts, K.; Rice, C. M.; Fleming, K.; Thompson, M.; Panyapiean, N.; Diezmann, S.; Moura, P. L.; Toye, A. M.; Amulic, B.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292345
Neutrophils are essential antimicrobial effector cells with short lifespans. During infection or sterile inflammation, accelerated production and release of immature neutrophils from the bone marrow serves to boost circulating neutrophil counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous helping in pigs is mediated by helper&amp;#39;s social attention and distress signals of individuals in need
Authors: Moscovice, L. R.; Eggert, A.; Manteuffel, C.; Rault, J.-L.
Score: 117.8, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.17.533160
Helping behaviour is of special interest for prosociality because it appears to be motivated by the needs of others. We developed a novel paradigm to investigate helping in pigs (Sus scrofa domesticus) and tested 75 individuals in eight groups in their home pens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>A systems-scale, integrated view of the ubiquitylation site occupancy and dynamics
Authors: Prus, G.; Satpathy, S.; Weinert, B.; Narita, T.; Choudhary, C.
Score: 32.7, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549470
Ubiquitylation regulates virtually all proteins and biological processes in a cell. However, the global site-specific occupancy (stoichiometry) and turnover rate of ubiquitylation have never been quantified. Here, we present the first integrated picture of ubiquitylation site occupancy and half-life. Ubiquitylation occupancy spans four orders of magnitude, but the median ubiquitylation site occupancy is three orders of magnitude lower than that of phosphorylation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous multi-site editing of individual genomes using retron arrays
Authors: Gonzalez-Delgado, A.; Lopez, S. C.; Rojas-Montero, M.; Fishman, C. B.; Shipman, S. L.
Score: 27.2, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549397
Our understanding of genomics is limited by the scale of our genomic technologies. While libraries of genomic manipulations scaffolded on CRISPR gRNAs have been transformative, these existing approaches are typically multiplexed across genomes. Yet much of the complexity of real genomes is encoded within a genome across sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Scalable querying of human cell atlases via a foundational model reveals commonalities across fibrosis-associated macrophages
Authors: Heimberg, G.; Kuo, T. C.; DePianto, D.; Heigl, T.; Diamant, N.; Salem, O.; Scalia, G.; Biancalani, T.; Rock, J.; Turley, S.; Bravo, H. C.; Kaminker, J.; Vander Heiden, J. A.; Regev, A.
Score: 150.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549537
Single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) studies have profiled over 100 million human cells across diseases, developmental stages, and perturbations to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Direct optical measurement of intra-molecular distances down to the Angstrom scale
Authors: Sahl, S. J.; Matthias, J.; Inamdar, K.; Khan, T. A.; Weber, M.; Becker, S.; Griesinger, C.; Broichhagen, J.; Hell, S. W.
Score: 123.9, Published: 2023-07-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548133
Optical investigations of nanometer distances between proteins, their subunits, or other biomolecules have been the exclusive prerogative of Forster Resonance Energy Transfer (FRET) microscopy for decades. Here we show that MINFLUX fluorescence nanoscopy measures intra-molecular distances down to 1 nm - and in planar projections down to 1 Angstrom - directly, linearly, and with Angstrom precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>PP2A inhibition instructs spliceosome phosphorylation to create splicing vulnerability in colon adenocarcinoma
Authors: Dias, M. H.; Liudkovska, V.; Bleijerveld, O. B.; Velds, A.; Bernards, R.; Ciesla, M.
Score: 225.8, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548685
Protein phosphatase 2A (PP2A) is a versatile enzyme affecting many aspects of cellular physiology. However, it remains unclear which of the cellular processes are most perturbed upon PP2A inhibition and how these perturbations could be exploited therapeutically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The Cardiovascular Impact and Genetics of Pericardial Adiposity
Authors: Ramo, J. T.; Kany, S.; Hou, C. R.; Friedman, S. F.; Roselli, C.; Nauffal, V.; Koyama, S.; Karjalainen, J.; FinnGen, ; Maddah, M.; Palotie, A.; Ellinor, P. T.; Pirruccello, J. P.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.16.23292729
BackgroundWhile previous studies have reported associations of pericardial adipose tissue (PAT) with cardiovascular diseases such as atrial fibrillation and coronary artery disease, they have been limited in sample size or drawn from selected populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Tepsin binds LC3B to promote ATG9A export and delivery at the cell periphery
Authors: Wallace, N. S.; Gadbery, J. E.; Cohen, C. I.; Kendall, A. K.; Jackson, L. P.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549521
Tepsin is an established accessory protein found in Adaptor Protein 4 (AP-4) coated vesicles, but the biological role of tepsin remains unknown. AP-4 vesicles originate at the trans-Golgi network (TGN) and target the delivery of ATG9A, a scramblase required for autophagosome biogenesis, to the cell periphery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Multiple embryonic sources converge to form the pectoral girdle skeleton in zebrafish
Authors: Kuroda, S.; Lalonde, R. L.; Mansour, T. A.; Mosimann, C.; Nakamura, T.
Score: 19.4, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.548949
The morphological transformation of the pectoral/shoulder girdle is fundamental to the water-to-land transition in vertebrate evolution. Although previous studies have resolved the embryonic origins of the tetrapod shoulder girdle, those of the fish pectoral girdle remain uncharacterized, creating a gap in the understanding of girdle transformation mechanisms from fish to modern tetrapods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>A fast-slow trait continuum at the level of entire communities
Authors: Neyret, M.; Le Provost, G.; Boesing, A. L.; Schneider, F. D.; Baulechner, D.; Bergmann, J.; de Vries, F.; Fiore-Donno, A. M.; Geisen, S.; Goldmann, K.; Kuechler, A.; Saifutdinov, R.; Simons, N. K.; Tobias, J.; Zaitsev, A. S.; Gossner, M. M.; Jung, K.; Kandeler, E.; Krauss, J.; Penone, C.; Schloter, M.; Schulz, S.; Staab, M.; Wolters, V.; Apostolakis, A.; Birkhofer, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Very Low Lipoprotein(a) Levels Are Associated With Higher Risks Of New-Onset Diabetes And Non-Alcoholic Liver Disease
Authors: Yeung, M. W.; Said, M. A.; van de Vegte, Y. J.; Verweij, N.; Dullaart, R. P.; van der Harst, P.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292471
AimWe aimed to study the association of very low serum Lipoprotein(a) [Lp(a)] concentrations with new-onset type 2 diabetes (T2D) and non-alcoholic liver disease (NAFLD) in the context of lipid-lowering medication usage in the UK Biobank, a large prospective population cohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Risk of severe outcomes among Omicron sub-lineages BA.4.6, BA.2.75 and BQ.1 compared to BA.5 in England
Authors: Seghezzo, G.; Nash, S. G.; Abdul Aziz, N.; Hope, R.; Lopez Bernal, J.; Gallagher, E.; Dabrera, G.; Thelwall, S.
Score: 143.7, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292656
Since the emergence of Omicron variant of SARS-CoV-2 in late 2021, a number of sub-lineages have arisen and circulated internationally. Little is known about the relative severity of Omicron sub-lineages BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Clockor2: Inferring global and local strict molecular clocks using root-to-tip regression
Authors: Featherstone, L. A.; Rambaut, A.; Duchene, S.; Wirth, W.
Score: 93.1, Published: 2023-07-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548947
Molecular sequence data from rapidly evolving organisms are often sampled at different points in time. Sampling times can then be used for molecular clock calibration. The root-to-tip (RTT) regression is an essential tool to assess the degree to which the data behave in a clock-like fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic Age Acceleration in Surviving versus Deceased COVID-19 Patients with Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome following Hospitalization
Authors: Bejaoui, Y.; Humaira Amanullah, F.; Saad, M.; Taleb, S.; Bradic, M.; Megarbane, A.; Ait Hssain, A.; Abi Khalil, C.; El Hajj, N.
Score: 198.9, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549478
Aging has been reported as a major risk factor for severe symptoms and higher mortality rates in COVID-19 patients. Molecular hallmarks such as epigenetic alterations and telomere attenuation reflect the biological process of aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Recurrent chromosome destabilization through repeat-mediated rearrangements in a fungal pathogen
Authors: Fouche, S.; Oggenfuss, U.; McDonald, B. A.; Croll, D.
Score: 19.8, Published: 2023-07-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549097
Genomic instability caused by chromosomal rearrangements has severe consequences for organismal fitness and progression of cancerous cell lines. The triggers of destabilized chromosomes remain poorly understood but are often assumed to be associated with fragile sites. Here, we retrace a runaway chromosomal degeneration process observed in a fungal pathogen using telomere-to-telomere assemblies across an experimental pedigree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The principal component-based clinical aging clock (PCAge) identifies signatures of healthy aging and provides normative targets for clinical intervention
Authors: Fong, S.; Pabis, K.; Latumalea, D.; Dugersuren, N.; Unfried, M.; Tolwinski, N.; Kennedy, B.; Gruber, J.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292604
Clinical healthy aging recommendations are disease-centric and reactive rather than focusing on holistic, organismal aging. In contrast, biological age (BA) estimation informs risk stratification by predicting all-cause mortality, however current BA clocks do not pinpoint aging mechanisms making it difficult to intervene clinically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of digital health insurance for low-income women in Kenya
Authors: de Groot, R.; Abajobir, A.; Wainaina, C.; Sidze, E. M.; Pradhan, M.; Janssens, W.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292292
ObjectiveThis study evaluates how a subsidized, mobile phone-based health insurance program affected insurance uptake, healthcare utilization and health expenditures for low-income women and their family members in Western Kenya. The program, targeting pregnant women and mothers of children below age four, addressed both demand- and supply-side constraints, providing subsidies through mobile money and support in digital registration while upgrading selected facilities and digitally training community health workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging Large Language Models for Generating Responses to Patient Messages
Authors: Liu, S.; McCoy, A. B.; Wright, A. P.; Carew, B.; Genkins, J. Z.; Huang, S. S.; Peterson, J. F.; Steitz, B.; Wright, A.
Score: 18.5, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292669
ObjectiveThis study aimed to develop and assess the performance of fine-tuned large language models for generating responses to patient messages sent via an electronic health record patient portal. MethodsUtilizing a dataset of messages and responses extracted from the patient portal at a large academic medical center, we developed a model (CLAIR-Short) based on a pre-trained large language model (LLaMA-65B).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics and quality of studies pertaining to masks published in the Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report
Authors: Hoeg, T. B.; Haslam, A.; Prasad, V.
Score: 619.3, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292338
ImportanceBecause the MMWR has substantial influence on United States public health policy and is not externally peer-reviewed, it is critical to understand the scientific process within the journal. Mask policies during COVID is one topic that has been highly influenced by data published in the MMWR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Utility of nasal swabs for assessing mucosal immune responses towards SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Roubidoux, E. K.; Brigleb, P. H.; Vegesana, K.; Souquette, A.; Whitt, K.; Freiden, P.; St. Jude Investigative Team, ; Green, A.; Thomas, P. G.; McGargill, M. A.; Wolf, J.; Schultz-Cherry, S.
Score: 16.9, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548630
SARS-CoV-2 has caused millions of infections worldwide since its emergence in 2019. Understanding how infection and vaccination induce mucosal immune responses and how they fluctuate over time is important, especially since they are key in preventing infection and reducing disease severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Early Biological Markers of Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection
Authors: Lu, S.; Peluso, M. J.; Glidden, D. V.; Davidson, M.; Lugtu, K.; Pineda-Ramirez, J.; Tassetto, M.; Garcia-Knight, M.; Zhang, A.; Goldberg, S. A.; Chen, J.; Forbes, M.; Park, S.; Martinez, A.; So, M.; Donovan, A.; Viswanathan, B.; Hoh, R.; Donohue, K.; McIlwain, D.; Gaudilliere, B.; Anglin, K.; Yee, B.; Chenna, A. A.; Winslow, J.; Petropoulos, C.; Briggs-Hagen, M.; Andino, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Perceptions and Experiences of ChatGPT in Medical Education: A Qualitative Study Among Medical College Faculty and Students in Saudi Arabia
Authors: Abouammoh, N.; Alhasan, K.; Raina, R.; Malki, K. A.; Aljamaan, F.; Tamimi, I.; Muaygil, R.; Wahabi, H.; Jamal, A.; Al-Tawfiq, J. A.; Al-Eyadhy, A.; Soliman, M.; Temsah, M. H.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292624
BackgroundWith the rapid development of artificial intelligence (AI) technologies, there is a growing interest in the potential use of AI-based tools like ChatGPT in medical education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>High-resolution profiling of bacterial and fungal communities using pangenome-informed taxon-specific amplicons and long-read sequencing
Authors: Stalder, L.; Maurhofer, M.; Croll, D.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549274
AO_SCPLOWBSTRACTC_SCPLOWHigh-throughput sequencing technologies have greatly advanced our understanding of microbiomes, but resolving microbial communities at species and strain levels remains challenging. In this study, we present a pipeline for designing, multiplexing, and sequencing highly polymorphic taxon-specific amplicons using PacBio circular consensus sequencing. We focus on the wheat microbiome as a proof-of-principle and demonstrate unprecedented resolution for the wheat-associated Pseudomonas microbiome and the ubiquitous fungal pathogen Zymoseptoria tritici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mechanism of outer kinetochore assembly on microtubules and its regulation by mitotic error correction
Authors: Muir, K. W.; Batters, C.; Dendooven, T.; Yang, J.; Zhang, Z.; Burt, A.; Barford, D.
Score: 47.0, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549907
Kinetochores couple chromosomes to the mitotic spindle and transduce the energy of microtubule depolymerization to segregate the genome during cell division. Kinetochore-microtubule attachments are often initially erroneous and subject to a mitotic error correction (EC) mechanism that drives their turnover until biorientation is achieved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>CSF proteome profiling reveals highly specific biomarkers for dementia with Lewy bodies.
Authors: del Campo, M.; Vermunt, L.; Peeters, C.; Hok-A-Hin, Y.; Lleo, A.; Alcolea, D.; van Nee, M.; Engelborghs, S.; Sieben, A.; Chen-Plotkin, A.; Irwin, D.; van der Flier, W.; Lemstra, A.; Teunissen, C.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292447
Diagnosis of dementia with Lewy bodies (DLB) is challenging and biofluid biomarkers specific for DLB are highly needed. Here we use proximity extension-based multiplex assays to establish the specific cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) proteomic changes that underlie DLB in an unprecedented well-characterized cohort of 109 DLB patients, 235 patients with Alzheime[r]s disease (AD) and 190 controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Sustaining wakefulness: Brainstem connectivity in human consciousness
Authors: Edlow, B. L.; Olchanyi, M.; Freeman, H. J.; Li, J.; Maffei, C.; Snider, S. B.; Zollei, L.; Iglesias, J. E.; Augustinack, J.; Bodien, Y. G.; Haynes, R. L.; Greve, D. N.; Diamond, B. R.; Stevens, A.; Giacino, J. T.; Destrieux, C.; van der Kouwe, A.; Brown, E. N.; Folkerth, R. D.; Fischl, B.; Kinney, H. C.
Score: 94.3, Published: 2023-07-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>The ADNEX risk prediction model for ovarian cancer diagnosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of external validation studies
Authors: Barrenada, L.; Ledger, A.; Dhiman, P.; Collins, G. S.; Wynants, L.; Verbakel, J. Y.; Timmerman, D.; Valentin, L.; Van Calster, B.
Score: 7.2, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23291935
Objectives: To conduct a systematic review of studies externally validating the ADNEX model for ovarian cancer diagnosis and perform a meta-analysis of its performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Association of Genetic Ancestry with Molecular Tumor Profiles in Colorectal Cancer
Authors: Rhead, B.; Hein, D.; Pouliot, Y.; Guinney, J.; De La Vega, F. M.; Sanford, N.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292571
PurposePrior research in the molecular correlates of disparities in incidence and outcomes of colorectal cancer (CRC) by race and ethnicity have typically used self-reported or observed categories, which can be missing or inaccurate. Furthermore, race and ethnicity do not always capture genetic similarity well, particularly in admixed populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Ethnicity is not biology: retinal pigment score to evaluate biological variability from ophthalmic imaging using machine learning
Authors: Rajesh, A. E.; Olvera-Barrios, A.; Warwick, A. N.; Wu, Y.; Stuart, K. V.; Biradar, M.; Ung, C. Y.; Khawaja, A. P.; Luben, R.; Foster, P. J.; Lee, C. S.; Tufail, A.; Lee, A. Y.; Egan, C.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-07-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.23291873
BackgroundFew metrics exist to describe phenotypic diversity within ophthalmic imaging datasets, with researchers often using ethnicity as an inappropriate marker for biological variability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Fusion of Electronic Health Records and Radiographic Images for a Multimodal Deep Learning Prediction Model of Atypical Femur Fractures
Authors: Schilcher, J.; Nilsson, A.; Andlid, O.; Eklund, A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.02.23292125
Atypical femur fractures (AFF) represent a very rare type of fracture that can be difficult to discriminate radiologically from normal femur fractures (NFF). AFFs are associated with drugs that are administered to prevent osteoporosis-related fragility fractures, which are highly prevalent in the elderly population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Oxygen isotopes in orangutan teeth reveal recent and ancient climate variation
Authors: Smith, T. M.; Arora, M.; Austin, C.; Avila, J. N.; Duval, M.; Lim, T. T.; Piper, P.; Vaiglova, P.; Vos, J. d.; Williams, I. S.; Zhao, J.-x.; Green, D. R.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549587
Studies of climate variation commonly rely on chemical and isotopic changes recorded in sequentially-produced growth layers, such as in corals, shells and tree rings, as well as in accretionary deposits--ice and sediment cores, and speleothems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>In situ cryo-electron tomography of beta-amyloid and tau in post-mortem Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease brain
Authors: Gilbert, M. A. G.; Fatima, N.; Jenkins, J.; O&amp;#39;Sullivan, T. J.; Schertel, A.; Halfon, Y.; Morrema, T. H. J.; Geibel, M.; Radford, S. E.; Hoozemans, J. J. M.; Frank, R. A. W.
Score: 57.0, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549278
A defining pathological feature of most neurodegenerative diseases is the assembly of proteins into amyloid that form disease-specific structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Maternal prenatal immune activation associated with brain tissue microstructure and metabolite concentrations in newborn infants
Authors: Spann, M.; Bansal, R.; Aydin, E.; Pollatou, A.; Alleyne, K.; Bennett, M.; Sawardekar, S.; Cheng, B.; Lee, S.; Monk, C.; Peterson, B.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292113
ImportanceFew translational human studies have assessed the association of prenatal maternal immune activation with altered brain development and psychiatric risk in newborn offspring. ObjectiveTo identify the effects of maternal immune activation during the 2nd and 3rd trimesters of pregnancy on newborn brain metabolite concentrations, tissue microstructure, and longitudinal motor development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Refining the impact of genetic evidence on clinical success
Authors: Minikel, E. V.; Painter, J. L.; Dong, C. C.; Nelson, M. R.
Score: 57.8, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23291765
The cost of drug discovery and development is driven primarily by failure, with just [~]10% of clinical programs eventually receiving approval. We previously estimated that human genetic evidence doubles the success rate from clinical development to approval. In this study we leverage the growth in genetic evidence over the past decade to better understand the characteristics that distinguish clinical success and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Optical Control of G-Actin with a Photoswitchable Latrunculin
Authors: Veprek, N. A.; Cooper, M. H.; Laprell, L.; Yang, E. J.-N.; Folkerts, S.; Bao, R.; Oertner, T. G.; Pon, L. A.; Zuchero, J. B.; Trauner, D. H.
Score: 17.5, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549222
Actin is one of the most abundant proteins in eukaryotic cells and a key component of the cytoskeleton. A range of small molecules have emerged that interfere with actin dynamics by either binding to polymeric F-actin or monomeric G-actin to stabilize or destabilize filaments or prevent their formation and growth, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of cambium stem cell factors and their positioning mechanism
Authors: Eswaran, G.; Rutten, J. P.; Han, J.; Iida, H.; Lopez Ortiz, J.; Makila, R.; Wybouw, B.; Vainio, L.; Porcher, A.; Leal Gavarron, M.; Zhang, J.; Blomster, T.; Wang, X.; Dolan, D. W. P.; Smetana, O.; Brady, S.; Kucukoglu Topcu, M.; ten Tusscher, K. H.; Etchells, P.; Mahonen, A. P.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549889
Wood constitutes the majority of terrestrial biomass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>LSD increases sleep duration the night after microdosing
Authors: Allen, N.; Jeremiah, A.; Murphy, R.; Sumner, R.; Forsyth, A.; Hoeh, N.; Menkes, D.; Evans, W.; Muthukumaraswamy, S.; Sundram, F.; Roop, P.
Score: 40.2, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.23291970
Microdosing psychedelic drugs, at a level below the threshold to induce hallucinations, is an increasingly common lifestyle practise. However, the effects of microdosing on sleep have not been previously reported. Here we report results from a Phase 1 randomised controlled trial in which 80 healthy adult male volunteers received a six week course of either LSD (10 {micro}g) or placebo with doses self-administered every third day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Effects of nutritional supplements on antibody levels in pregnant women vaccinated with inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccines
Authors: Zhang, X.; Han, X.; Chen, B.; Fu, X.; Gong, Y.; Yang, W.; CHEN, Q.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.16.23292747
BackgroundBecause of the significantly higher demand for nutrients during pregnancy, pregnant women are more likely to have nutrient deficiencies, which may adversely affect maternal and fetal health. The effect of nutritional supplements on the immune effects of inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccines during pregnancy is not clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Magnetic susceptibility is predictive of future clinical severity in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Thomas, G. E. C.; Hannaway, N.; Zarkali, A.; Shmueli, K.; Weil, R.
Score: 14.0, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292555
Dementia is common in Parkinsons disease, but there is wide variation in its timing. With the emergence of disease modifying treatments in neurodegeneration, there is increasing need to detect and treat disease at the earliest stages and to monitor disease progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 12.4, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Development and Assessment of a Sustainable PhD Internship Program Supporting Diverse Biomedical Career Outcomes
Authors: Brandt, P. D.; Whittington, D.; Wood, K. D.; Holmquist, C. E.; Nogueira, A. T.; Gaines, C. H.; Brennwald, P. J.; Layton, R. L.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548912
A doctoral-level internship program was developed at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill with the intent to create customizable experiential learning opportunities for biomedical trainees to support career exploration, preparation, and transition into their post-graduate professional roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Late reproduction is associated with extended female survival but not with familial longevity
Authors: Kat, A. d.; Roelofs, F.; Slagboom, E.; Broekmans, F.; Beekman, M.; Berg, N. v. d.
Score: 17.2, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291896
ObjectiveFemale reproductive health comprises adequate oocyte quality and quantity, normal fecundability, a normal course of pregnancy, and the delivery of healthy offspring. General aging patterns and the maintenance of somatic health have been associated with female reproductive health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The night-time sleep and autonomic activity of male and female professional road cyclists competing in the Tour de France and Tour de France Femmes.
Authors: Sargent, C.; Jasinkski, S.; Capodilupo, E. R.; Powers, J.; Miller, D. J.; Roach, G. D.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2023-07-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.06.23292280
ObjectiveThe objective of this study was to examine the capacity of male and female professional cyclists to recover between daily race stages while competing in the 109th edition of the Tour de France (2022) and the 1st edition of the Tour de France Femmes (2022), respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Platform for Controlled Template-Independent Enzymatic Synthesis of RNA Oligonucleotides and Therapeutics
Authors: Wiegand, D. J.; Rittichier, J.; Meyer, E.; Lee, H.; Conway, N. J.; Ahlstedt, D.; Yurtsever, Z.; Rainone, D.; Kuru, E.; Church, G.
Score: 16.3, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.547106
Therapeutic RNA oligonucleotides have shown tremendous potential to manage and treat disease, yet current manufacturing methods cannot deliver on this promise. Here, we report the development and optimization of a novel, aqueous-based, template-independent enzymatic RNA oligonucleotide synthesis platform as an alternative to traditional chemical methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systems Age: A single blood methylation test to quantify aging heterogeneity across 11 physiological systems
Authors: Sehgal, R.; Meer, M.; Shadyab, A. H.; Casanova, R.; Manson, J. E.; Bhatti, P.; Crimmins, E. M.; Assimes, T. L.; Whitsel, E. A.; Higgins-Chen, A. T.; Levine, M.
Score: 40.5, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548904
Individuals, organs, tissues, and cells age in diverse ways throughout the lifespan. Epigenetic clocks attempt to quantify differential aging between individuals, but they typically summarize aging as a single measure, ignoring within-person heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Shedding light on the Ophel biome: The Trans-Tethyan phylogeography of the sulfide shrimp Tethysbaena (Peracarida: Thermosbaenacea) in the Levant
Authors: Guy-Haim, T.; Kolodny, O.; Frumkin, A.; Achituv, Y.; Velasquez, X.; Morov, A. R.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549641
Tethysbaena are small peracarid crustaceans found in extreme environments such as subterranean lakes and thermal springs, represented by endemic species found around the ancient Tethys, including the Mediterranean, Arabian Sea, Mid-East Atlantic, and the Caribbean Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
