<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Neutrophils cultured ex vivo from CD34&amp;#43; stem cells are immature and genetically tractable
Authors: Naveh, C. A.; Roberts, K.; Rice, C. M.; Fleming, K.; Thompson, M.; Panyapiean, N.; Diezmann, S.; Moura, P. L.; Toye, A. M.; Amulic, B.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292345
Neutrophils are essential antimicrobial effector cells with short lifespans. During infection or sterile inflammation, accelerated production and release of immature neutrophils from the bone marrow serves to boost circulating neutrophil counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous helping in pigs is mediated by helper&amp;#39;s social attention and distress signals of individuals in need
Authors: Moscovice, L. R.; Eggert, A.; Manteuffel, C.; Rault, J.-L.
Score: 116.8, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.17.533160
Helping behaviour is of special interest for prosociality because it appears to be motivated by the needs of others. We developed a novel paradigm to investigate helping in pigs (Sus scrofa domesticus) and tested 75 individuals in eight groups in their home pens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Engineering and Evolution of the Complete Reductive Glycine Pathway in Saccharomyces cerevisiae for Formate and CO2 Assimilation
Authors: Bysani, V. R.; Alam, A. S. M.; Bar-Even, A.; Machens, F.
Score: 16.6, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548313
Using captured CO2 and C1-feedstocks like formate and methanol derived from electrochemical activation of CO2 are key solutions for transforming industrial processes towards a circular carbon economy. Engineering formate and CO2-based growth in the biotechnologically relevant yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae could boost the emergence of a formate-mediated circular bio-economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Simultaneous multi-site editing of individual genomes using retron arrays
Authors: Gonzalez-Delgado, A.; Lopez, S. C.; Rojas-Montero, M.; Fishman, C. B.; Shipman, S. L.
Score: 23.8, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549397
Our understanding of genomics is limited by the scale of our genomic technologies. While libraries of genomic manipulations scaffolded on CRISPR gRNAs have been transformative, these existing approaches are typically multiplexed across genomes. Yet much of the complexity of real genomes is encoded within a genome across sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Petascale Homology Search for Structure Prediction
Authors: Lee, S.; Kim, G.; Levy Karin, E.; Mirdita, M.; Park, S.; Chikhi, R.; Babaian, A.; Kryshtafovych, A.; Steinegger, M.
Score: 72.9, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548308
The recent CASP15 competition highlighted the critical role of multiple sequence alignments (MSAs) in protein structure prediction, as demonstrated by the success of the top AlphaFold2-based prediction methods. To push the boundaries of MSA utilization, we conducted a petabase-scale search of the Sequence Read Archive (SRA), resulting in gigabytes of aligned homologs for CASP15 targets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Direct optical measurement of intra-molecular distances down to the Angstrom scale
Authors: Sahl, S. J.; Matthias, J.; Inamdar, K.; Khan, T. A.; Weber, M.; Becker, S.; Griesinger, C.; Broichhagen, J.; Hell, S. W.
Score: 124.4, Published: 2023-07-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548133
Optical investigations of nanometer distances between proteins, their subunits, or other biomolecules have been the exclusive prerogative of Forster Resonance Energy Transfer (FRET) microscopy for decades. Here we show that MINFLUX fluorescence nanoscopy measures intra-molecular distances down to 1 nm - and in planar projections down to 1 Angstrom - directly, linearly, and with Angstrom precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>PP2A inhibition instructs spliceosome phosphorylation to create splicing vulnerability in colon adenocarcinoma
Authors: Dias, M. H.; Liudkovska, V.; Bleijerveld, O. B.; Velds, A.; Bernards, R.; Ciesla, M.
Score: 225.8, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548685
Protein phosphatase 2A (PP2A) is a versatile enzyme affecting many aspects of cellular physiology. However, it remains unclear which of the cellular processes are most perturbed upon PP2A inhibition and how these perturbations could be exploited therapeutically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Appropriateness of ChatGPT in answering heart failure related questions
Authors: King, R.; Samaan, J. S.; Yeo, Y. H.; Mody, B.; Lombardo, D. M.; Ghashghaei, R.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292385
BackgroundHeart failure requires complex management with increased patient knowledge shown to improve outcomes. The large language model (LLM), Chat Generative Pre-Trained Transformer (ChatGPT), may be a useful supplemental resource of information for patients with heart failure. MethodsResponses produced by GPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Pooled endogenous protein tagging and recruitment for scalable discovery of effectors for induced proximity therapeutics
Authors: Serebrenik, Y. V.; Mani, D.; Maujean, T.; Burslem, G. M.; Shalem, O.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548759
The field of induced proximity therapeutics is in its ascendancy but is limited by a lack of scalable tools to systematically explore effector-target protein pairs in an unbiased manner. Here, we combined Scalable POoled Targeting with a LIgandable Tag at Endogenous Sites (SPOTLITES) for the high-throughput tagging of endogenous proteins, with generic small molecule-based protein recruitment to screen for novel proximity-based effectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>GPT-4, an artificial intelligence large language model,exhibits high levels of accuracy on dermatology specialty certificate exam questions.
Authors: Shetty, M.; Ettlinger, M.; Lynch, M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292418
Artificial Intelligence (AI) has shown considerable potential within medical fields including dermatology. In recent years a new form of AI, large language models, has shown impressive performance in complex textual reasoning across a wide range of domains including standardised medical licensing exam questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Multiple embryonic sources converge to form the pectoral girdle skeleton in zebrafish
Authors: Kuroda, S.; Lalonde, R. L.; Mansour, T. A.; Mosimann, C.; Nakamura, T.
Score: 18.9, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.548949
The morphological transformation of the pectoral/shoulder girdle is fundamental to the water-to-land transition in vertebrate evolution. Although previous studies have resolved the embryonic origins of the tetrapod shoulder girdle, those of the fish pectoral girdle remain uncharacterized, creating a gap in the understanding of girdle transformation mechanisms from fish to modern tetrapods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>A fast-slow trait continuum at the level of entire communities
Authors: Neyret, M.; Le Provost, G.; Boesing, A. L.; Schneider, F. D.; Baulechner, D.; Bergmann, J.; de Vries, F.; Fiore-Donno, A. M.; Geisen, S.; Goldmann, K.; Kuechler, A.; Saifutdinov, R.; Simons, N. K.; Tobias, J.; Zaitsev, A. S.; Gossner, M. M.; Jung, K.; Kandeler, E.; Krauss, J.; Penone, C.; Schloter, M.; Schulz, S.; Staab, M.; Wolters, V.; Apostolakis, A.; Birkhofer, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Very Low Lipoprotein(a) Levels Are Associated With Higher Risks Of New-Onset Diabetes And Non-Alcoholic Liver Disease
Authors: Yeung, M. W.; Said, M. A.; van de Vegte, Y. J.; Verweij, N.; Dullaart, R. P.; van der Harst, P.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292471
AimWe aimed to study the association of very low serum Lipoprotein(a) [Lp(a)] concentrations with new-onset type 2 diabetes (T2D) and non-alcoholic liver disease (NAFLD) in the context of lipid-lowering medication usage in the UK Biobank, a large prospective population cohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Marburg Virus Disease outbreaks, mathematical models, and disease parameters: a Systematic Review
Authors: Cuomo-Dannenburg, G.; McCain, K.; McCabe, R.; Unwin, H. J. T.; Doohan, P.; Nash, R. K.; Hicks, J. T.; Charniga, K.; Geismar, C.; Lambert, B.; Nikitin, D.; Skarp, J. E.; Wardle, J.; Pathogen Epidemiology Review Group, ; Kont, M.; Bhatia, S.; Imai, N.; van Elsland, S. L.; Cori, A.; Morgenstern, C.
Score: 16.3, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292424</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Enamel proteins reveal biological sex and genetic variability within southern African Paranthropus
Authors: Madupe, P. P.; Koenig, C.; Patramanis, I.; Rüther, P. L.; Hlazo, N.; Mackie, M.; Tawane, M.; Krueger, J.; Taurozzi, A. J.; Troche, G. B.; Kibii, J.; Pickering, R.; Dickinson, M. R.; Sahle, Y.; Kgotleng, D.; Musiba, C.; Manthi, F.; Bell, L.; du Plessis, M.; Gilbert, C.; Zipfel, B.; Kuderna, L.; Lizano, E.; Welker, F.; Kyriakidou, P.; Cox, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Novel autoantibody targets identified in patients with autoimmune hepatitis (AIH) by PhIP-Seq reveal pathogenic insights
Authors: Klepper, A.; Kung, A.; Vazquez, S. E.; Mitchell, A.; Mann, S.; Avila-Vargas, I.; Kari, S.; Tekeste, M.; Castro, J.; Lee, B.; Duarte, M.; Khalili, M.; Wilson, M. R.; Yang, M.; Wolters, P.; Price, J.; Perito, E.; Feng, S.; Maher, J. J.; Lai, J. C.; Weiler-Normann, C.; Lohse, A.; DeRisi, J.; Tana, M.
Score: 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Estimation of indirect genetic effects and heritability under assortative mating
Authors: Young, A. S.
Score: 34.5, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548458
Both direct genetic effects (effects of alleles in an individual on that individual) and indirect genetic effects -- effects of alleles in an individual (e.g. parents) on another individual (e.g. offspring) -- can contribute to phenotypic variation and genotype-phenotype associations. Here, we consider a phenotype affected by direct and parental indirect genetic effects under assortative mating at equilibrium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>High throughput PRIME editing screens identify functional DNA variants in the human genome
Authors: Ren, X.; Yang, H.; Nierenberg, J. L.; Sun, Y.; Chen, J.; Beaman, C.; Pham, T.; Nobuhara, M.; Takagi, M. A.; Narayan, V.; Li, Y.; Ziv, E.; Shen, Y.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548736
Despite tremendous progress in detecting DNA variants associated with human disease, interpreting their functional impact in a high-throughput and base-pair resolution manner remains challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The principal component-based clinical aging clock (PCAge) identifies signatures of healthy aging and provides normative targets for clinical intervention
Authors: Fong, S.; Pabis, K.; Latumalea, D.; Dugersuren, N.; Unfried, M.; Tolwinski, N.; Kennedy, B.; Gruber, J.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.23292604
Clinical healthy aging recommendations are disease-centric and reactive rather than focusing on holistic, organismal aging. In contrast, biological age (BA) estimation informs risk stratification by predicting all-cause mortality, however current BA clocks do not pinpoint aging mechanisms making it difficult to intervene clinically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the hype: large language models propagate race-based medicine
Authors: Omiye, J. A.; Lester, J.; Spichak, S.; Rotemberg, V.; Daneshjou, R.
Score: 63.1, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292192
ImportanceLarge language models (LLMs) are being integrated into healthcare systems; but these models recapitulate harmful, race-based medicine. ObjectiveThe objective of this study is to assess whether four commercially available large language models (LLMs) propagate harmful, inaccurate, race-based content when responding to eight different scenarios that historically included race-based medicine or widespread misconceptions around race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics and quality of studies pertaining to masks published in the Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report
Authors: Hoeg, T. B.; Haslam, A.; Prasad, V.
Score: 503.7, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.23292338
ImportanceBecause the MMWR has substantial influence on United States public health policy and is not externally peer-reviewed, it is critical to understand the scientific process within the journal. Mask policies during COVID is one topic that has been highly influenced by data published in the MMWR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Utility of nasal swabs for assessing mucosal immune responses towards SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Roubidoux, E. K.; Brigleb, P. H.; Vegesana, K.; Souquette, A.; Whitt, K.; Freiden, P.; St. Jude Investigative Team, ; Green, A.; Thomas, P. G.; McGargill, M. A.; Wolf, J.; Schultz-Cherry, S.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548630
SARS-CoV-2 has caused millions of infections worldwide since its emergence in 2019. Understanding how infection and vaccination induce mucosal immune responses and how they fluctuate over time is important, especially since they are key in preventing infection and reducing disease severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Early Biological Markers of Post-Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 Infection
Authors: Lu, S.; Peluso, M. J.; Glidden, D. V.; Davidson, M.; Lugtu, K.; Pineda-Ramirez, J.; Tassetto, M.; Garcia-Knight, M.; Zhang, A.; Goldberg, S. A.; Chen, J.; Forbes, M.; Park, S.; Martinez, A.; So, M.; Donovan, A.; Viswanathan, B.; Hoh, R.; Donohue, K.; McIlwain, D.; Gaudilliere, B.; Anglin, K.; Yee, B.; Chenna, A. A.; Winslow, J.; Petropoulos, C.; Briggs-Hagen, M.; Andino, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Perceptions and Experiences of ChatGPT in Medical Education: A Qualitative Study Among Medical College Faculty and Students in Saudi Arabia
Authors: Abouammoh, N.; Alhasan, K.; Raina, R.; Malki, K. A.; Aljamaan, F.; Tamimi, I.; Muaygil, R.; Wahabi, H.; Jamal, A.; Al-Tawfiq, J. A.; Al-Eyadhy, A.; Soliman, M.; Temsah, M. H.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292624
BackgroundWith the rapid development of artificial intelligence (AI) technologies, there is a growing interest in the potential use of AI-based tools like ChatGPT in medical education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>ORBIT for E. coli: Kilobase-scale oligonucleotide recombineering at high throughput and high efficiency
Authors: Saunders, S. H.; Ahmed, A. M.
Score: 44.3, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.546561
Microbiology and synthetic biology depend on reverse genetic approaches to manipulate bacterial genomes; however, existing methods require molecular biology to generate genomic homology, suffer from low efficiency, and are not easily scaled to high throughput applications. To overcome these limitations, we developed a system for creating kilobase-scale genomic modifications that uses DNA oligonucleotides to direct the integration of a non-replicating plasmid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Chromatin remodeling of histone H3 variants underlies epigenetic inheritance of DNA methylation
Authors: Lee, S. C.; Adams, D. W.; Ipsaro, J. J.; Cahn, J.; Lynn, J.; Kim, H.-S.; Berube, B.; Major, V.; Calarco, J. P.; LeBlanc, C.; Bhattacharjee, S.; Ramu, U.; Grimanelli, D.; Jacob, Y.; Voigt, P.; Joshua-Tor, L.; Martienssen, R. A.
Score: 20.5, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.11.548598
Epigenetic inheritance refers to the faithful replication of DNA methylation and histone modification independent of DNA sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>CSF proteome profiling reveals highly specific biomarkers for dementia with Lewy bodies.
Authors: del Campo, M.; Vermunt, L.; Peeters, C.; Hok-A-Hin, Y.; Lleo, A.; Alcolea, D.; van Nee, M.; Engelborghs, S.; Sieben, A.; Chen-Plotkin, A.; Irwin, D.; van der Flier, W.; Lemstra, A.; Teunissen, C.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292447
Diagnosis of dementia with Lewy bodies (DLB) is challenging and biofluid biomarkers specific for DLB are highly needed. Here we use proximity extension-based multiplex assays to establish the specific cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) proteomic changes that underlie DLB in an unprecedented well-characterized cohort of 109 DLB patients, 235 patients with Alzheime[r]s disease (AD) and 190 controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Barcoding of episodic memories in the hippocampus of a food-caching bird
Authors: Chettih, S. N.; Mackevicius, E. L.; Hale, S.; Aronov, D.
Score: 226.7, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.27.542597
Episodic memory, or memory of experienced events, is a critical function of the hippocampus1-3. It is therefore important to understand how hippocampal activity represents specific events in an animals life. We addressed this question in chickadees - specialist food-caching birds that hide food at scattered locations and use memory to find their caches later in time4, 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>The ADNEX risk prediction model for ovarian cancer diagnosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of external validation studies
Authors: Barrenada, L.; Ledger, A.; Dhiman, P.; Collins, G. S.; Wynants, L.; Verbakel, J. Y.; Timmerman, D.; Valentin, L.; Van Calster, B.
Score: 6.7, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23291935
Objectives: To conduct a systematic review of studies externally validating the ADNEX model for ovarian cancer diagnosis and perform a meta-analysis of its performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Association of Genetic Ancestry with Molecular Tumor Profiles in Colorectal Cancer
Authors: Rhead, B.; Hein, D.; Pouliot, Y.; Guinney, J.; De La Vega, F. M.; Sanford, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292571
PurposePrior research in the molecular correlates of disparities in incidence and outcomes of colorectal cancer (CRC) by race and ethnicity have typically used self-reported or observed categories, which can be missing or inaccurate. Furthermore, race and ethnicity do not always capture genetic similarity well, particularly in admixed populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Ethnicity is not biology: retinal pigment score to evaluate biological variability from ophthalmic imaging using machine learning
Authors: Rajesh, A. E.; Olvera-Barrios, A.; Warwick, A. N.; Wu, Y.; Stuart, K. V.; Biradar, M.; Ung, C. Y.; Khawaja, A. P.; Luben, R.; Foster, P. J.; Lee, C. S.; Tufail, A.; Lee, A. Y.; Egan, C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.23291873
BackgroundFew metrics exist to describe phenotypic diversity within ophthalmic imaging datasets, with researchers often using ethnicity as an inappropriate marker for biological variability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Fusion of Electronic Health Records and Radiographic Images for a Multimodal Deep Learning Prediction Model of Atypical Femur Fractures
Authors: Schilcher, J.; Nilsson, A.; Andlid, O.; Eklund, A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.02.23292125
Atypical femur fractures (AFF) represent a very rare type of fracture that can be difficult to discriminate radiologically from normal femur fractures (NFF). AFFs are associated with drugs that are administered to prevent osteoporosis-related fragility fractures, which are highly prevalent in the elderly population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>In situ cryo-electron tomography of beta-amyloid and tau in post-mortem Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease brain
Authors: Gilbert, M. A. G.; Fatima, N.; Jenkins, J.; O&amp;#39;Sullivan, T. J.; Schertel, A.; Halfon, Y.; Morrema, T. H. J.; Geibel, M.; Radford, S. E.; Hoozemans, J. J. M.; Frank, R. A. W.
Score: 32.5, Published: 2023-07-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549278
A defining pathological feature of most neurodegenerative diseases is the assembly of proteins into amyloid that form disease-specific structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Maternal prenatal immune activation associated with brain tissue microstructure and metabolite concentrations in newborn infants
Authors: Spann, M.; Bansal, R.; Aydin, E.; Pollatou, A.; Alleyne, K.; Bennett, M.; Sawardekar, S.; Cheng, B.; Lee, S.; Monk, C.; Peterson, B.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292113
ImportanceFew translational human studies have assessed the association of prenatal maternal immune activation with altered brain development and psychiatric risk in newborn offspring. ObjectiveTo identify the effects of maternal immune activation during the 2nd and 3rd trimesters of pregnancy on newborn brain metabolite concentrations, tissue microstructure, and longitudinal motor development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Refining the impact of genetic evidence on clinical success
Authors: Minikel, E. V.; Painter, J. L.; Dong, C. C.; Nelson, M. R.
Score: 57.5, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23291765
The cost of drug discovery and development is driven primarily by failure, with just [~]10% of clinical programs eventually receiving approval. We previously estimated that human genetic evidence doubles the success rate from clinical development to approval. In this study we leverage the growth in genetic evidence over the past decade to better understand the characteristics that distinguish clinical success and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Multidrug Efflux in Gram-Negative Bacteria: Rationally Modifying Compounds to Avoid Efflux Pumps
Authors: Gurvic, D.; Zachariae, U.
Score: 4.3, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548850
Gram-negative bacteria cause the majority of critically drug-resistant infections, necessitating the rapid development of new drugs with Gram-negative activity. However, drug design is hampered by the low permeability of the Gram-negative cell envelope and the function of drug efflux pumps, which extrude foreign molecules from the cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 20.1, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Teosinte Pollen Drive guides maize domestication and evolution by RNAi
Authors: Berube, B.; Ernst, E.; Cahn, J.; Roche, B.; de Santis Alves, C.; Lynn, J.; Scheben, A.; Siepel, A.; Ross-Ibarra, J.; Kermicle, J.; Martienssen, R. A.
Score: 18.7, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.548689
Meiotic drivers subvert Mendelian expectations by manipulating reproductive development to bias their own transmission. Chromosomal drive typically functions in asymmetric female meiosis, while gene drive is normally postmeiotic and typically found in males.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning-based classification of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease and its at-risk states using personality traits, anxiety, and depression
Authors: Waschkies, K.; Soch, J.; Darna, M.; Richter, A.; Altenstein, S.; Beyle, A.; Brosseron, F.; Buchholz, F.; Butryn, M.; Dobisch, L.; Ewers, M.; Fliessbach, K.; Gabelin, T.; Glanz, W.; Goerss, D.; Gref, D.; Janowitz, D.; Kilimann, I.; Lohse, A.; Munk, M. H.; Rauchmann, B.-S.; Rostamzadeh, A.; Roy, N.; Spruth, E. J.; Dechent, P.; Heneka, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Risk of COVID-19 death in adults who received booster COVID-19 vaccinations: national retrospective cohort study on 14.6 million people in England
Authors: Ward, I. L.; Robertson, C.; Agrawal, U.; Patterson, L.; Bradley, D. T.; Shi, T.; de Lusignan, S.; Hobbs, R.; Sheikh, A.; Nafilyan, V.
Score: 20.0, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23291596
ImportanceThe emergence of the COVID-19 vaccination has been critical in changing the course of the COVID-19 pandemic, with estimates suggesting vaccinations have prevented millions of deaths worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Magnetic susceptibility is predictive of future clinical severity in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Thomas, G. E. C.; Hannaway, N.; Zarkali, A.; Shmueli, K.; Weil, R.
Score: 14.0, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292555
Dementia is common in Parkinsons disease, but there is wide variation in its timing. With the emergence of disease modifying treatments in neurodegeneration, there is increasing need to detect and treat disease at the earliest stages and to monitor disease progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Development and Assessment of a Sustainable PhD Internship Program Supporting Diverse Biomedical Career Outcomes
Authors: Brandt, P. D.; Whittington, D.; Wood, K. D.; Holmquist, C. E.; Nogueira, A. T.; Gaines, C. H.; Brennwald, P. J.; Layton, R. L.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548912
A doctoral-level internship program was developed at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill with the intent to create customizable experiential learning opportunities for biomedical trainees to support career exploration, preparation, and transition into their post-graduate professional roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Late reproduction is associated with extended female survival but not with familial longevity
Authors: Kat, A. d.; Roelofs, F.; Slagboom, E.; Broekmans, F.; Beekman, M.; Berg, N. v. d.
Score: 17.2, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.26.23291896
ObjectiveFemale reproductive health comprises adequate oocyte quality and quantity, normal fecundability, a normal course of pregnancy, and the delivery of healthy offspring. General aging patterns and the maintenance of somatic health have been associated with female reproductive health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alterations of the gut microbiome are associated with epigenetic age acceleration and physical fitness
Authors: Torma, F.; Kerepesi, C.; Jokai, M.; Bakonyi, P.; Koltai, E.; Babszki, G.; Ligeti, B.; Kalcsevszki, R.; McGreevy, K. M.; Horvath, S.; Radak, Z.
Score: 23.7, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292191
Epigenetic clocks can measure aging and predict the incidence of diseases and mortality. Higher levels of physical fitness are associated with a slower aging process and a healthier lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Emergent digital bio-computation through spatial diffusion and engineered bacteria
Authors: Fedorec, A. J. H.; Treloar, N. J.; Wen, K. Y.; Dekker, L.; Ong, Q. H.; Jurkeviciute, G.; Lyu, E.; Rutter, J.; Rosa, L.; Zaikin, A.; Barnes, C. P.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548081
Building computationally capable biological systems has long been an aim of synthetic biology. The potential utility of biocomputing devices ranges from biosafety and environmental applications to diagnosis and personalised medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systems Age: A single blood methylation test to quantify aging heterogeneity across 11 physiological systems
Authors: Sehgal, R.; Meer, M.; Shadyab, A. H.; Casanova, R.; Manson, J. E.; Bhatti, P.; Crimmins, E. M.; Assimes, T. L.; Whitsel, E. A.; Higgins-Chen, A. T.; Levine, M.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.548904
Individuals, organs, tissues, and cells age in diverse ways throughout the lifespan. Epigenetic clocks attempt to quantify differential aging between individuals, but they typically summarize aging as a single measure, ignoring within-person heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 10:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Swimmers itch control: timely waterfowl brood relocation significantly reduces an avian schistosome population and human cases on recreational lakes
Authors: DeJong, R. J.; Blankespoor, C.; Blankespoor, H.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-07-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.548414
Swimmers itch (SI) is a dermatitis in humans caused by cercariae of avian and mammalian schistosomes which emerge from infected snails on a daily basis. Mitigation methods for SI have long been sought with little success. Copper sulfate application to the water to kill the snail hosts is the historically employed method, but is localized, temporary, and harmful to many aquatic species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
