<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Physically stressed bees expect less reward in an active choice judgement bias test
Authors: Procenko, O.; Read, J.; Nityananda, V.
Score: 16.9, Published: 2023-10-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561175
Emotion-like states in animals are commonly assessed using judgment bias tests, which measure responses to ambiguous information. A few studies have recently used these tests to argue for the presence of emotion-like states in insects. However, the results from most of these studies could have other explanations, including changes in motivation and attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Generalized Biomolecular Modeling and Design with RoseTTAFold All-Atom
Authors: Krishna, R.; Wang, J.; Ahern, W.; Sturmfels, P.; Venkatesh, P.; Kalvet, I.; Lee, G. R.; Morey-Burrows, F. S.; Anishchenko, I.; Humphreys, I. R.; McHugh, R.; Vafeados, D.; Li, X.; Sutherland, G. A.; Hitchcock, A.; Hunter, C. N.; Baek, M.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 287.9, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561603
Although AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RoseTTAFold (RF) have transformed structural biology by enabling high-accuracy protein structure modeling, they are unable to model covalent modifications or interactions with small molecules and other non-protein molecules that can play key roles in biological function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>A Drug-Free Pathogen Capture and Neutralizing Nasal Spray to Prevent Emerging Respiratory Infections
Authors: Joseph, J.; Baby, H. M.; Quintero, J. R.; Kenney, D.; Mebratu, Y.; Bhatia, E.; Shah, P.; Swain, K.; Kaur, S.; Li, X. L.; Mwangi, J.; Snapper, O.; Nair, R.; Agus, E.; Ranganathan, S.; Kage, J.; Gao, J.; Luo, J. N.; Yu, A.; Douam, F.; Tesfaigzi, Y.; Karp, J.; Joshi, N.
Score: 49.7, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>GPN-MSA: an alignment-based DNA language model for genome-wide variant effect prediction
Authors: Benegas, G.; Albors, C.; Aw, A. J.; Ye, C.; Song, Y. S.
Score: 52.4, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561776
Whereas protein language models have demonstrated remarkable efficacy in predicting the effects of missense variants, DNA counterparts have not yet achieved a similar competitive edge for genome-wide variant effect predictions, especially in complex genomes such as that of humans. To address this challenge, we here introduce GPN-MSA, a novel framework for DNA language models that leverages whole-genome sequence alignments across multiple species and takes only a few hours to train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>An ultrasensitive genetically encoded voltage indicator uncovers the electrical activity of non-excitable cells
Authors: Ruehl, P.; Nair, A. G.; Gawande, N.; Dehiwalage, S. N. C. W.; Muenster, L.; Schoenherr, R.; Heinemann, S. H.
Score: 19.4, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.05.560122
Genetically encoded voltage indicators (GEVIs) are powerful, non-invasive tools for recording action potentials in excitable cells. However, most animal cell types are non-excitable, and yet variations in the membrane potential are biologically relevant in these cells as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>ASCT2 is the primary serine transporter in cancer cells
Authors: Conger, K. O.; Chidley, C.; Ozgurses, M. E.; Zhao, H.; Kim, Y.; Semina, S. E.; Burns, P. A.; Rawat, V.; Sheldon, R.; Ben-Sahra, I.; Frasor, J.; Sorger, P. K.; DeNicola, G. M.; Coloff, J. L.
Score: 24.3, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561530
The non-essential amino acid serine is a critical nutrient for cancer cells due to its diverse biosynthetic functions. While some tumors can synthesize serine de novo, others are auxotrophic for serine and therefore reliant on the uptake of exogenous serine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Identification of EPHB4 variants in dilated cardiomyopathy patients
Authors: Luxan, G.; Muhly-Reinholz, M.; Glaser, S. F.; Trebing, J.; Reich, C.; Haas, J.; Sedaghat-Hamedani, F.; Meder, B.; Dimmeler, S.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2022.12.16.22283442
Cardiac homeostasis relies on the appropriate provision of nutrients to the working myocardium. EPHB4 is required for the maintenance of vascular integrity and correct fatty acid transport uptake in the heart via regulating the caveolar trafficking of the fatty acid receptor CD36.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Basal spot junctions of epithelial tissues respond to morphogenetic forces and regulate Hippo signalling
Authors: Kroeger, B.; Manning, S. A.; Fonseka, Y.; Oorschot, V.; Crawford, S. A.; Ramm, G.; Harvey, K. F.
Score: 27.9, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558144
Organ size is controlled by numerous factors including mechanical forces, which are mediated in part by the Hippo pathway. In growing Drosophila melanogaster epithelial tissues, cytoskeletal tension influences Hippo signalling by modulating the subcellular localisation of key pathway proteins in different apical domains, namely adherens junctions, the sub-apical region and the medial apical cortex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Spatial transcriptomics in adult Drosophila reveals new cell types in the brain and identifies subcellular mRNA patterns in muscles
Authors: Janssens, J.; Mangeol, P.; Hecker, N.; Partel, G.; Spanier, K.; Ismail, J. N.; Hulselmans, G. J.; Aerts, S.; Schnorrer, F.
Score: 66.4, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561233
Recently, we have achieved a significant milestone with the creation of the Fly Cell Atlas. This single-nuclei atlas encompasses the entire fly, covering the entire head and body, in addition to all major organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Diet and chemical defenses of the Sonoran Desert toads
Authors: Luccioni, M. D.; Wyman, J. T.; O&amp;#39;Connell, L. A.; Espinoza, E.
Score: 19.5, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561297
The Sonoran Desert Toad (Incilius alvarius) is the only animal known to secrete the psychedelic compound 5-MeO-DMT as a chemical defense, but the source of 5-MeO-DMT in I. alvarius remains unknown. Some amphibians endogenously produce chemical defenses while others acquire them from specialized diets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Inequalities in Accident and Emergency department attendance by socio-economic characteristics: population based study.
Authors: Gethings, O.; Machuel, P.; Nafilyan, V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296793
Objectives To examine the relationship between deprivation and Accident and Emergency department attendance. Design Retrospective cohort study. Setting England, United Kingdom, from 21 March 2021 to March 2022 Participants All individuals in the 2021 Census, aged 0 to 95 with an Emergency Department attendance record within the Emergency Care Dataset (ECDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>A set of circulating microRNAs belonging to the 14q32 chromosomic locus identifies two clinically and phenotypically different subgroups of individuals with recent onset Stage 3 type 1 diabetes
Authors: Sebastiani, G.; Grieco, G. E.; Bruttini, M.; Auddino, S.; Mori, A.; Toniolli, M.; Fignani, D.; Licata, G.; Nigi, L.; Formichi, C.; Pugliese, A.; Evans-Molina, C.; Overbergh, L.; Tree, T.; Peakman, M.; Mathieu, C.; Dotta, F.; INNODIA, Score: 6.4, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Self-report inaccuracy in the UK Biobank: Impact on inference and interplay with selective participation
Authors: Schoeler, T.; Pingault, J.-B.; Kutalik, Z.
Score: 23.2, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.23296652
While the use of short self-report measures is common practice in biobank initiatives, such phenotyping strategy is inherently prone to reporting errors. In this work, we aimed to explore challenges related to self-report errors for biobank-scale research. We derived a reporting error score (RESUM) for n=73,129 UK Biobank (UKBB) participants, capturing inconsistent self-reporting in time-invariant phenotypes across multiple measurement occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>The landscape of ancient human pathogens in Eurasia from the Stone Age to historical times
Authors: Sikora, M.; Canteri, E.; Fernandez-Guerra, A.; Oskolkov, N.; Agren, R.; Hansson, L.; Irving-Pease, E. K.; Muehlemann, B.; Holtsmark Nielsen, S.; Scorrano, G.; Allentoft, M. E.; Seersholm, F. V.; Schroeder, H.; Gaunitz, C.; Stenderup, J.; Vinner, L.; Jones, T. C.; Nystedt, B.; Parkhill, J.; Fugger, L.; Racimo, F.; Kristiansen, K.; Iversen, A. K. N.; Willerslev, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Microbiome-based risk prediction in incident heart failure: a community challenge
Authors: Erawijantari, P. P.; Kartal, E.; Linares-Blanco, J.; Laajala, T. D.; Feldman, L. E.; The FINRISK Microbiome DREAM Challenge and ML4Microbiome Communities, ; Carmona-Saez, P.; Shigdel, R.; Claesson, M. J.; Bertelsen, R. J.; Gomez-Cabrero, D.; Minot, S.; Albrecht, J.; Chung, V.; Inouye, M.; Jousilahti, P.; Schultz, J.-H.; Friederich, H.-C.; Knight, R.; Salomaa, V.; Niiranen, T.; Havulinna, A. S.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Applying Machine Learning on UK Biobank biomarker data empowers case-control discovery yield
Authors: Garg, M.; Karpinski, M.; Matelska, D.; Middleton, L.; Mitchell, J.; O&amp;#39;Neill, A.; Wang, Q.; Harper, A. R.; Dhindsa, R. S.; Petrovski, S.; Vitsios, D.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296832
Missing or inaccurate diagnoses in biobank datasets can reduce the power of human genetic association studies. We present a machine-learning framework (MILTON) that utilizes the wealth of phenotypic information available in a biobank dataset to identify undiagnosed individuals within the cohort who have biomarker profiles similar to those of positively diagnosed cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>A likelihood-based framework for demographic inference from genealogical trees
Authors: Fan, C.; Cahoon, J. L.; Dinh, B. L.; Ortega-Del Vecchyo, D.; Huber, C. D.; Edge, M. D.; Mancuso, N.; Chiang, C. W. K.
Score: 12.8, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.561787
The demographic history of a population drives the pattern of genetic variation and is encoded in the gene-genealogical trees of the sampled alleles. However, existing methods to infer demographic history from genetic data tend to use relatively low-dimensional summaries of the genealogy, such as allele frequency spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Deep indel mutagenesis reveals the impact of insertions and deletions on protein stability and function
Authors: Topolska, M.; Beltran, T.; Lehner, B.
Score: 32.8, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561180
Amino acid insertions and deletions (indels) are an abundant class of genetic variants. However, compared to substitutions, the effects of indels are not well understood and poorly predicted. Here we address this shortcoming by performing deep indel mutagenesis (DIM) of structurally diverse proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of the updated COVID-19 mRNA Autumn 2023 vaccines in Germany
Authors: Joshi, K.; Scholz, S.; Maschio, M.; Kohli, M.; Lee, A.; Fust, K.; Ultsch, B.; van de Velde, N.; Beck, E.
Score: 32.1, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296505
ObjectivesTo assess the potential clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mRNA vaccines updated for Autumn 2023 in adults aged [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years and high-risk persons aged 30-59 years in Germany over a 1-year analytic time horizon (September 2023--August 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Real World Performance of the 21st Century Cures Act Population Level Application Programming Interface
Authors: Jones, J. R.; Gottlieb, D. I.; McMurry, A. J.; Atreja, A.; Desai, P. M.; Dixon, B. E.; Payne, P. R.; Saldanha, A. J.; Shankar, P. R.; Solad, Y. V.; Wilcox, A. B.; Ali, M. S.; Kang, E.; Martin, A. M.; Sprouse, E. A.; Taylor, D.; Terry, M.; Ignatov, V.; SMART Cumulus Network, ; Mandl, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Value-Based Integrated Care: A Systematic Literature Review
Authors: van Hoorn, E. S.; Ye, L.; van Leeuwen, N.; Raat, H.; Lingsma, H. F.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296735
BackgroundHealthcare services worldwide are transforming themselves into value-based organizations. Integrated care is an important aspect of value-based healthcare (VBHC), but practical evidence-based recommendations for the successful implementation of integrated care within a VBHC context are lacking. This systematic review aims to identify how value-based integrated care (VBIC) is defined in literature, and to summarize the literature regarding the effects of VBIC, and the facilitators and barriers for its implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>The TB vaccine clinical trial centre directory: an inventory of clinical trial centres in sub-Saharan Africa
Authors: Pelzer, P. T.; Holleman, M.; Helinski, M. E.; Weinberg, A. L.; Beattie, P.; Nyirenda, T.; van Rest, J.; Voss, G.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296539
BackgroundThere are over ten vaccine candidates for tuberculosis (TB) in the clinical pipeline that require testing in TB-prevalent populations. To accelerate the clinical development of TB vaccines, a directory of clinical trial centres was established in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) to assess capacity for conducting late-stage TB vaccine trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Facilitators and barriers to community pharmacy PrEP delivery: A scoping review.
Authors: Harrison, c.; Family, H.; Kesten, J.; Denford, S.; Scott, A.; Dawson, S.; Scott, J.; Sabin, C. A.; Copping, J.; Harryman, L.; Cochrane, S.; Horwood, J.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.23296672
IntroductionPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is an effective medication to reduce the risk of acquiring HIV. PrEP is available free of charge in the United Kingdom from sexual health clinics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 antibodies cross-react and enhance dengue infection
Authors: Jakhar, K.; Sonar, S.; Singh, G.; Sarkar, T.; Tiwari, M.; Kaur, J.; Rathore, D. K.; Lal, B.; Kumar, S.; Srivastav, P.; Kumar, S.; Phagna, V.; Kumar, L.; Gupta, V.; Kshetrapal, P.; Singh, S.; Wadhwa, N.; Thiruvengadam, R.; Raghavan, S.; Gosain, M.; Shrivastava, T.; Bhattacharyya, S.; Bhattacharya, J.; Asthana, S.; Mani, S.
Score: 187.0, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.557914
Dengue disease is highly prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>The more symptoms the better? Covid-19 vaccine side effects and long-term neutralizing antibody response
Authors: Dutcher, E. G.; Epel, E. S.; Mason, A. E.; Hecht, F. M.; Robinson, J. E.; Drury, S. S.; Prather, A. A.
Score: 218.4, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296186
Protection against SARS-CoV-2 wanes over time, and booster uptake has been low, in part because of concern about side effects. We examined the relationships between local and systemic symptoms, biometric changes, and neutralizing antibodies (nAB) after mRNA vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Simulated Placements in Healthcare Education: A scoping review
Authors: Samson, J.; Gilbey, M.; Taylor, N.; Kneafsey, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.23296932
Abstract Introduction A virtual simulated placement (VSP) is a computer-generated version of a practice placement. COVID-19 drove increased adoption of virtual technology in clinical education. Accordingly, the number of VSP publications increased from 2020. This review aims to determine the scope of this literature to inform future research questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Integration of 168,000 samples reveals global patterns of the human gut microbiome
Authors: Abdill, R. J.; Graham, S. P.; Rubinetti, V.; Albert, F. W.; Greene, C. S.; Davis, S.; Blekhman, R.
Score: 79.6, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.560955
Understanding the factors that shape variation in the human microbiome is a major goal of research in biology. While other genomics fields have used large, pre-compiled compendia to extract systematic insights requiring otherwise impractical sample sizes, there has been no comparable resource for the 16S rRNA sequencing data commonly used to quantify microbiome composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Hibernating ribosomes tether to mitochondria as an adaptive response to cellular stress during glucose depletion
Authors: Gemin, O.; Gluc, M.; Purdy, M.; Rosa, H.; Niemann, M.; Peskova, Y.; Mattei, S.; Jomaa, A.
Score: 113.1, Published: 2023-10-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.08.561365
Cell survival under nutrient-deprived conditions relies on cells ability to adapt their organelles and to rewire their metabolic pathways. In the fission yeast Schizosaccharomyces pombe, nutrient depletion is an unfavorable condition for protein synthesis and triggers a response characterized by mitochondrial fragmentation and the sequestration of cytosolic ribosomes on mitochondria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the multidimensional geometric landscape of graded phenotypic variation and progression in neurodegenerative syndromes
Authors: Ramanan, S.; Akarca, D.; Henderson, S. K.; Rouse, M.; Allinson, K.; Patterson, K.; Rowe, J.; Lambon Ralph, M. A.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296861
Clinical variants of Alzheimers disease (AD) and frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) display a spectrum of cognitive-behavioural changes varying between individuals and over time. Understanding the landscape of these graded individual-/group-level longitudinal variations is critical for precise phenotyping; however, this remains challenging to model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A neural mechanism for learning from delayed postingestive feedback
Authors: Zimmerman, C. A.; Pan-Vazquez, A.; Wu, B.; Keppler, E. F.; Guthman, E. M.; Fetcho, R. N.; Bolkan, S. S.; McMannon, B.; Lee, J.; Hoag, A. T.; Lynch, L. A.; Janarthanan, S. N.; Lopez Luna, J. F.; Bondy, A. G.; Falkner, A. L.; Wang, S. S.-H.; Witten, I. B.
Score: 47.4, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561214
Animals learn the value of foods based on their postingestive effects and thereby develop aversions to foods that are toxic1-6 and preferences to those that are nutritious7-14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>The tumor multi-omic landscape of endometrial cancers developed on a germline genetic background of adiposity
Authors: Richenberg, G.; Francis, A.; Owen, C. N.; Gray, V.; Robinson, T.; Gabriel, A. A. G.; Lawrenson, K.; Crosbie, E. J.; Schildkraut, J. M.; Mckay, J. D.; Gaunt, T. R.; Relton, C. L.; Vincent, E. E.; Kar, S. P.
Score: 6.7, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296765
High body mass index (BMI) is a causal risk factor for endometrial cancer but the tumor molecular mechanisms affected by adiposity and their therapeutic relevance remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Individuals with knee osteoarthritis show few limitations in reactive stepping responses after gait perturbations
Authors: Boekesteijn, R. J.; Keijsers, N. L. W.; Defoort, K.; Geurts, A. C. H.; Smulders, K.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296525
BackgroundKnee osteoarthritis (OA) causes structural joint damage. The resultant symptoms can impair the ability to recover from unexpected gait perturbations, contributing to an increased fall risk. This study compared reactive stepping responses to gait perturbations between individuals with knee OA and healthy individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of hind limb morphology of Titanosauriformes (Dinosauria, Sauropoda) via 3D Geometric Morphometrics reveals wide-gauge posture as an exaptation for gigantism
Authors: Paramo Blazquez, A.; Mocho, P.; Escaso, F.; Ortega, F.
Score: 14.1, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.560839
AbstractThe sauropod hind limb is the main support that allowed their gigantic body masses and a wide range of dynamic stability adaptations. It is closely related with the position of the centre of masses of their multi-toned barrel-shaped bodies, and experiences one of the most noticeable posture changes along macronarian evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>OxPhos in adipose tissue macrophages regulated by BTK enhances their M2-like phenotype and confers a systemic immunometabolic benefit in obesity
Authors: Purvis, G.; Collino, M.; Van Dam, A.; Einaudi, G.; Ng, Y.; Shanmuganathan, M.; Patel, S.; Thiemermann, C.; Channon, K.; Greaves, D.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-10-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561199
Bruton&amp;#39;s tyrosine kinase (BTK) is a non-receptor bound kinase involved in pro-inflammatory signalling in activated macrophages, however, its role within adipose tissue macrophages remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Exploration of the Tunability of BRD4 Degradation by DCAF16 Trans-labelling Covalent Glues
Authors: Hassan, M. M.; Li, Y.-D.; Ma, M. W.; Teng, M.; Byun, W. S.; Puvar, K.; Lumpkin, R.; Sandoval, B.; Rutter, J. C.; Jin, C. Y.; Wang, M. Y.; Xu, S.; Schmoker, A. M.; Cheong, H.; Groendyke, B. J.; Qi, J.; Fischer, E. S.; Ebert, B. L.; Gray, N.
Score: 6.1, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.07.561308
Small molecules that can induce protein degradation by inducing proximity between a desired target and an E3 ligase have the potential to greatly expand the number of proteins that can be manipulated pharmacologically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>The impact of short-lived controls on the interpretation of lifespan experiments and progress in geroscience
Authors: Pabis, K. K.; Barardo, D.; Gruber, J.; Sirbu, O.; Selvarajoo, K.; Kaeberlein, M.; Kennedy, B. K.
Score: 19.1, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.08.561459
Although lifespan extension remains the gold standard for assessing interventions hypothesized to impact the biology of aging, there are important limitations to this approach. Our reanalysis of lifespan studies from multiple sources suggests that the use of short-lived control cohorts tends to exaggerate the relative efficacy of putative longevity interventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of research topics and paradigms in plant sciences
Authors: Shiu, S.-H.; Lehti-Shiu, M. D.
Score: 76.8, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.560457
Scientific advances due to conceptual or technological innovations can be revealed by examining how research topics have evolved. But such topical evolution is difficult to uncover and quantify because of the large body of literature and the needs of expert knowledge from a wide range of areas in any field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Brain-targeted autoimmunity is strongly associated with Long COVID and its chronic fatigue syndrome as well as its affective symptoms.
Authors: Almulla, A. F.; Maes, M.; Zhou, B.; Al-Hakeim, H.; Vojdani, A.
Score: 204.9, Published: 2023-10-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.23296554
BackgroundAutoimmune responses contribute to the pathophysiology of Long COVID, affective symptoms and myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS). ObjectivesTo examine whether Long COVID, and its accompanying affective symptoms and CFS are associated with immunoglobulin (Ig)A/IgM/IgG directed at neuronal proteins including myelin basic protein (MBP), myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein (MOG), synapsin, &amp;#43;{beta}-tubulin, neurofilament protein (NFP), cerebellar protein-2 (CP2), and the blood-brain-barrier-brain-damage (BBD) proteins claudin-5 and S100B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Estimating changes in antibiotic consumption with the introduction of doxycycline post-exposure prophylaxis in the United States
Authors: Oliveira Roster, K. I.; Grad, Y.
Score: 21.9, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295787
Doxycycline as post-exposure prophylaxis (doxy-PEP) reduces the risk of gonorrhea, chlamydia, and syphilis in studies of men who have sex with men (MSM) and transgender women (TGW) on HIV Pre-exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP) and people living with HIV (PLWH)). Doxy-PEP is an important tool to address the increasing burden of sexually transmitted infections (STIs), but there is concern that increased consumption of doxycycline may drive antimicrobial resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Microstructure-Informed Myelin Mapping (MIMM) from Gradient Echo MRI using Stochastic Matching Pursuit
Authors: Sisman, M.; Nguyen, T. D.; Roberts, A. G.; Romano, D. J.; Dimov, A. V.; Kovanlikaya, I.; Spincemaille, P.; Wang, Y.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295993
Quantification of the myelin content of the white matter is important for studying demyelination in neurodegenerative diseases such as Multiple Sclerosis (MS), particularly for longitudinal monitoring. A novel noninvasive MRI method, called Microstructure-Informed Myelin Mapping (MIMM), is developed to quantify the myelin volume fraction (MVF) by utilizing a multi gradient echo sequence (mGRE) and a detailed biophysical model of tissue microstructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2, influenza A/B and respiratory syncytial virus positivity and association with influenza-like illness and self-reported symptoms, over the 2022/23 winter season in the UK: a longitudinal surveillance cohort
Authors: Dietz, E.; Pritchard, E. E.; Pouwels, K.; Ehsaan, M.; Blake, J.; Gaughan, C.; Haduli, E.; Boothe, H.; Vihta, K.-D.; Peto, T.; Stoesser, N.; Matthews, P.; Taylor, N.; Diamond, I.; Studley, R.; Rourke, E.; Birrell, P.; De Angelis, D.; Fowler, T.; Watson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Immunomodulators and risk for breakthrough infection after third COVID-19 mRNA vaccine among patients with rheumatoid arthritis: A cohort study
Authors: Schiff, A. E.; Wang, X.; Patel, N. J.; Kawano, Y.; Kowalski, E. N.; Cook, C. E.; Vanni, K. M. M.; Qian, G.; Bade, K. J.; Saavedra, A. A.; Srivatsan, S.; Williams, Z. K.; Venkat, R. K.; Wallace, Z. S.; Sparks, J. A.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.08.23296717
ObjectivesTo investigate COVID-19 breakthrough infection after third mRNA vaccine dose among patients with RA by immunomodulator drug class, and we hypothesized that CD20 inhibitors (CD20i) would have higher risk for breakthrough COVID-19 vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Keywords to success: a practical guide to maximise the visibility and impact of academic papers
Authors: Pottier, P.; Lagisz, M.; Burke, S.; Drobniak, S. M.; Downing, P. A.; Macartney, E. L.; Martinig, A. R.; Mizuno, A.; Morrison, K.; Pollo, P.; Ricolfi, L.; Tam, J.; Williams, C.; Yang, Y.; Nakagawa, S.
Score: 38.5, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.559861
In a growing digital landscape, enhancing the discoverability and resonance of scientific articles is essential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Experiences and impacts of side effects among contraceptive users in the UK: exploring individual narratives of contraceptive side effects
Authors: Stewart, C. L.; Stevens, R.; Kennedy, F.; Cecula, P.; Rueda Carrasco, E.; Hall, J.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.02.23296334
PurposeWhile many women worldwide use contraception, there is a paucity of research on individual experiences of side effects and their impacts. To address this gap, we analysed free-text responses of contraception experiences from 337 women aged 18 to 35, based in the UK who took part in an online survey on contraception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Modular RNA motifs for orthogonal phase separated compartments
Authors: Stewart, J. M.; Li, S.; Tang, A.; Klocke, M. A. K. A.; Gobry, M. V.; Fabrini, G.; Di Michele, L.; Rothemund, P. W. K.; Franco, E.
Score: 37.7, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.561123
Recent discoveries in biology have highlighted the importance of protein and RNA-based condensates as an alternative to classical membrane-bound organelles for the task of compartmentalizing molecules and biochemical reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>The fitness cost of spurious phosphorylation
Authors: Bradley, D.; Hogrebe, A.; Dandage, R.; Dube, A. K.; Leutert, M.; Dionne, U.; Chang, A.; Villen, J.; Landry, C. R.
Score: 17.0, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.08.561337
The fidelity of signal transduction requires the binding of regulatory molecules to their cognate targets. However, the crowded cell interior risks off-target interactions between proteins that are functionally unrelated. How such off-target interactions impact fitness is not generally known, but quantifying this is required to understand the constraints faced by cell systems as they evolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Diminishing growth of zoological natural history collections threatens future research in the life sciences and beyond
Authors: Card, D. C.
Score: 32.8, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.560208
Natural history museums comprise a unique and important component of biological infrastructure worldwide, and underlie diverse research, education, and outreach in the natural sciences. Each museum is built around one or more biological collections that serve as a repository of important materials for study, which have contributed to scientific research in increasingly important areas ranging from understanding global climate change to developing new biotechnological applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
