<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Naturalistic drug cue reactivity in heroin use disorder: orbitofrontal synchronization as a marker of craving and recovery
Authors: Kronberg, G.; Ceceli, A. O.; Huang, Y.; Gaudreault, P.-O.; King, S. G.; McClain, N.; Alia-Klein, N.; Goldstein, R. Z.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.23297937
Movies captivate groups of individuals (the audience), especially if they contain themes of common motivational interest to the group. In drug addiction, a key mechanism is maladaptive motivational salience attribution whereby drug cues outcompete other reinforcers within the same environment or context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Comprehending Atopic Risk Elements (CARE): An observational study to determine lifestyle, biophysical and environmental risk factors in the development of early-onset pediatric atopic dermatitis
Authors: Brandwein, M.; Gamrasni, K.; Landau, T.; Levin, A.; Smolkin, T.; Bauer-Rusek, S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.23297922
BackgroundAtopic dermatitis and food allergies affect a growing swath of the population and there is consensus that their development is determined by a confluence of inherent and environmental factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Behavioural changes in aposematic Heliconius melpomene butterflies in response to their predatory bird calls
Authors: Potdar, S.; Dinakar, M.; Westerman, E. L.
Score: 10.1, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563859
Prey-predator interactions have resulted in the evolution of many anti-predatory traits. One of them is the ability for prey to listen to predators and avoid them. Although prey anti-predatory behavioural responses to predator auditory cues are well described in a wide range of taxa, studies on whether butterflies change their behaviours in response to their predatory calls are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>De novo design of allosterically switchable protein assemblies
Authors: Pillai, A.; Idris, A.; Philomin, A.; Weidle, C.; Skotheim, R.; Leung, P. J. Y.; Broerman, A.; Demakis, C.; Borst, A. J.; Praetorius, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 32.4, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.565167
Allosteric modulation of protein function, wherein the binding of an effector to a protein triggers conformational changes at distant functional sites, plays a central role in the control of metabolism and cell signaling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>EV-Elute: a universal platform for enrichment of functional surface marker-defined extracellular vesicle subpopulations
Authors: de Voogt, W. S.; Frunt, R.; Leandro, R. M.; Triesscheijn, C. S.; Monica, B.; Paspali, I.; Tielemans, M.; Francois, J. J.; Seinen, C. W.; de Jong, O. G.; Kooijmans, S. A.
Score: 11.3, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.563755
Intercellular communication via extracellular vesicles (EVs) has been identified as a vital component of a steadily expanding number of physiological and pathological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Identifying cell states in single-cell RNA-seq data at statistically maximal resolution
Authors: Grobecker, P.; van Nimwegen, E.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.564980
Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) has become a popular experimental method to study variation of gene expression within a population of cells. However, obtaining an accurate picture of the diversity of distinct gene expression states that are present in a given dataset is highly challenging because the sparsity of the scRNA-seq data and its inhomogeneous measurement noise properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>The genetic architecture of protein stability
Authors: Faure, A. J.; Marti-Aranda, A.; Hidalgo, C.; Schmiedel, J. M.; Lehner, B.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.564339
There are more ways to synthesize a 100 amino acid protein (20100) than atoms in the universe. Only a miniscule fraction of such a vast sequence space can ever be experimentally or computationally surveyed. Deep neural networks are increasingly being used to navigate high-dimensional sequence spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Charting the transcriptomic landscape of primary and metastatic cancers in relation to their origin and target normal tissues
Authors: Sanghvi, N.; Calvo-Alcaniz, C.; Rajagopal, P.; Scalera, S.; Canu, V.; Sinha, S.; Schischlik, F.; Wang, K.; Madan, S.; Shulman, E.; Papanicolau-Sengos, A.; Blandino, G.; Ruppin, E.; Nair, N.
Score: 31.7, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.564810
Metastasis is a leading cause of cancer-related deaths, yet understanding how metastatic tumors adapt from their origin to target tissues is challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Cardiovascular risk prediction using metabolomic biomarkers and polygenic risk scores: A cohort study and modelling analyses
Authors: Ritchie, S. C.; Jiang, X.; Pennells, L.; Xu, Y.; Coffey, C.; Liu, Y.; Surendran, P.; Karthikeyan, S.; Lambert, S. A.; Danesh, J.; Butterworth, A. S.; Wood, A.; Kaptoge, S.; Di Angelantonio, E.; Inouye, M.
Score: 21.8, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297859
Metabolomic platforms using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy can now rapidly quantify many circulating metabolites which are potential biomarkers of cardiovascular disease (CVD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>CZ CELLxGENE Discover: A single-cell data platform for scalable exploration, analysis and modeling of aggregated data
Authors: CZI Single-Cell Biology, ; Abdulla, S.; Aevermann, B.; Assis, P.; Badajoz, S.; Bell, S. M.; Bezzi, E.; Cakir, B.; Chaffer, J.; Chambers, S.; Cherry, J. M.; Chi, T.; Chien, J.; Dorman, L.; Gloria, N.; Garcia-Nieto, P.; Hastie, M.; Hegeman, D.; Hilton, J.; Huang, T.; Infeld, A.; Istrate, A.-M.; Jelic, I.; Katsuya, K.; Kim, Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular basis for positional memory and its reprogrammability in limb regeneration
Authors: Otsuki, L.; Plattner, S. A.; Taniguchi-Sugiura, Y.; Tanaka, E. M.
Score: 69.1, Published: 2023-10-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.564423
Upon limb amputation in salamanders, anterior and posterior connective tissue cells form distinct signalling centres that together fuel successful regeneration. The molecular properties that distinguish anterior and posterior cells prior to injury, which enable them to initiate different signalling centres after amputation, are not known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Drab and distant birds are studied less than their fancy-feathered friends
Authors: Fischer, S. E.; Lindsay, A. M.; Otten, J. G.; Miles, D. B.; Streby, H. M.
Score: 98.3, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.560707
Human decisions are influenced by implicit biases, and scientists do not exist in an objectivity vacuum. Subconscious biases in scientists choices about which species to study may beget distorted knowledge bases and stagnant paradigms. Disparities in biological knowledge can result from bias in study species selection within a cycle of policymaking, funding, and publication, all subject to implicit biases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of Stroke Risk Following COVID-19 mRNA Bivalent Vaccines Among U.S. Adults Aged &amp;gt;=65 Years
Authors: Lu, Y.; Matuska, K.; Nadimpalli, G.; Ma, Y.; Duma, N.; Zhang, H.; Chiang, Y.; Lyu, H.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R. A.; Anderson, S. A.
Score: 1127.8, Published: 2023-10-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296624
In January 2023, the United States Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention noted a safety concern for ischemic stroke in adults [&amp;amp;ge;]65 years receiving the BNT162b2; WT/OMI BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Spoink, a LTR retrotransposon, invaded D. melanogaster populations in the 1990s
Authors: Pianezza, R.; Scarpa, A.; Narayanan, P.; Signor, S.; Kofler, R.
Score: 30.6, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.564725
During the last few centuries Drosophila melanogaster populations were invaded by several transposable elements, the most recent of which was thought to be the P-element between 1950 and 1980. Here we describe a novel TE, which we named Spoink, that has invaded D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Multiple indicators of gut dysbiosis predict all-cause and cause-specific mortality in solid organ transplant recipients
Authors: Swarte, C. J.; Zhang, S.; Nieuwenhuis, L. M.; Gacesa, R.; Knobbe, T. J.; TransplantLines Investigators, ; de Meijer, V. E.; Damman, K.; Verschuuren, E. A.; Gan, C. T.; Fu, J.; Zhernakova, A.; Harmsen, H. J.; Blokzijl, H.; Bakker, S. J.; Bjork, J. R.; Weersma, R. K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.28.23297709
ObjectiveGut microbiome composition is associated with multiple diseases, but relatively little is known about its relationship with long-term outcome measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>CXCL12 regulates coronary artery dominance in diverse populations and links development to disease
Authors: Rios Coronado, P. E.; Zanetti, D.; Zhou, J.; Naftaly, J. A.; Prabala, P.; Kho, P. F.; Martinez Jaimes, A. M.; Hilliard, A. T.; Pyarajan, S.; Dochtermann, D.; Chang, K.-M.; Winn, V. D.; Pasca, A. M.; Plomondon, M. E.; Waldo, S. W.; Tsao, P. S.; Clarke, S. L.; Red-Horse, K.; Assimes, T. L.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Clark (2023) and the Persistence of Hereditarian Fallacies
Authors: Benning, J. W.; Carlson, J.; Shaw, R.; Harpak, A. W.
Score: 88.2, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.565061
Clark (2023) considers the similarity in socioeconomic status between relatives, drawing on records spanning four centuries in England. The paper adapts a classic quantitative genetics model in order to argue the fit of the model to the data suggests that: (1) variation in socioeconomic status is largely determined by additive genetic variation; (2) contemporary English people &amp;#34;remain correlated in outcomes with their lineage relatives in exactly the same way as in preindustrial England&amp;#34;; and (3) social mobility has remained static over this time period due to strong assortative mating on a &amp;#34;social genotype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Systematic identification of cargo-carrying genetic elements reveals new dimensions of eukaryotic diversity
Authors: Gluck-Thaler, E.; Vogan, A. A.
Score: 34.8, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563810
Cargo-carrying mobile elements (CCEs) are genetic entities that transpose diverse protein coding sequences. Although common in bacteria, we know little about the biology of eukaryotic CCEs because no appropriate tools exist for their annotation. For example, Starships are fungal CCEs whose functions are largely unknown because they require time-intensive manual curation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Moving together: Effect of a 12-week online dance training intervention on static and dynamic postural stability and gait speed in older adults. A pre-post intervention study
Authors: Hansen, R. K.; Jochum, E.; Egholm, D.; Villumsen, M.; Hirata, R. P.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.23297899
BackgroundPhysical inactivity negatively affects gait performance and postural stability in older adults, which results in a higher risk of fall accidents. Previous research has shown that in-person dance training improves various aspects of balance and lower extremity function, however, the potential benefits of dance training delivered online on variables used for fall risk stratification in older adults have yet to be studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Development of meta-prompts for Large Language Models to screen titles and abstracts for diagnostic test accuracy reviews
Authors: KATAOKA, Y.; So, R.; Banno, M.; Kumasawa, J.; Someko, H.; Taito, S.; Terasawa, T.; Tsujimoto, Y.; Tsutsumi, Y.; Wada, Y.; Furukawa, T. A.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297818
Systematic reviews (SRs) are a critical component of evidence-based medicine, but the process of screening titles and abstracts is time-consuming. This study aimed to develop and externally validate a method using large language models to classify abstracts for diagnostic test accuracy (DTA) systematic reviews, thereby reducing the human workload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Who would be affected by a ban on disposable vapes? A population study in Great Britain
Authors: Jackson, S. E.; Tattan-Birch, H. O.; Shahab, L.; Oldham, M.; Kale, D.; Brose, L.; Brown, J.
Score: 29.7, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.23297396
ObjectivesThe UK government is consulting on banning disposable e-cigarettes. This study aimed to describe trends in disposable e-cigarette use among adults in Great Britain since 2021 and establish who would currently be affected by a ban on disposables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the landscape: A protocol for a jurisdictional scan of self-identified learning health systems
Authors: Vanderhout, S.; Bird, M.; Giannarakos, A.; Whitmore, C.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.23297605
BackgroundThere is a growing movement to implement learning health systems (LHS), in which real-time evidence, informatics, patient-provider partnerships and experiences, and organizational culture are aligned to support improvements in care. However, what constitutes a LHS varies based on context and capacity, hindering standardization, scale-up, and knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Facilitators and barriers to community pharmacy PrEP delivery: A scoping review.
Authors: Harrison, c.; Family, H.; Kesten, J.; Denford, S.; Scott, A.; Dawson, S.; Scott, J.; Sabin, C. A.; Copping, J.; Harryman, L.; Cochrane, S.; Horwood, J.
Score: 39.6, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.06.23296672
IntroductionPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is an effective medication to reduce the risk of acquiring HIV. PrEP is available free of charge in the United Kingdom from sexual health clinics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 antibodies cross-react and enhance dengue infection
Authors: Jakhar, K.; Sonar, S.; Singh, G.; Sarkar, T.; Tiwari, M.; Kaur, J.; Rathore, D. K.; Lal, B.; Kumar, S.; Srivastav, P.; Kumar, S.; Phagna, V.; Kumar, L.; Gupta, V.; Kshetrapal, P.; Singh, S.; Wadhwa, N.; Thiruvengadam, R.; Raghavan, S.; Gosain, M.; Shrivastava, T.; Bhattacharyya, S.; Bhattacharya, J.; Asthana, S.; Mani, S.
Score: 363.0, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.557914
Dengue disease is highly prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Swank, Z. N.; Goldberg, S. A.; Lu, S.; Dalhuisen, T.; Borberg, E.; Senussi, Y.; Luna, M. A.; Chang Song, C.; Clark, A.; Zamora, A.; Lew, M.; Viswanathan, B.; Huang, B.; Anglin, K.; Hoh, R.; Hsue, P. Y.; Durstenfeld, M. S.; Spinelli, M. A.; Glidden, D. V.; Henrich, T. J.; Kelly, J. D.; Deeks, S. G.; Walt, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 variant
Authors: Tamura, T.; Mizuma, K.; Nasser, H.; Deguchi, S.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Uriu, K.; Tolentino, J. E. M.; Tsujino, S.; Suzuki, R.; Kojima, I.; Nao, N.; Shimizu, R.; Jonathan, M.; Kosugi, Y.; Guo, Z.; Hinay, A. A.; Putri, O.; Kim, Y.; Tanaka, Y. L.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Saito, A.; Ito, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Structural basis for plasmid restriction by SMC JET nuclease
Authors: Roisne-Hamelin, F.; Liu, H. W.; Taschner, M.; Li, Y.; Gruber, S.
Score: 30.4, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.565488
DNA loop-extruding SMC complexes play crucial roles in chromosome folding and DNA immunity. Prokaryotic SMC Wadjet (JET) complexes limit the spread of circular plasmids through DNA cleavage; yet the mechanisms for target recognition are unresolved. We show that artificial DNA circularization renders linear DNA susceptible to JET cleavage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>An efficient design for whole genome trio sequencing identifies key variants in rare neurological disorder cases
Authors: Ramsey, K.; Kruglyak, S.; Naymik, M.; Lajoie, B. R.; Wiseman, K. N.; Sanchez-Castillo, M.; Billings, S.; Jepsen, W.; Huentelman, M.; Narayanan, V.
Score: 524.1, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23296768
We sequenced nine trios in which the probands in an underserved population were affected by a rare and undiagnosed disorder with neurological features. Sequencing was performed with one trio per flowcell on a benchtop sequencing instrument, leveraging the design of sequencing the proband at twice the coverage of the parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Integrating brainstem and cortical functional architectures
Authors: Hansen, J. Y.; Cauzzo, S.; Singh, K.; Garcia-Gomar, M. G.; Shine, J. M.; Bianciardi, M.; Misic, B.
Score: 67.0, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564245
The brainstem is a fundamental component of the central nervous system yet it is typically excluded from in vivo human brain mapping efforts, precluding a complete understanding of how the brainstem influences cortical function. Here we use high-resolution 7 Tesla fMRI to derive a functional connectome encompassing cortex as well as 58 brainstem nuclei spanning the midbrain, pons and medulla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>To assess the occupational hazards and factors contributing to the health effects among female market traders in Nakasero market, central Kampala
Authors: RONALD, W.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297787
Background: In Uganda, the informal sector, particularly public markets, presents a concerning array of unregulated workplace hazards, predominantly affecting female traders. These hazards pose significant threats to the health of female market traders, who make up the majority of the workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of Large Language Models in Answering Immuno-Oncology Questions: A Cross-Sectional Study
Authors: Iannantuono, G. M.; Bracken-Clarke, D.; Karzai, F.; Choo-Wosoba, H.; Gulley, J. L.; Floudas, C. S.
Score: 8.3, Published: 2023-10-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297825
BackgroundThe capability of large language models (LLMs) to understand and generate human-readable text has prompted the investigation of their potential as educational and management tools for cancer patients and healthcare providers. Materials and MethodsWe conducted a cross-sectional study aimed at evaluating the ability of ChatGPT-4, ChatGPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Regular Non-steroidal Anti-inflammatory Drug Use Increases Stress Fracture Risk in the General Population: A Retrospective Case-Control Study
Authors: Ciuciu, A.; Mulholland, C.; Bozzi, M. A.; Frymoyer, C. C.; Cavinatto, L.; Yaron, D.; Harwood, M. I.; Close, J. D.; Mehallo, C. J.; Tomlinson, R. E.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-10-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.23297788
Previous studies have shown that the use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) is associated with increased stress fracture risk, potentially due to diminished skeletal adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Recommendations For a Standardized Approach to Histopathologic Evaluation of Synovial Membrane in Murine Models of Experimental Osteoarthritis
Authors: Obeidat, A. M.; Kim, S. Y.; Burt, K. G.; Hu, B.; Li, J.; Ishihara, S.; Xiao, R.; Miller, R. E.; Little, C. B.; Malfait, A.-M.; Scanzello, C.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2023-10-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.14.562259
BackgroundSynovial pathology has been linked to osteoarthritis (OA) pain in patients. Microscopic grading systems for synovial changes in human OA have been described, but a standardized approach for murine models of OA is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Structure-Based Discovery of a NPFF1R Antagonist with Analgesic Activity
Authors: Bender, B. J.; Pickett, J. E.; Braz, J.; Kang, H. J.; Gahbauer, S.; Bhardwaj, K.; Rodriguez-Rosado, S.; Liu, Y.; Jain, M.; Basbaum, A.; Roth, B. L.; Shoichet, B. K.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.564029
While opioid drugs remain among the most effective analgesics for pain management, adverse effects limit their use. Molecules that synergize with opioids, increasing analgesia without increasing side effects, could prove beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Fecal microbial transfer and complex carbohydrates mediate protection against COPD
Authors: Budden, K. F.; Shukla, S.; Bowerman, K. L.; Gellatly, S. L.; Wood, D. L. A.; Lachner, N.; Idrees, S.; Patel, V.; Faiz, A. F.; Rehman, S. F.; Donovan, C.; Alemao, C.; Shen, S.; Vanka, K. S.; Mason, J.; Haw, T. J.; Fricker, M.; Keely, S.; Hansbro, N. G.; Belz, G.; Horvat, J. C.; Ashhurst, T. M.; van Vreden, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The Marchantia pangenome reveals ancient mechanisms of plant adaptation to the environment
Authors: Beaulieu, C.; Libourel, C.; Mbadinga Zamar, D.-L.; El Mahboubi, K.; Hoey, D. J.; Keller, J.; Girou, C.; San Clemente, H.; Diop, I.; Amblard, E.; Theron, A.; Cauet, S.; Rodde, N.; Sabine, Z.; Halpape, W.; Meierhenrich, A.; Laker, B.; Braeutigam, A.; Greiff, G. R. L.; The SLCU Outreach Consortium, ; Szovenyi, P.; Cheng, S.; Tanizawa, Y.; Leebens-Mack, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Clinical sarcopenia identification: Justification for increased sensitivity in SARC-F scores for probable sarcopenia
Authors: Propst, D.; Biscardi, L.; Dornemann, T.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297840
BackgroundThe European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People (EWGSOP2) recommends the use of the 5-item SARC-F questionnaire by clinicians to screen for probable sarcopenia. The recommended threshold of [&amp;amp;ge;]4 has low sensitivity and high specificity in identifying probable sarcopenia. While this high threshold is capable of excluding clients without probable sarcopenia, difficulty lies in using this screening tool to identify clients with low muscle strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Rumination Induction Task in fMRI: Test-Retest Reliability in Youth and Potential Mechanisms of Change with Intervention
Authors: Westlund Schreiner, M.; Miller, R. H.; Jacobsen, A. M.; Crowell, S. E.; Kaufman, E. A.; Farstead, B.; Feldman, D. A.; Thomas, L.; Bessette, K. L.; Welsh, R. C.; Watkins, E. R.; Langenecker, S. A.
Score: 37.2, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296759
BackgroundRumination is a transdiagnostic problem that is common in major depressive disorder (MDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Potential impact of annual vaccination with reformulated COVID-19 vaccines: lessons from the U.S. COVID-19 Scenario Modeling Hub
Authors: Jung, S.-m.; Loo, S. L.; Howerton, E.; Contamin, L.; Smith, C. P.; Carcelen, E. C.; Yan, K.; Bents, S. J.; Espino, J.; Levander, J.; Reich, N. G.; Lemaitre, J. C.; Sato, K.; McKee, C. D.; Hill, A. L.; Chinazzi, M.; Davis, J. T.; Mu, K.; Vespignani, A.; Rosenstrom, E. T.; Rodriguez-Cartes, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Dissecting unique and common variance across body and brain health indicators using age prediction
Authors: Beck, D.; de Lange, A.-M. G.; Gurholt, T. P.; Voldsbekk, I.; Subramaniapillai, S.; Schindler, L.; Hindley, G.; Leonardsen, E. H.; Rahman, Z.; van der Meer, D.; Korbmacher, M.; Linge, J.; Leinhard, O. D.; Kalleberg, K. T.; Engvig, A.; Sonderby, I.; Andreassen, O. A.; Westlye, L. T.
Score: 1.9, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.23298017
Ageing is a heterogeneous multisystem process involving different rates of decline in physiological integrity across biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>White matter hyperintensities modify relationships between corticospinal tract damage and motor outcomes after stroke
Authors: Ferris, J. K.; Lo, B. P.; Barisano, G.; Brodtmann, A.; Buetefisch, C. M.; Conforto, A. B.; Donnelly, M. R.; Egorova-Brumley, N.; Hayward, K. S.; Khlif, M. S.; Revill, K. P.; Zavaliangos-Petropulu, A.; Boyd, L. A.; Liew, S.-L.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.29.23297734
Motor outcomes after stroke relate to corticospinal tract (CST) damage. Concurrent damage from white matter hyperintensities (WMHs) might impact neurological capacity for recovery after CST injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Women&amp;#39;s representation in Indian academia and conferences
Authors: Muralidhar, S.; Ananthanarayanan, V.
Score: 60.5, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564078
Abstract/IntroductionIndian science academia has a dearth of women researchers at all levels. Not only are they under-represented, but they are also under-highlighted, under-mentored and overlooked for awards, grants and other career-advancing steps. To effectively address this problem and devise a solution for the inequity, we need data on the proportion of women faculty across multiple STEM institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Turn-On Protein Switches for Controlling Actin Binding in Cells
Authors: Effiong, U. M.; Khairandish, H.; Ramirez-Velez, I.; Wang, Y.; Belardi, B.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.561921
Within a shared cytoplasm, filamentous actin (F-actin) plays numerous and critical roles across the cell body. Cells rely on actin-binding proteins (ABPs) to organize F-actin and to integrate its polymeric characteristics into diverse cellular processes. Yet, the multitude of ABPs that engage with and shape F-actin make studying a single ABPs influence on cellular activities a significant challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Principles of Computation by Competitive Protein Dimerization Networks
Authors: Parres-Gold, J.; Levine, M.; Emert, B.; Stuart, A.; Elowitz, M.
Score: 47.9, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.564854
Many biological signaling pathways employ proteins that competitively dimerize in diverse combinations. These dimerization networks can perform biochemical computations, in which the concentrations of monomers (inputs) determine the concentrations of dimers (outputs). Despite their prevalence, little is known about the range of input-output computations that dimerization networks can perform (their &amp;#34;expressivity&amp;#34;) and how it depends on network size and connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Ticks without borders: Microbial communities of immature Neotropical tick species parasitizing migratory landbirds along northern Gulf of Mexico
Authors: Karim, S.; Zenzal, T. J.; Beati, L.; Sen, R.; Adegoke, A.; Kumar, D.; Downs, L.; Keko, M.; Nussbaum, A.; Becker, D.; Moore, F.
Score: 7.1, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.563347
The long-distance, seasonal migrations of birds make them an effective ecological bridge for the movement of ticks. The introduction of exotic tick species to new geographical regions can lead to the emergence of novel tick-borne pathogens or the re-emergence of previously eradicated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
