<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Repeated Hand Grip Strength is an Objective Marker for Disability and Severity of Key Symptoms in Post-COVID ME/CFS
Authors: Paffrath, A.; Kim, L.; Kedor, C.; Stein, E.; Rust, R.; Freitag, H.; Hoppmann, U.; Hanitsch, L. G.; Bellmann-Strobl, J.; Wittke, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Sotzny, F.
Score: 79.3, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301776
Post-COVID Syndrome (PCS) refers to a diverse array of symptoms that persist beyond 3 months of the acute phase of a SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Noxious stimulation induces self-protective behaviour in bumblebees
Authors: Gibbons, M.; Pasquini, E.; Kowalewska, A.; Read, E.; Gibson, S.; Crump, A.; Solvi, C.; Versace, E.; Chittka, L.
Score: 86.4, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575734
Self-grooming directed towards a noxiously-stimulated body part is one indicator that an animal may feel pain. In insects, the lack of evidence for such behaviour has been widely argued to reflect the absence of pain experiences. Here, we tested whether bumblebees (Bombus terrestris) selectively groom one of their antennae that was touched with a noxiously-heated (65 {square}C) probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Highly specific intracellular ubiquitination of a small molecule
Authors: Li, W.; Garcia-Rivera, E. M.; Mitchell, D. C.; Chick, J. M.; Maetani, M.; Knapp, J. M.; Matthews, G. M.; Shirasaki, R.; de Matos Simoes, R.; Viswanathan, V.; Pulice, J. L.; Rees, M. G.; Roth, J. A.; Gygi, S. P.; Mitsiades, C. S.; Kadoch, C.; Schreiber, S. L.; Ostrem, J. M. L.
Score: 68.5, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577493
Ubiquitin is a small, highly conserved protein that acts as a posttranslational modification in eukaryotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>An experimental census of retrons for DNA production and genome editing
Authors: Khan, A. G.; Rojas-Montero, M.; Gonzalez-Delgado, A.; Lopez, S. C.; Fang, R. F.; Shipman, S. L.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577267
Retrons are bacterial immune systems that use reverse transcribed DNA as a detector of phage infection. They are also increasingly deployed as a component of biotechnology. For genome editing, for instance, retrons are modified so that the reverse transcribed DNA (RT-DNA) encodes an editing donor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>edgeR 4.0: powerful differential analysis of sequencing data with expanded functionality and improved support for small counts and larger datasets
Authors: Chen, Y.; Chen, L.; Lun, A. T. L.; Baldoni, P. L.; Smyth, G. K.
Score: 79.5, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.576131
edgeR is an R/Bioconductor software package for differential analyses of sequencing data in the form of read counts for genes or genomic features. Over the past 15 years, edgeR has been a popular choice for statistical analysis of data from sequencing technologies such as RNA-seq or ChIP-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Sifting Through the Noise: A Computational Pipeline for Accurate Prioritization of Protein- Protein Binding Candidates in High-Throughput Protein Libraries
Authors: Mondal, A.; Singh, B.; Felkner, R. H.; De Falco, A.; Swapna, G.; Montelione, G. T.; Roth, M.; Perez, A.
Score: 13.3, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576374
Identifying the interactome for a protein of interest is challenging due to the large number of possible binders. High-throughput experimental approaches narrow down possible binding partners, but often include false positives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Therapeutic targeting of KRAS mutation-driven tumorigenesis by extracellular vesicles loaded with small interfering RNA
Authors: Zhai, Y.; Niu, S.; Qiu, T.; Yi, Y.; Yan, Y.; Hu, R.; He, X.; Xu, K.
Score: 51.5, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576015
RAS is a well-known oncogene contributing to significant proportion of cancer incidences, yet it remains as an undruggable target to majority of therapeutic modalities. Here, we explored the potential of extracellular vesicles (EVs) for therapeutic targeting of KRAS mutation-driven tumorigenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>THE IMPACT OF ROUTINE CARDIAC TROPONIN I-BASED CARDIOTOXICITY SCREENING ON CLINICAL OUTCOMES IN PATIENTS ON CANCER IMMUNOTHERAPY
Authors: Ivanovic, M.; Chan, A.; Cheng, E.; Xu, S.; Le, C.; Franquiz, M.; You, J.; Fazal, M.; Batchelder, R.; Reddy, S. A.; Katsumoto, T. R.; Ramchandran, K.; Colevas, A. D.; Khan, S.; Fan, A.; Cheng, P.; Wakelee, H.; Wu, S. M.; Witteles, R. M.; Neal, J. W.; Waliany, S.; Zhu, H.
Score: 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Optogenetic generation of leader cells reveals a force-velocity relation for collective cell migration
Authors: Rossetti, L.; Grosser, S.; Abenza, J. F.; Valon, L.; Roca-Cusachs, P.; Alert, R.; Trepat, X.
Score: 50.5, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576733
The front of migratory cellular clusters during development, wound healing and cancer invasion is typically populated with highly protrusive cells that are called leader cells. Leader cells are thought to physically pull and direct their cohort of followers, but how leaders and followers are mechanically organized to migrate collectively remains controversial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A new genetically tractable non-vertebrate system to study complete camera-type eye regeneration
Authors: Accorsi, A.; Pardo, B.; Ross, E.; Corbin, T. J.; McClain, M.; Weaver, K.; Delventhal, K.; Morrison, J. A.; McKinney, M. C.; McKinney, S. A.; Sanchez Alvarado, A.
Score: 74.5, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577494
Camera-type eyes are complex sensory organs susceptible to irreversible damage. Their repair is difficult to study due to the paucity of camera-type eye regeneration models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Sonic restoration: Acoustic stimulation enhances soil fungal biomass and activity of plant growth-promoting fungi
Authors: Robinson, J. M.; Cando-Dumancela, C.; Breed, M. F.
Score: 57.2, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575298
Ecosystem restoration interventions often utilise visible elements to restore an ecosystem (e.g., replanting native plant communities and reintroducing lost species). However, using acoustic stimulation to restore ecosystems has received little attention. Our study aimed to (a) investigate the potential effects of acoustic stimulation on fungal biomass and organic matter decomposition, which are both crucial components of ecosystem functioning and (b) assess the effect of acoustic stimulation on the growth rate and sporulation of the plant growth-promoting fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>A Genetic Perspective on Diabetic Complications: A Mendelian Randomization Study on the Increased Risk of Cataracts in Type 1 Diabetes
Authors: Pei, D.; Wang, S.; Wang, Y.; Sun, C.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.24301964
Background: The well-documented epidemiological link between type 1 diabetes and cataract is recognized. Yet, the question of a shared genetic foundation for these conditions, and the potential implication of a causal connection, is still an area of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Deaths induced by compassionate use of hydroxychloroquine during the first COVID-19 wave: the devil is in the details.
Authors: Beaudart, C.; Douxfils, J.; Musuamba, F.; Dogne, J.-M.
Score: 165.0, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301464
Several trials of different designs were conducted to investigate the efficacy and safety of hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) for the prevention and/or the treatment of COVID-19 patients. Recently, it has been reported that HCQ might have been associated with an excess of 16,990 deaths during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic in 6 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Changes in the cellular makeup of motor patterning circuits drive courtship song evolution in Drosophila
Authors: Ye, D.; Walsh, J. T.; Junker, I. P.; Ding, Y.
Score: 18.3, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576861
How evolutionary changes in genes and neurons encode species variation in complex motor behaviors are largely unknown. Here, we develop genetic tools that permit a neural circuit comparison between the model species Drosophila melanogaster and the closely-related species D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Metagenomic analysis of colonic tissue and stool microbiome in patients with colorectal cancer in a South Asian population
Authors: Gamage, B.; Ranasinghe, D.; Sahankumari, P.; Malavige, G. N.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301775
ObjectiveThe gut microbiome is thought to play an important role in the development of colorectal cancer (CRC). However, as the gut microbiome varies widely based on diet, we sought to investigate the gut microbiome changes in patients with CRC in a South Asian population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>PWAS Hub: Exploring Gene-Based Associations of Common Complex Diseases
Authors: Kelman, G.; Zucker, R.; Brandes, N.; Linial, M.
Score: 11.4, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.23300645
PWAS (Proteome-Wide Association Study) is an innovative genetic association approach that complements widely-used methods like GWAS (Genome-Wide Association Study). The PWAS platform involves consecutive phases. Initially, machine learning modeling and probabilistic considerations quantified the impact of genetic variants on protein-coding genes biochemical functions. Secondly, aggregating the variants per gene for each individual determines a gene-damaging score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Patient derived model of UBA5-associated encephalopathy identifies defects in neurodevelopment and highlights potential therapies
Authors: Chen, H.; Wang, Y.-D.; Blan, A. W.; Almanza-Fuerte, E. P.; Bonkowski, E. S.; Bajpai, R.; Pruett-Miller, S. M.; Mefford, H. C.
Score: 12.6, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577254
UBA5 encodes for the E1 enzyme of the UFMylation cascade, which plays an essential role in ER homeostasis. The clinical phenotypes of UBA5-associated encephalopathy include developmental delays, epilepsy and intellectual disability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Randomizing the human genome by engineering recombination between repeat elements
Authors: Koeppel, J.; Ferreira, R.; Vanderstichele, T.; Riedmayr, L. M.; Peets, E. M.; Girling, G.; Weller, J.; Liberante, F. G.; Ellis, T.; Church, G. M.; Parts, L.
Score: 98.4, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.576745
While protein-coding genes are characterized increasingly well, 99% of the human genome is non-coding and poorly understood. This gap is due to a lack of tools for engineering variants that affect sequence to the necessary extent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Predicting Adverse Behavior in Individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder Through Off-body Sleep Analysis
Authors: Kiarashi, Y.; Suresha, P. B.; Bahrami Rad, A.; Reyna, M.; Anderson, C.; Foster, J.; Lantz, J.; Villavicencio, T.; Hamlin, T.; Clifford, G. D.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301681
Poor sleep quality in Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) individuals is linked to severe daytime behaviors. This study explores the relationship between a prior nights sleep structure and its predictive power for next-day behavior in ASD individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>In silico assessment of immune cross protection between BCoV and SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Beirao, B. C. B.; Querne, L. B.; Zettel Bastos, F.; Adur, M. d. A.; Cavalheiro, V. L.
Score: 162.8, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577193
BackgroundHumans have long shared infectious agents with cattle, and the bovine-derived human common cold OC-43 CoV is a not-so-distant example of cross-species viral spill over of coronaviruses. Human exposure to the Bovine Coronavirus (BCoV) is certainly common, as the virus is endemic in most high-density cattle-raising regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Altered IgG4 Antibody Response to Repeated mRNA versus Protein COVID Vaccines
Authors: Kalkeri, R.; Zhu, M.; Cloney-Clark, S.; Plested, J. S.; Parekh, A.; Gorinson, D.; Cai, R.; Mahato, S.; Ramanathan, P.; Aurelia, L. C.; John Selva, K.; Marchese, A. M.; Fries, L.; Chung, A. W.; Dunkle, L. M.
Score: 323.2, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301374
Repeated mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination has been associated with increases in the proportion of IgG4 in spike-specific antibody responses and concurrent reductions in Fc{gamma}-mediated effector functions that may limit control of viral infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive ML-based Respiratory Monitoring System for Physiological Monitoring &amp;amp; Resource Planning in the ICU
Authors: Hüser, M.; Lyu, X.; Faltys, M.; Pace, A.; Hoche, M.; Hyland, S. L.; Yeche, H.; Burger, M.; Merz, T. M.; Rätsch, G.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301516
Respiratory failure (RF) is a frequent occurrence in critically ill patients and is associated with significant morbidity and mortality as well as resource use. To improve the monitoring and management of RF in intensive care unit (ICU) patients, we used machine learning to develop a monitoring system covering the entire management cycle of RF, from early detection and monitoring, to assessment of readiness for extubation and prediction of extubation failure risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Viroid-like colonists of human microbiomes
Authors: Zheludev, I. N.; Edgar, R. C.; Galiano, M. J. L.; De la Pena, M.; Babaian, A.; Bhatt, A. S.; Fire, A. Z.
Score: 385.7, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576352
Here, we describe the &amp;#34;Obelisks,&amp;#34; a previously unrecognised class of viroid-like elements that we first identified in human gut metatranscriptomic data. &amp;#34;Obelisks&amp;#34; share several properties: (i) apparently circular RNA [~]1kb genome assemblies, (ii) predicted rod-like secondary structures encompassing the entire genome, and (iii) open reading frames coding for a novel protein superfamily, which we call the &amp;#34;Oblins&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>CryoCycle your grids: Plunge vitrifying and reusing clipped grids to advance cryoEM democratization
Authors: Serbynovskyi, V.; Wang, J.; Chua, E. Y. D.; Ishemgulova, A.; Alink, L. M.; Budell, W. C.; Johnston, J. D.; Dubbeldam, C.; Gonzalez, F. A.; Rozovsky, S.; Eng, E. T.; de Marco, A.; Noble, A. J.
Score: 43.1, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576763
CryoEM democratization is hampered by access to costly plunge-freezing supplies. We introduce methods called CryoCycle, for reliably blotting, vitrifying, and reusing clipped cryoEM grids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The effects of intermittent or continuous exercise on renal haemodynamics during moderate-intensity exercise
Authors: Kawakami, S.; Yasuno, T.; Kawakami, S.; Ito, A.; Fujimi, K.; Matsuda, T.; Nakashima, S.; Masutani, K.; Uehara, Y.; Higaki, Y.; Michishita, R.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301695
PurposeModerate-intensity exercise has beneficial effects for individuals with CKD. However, it is unclear whether intermittent exercise (IE) has a different effect on renal haemodynamics compared to continuous exercise (CE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating GPT-4 as a Clinical Decision Support Tool in Ischemic Stroke Management
Authors: Haim, A.; Katson, M.; Cohen-Shelly, M.; Peretz, S.; Aran, D.; Shelly, S.
Score: 54.8, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301409
Cerebrovascular diseases are the second most common cause of death worldwide and one of the major causes of disability burden. Advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) have the potential to revolutionize healthcare delivery, particularly in critical decision-making scenarios such as ischemic stroke management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Sensory Input, Sex, and Function Shape Hypothalamic Cell Type Development
Authors: Kaplan, H. S.; Logeman, B. L.; Zhang, K.; Santiago, C.; Sohail, N.; Naumenko, S.; Ho Sui, S. J.; Ginty, D. D.; Ren, B.; Dulac, C.
Score: 43.1, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576835
Mammalian behavior and physiology undergo dramatic changes in early life. Young animals rely on conspecifics to meet their homeostatic needs, until weaning and puberty initiate nutritional independence and sex-specific social interactions, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Non-invasive multi-cancer diagnosis using DNA hypomethylation of LINE-1 retrotransposons
Authors: Michel, M.; Heidary, M.; Mechri, A.; Da Silva, K.; Gorse, M.; von Grafenstein, K.; Hego, C.; Rampanou, A.; Lamy, C.; Kamal, M.; Le Tourneau, C.; Sene, M.; Bieche, I.; Reyes, C.; Gentien, D.; Stern, M.-H.; Lantz, O.; Cabel, L.; Pierga, J.-Y.; Bidard, F.-C.; Azencott, C.-A.; Proudhon, C.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.23288905
The detection of circulating tumor DNA, which allows non-invasive tumor molecular profiling and disease follow-up, promises optimal and individualized management of patients with cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Adequacy of Morphological Models used in Palaeobiology
Authors: Mulvey, L. P. A.; May, M. R.; Brown, J. M.; Hoehna, S.; Wright, A. M.; Warnock, R. C. M.
Score: 9.3, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577179
Reconstructing the evolutionary history of different groups of organisms provides insight into how life originated and diversified on Earth. Phylogenetic trees are commonly used to estimate this evolutionary history, providing a hypothesis of the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>The SUbventral-Gland master Regulator (SUGR) of nematode virulence
Authors: Pellegrin, C.; Damm, A.; Sperling, A. L.; Molloy, B.; Shin, D. S.; Long, J.; Brett, P.; Bravo, A. D.-T.; Lynch, S. J.; Senatori, B.; Vieira, P.; Mejias, J.; Kumar, A.; Masonbrink, R. E.; Maier, T. R.; Baum, T. J.; Eves-van den Akker, S.
Score: 36.2, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.576598
All pathogens must tailor their gene expression to their environment. Therefore, targeting host:parasite biology that regulates these changes in gene expression could open up routes to pathogen control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>A Non-targeted Proteomics Newborn Screening Platform for Genetic Disorders
Authors: Shibata, H.; Nakajima, D.; Konno, R.; Hijikata, A.; Higashiguchi, M.; Nihira, H.; Shimodera, S.; Miyamoto, T.; Nishitani-Isa, M.; Hiejima, E.; Izawa, K.; Takita, J.; Heike, T.; Okamura, K.; Ohnishi, H.; Ishimura, M.; Okada, S.; Yamashita, M.; Morio, T.; Kanegane, H.; Imai, K.; Nakamura, Y.; Nonoyama, S.; Uchiyama, T.; Onodera, M.; Nishikomori, R.; Ohara, O.; Kawashima, Y.; Yasumi, T.
Score: 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Pharmacogenomics Guided Spaceflight: the intersection between space-flown drugs and space genes
Authors: Nelson, T. M.; Rose, J. K.; Walter, C. E.; Cervantes-Navarro, G. L.; Schmidt, C. M.; Lin, R.; Alexander, E.; Zheng, J. T.; Glicksberg, B. S.; Schmidt, J. C.; Overbey, E.; Rana, B.; Patel, H.; Schmidt, M. A.; Mason, C. E.
Score: 11.0, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575951
Ten years ago, it was predicted that the multi-omics revolution would also revolutionize space pharmacogenomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin protects the heart against chronic intermittent hypoxia through AMPK-dependent phosphorylation of HIF-1α
Authors: Moulin, S.; Blachot-Minassian, B.; Kneppers, A.; Thomas, A.; Paradis, S.; Bultot, L.; Arnaud, C.; Pepin, J.-L.; Bertrand, L.; Mounier, R.; Belaidi, E.
Score: 15.8, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575152
Chronic intermittent hypoxia (IH), a major feature of obstructive sleep apnea syndrome (OSA), is associated with a more severe myocardial infarction. In this study, we performed RNA sequencing of cardiac samples from mice exposed to IH, which reveals a specific transcriptomic signature of the disease, relative to mitochondrial remodeling and cell death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 106.7, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Major depressive disorder, neuroticism, suicidal behaviors, and depression severity are all associated with neurotoxic immune networks and their intricate interactions with metabolic syndrome.
Authors: Maes, M.; Jirakran, K.; Vasupanrajit, A.; Zhou, B.; Tunvirachaisakul, C.; Almulla, A. F.
Score: 10.5, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24301553
BackgroundMajor depressive disorder (MDD) is considered to be a neuroimmune disorder. However, there are no data regarding the association between comprehensive immune profiles and their interactions with the metabolic syndrome (MetS) in predicting neuroticism, suicidal behaviors, and severity of outpatient MDD (OMDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Safety Monitoring of Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA Vaccines Among Recipients 6 months and Older in the United States
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Smith, E. R.; Gruber, J. F.; Ondari, M.; Wong, H. L.; Hu, M.; Clarke, T. C.; McEvoy, R.; Amend, K. L.; Bleacher, D. C.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Seeger, J. D.; Secora, A.; Djibo, D. A.; Song, J.; Selvam, N.; DeShazo, J. P.; Clifford, R.; Abente, E.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive Benchmarking of CNN-Based Tumor Segmentation Methods Using Multimodal MRI Data
Authors: Kundal, K.; Rao, K. V.; Majumdar, A.; Kumar, N.; Kumar, R.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.24301602
Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is become an essential and a frontline technique in the detection of brain tumor. However, manual segmentation of tumor from MRI scans is a time-consuming and labour-intensive process. There is a prevalent trend in employing fully automated methods for accurate tumor segmentation using MRI scans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>The Effect of Sensory Reweighting on Postural Control and Cortical Activity in Parkinsons Disease
Authors: Sadeghi, M.; Bristow, T.; Fakorede, S.; Liao, K.; Palmer, J. A.; Lyons, K.; Pahwa, R.; Huang, C.-K.; Akinwuntan, A.; Devos, H.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2024-01-30 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.24301687
Abstract Aims: Balance requires the cortical control of visual, somatosensory, and vestibular inputs. The aim of this cross-sectional study was to compare the contributions of each of these systems on postural control and cortical activity using a sensory reweighting approach between participants with Parkinsons disease (PD) and controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathogenic autoantibody internalization in myositis
Authors: Pinal-Fernandez, I.; Munoz-Braceras, S.; Casal-Dominguez, M.; Pak, K.; Torres-Ruiz, J.; Musai, J.; Dell&amp;#39;Orso, S.; Naz, F.; Islam, S.; Gutierrez-Cruz, G.; Dolores Cano, M.; Matas-Garcia, A.; Padrosa, J.; Tobias-Baraja, E.; Garrabou, G.; Aldecoa, I.; Espinosa, G.; Simeon-Aznar, C. P.; Guillen-Del-Castillo, A.; Gil-Vila, A.; Trallero-Araguas, E.; Christopher-Stine, L.; Lloyd, T. E.; Liewluck, T.; Naddaf, E.; Stenzel, W.; Greenberg, S. A.; Maria Grau, J.; Selva-O&amp;#39;Callaghan, A.; Milisenda, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Undergraduate Research in the Department of Biology at Western University: Effect on project types, learning outcomes, and student perceptions.
Authors: Chaplin, A.; Kohalmi, S. E.; Simon, A. F.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2024-01-28 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.577125
Undergraduate research is a high impact practice that offers numerous benefits to students, academic institutions, and the wider scientific community. Unfortunately, undergraduate research has faced restrictions due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>DIB-BOT: An open-source hardware approach for high throughput droplet interface bilayer deposition
Authors: Mason, A. F.; Wickham, S. F.; Baker, M. A.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577347
Droplet interface bilayers (DIBs) provide a controlled lipid environment for the single-molecule investigation of a range of biologically relevant membrane-bound processes and have garnered attention for their potential applications in bottom-up artificial cells, biosensing, and biophysics. However, the fabrication of DIBs is currently hindered by time-consuming processes and specialized equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic mapping of antibiotic cross-resistance and collateral sensitivity with chemical genetics
Authors: Sakenova, N.; Cacace, E.; Orakov, A.; Huber, F.; Varik, V.; Kritikos, G.; Michiels, J.; Bork, P.; Cossart, P.; Goemans, C.; Typas, A.
Score: 45.2, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.576750
By acquiring or evolving resistance to one antibiotic, bacteria can become resistant to a second one, due to shared underlying mechanisms. This is called cross-resistance (XR) and further limits therapeutic choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>MRI-Targeted Prostate Biopsy Introduces Grade Inflation and Overtreatment
Authors: Batouche, A. O.; Czeizler, E.; Lehto, T.-P.; Erickson, A.; Shadbahr, T.; Laajala, T. D.; Pohjonen, J.; Vickers, A. J.; Mirtti, T.; Rannikko, A. S.
Score: 8.4, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.24300922
PurposeThe use of MRI-targeted biopsies has led to lower detection of Gleason Grade Group 1 (GG1) prostate cancer and increased detection of GG2 disease. Although this finding is generally attributed to improved sensitivity and specificity of MRI for aggressive cancers, it might also be explained by grade inflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Wild bird mass mortalities in eastern Canada associated with the Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza A(H5N1) virus, 2022
Authors: Avery-Gomm, S.; Barychka, T.; English, M.; Ronconi, R.; Wilhelm, S. I.; Rail, J.-F.; Cormier, T.; Beaumont, M.; Bowser, C.; Burt, T. V.; Collins, S.; Duffy, S.; Giacinti, J. A.; Gilliland, S.; Giroux, J.-F.; Gjerdrum, C.; Guillemette, M.; Hargan, K. E.; Jones, M.; Kennedy, A.; Kusalik, L.; Lair, S.; Lang, A. S.; Lavoie, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
