<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Disproportionate increase in cannabis use among individuals with serious psychological distress and association with psychiatric hospitalization and outpatient service use in the National Survey on Drug Use and Health 2009-2019
Authors: Hyatt, A. S.; Flores, M.; Cook, B.
Score: 24.3, Published: 2023-12-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300036
AimsEstimate trends in levels of cannabis use among adults with and without serious psychological distress (SPD) in the United States from 2009-2019, and to ascertain whether cannabis use among individuals with SPD was associated with inpatient psychiatric hospitalization and outpatient mental health care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the autoreactome: Proteome-wide immunological fingerprints reveal the promise of plasma cell depleting therapy
Authors: Bodansky, A.; Yu, D. J.; Rallistan, A.; Kalaycioglu, M.; Boonyaratanakornkit, J.; Green, D. J.; Gauthier, J.; Turtle, C. J.; Zorn, K.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, B.; Mandel-Brehm, C.; Asaki, J.; Kortbawi, H.; Kung, A. F.; Rackaityte, E.; Wang, C.-Y.; Saxena, A.; de Dios, K.; Masi, G.; Nowak, R. J.; O&amp;#39;Connor, K. C.; Li, H.; Diaz, V. E.; Casaletto, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Whole group tracking reveals that relatedness drives consistent subgrouping patterns in white-nosed coatis
Authors: Grout, E. M.; Ortega, J.; Minasandra, P.; Quin, M. J.; Crofoot, M. C.; Strandburg-Peshkin, A.; Hirsch, B. T.
Score: 16.2, Published: 2023-12-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.14.571650
The formation of subgroups can allow group-living animals flexibility to balance the costs and benefits of sociality over time. Subgrouping dynamics emerge from individual decisions about whether and with whom to maintain cohesion, with these decisions potentially influenced by ecological, physiological, and social factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>De novo design of diverse small molecule binders and sensors using Shape Complementary Pseudocycles
Authors: An, L.; Said, M.; Tran, L.; Majumder, S.; Goreshnik, I.; Lee, G. R.; Juergens, D.; Dauparas, J.; Anishchenko, I.; Coventry, B.; Bera, A. K.; Kang, A.; Levine, P. M.; Alvarez, V.; Pillai, A.; Norn, C.; Feldman, D.; Zorine, D.; Hicks, D. R.; Li, X.; Sanchez, M. G.; Vafeados, D. K.; Salveson, P. J.; Vorobieva, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Human neuron subtype programming through combinatorial patterning with scRNA-seq readouts
Authors: Lin, H.-C.; Janssens, J.; Kroell, A.-S.; Hornauer, P.; Santel, M.; Okamoto, R.; Karava, K.; Priouret, M.; Garcia, M. P.; Schroeter, M.; Camp, J. G.; Treutlein, B.
Score: 46.7, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.12.571318
Human neurons programmed from induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) through transcription factor (TF) overexpression are widely used to study neuronal differentiation mechanisms and to model neurological diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>DeepPBS: Geometric deep learning for interpretable prediction of protein-DNA binding specificity
Authors: Mitra, R.; Li, J.; Sagendorf, J. M.; Jiang, Y.; Chiu, T.-P.; Rohs, R.
Score: 37.4, Published: 2023-12-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.571942
Predicting specificity in protein-DNA interactions is a challenging yet essential task for understanding gene regulation. Here, we present Deep Predictor of Binding Specificity (DeepPBS), a geometric deep-learning model designed to predict binding specificity across protein families based on protein-DNA structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>High-throughput computational discovery of inhibitory protein fragments with AlphaFold
Authors: Savinov, A.; Swanson, S.; Keating, A. E.; Li, G.-W.
Score: 74.7, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572389
Peptides can bind to specific sites on larger proteins and thereby function as inhibitors and regulatory elements. Peptide fragments of larger proteins are particularly attractive for achieving these functions due to their inherent potential to form native-like binding interactions. Recently developed experimental approaches allow for high-throughput measurement of protein fragment inhibitory activity in living cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>ROR2 regulates cellular plasticity in pancreatic neoplasia and adenocarcinoma
Authors: Benitz, S.; Steep, A.; Nasser, M.; Preall, J.; Mahajan, U. M.; McQuithey, H.; Loveless, I.; Davis, E. T.; Wen, H.-J.; Long, D. W.; Metzler, T.; Zwernik, S.; Louw, M.; Rempinski, D.; Salas-Escabillas, D.; Brender, S.; Song, L.; Huang, L.; Zhang, Z.; Steele, N.; Regel, I.; Bednar, F.; Crawford, H. C.
Score: 22.1, Published: 2023-12-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.571566
Cellular plasticity is a hallmark of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) starting from the conversion of normal cells to precancerous lesions to the progression of carcinoma subtypes associated with aggressiveness and therapeutic response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Integrative proteomic analyses across common cardiac diseases yield new mechanistic insights and enhanced prediction
Authors: Schuermans, A.; Pournamdari, A. B.; Lee, J.; Bhukar, R.; Ganesh, S.; Darosa, N.; Small, A. M.; Yu, Z.; Hornsby, W.; Koyama, S.; Januzzi, J. L.; Honigberg, M. C.; Natarajan, P.
Score: 25.9, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.23300218
Cardiac diseases represent common highly morbid conditions for which underlying molecular mechanisms remain incompletely understood. Here, we leveraged 1,459 protein measurements in 44,313 UK Biobank participants to characterize the circulating proteome associated with incident coronary artery disease, heart failure, atrial fibrillation, and aortic stenosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Global organelle profiling reveals subcellular localization and remodeling at proteome scale
Authors: Hein, M. Y.; Peng, D.; Todorova, V.; McCarthy, F.; Kim, K.; Liu, C.; Savy, L.; Januel, C.; Baltazar-Nunez, R.; Bax, S.; Vaid, S.; Vangipuram, M.; Ivanov, I. E.; Byrum, J. R.; Pradeep, S.; Gonzalez, C. G.; Aniseia, Y.; Wang, E.; Creery, J. S.; McMorrow, A. H.; Burgess, J.; Sunshine, S.; Yeung-Levy, S.; DeFelice, B. C.; Mehta, S. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Persistence of the primary somatosensory system in zebrafish
Authors: Navajas Acedo, J.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.19.572352
The somatosensory system detects peripheral stimuli that are translated into behaviors necessary for survival. Fishes and amphibians possess two somatosensory systems in the trunk: the primary somatosensory system, formed by the Rohon-Beard neurons, and the secondary somatosensory system, formed by the neural crest cell-derived neurons of the Dorsal Root Ganglia. Rohon-Beard neurons have been characterized as a transient population that mostly disappears during the first days of life and is functionally replaced by the Dorsal Root Ganglia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>DNA barcoding reveals an increased diversity within the genus Culex (Diptera: Culicidae) in Ireland
Authors: Curran, T. G.; O&amp;#39;Hanlon, A.; Gallagher, F.; Pedersen, R. S.; Zintl, A.; Isiye, E.; Olmeda, A. V.; O&amp;#39;Neill, D.; McDevitt, A.; O&amp;#39;Reilly, C.; O&amp;#39;Meara, D. B.
Score: 9.3, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572570
Arthropod populations are changing globally due to the combined impacts of climate change, land-use transformation, globalisation and trade. Changes in arthropod populations can potentially result in the decline and extinction of some native and/or endemic species, while other species that potentially pose threats may increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Endogenous glucagon-like peptide 1 diminishes prandial glucose counterregulatory response to hypoglycemia after gastric bypass surgery
Authors: Honka, H.; Gastaldelli, A.; Pezzica, S.; Peterson, R.; DeFronzo, R.; Salehi, M.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2023-12-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295840
We have previously shown that prandial endogenous glucose production (EGP) during insulin-induced hypoglycemia is smaller in non-diabetic subjects with gastric bypass (GB), where prandial glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1) concentrations are 5-10 times higher than those in non-operated controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Early COVID-19 vaccine effectiveness of XBB.1.5 vaccine against hospitalization and ICU admission, the Netherlands, 9 October - 5 December 2023
Authors: van Werkhoven, H.; Valk, A.-W.; Smagge, B.; de Melker, H. E.; Knol, M. J.; Hahne, S.; van den Hof, S.; de Gier, B.
Score: 871.5, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.12.23299855
We present early vaccine effectiveness (VE) estimates of the 2023 seasonal COVID-19 vaccination campaign using XBB.1.5 vaccine against COVID-19 hospitalization and ICU admission in previously vaccinated adults [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years old in the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Fast and accurate estimation of selection coefficients and allele histories from ancient and modern DNA
Authors: Vaughn, A.; Nielsen, R.
Score: 32.7, Published: 2023-12-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.16.572012
We here present CLUES2, a full-likelihood method to infer natural selection from sequence data that is an extension of the method CLUES. We make several substantial improvements to the CLUES method that greatly increases both its applicability and its speed. We add the ability to use ARGs on ancient data as emissions to the underlying HMM, which enables CLUES2 to use both temporal and linkage information to make estimates of selection coefficients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Imputation of structural variants using a multi-ancestry long-read sequencing panel enables identification of disease associations
Authors: Noyvert, B.; Erzurumluoglu, A. M.; Drichel, D.; Omland, S.; Andlauer, T. F. M.; Mueller, S.; Sennels, L.; Becker, C.; Kantorovich, A.; Bartholdy, B. A.; Braenne, I.; Bolivar-Lopez, J. C.; Mistrellides, C.; Belbin, G. M.; Li, J. H.; Pickrell, J. K.; de Jong, J.; Arora, J.; Hu, Y.; Boehringer Ingelheim - Global Computational Biology and Digital Sciences, ; Wood, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Rewriting regulatory DNA to dissect and reprogram gene expression
Authors: Martyn, G. E.; Montgomery, M. T.; Jones, H.; Guo, K.; Doughty, B. R.; Linder, J.; Chen, Z.; Cochran, K.; Lawrence, K. A.; Munson, G.; Pampari, A.; Fulco, C. P.; Kelley, D. R.; Lander, E. S.; Kundaje, A.; Engreitz, J. M.
Score: 44.7, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572268
Regulatory DNA sequences within enhancers and promoters bind transcription factors to encode cell type-specific patterns of gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Genomic analysis of Staphylococcus aureus isolates from bacteremia reveals genetic features associated with the COVID-19 pandemic
Authors: Sanchez-Osuna, M.; Pedrosa, M.; Bierge, P.; Gomez-Sanchez, I.; Alguacil-Guillen, M.; Espasa, M.; Erill, I.; Gasch, O.; Pich, O. Q.
Score: 151.1, Published: 2023-12-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572975
Genomic analyses of bacterial isolates are necessary to monitor the prevalence of antibiotic resistance genes and virulence determinants. Herein, we provide a comprehensive genomic description of a collection of 339 Staphylococcus aureus strains isolated from patients with bacteremia between 2014 and 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>P-tau217 and other blood biomarkers of dementia: variation with time of day
Authors: della Monica, C.; Revell, V. L.; Atzori, G.; Laban, R.; Skene, S. S.; Heslegrave, A.; Hassanin, H.; Nilforooshan, R.; Zetterberg, H.; Dijk, D.-J.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299805
Plasma biomarkers of dementia, including phosphorylated tau (p-tau217), offer promise as tools for diagnosis, stratification for clinical trials, monitoring disease progression, and assessing the success of interventions in those living with Alzheimers disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Cost-effectiveness of vector control strategies for supplementing mass drug administration for eliminating lymphatic filariasis in India
Authors: Shepard, D. S.; Lwin, A. K.; Pulikkottil, S. I.; Kalimuthu, M.; Arunachalam, N.; Tyagi, B. K.; White, G. B.
Score: 6.0, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.10.23299653
Background/MethodologyDespite progress using mass drug administration (MDA), lymphatic filariasis (LF) remains a major public health issue in India. Vector control (VC) is hypothesized as a potentially useful addition to MDA towards LF elimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory electronic health record analysis with ehrapy
Authors: Heumos, L.; Ehmele, P.; Treis, T.; Upmeier zu Belzen, J.; Namsaraeva, A.; Horlava, N.; Shitov, V. A.; Zhang, X.; Zappia, L.; Knoll, R.; Lang, N. J.; Hetzel, L.; Virshup, I.; Sikkema, L.; Roellin, E.; Curion, F.; Eils, R.; Schiller, H. B.; Hilgendorff, A.; Theis, F.
Score: 52.8, Published: 2023-12-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299816
With progressive digitalization of healthcare systems worldwide, large-scale collection of electronic health records (EHRs) has become commonplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Calling for diversity: improving transfusion safety through high-throughput blood group microarray genotyping
Authors: Wittig, M.; Steiert, T. A.; ElAbd, H.; Degenhardt, F.; Valenti, L.; Prati, D.; Ronzoni, L.; Bujanda, L.; Banales, J. M.; Blay, N.; Invernizzi, P.; Buti, M.; Albillos, A.; Fernandez, J.; Sacchi, N.; Julia, A.; Latiano, A.; de Cid, R.; D&amp;#39;Amato, M.; Asselta, R.; Laudes, M.; Lieb, W.; Juhl, D.; Gassner, C.; Franke, A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>The global burden of HIV among Long-distance truck drivers: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: MUTIE, C.; Otieno, B.; Mwangi, E.; Kawira, R.; Mutisya, A.; Gachohi, J.; Mbuthia, G.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23300177
Long-distance truck drivers (LDTDs) endure a disproportionately high burden of HIV in various global settings. However, unlike other most at-risk populations, the global burden of HIV among LDTDs has not been documented so far. The result has been poor allocation and distribution of the limited HIV preventive resources for LDTDs in most parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 1297.1, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 serosurvey across multiple waves of the COVID-19 pandemic in New York City between 2020-2023
Authors: Carreno Quiroz, J. M.; Wagner, A.; Monahan, B.; Floda, D.; Gonzalez-Reiche, A. S.; Tcheou, J.; Raskin, A.; Bielak, D.; Singh, G.; Morris, S.; Fried, M.; Yellin, T.; Sullivan, L.; Study Group, P.; Sordillo, E. M.; Gordon, A.; van Bakel, H.; Simon, V.; Krammer, F.
Score: 45.6, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23300131
Sero-monitoring provides context to the epidemiology of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infections and changes in population immunity following vaccine introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical students&amp;#39; perceptions towards artificial intelligence in education and practice: A multinational, multicenter cross-sectional study
Authors: Busch, F.; Hoffmann, L.; Truhn, D.; Ortiz-Prado, E.; Makowski, M. R.; Bressem, K. K.; Adams, L. C.; COMFORT Consortium, Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.23299744
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) is anticipated to fundamentally change the educational and professional landscape for the next generation of physicians, but its successful integration depends on the global perspectives of all stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 JN.1 variant
Authors: Kaku, Y.; Okumura, K.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Kosugi, Y.; Uriu, K.; Hinay, A. A.; Chen, L.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Kobiyama, K.; Ishii, K. J.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Zahradnik, J.; Ito, J.; Sato, K.
Score: 757.9, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570782
The SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 lineage, first identified in August 2023, is phylogenetically distinct from the currently circulating SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB lineages, including EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Structure and mechanism of Zorya anti-phage defense system
Authors: Hu, H.; Hughes, T. C. D.; Popp, P. F.; Roa-Eguiara, A.; Martin, F. J. O.; Rutbeek, N. R.; Hendriks, I. A.; Payne, L. J.; Yan, Y.; Sousa, V. K. d.; Wang, Y.; Nielsen, M. L.; Berry, R. M.; Erhardt, M.; Jackson, S. A.; Taylor, N. M. I.
Score: 67.0, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.572097
Zorya is a recently identified and widely distributed bacterial immune system, which protects against phage invasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Association Between Person-Centered Care Quality and Advance Care Planning Participation in Patients Undergoing Hemodialysis: A Multicenter Cross-Sectional Study
Authors: Kanakubo, Y.; Kurita, N.; Ukai, M.; Aita, T.; Inanaga, R.; Kawaji, A.; Toishi, T.; Matsunami, M.; Munakata, Y.; Suzuki, T.; Okada, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300045
Rationale &amp;amp; ObjectivePerson-centered care (PCC), which incorporates patients preferences and values not only for medical care but also for their life, in decision making has been proposed for promoting advance care planning (ACP) among patients with kidney failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence of orthostatic intolerance in Long Covid clinic patients - A multicentre observational study
Authors: Lee, C.; Greenwood, D.; Master, H.; Balasundaram, K.; Williams, P.; Scott, J.; Wood, C.; Cooper, R.; Darbyshire, J.; Espinosa Gonzalez, A.; Davies, H.; Osborne, T.; Corrado, J.; Iftekhar, N.; Rogers, N.; Delaney, B. C.; Greenhalgh, T.; Sivan, M.; LOCOMOTION Consortium, Score: 31.4, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.23299958
PurposeOrthostatic intolerance (OI), including postural orthostatic tachycardia syndrome (PoTS) and orthostatic hypotension (OH), are often reported in long covid, but published studies are small with inconsistent results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A subcortical switchboard for exploratory, exploitatory, and disengaged states
Authors: Ahmadlou, M.; Yasamin Shirazi, M.; Zhang, P.; Rogers, I. L. M.; Dziubek, J.; Hofer, S. B.
Score: 74.5, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572654
To survive in evolving environments with uncertain resources, animals need to dynamically adapt their behavior and exhibit flexibility in choosing appropriate behavioral strategies, for example, to exploit familiar choices, to explore and acquire novel information, or to disengage altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive Therapy Approach For Post- Stroke Patients: A Review Of Literature
Authors: manurung, s. s.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-12-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300013
IntroductionStroke is a highly consequential medical condition, characterized by a substantial risk of death and disability. Based on the data of the World Health Organization (WHO), stroke was contibuted for 6.2 million of mortalities, the second cause of death globally. In particular, half of stroke survivors encounter challenges in performing daily activities, and the psychosocial aspects of their experience often lead to a diminished quality of life, contributing to conditions like depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Consuming less ultra-processed food is associated with inadequate protein intake among vegan dieters
Authors: Leitao, A. E.; Esteves, G. P.; Mazzolani, B. C.; Smaira, F. I.; Santini, M. H.; Santo Andre, H. C.; Gualano, B.; Roschel, H.
Score: 10.9, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299823
ImportanceMajor concerns regarding vegan dieters are whether they meet protein and essential amino acids (EAA) recommendations, and how reliant they are on ultra-processed foods (UPF). ObjectivesTo investigate whether vegan dieters meet protein and EAA recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Placental transfer dynamics and durability of maternal COVID-19 vaccine-induced antibodies in infants
Authors: Lopez, P. A.; Nziza, N.; Chen, T.; Shook, L. A.; Burns, M.; Demidkin, S.; Jasset, O.; Akinwunmi, B.; Yonker, L. M.; Gray, K. J.; Elovitz, M. A.; Lauffenburger, D. A.; Julg, B. D.; Edlow, A. G.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.23299716
Completion of a COVID-19 vaccination series during pregnancy effectively reduces COVID-19 hospitalization among infants less than 6 months of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>HIPTox. Hazard Identification Platform to Assess the Health Impacts from Indoor and Outdoor Air Pollutant Exposures, through Mechanistic Toxicology: A single-centre double-blind human exposure trial protocol
Authors: Faherty, T.; Badri, H.; Hu, D.; Voliotis, A.; Pope, F. D.; Mudway, I.; Smith, J.; McFiggans, G.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-12-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.23299801
Over the past decade, our understanding of the impact of air pollution on short- and long-term population health has advanced considerably, focusing on adverse effects on cardiovascular and respiratory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A Video Intervention to Improve Patient Understanding of Tumor Genomic Testing in Patients with Cancer
Authors: Veney, D.; Wei, L.; Toland, A. E.; Presley, C. J.; Hampel, H.; Padamsee, T. J.; Lee, C. N.; Irvin, W. J.; Bishop, M.; Kim, J.; Hovick, S. R.; Senter, L.; Stover, D.
Score: 7.6, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299443
BackgroundTumor genomic testing (TGT) has become standard-of-care for most patients with advanced/metastatic cancer. Despite established guidelines, patient education prior to TGT is variable or frequently omitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Nanoscale Imaging and Microanalysis of Ice Age Bone Offers New Perspective on &amp;#39;Subfossils&amp;#39; and Fossilization
Authors: Anderson, L. A.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570041
The 3-D structure and organization of type-1 collagen protein and vasculature for a set of ancient permafrost bones is extensively documented at the nanoscale (up to 150,000x magnification) for the first time. The chemical mapping technique ToF-SIMS is additionally used to directly localize chemical signal to these structures; C:N and isotope measurements are also reported for the bulk organic bone matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Neuropathological assessment of the olfactory bulb and tract in individuals with COVID-19
Authors: Lengacher, N. A.; Tomlinson, J. J.; Jochum, A.-K.; Franz, J.; Hasan Ali, O.; Flatz, L.; Jochum, W.; Penninger, J.; aSCENT-PD Investigators, ; Stadelmann-Nessler, C.; Woulfe, J. M.; Schlossmacher, M. G.
Score: 24.2, Published: 2023-12-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.18.572180
The majority of patients with Parkinson disease (PD) experience a loss in their sense of smell and accumulate insoluble -synuclein aggregates in their olfactory bulbs (OB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety and efficacy of orally administered full-spectrum medicinal cannabis plant extract 0.08% THC (NTI-164) in children with autism spectrum disorder: An open-label study.
Authors: El-Sukkari, D.; Sharma, K. G.; Fleiss, B.; Bragazna, D.; Crichton, A.; Fahey, M.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299505
Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is commonly associated with debilitating comorbidities impacting the well-being of affected children and their families. Some children with ASD experience behavioural difficulties that do not respond well to current medications and may also experience unwanted side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Investigation of genomic and transcriptomic risk factors in clopidogrel response in African Americans.
Authors: Yang, G.; Alarcon, C.; Chanfreau-Coffinier, C.; Lee, N. H.; Friedman, P.; Nutescu, E.; Tuck, M.; O&amp;#39;Brien, T.; Gong, L.; Klein, T. E.; Chang, K.-M.; Tsao, P. S.; Meltzer, D. O.; Million Veteran Program, ; Tuteja, S.; Perera, M. A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299140
Clopidogrel, an anti-platelet drug, used to prevent thrombosis after percutaneous coronary intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>AlphaFold2 structures template ligand discovery
Authors: Lyu, J.; Kapolka, N.; Gumpper, R.; Alon, A.; Wang, L.; Jain, M.; Alvarez, X.; Sakamoto, K.; Kim, Y.; DiBerto, J.; Kim, K.; Tummino, T.; Huang, S.; Irwin, J.; Tarkhanova, O.; Moroz, Y.; Skiniotis, G.; Kruse, A.; Shoichet, B.; Roth, B.
Score: 51.5, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572662
AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RosettaFold have greatly expanded the number of structures available for structure-based ligand discovery, even though retrospective studies have cast doubt on their direct usefulness for that goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Human Heart Failure Alters Mitochondria and Fiber 3D Structure Triggering Metabolic Shifts
Authors: Vue, Z.; Ajayi, P. T.; Neikirk, K.; Murphy, A.; Prasad, P.; Jenkins, B. C.; Vang, L.; Garza-Lopez, E.; Mungai, M.; Marshall, A. G.; Beasley, H. K.; Killion, M.; Parker, R.; Anukodem, J.; Lavine, K.; Ajijola, O.; Mobley, B.; Dai, D.-F.; Exil, V.; Kirabo, A.; Ru Su, Y.; Tomasek, K.; Zhang, X.; Wanjalla, C. N.; Hubert, D. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Activation of plant immunity through conversion of a helper NLR homodimer into a resistosome
Authors: Selvaraj, M.; Toghani, A.; Pai, H.; Sugihara, Y.; Kourelis, J.; Yuen, E. L. H.; Ibrahim, T.; Zhao, H.; Xie, R.; Maqbool, A.; De la Concepcion, J. C.; Banfield, M. J.; Derevnina, L.; Petre, B.; Lawson, D. M.; Bozkurt, T. O.; Wu, C.-H.; Kamoun, S.; Contreras, M. P.
Score: 60.9, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.17.572070
Nucleotide-binding domain and leucine-rich repeat (NLR) proteins can engage in complex interactions to detect pathogens and execute a robust immune response via downstream helper NLRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID is associated with severe cognitive slowing
Authors: Zhao, S.; Martin, E. M.; Reuken, P. A.; Scholcz, A.; Ganse-Dumrath, A.; Srowig, A.; Utech, I.; Kozik, V.; Radscheidt, M.; Brodoehl, S.; Stallmach, A.; Schwab, M.; Fraser, E.; Finke, K.; Husain, M.
Score: 553.4, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.23299331
BackgroundCOVID-19 survivors may suffer from a wide range of chronic cognitive symptoms for months or years as part of post-COVID-19 conditions (PCC). To date, there is no definitive objective cognitive marker for PCC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence, risk factors and clinical presentations of post-COVID-19 condition: a follow-up study of reported COVID-19 infections in Montreal, Canada.
Authors: Allard, R.; Balegamire, S. J.; Malloum, K. B.; Cantalino, J.; Signor, C.; Leclerc, P.; Bergeron, G.; Mercure, S.-A.; Cadieux, G.
Score: 154.3, Published: 2023-12-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300022
BackgroundMeta-analyses suggest that post-COVID-19 condition (PCC) mostly takes three clinical presentations: fatigue, cognitive and respiratory. We sought to estimate the prevalence of these presentations and the strength of their associations with potential risk/protective factors, activity limitations and healthcare utilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Best Paper awards lack transparency, inclusivity, and support for Open Science
Authors: Lagisz, M.; Rutkowska, J.; Aich, U.; Ross, R. M.; Santana, M. S.; Wang, J.; Trubanova, N.; Page, M. J.; Pua, A. A. Y.; Yang, Y.; Amin, B.; Martinig, A. R.; Barnett, A.; Surendran, A.; Zhang, J.; Borg, D. N.; Elisee, J.; Wrightson, J. G.; Nakagawa, S.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.571170
Awards can propel academic careers. They also reflect the culture and values of the scientific community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Sculpting conducting nanopore size and shape through de novo protein design
Authors: Berhanu, S.; Majumder, S.; Muntener, T.; Whitehouse, J.; Berner, C.; Bera, A. K.; Kang, A.; Liang, B.; Khan, G. N.; Sankaran, B.; Tamm, L.; Brockwel, D. J.; Hiller, S.; Radford, S.; Baker, D.; Vorobieva, A. A.
Score: 26.1, Published: 2023-12-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572500
Transmembrane {beta}-barrels (TMBs) are widely used for single molecule DNA and RNA sequencing and have considerable potential for a broad range of sensing and sequencing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>A foundational atlas of autism protein interactions reveals molecular convergence
Authors: Wang, B.; Vartak, R.; Zaltsman, Y.; Naing, Z. Z. C.; Hennick, K. M.; Polacco, B. J.; Bashir, A.; Eckhardt, M.; Bouhaddou, M.; Xu, J.; Sun, N.; Lasser, M.; Zhou, Y.; Guiley, K. Z.; Chan, U.; Kaye, J. A.; Khare, P.; Drake, S.; Drury, V.; Burke, D. F.; Gonzalez, S.; Alkhairy, S.; Morris, M.; Baum, T.; Krasnoff, R.; Wang, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 10:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) - a new record of butterfly for Saudi Arabia
Authors: ALFAKIH, A.; AL FAIFY, E. A.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572884
The clouded mother-of-pearl Protogoniomorpha anacardii Linnaeus, 1758 (Lepidoptera: Nymphalidae) was recorded for the first time in Saudi Arabia. At this stage, we confirmed the presence of this species in the southernmost part of Saudi Arabia based on photographs taken in 2020-2023 from Fayfa and the adjacent mountains in Jazan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
