<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Animal Emotions and Consciousness: Researchers&amp;#39; Perceptions, Biases, and Prospects for Future Progress
Authors: Zipple, M. N.; Hazelwood, C.; Webster, M. F.; Benitez, M. E.
Score: 14.6, Published: 2023-10-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.562087
Do animals have emotions? Scientists and philosophers have long struggled with this question, with debates ranging from whether animals experience an &amp;#34;internal world&amp;#34; to whether we are capable of studying it. Recently, theoretical, and methodological advances have rekindled this debate, yet, it is unclear where the scientific consensus on these topics lies today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Generalized Biomolecular Modeling and Design with RoseTTAFold All-Atom
Authors: Krishna, R.; Wang, J.; Ahern, W.; Sturmfels, P.; Venkatesh, P.; Kalvet, I.; Lee, G. R.; Morey-Burrows, F. S.; Anishchenko, I.; Humphreys, I. R.; McHugh, R.; Vafeados, D.; Li, X.; Sutherland, G. A.; Hitchcock, A.; Hunter, C. N.; Baek, M.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 338.5, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561603
Although AlphaFold2 (AF2) and RoseTTAFold (RF) have transformed structural biology by enabling high-accuracy protein structure modeling, they are unable to model covalent modifications or interactions with small molecules and other non-protein molecules that can play key roles in biological function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Regionally-Activated Drugs for Neuroscience
Authors: Huang, Z.; Mitrofan, A.; Nouraein, S.; Horak, C.; Seo, J. P.; Harb, M.; Jin, R.; Szablowski, J. O.
Score: 31.3, Published: 2023-10-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.562069
The brain is comprised of multiple regions performing distinct functions. Within each of these regions, there are multiple cell types that can affect brain physiology. Finally, within each cell there are multiple signaling pathways, that, when activated or inhibited, control the cells activity, and consequently the brain function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the limits of zero-shot foundation models in single-cell biology
Authors: Kedzierska, K. Z.; Crawford, L.; Amini, A. P.; Lu, A. X.
Score: 79.6, Published: 2023-10-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.16.561085
The advent and success of foundation models such as GPT has sparked growing interest in their application to single-cell biology. Models like Geneformer and scGPT have emerged with the promise of serving as versatile tools for this specialized field. However, the efficacy of these models, particularly in zero-shot settings where models are not fine-tuned but used without any further training, remains an open question, especially as practical constraints require useful models to function in settings that preclude fine-tuning (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Multi-pass, single-molecule nanopore reading of long protein strands with single-amino acid sensitivity
Authors: Motone, K.; Kontogiorgos-Heintz, D.; Wee, J.; Kurihara, K.; Yang, S.; Roote, G.; Fang, Y.; Cardozo, N.; Nivala, J.
Score: 164.5, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563182
The ability to sequence single protein molecules in their native, full-length form would enable a more comprehensive understanding of proteomic diversity. Current technologies, however, are limited in achieving this goal. Here, we establish a method for long-range, single-molecule reading of intact protein strands on a commercial nanopore sensor array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Revealing Molecular Mechanisms of Early-Onset Tongue Cancer by Spatial Transcriptomics
Authors: Patysheva, M.; Kolegova, E.; Khozyainova, A.; Prostakishina, E.; Menyailo, M.; Larionova, I.; Kovalev, O.; Zavyalova, M.; Fedorova, I.; Kulbakin, D.; Polyakov, A.; Yakovleva, L.; Kropotov, M.; Sukortseva, N.; Arora, R.; Choinzonov, E.; Bose, P.; Denisov, E.
Score: 172.5, Published: 2023-10-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.562054
Tongue cancer at a young age demonstrates an increase in incidence, aggressiveness, and poor response to therapy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Integrating metabolomics and proteomics to identify novel drug targets for heart failure and atrial fibrillation
Authors: van Vugt, M.; Finan, C.; Chopade, S.; Providencia, R.; Bezzina, C. R.; Asselbergs, F. W.; van Setten, J.; Schmidt, A. F.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.23297247
BackgroundAltered metabolism plays a role in the pathophysiology of cardiac diseases, such as atrial fibrillation (AF) and heart failure (HF). We aimed to identify novel plasma metabolites and proteins associating with cardiac disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Recombinant biosensors for multiplex and super-resolution imaging of phosphoinositides
Authors: Maib, H.; Adarska, P.; Hunton, R.; Vines, J.; Strutt, D.; Bottanelli, F.; Murray, D. H.
Score: 50.7, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.18.562882
Phosphoinositides are a small family of phospholipids, acting as signalling hubs and key regulators of cellular function. Detecting their subcellular distribution is crucial to gain insights into membrane organisation and is most commonly done by over-expression of biosensors. However, this leads to perturbations of phosphoinositide signalling and is challenging in systems that cannot be transfected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Somatic mutations reveal hyperactive Notch signaling and racial disparities in prurigo nodularis
Authors: Rajeh, A.; Cornman, H. L.; Gupta, A.; Szeto, M. D.; Kambala, A.; Oladipo, O.; Parthasarathy, V.; Deng, J.; Wheelan, S.; Pritchard, T.; Kwatra, M. M.; Semenov, Y. R.; Gusev, A.; Yegnasubramanian, S.; Kwatra, S. G.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.23295810
Prurigo nodularis (PN) is a chronic inflammatory skin disease that disproportionately affects African Americans and is characterized by pruritic skin nodules of unknown etiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Transposable elements acquire time- and sex-specific transcriptional and epigenetic signatures along mouse fetal gonad development
Authors: Stevant, I.; Gonen, N.; Poulat, F.
Score: 12.6, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563600
Gonadal sex determination in mice is a complex and dynamic process, crucial for the development of functional reproductive organs. The expression of genes involved in this process is regulated by a variety of genetic and epigenetic mechanisms. Recently, there has been increasing evidence that transposable elements (TEs), which are a class of mobile genetic elements, play a significant role in regulating gene expression during embryogenesis and organ development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>The Moa the Merrier: Resolving When the Dinornithiformes Went Extinct
Authors: Foxon, F.
Score: 33.5, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552261
The Moa (Aves: Dinornithiformes) are an extinct group of the ratite clade from New Zealand. The overkill hypothesis asserts that the first New Zealand settlers hunted the Moa to extinction by circa 1450 CE, whereas the staggered survival hypothesis allows for Moa survival until after Europeans began to arrive on New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Did long COVID increase road deaths in the U.S.?
Authors: Robertson, L. S.
Score: 360.8, Published: 2023-10-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296868
ObjectiveTo examine data on COVID-19 disease associated with a 10 percent increase in U.S. road deaths from 2020 to 2021 that raises the question of the potential effect of pandemic stress and neurological damage from COVID-19 disease. MethodsPoisson regression was used to estimate the association of recent COVID-19 cases, accumulated cases, maximum temperatures, truck registrations, and gasoline prices with road deaths monthly among U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>The Selection Landscape and Genetic Legacy of Ancient Eurasians
Authors: Irving-Pease, E. K.; Refoyo-Martinez, A.; Barrie, W.; Ingason, A.; Pearson, A.; Fischer, A.; Sjögren, K.-G.; Halgren, A. S.; Macleod, R.; Demeter, F.; Henriksen, R. A.; Vimala, T.; McColl, H.; Vaughn, A.; Speidel, L.; Stern, A. J.; Scorrano, G.; Ramsoe, A.; Schork, A. J.; Rosengren, A.; Zhao, L.; Kristiansen, K.; Iversen, A. K. N.; Fugger, L.; Sudmant, P. H.; Lawson, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Microbiome-based risk prediction in incident heart failure: a community challenge
Authors: Erawijantari, P. P.; Kartal, E.; Linares-Blanco, J.; Laajala, T. D.; Feldman, L. E.; The FINRISK Microbiome DREAM Challenge and ML4Microbiome Communities, ; Carmona-Saez, P.; Shigdel, R.; Claesson, M. J.; Bertelsen, R. J.; Gomez-Cabrero, D.; Minot, S.; Albrecht, J.; Chung, V.; Inouye, M.; Jousilahti, P.; Schultz, J.-H.; Friederich, H.-C.; Knight, R.; Salomaa, V.; Niiranen, T.; Havulinna, A. S.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Large-scale evaluation of outcomes following a genetic diagnosis in children with severe developmental disorders
Authors: Copeland, H.; Low, K. J.; Wynn, S.; Ahmed, A.; Arthur, V.; Balasubramanian, M.; Bennett, K.; Berg, J.; Bertoli, M.; Bryson, L.; Bucknall, C.; Campbell, J.; Chandler, K.; Chauhan, J.; Clarkson, A.; Coles, R.; Conti, H.; Costello, P.; Coupar, T.; Craig, A.; Dean, J.; Dillon, A.; Dixit, A.; Drew, K.; Eason, J.; Forzano, F.; Foulds, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Integrator-mediated clustering of poised RNA polymerase II synchronizes histone transcription
Authors: Lu, F.; Park, B. J.; Fujiwara, R.; Wilusz, J. E.; Gilmour, D. S.; Lehmann, R.; Lionnet, T.
Score: 41.1, Published: 2023-10-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.07.561364
Dynamic clustering of transcription players, including RNA polymerase II (Pol II), is thought to rely on multivalent interactions of their intrinsically disordered regions, thereby enhancing active transcription. Using the histone locus bodies (HLBs) of Drosophila nurse cells as a model, we find that Pol II forms long-lived, transcriptionally poised clusters distinct from liquid droplets, which contain unbound and paused Pol II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>A novel approach to exploring the dark genome and its application to mapping of the vertebrate virus &amp;#39;fossil record&amp;#39;.
Authors: Blanco-Melo, D.; Campbell, M. A.; Zhu, H.; Dennis, T.; Mohda, S.; Lytras, S.; Hughes, J. J.; Gatseva, A.; Gifford, R. J.
Score: 30.3, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.17.562709
BackgroundGenomic regions that remain poorly understood, often referred to as the &amp;#34;dark genome,&amp;#34; contain a variety of functionally relevant and biologically informative genome features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of the updated COVID-19 mRNA Autumn 2023 vaccines in Germany
Authors: Joshi, K.; Scholz, S.; Maschio, M.; Kohli, M.; Lee, A.; Fust, K.; Ultsch, B.; van de Velde, N.; Beck, E.
Score: 38.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296505
ObjectivesTo assess the potential clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mRNA vaccines updated for Autumn 2023 in adults aged [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years and high-risk persons aged 30-59 years in Germany over a 1-year analytic time horizon (September 2023--August 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Improving epileptogenic zone estimation using Bayesian inference on neural field models
Authors: Vattikonda, A. N.; Woodman, M. M.; Lemarechal, J.-D.; Daini, D.; Hashemi, M.; Bartolomei, F.; Jirsa, V.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.01.23296377
Epilepsy remains a significant medical challenge, particularly in drug-resistant cases where surgical intervention may be the only viable treatment option. Identifying the epileptogenic zone, the brain region responsible for seizure initiation, is a critical step in surgical planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the factors affecting global political priority for controlling sexually transmitted infections: a qualitative policy analysis
Authors: Wu, D.; Low, N.; Hawkes, S. J.
Score: 8.5, Published: 2023-10-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.03.23296476
IntroductionSexually transmitted infections (STIs) are a significant public health challenge, but there is a perceived lack of political priority in addressing STIs as a global health issue. Our study aimed to understand the determinants of global political priority for STIs since the 1980s and to discern implications for future prioritisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>The influence of skin pigmentation on pulse oximetry readings: a protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Ahmed, S.; Afrin, S.; Hasan, S. M.; Sarker, S. S.; Azrin, F.; Jahan, E.; Rahman, A. E.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-10-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.18.23297133
BackgroundPulse oximeters are widely used crucial devices to triage and monitor sign of diseases and make informed decisions on patients health. Various studies have found a bias in pulse oximetry readings based on skin pigmentation/ ethnicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Effects of COVID-19 mRNA vaccination on HIV viremia and reservoir size
Authors: Duncan, M. C.; Omondi, F. H.; Kinloch, N. N.; Lapointe, H. R.; Speckmaier, S.; Moran Garcia, N.; Lawson, T.; DeMarco, M. L.; Simons, J.; Holmes, D. T.; Lowe, C. F.; Bacani, N.; Sereda, P.; Barrios, R.; Harris, M.; Romney, M. G.; Montaner, J. S. G.; Brumme, C. J.; Brockman, M. A.; Brumme, Z. L.
Score: 15.1, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 antibodies cross-react and enhance dengue infection
Authors: Jakhar, K.; Sonar, S.; Singh, G.; Sarkar, T.; Tiwari, M.; Kaur, J.; Rathore, D. K.; Lal, B.; Kumar, S.; Srivastav, P.; Kumar, S.; Phagna, V.; Kumar, L.; Gupta, V.; Kshetrapal, P.; Singh, S.; Wadhwa, N.; Thiruvengadam, R.; Raghavan, S.; Gosain, M.; Shrivastava, T.; Bhattacharyya, S.; Bhattacharya, J.; Asthana, S.; Mani, S.
Score: 242.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.557914
Dengue disease is highly prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Is Recovery Just the Beginning? Persistent Symptoms and Health and Performance Deterioration in Post-COVID-19, non-hospitalised University Students - A Cross-Sectional Study
Authors: Latifi, A.; Flegr, J.
Score: 105.0, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.23297203
Many individuals experience persistent symptoms such as deteriorated physical and mental health, increased fatigue, and reduced cognitive performance months after recovering from COVID-19. Current data are limited on the long-term trajectory of these symptoms and their prevalence in milder cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>MagSlice - Ultra Low-cost, modular and rapid 3D printed anatomical models for preoperative planning and patient education
Authors: Tucker, H.; Pickering, E.; Fysh, C.; Chen, M. Y.; Rukin, N.; Woodruff, M. A.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23295151
3D printed, patient-specific anatomical models have been demonstrated as effective tools for preoperative training, especially in complex surgeries involving rare cases or unique anatomy. Current, state-of-the-art solutions are expensive, requiring 3D printers with large capital and operating costs, making them impractical for common usage and less likely to be adopted in healthcare settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron EG.5.1 variant
Authors: Tsujino, S.; Deguchi, S.; Nomai, T.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Wang, L.; Begum, M. M.; Uriu, K.; Mizuma, K.; Nao, N.; Kojima, I.; Tsubo, T.; Li, J.; Matsumura, Y.; Nagao, M.; Oda, Y.; Tsuda, M.; Anraku, Y.; Kita, S.; Yajima, H.; Tabata, K.; Guo, Z.; Hinay, A. A.; Yoshimatsu, K.; Yamamoto, Y.; Nagamoto, Y.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>XIST dampens X chromosome activity in a SPEN-dependent manner during early human development
Authors: Alfeghaly, C.; Castel, G.; Cazottes, E.; Moscatelli, M.; Moinard, E.; Casanova, M.; Boni, J.; Mahadik, K.; Lammers, J.; Freour, T.; Chauviere, L.; Piqueras, C.; Boers, R.; Boers, J.; Gribnau, J.; David, L.; Ouimette, J.-F.; Rougeulle, C.
Score: 23.5, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563078
XIST long non-coding RNA is responsible for X chromosome inactivation (XCI) in placental mammals, yet it accumulates on both X chromosomes in human female pre-implantation embryos without triggering X chromosome silencing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>An efficient design for whole genome trio sequencing identifies key variants in rare neurological disorder cases
Authors: Ramsey, K.; Kruglyak, S.; Naymik, M.; Lajoie, B. R.; Wiseman, K. N.; Sanchez-Castillo, M.; Billings, S.; Jepsen, W.; Huentelman, M.; Narayanan, V.
Score: 514.2, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.13.23296768
We sequenced nine trios in which the probands in an underserved population were affected by a rare and undiagnosed disorder with neurological features. Sequencing was performed with one trio per flowcell on a benchtop sequencing instrument, leveraging the design of sequencing the proband at twice the coverage of the parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuroinflammation in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) as assessed by PBR28 PET correlates with vascular disease measures
Authors: VanElzakker, M. B.; Bues, H. F.; Brusaferri, L.; Kim, M.; Saadi, D.; Ratai, E.-M.; Dougherty, D. D.; Loggia, M. L.
Score: 1005.0, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563117
The COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has triggered a consequential public health crisis of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC), sometimes referred to as long COVID. The mechanisms of the heterogeneous persistent symptoms and signs that comprise PASC are under investigation, and several studies have pointed to the central nervous and vascular systems as being potential sites of dysfunction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Discordance between gut-derived appetite hormones and energy intake in humans
Authors: Hengist, A.; Sciarrillo, C. M.; Guo, J.; Walter, M.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 53.9, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.10.23289718
Gut-derived hormones affect appetite and are thought to play an important role in body weight regulation. Dietary macronutrient composition can influence gut-derived appetite hormone concentrations, thereby providing theoretical basis for why some diets might facilitate weight loss better than others. We investigated postprandial gut-derived appetite hormones in 20 inpatient adults after 2 weeks of eating either a low carbohydrate (LC) or a low fat (LF) diet followed by the alternate diet in random order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Disruption of maternal IgA by prenatal antibiotics precedes intestinal E. coli colonization and late-onset sepsis in neonates
Authors: McDonald, K.; Browning, D.; Greenfield, K.; Lin, K.; Meier, J.; Butoryak, M.; Sasaki, A.; Hand, T.; Megli, C.; Knoop, K.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.23295031
Neonates, most notably prematurely born neonates, are particularly vulnerable to enteric pathogens. It is recommended that all pregnant patients receive antibiotics following Preterm Premature Rupture of Membranes (PPROM) to prolong pregnancy, yet not all antibiotic regimens have been studied for efficacy, especially when considering neonatal outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Light exposure during sleep is associated with irregular sleep timing: the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis (MESA)
Authors: Wallace, D. A.; Qiu, X.; Schwartz, J.; Scheer, F. A.; Redline, S.; Sofer, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296889
ObjectiveExposure to light at night (LAN) may influence sleep timing and regularity. Here, we test whether greater light exposure during sleep (LEDS) associates with greater irregularity in sleep onset timing in a large cohort of older adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Variant-Specific Landscape of Mutual Exclusivity Among BRAF, EGFR, and KRAS Oncogenes in Human Cancer
Authors: Vaeyens, F.; Hetzel, J.-P.; Mernberger, M.; Eggermont, C.; Olsen, C.; Maes, K.; Vlaeminck, J.; Hes, F.; Pichler, M.; Giron, P.; Timofeev, O.; Noeparast, M.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-10-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.21.23297089
In this cross-sectional study, we report the findings of our investigation into the mutual exclusivity (ME) and co-occurrence (CO) patterns of BRAF, KRAS, and EGFR mutations in human cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of hind limb morphology of Titanosauriformes (Dinosauria, Sauropoda) via 3D Geometric Morphometrics reveals wide-gauge posture as an exaptation for gigantism
Authors: Paramo Blazquez, A.; Mocho, P.; Escaso, F.; Ortega, F.
Score: 15.5, Published: 2023-10-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.560839
AbstractThe sauropod hind limb is the main support that allowed their gigantic body masses and a wide range of dynamic stability adaptations. It is closely related with the position of the centre of masses of their multi-toned barrel-shaped bodies, and experiences one of the most noticeable posture changes along macronarian evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Protective Role of RIPK1 Scaffolding against HDV-Induced Hepatocyte cell death and the Significance of Cytokines in Mice
Authors: Camps, G.; Maestro, S.; Torella, L.; Usai, C.; Aldaz, A.; Olague, C.; Vales, A.; Montfort, A.; Segui, B.; Suarez, L.; Aldabe, R.; Gonzalez-Aseguinolaza, G.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-10-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.15.562448
Hepatitis delta virus (HDV) infection represents the most severe form of human viral hepatitis; however, the mechanisms underlying its pathology remain incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Discovery of Ancestry-Specific Variants Associated with Clopidogrel Response among Caribbean Hispanics.
Authors: Yang, G.; Gonzalez, P.; Monero, M.; Carrasquillo, K.; Renta, J. Y.; Hernandez-Suarez, D. F.; Botton, M. R.; Melin, K.; Scott, S.; Ruano, G.; Roche-Lima, A.; Alarcon, C.; Ritchie, M.; Perara, M.; Duconge, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.23296372
BackgroundHigh on-treatment platelet reactivity (HTPR) with clopidogrel is predictive of ischemic events in adults with coronary artery disease. Despite strong data suggesting HTPR varies with ethnicity, including clinical and genetic variables, no genome-wide association study (GWAS) of clopidogrel response has been performed among Caribbean Hispanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Pharmacological AMP-activated protein kinase activation suppresses low glucose-dependent macrophage migration inhibitory factor release from macrophages
Authors: Zhang, J.; Pollard, A. E.; Carling, D.; Benoit, V.; Ellacott, K. L.; Beall, C.
Score: 9.0, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.16.562445
Aims/hypothesisAcute hypoglycemia promotes pro-inflammatory cytokine production, increasing risk for cardiovascular events in diabetes. AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) is regulated by and influences production of pro-inflammatory cytokines. We tested the mechanistic role of AMPK in low glucose induced changes in the pro-inflammatory cytokine macrophage migration inhibitory factor (MIF), which is elevated in patients with diabetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Exceptional longevity of mammalian ovarian and oocyte macromolecules throughout the reproductive lifespan
Authors: Bomba-Warczak, E. K.; Velez, K. M.; Zhou, L. T.; Guillermier, C.; Edassery, S.; Steinhauser, M.; Savas, J. N.; Elizabeth Duncan, F.
Score: 10.1, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.18.562852
The mechanisms contributing to age-related deterioration of the female reproductive system are complex, but aberrant protein homeostasis is a major contributor. We elucidated the exceptionally stable proteins, structures, and macromolecules that persist in mammalian ovaries and gametes across the reproductive lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Zinc-finger (ZiF) fold secreted effectors form a functionally diverse family across lineages of the blast fungus Magnaporthe oryzae.
Authors: Concepcion, J. C. D. l.; Langner, T.; Fujisaki, K.; Were, V.; Yan, X.; Lam, A. H. C.; Saado, I.; Brabham, H.; Win, J.; Yoshida, K.; Talbot, N. J.; Terauchi, R.; Kamoun, S.; Banfield, M. J.
Score: 36.1, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.18.562914
Filamentous plant pathogens deliver effector proteins into host cells to suppress host defence responses and manipulate metabolic processes to support colonization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Sex differences in ADHD diagnosis and clinical care: A national study of population healthcare records in Wales
Authors: Martin, J.; Langley, K.; Cooper, M.; Rouquette, O. Y.; John, A.; Sayal, K.; Ford, T.; Thapar, A.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.23297324
Background: Population-based studies have observed sex biases in the diagnosis and treatment of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). Females are less likely to be diagnosed or prescribed ADHD medication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Reduced risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection among household contacts with recent vaccination and past COVID-19 infection: results from two multi-site case-ascertained household transmission studies
Authors: Rolfes, M. A.; Talbot, H. K.; Morrissey, K. G.; Stockwell, M. S.; Maldonado, Y.; McLean, H. Q.; Lutrick, K.; Bowman, N. M.; Rao, S.; Izurieta, H. S.; Zhu, Y.; Chappell, J.; Battan-Wraith, S.; Merrill, L. S.; McLaren, S. H.; Sano, E.; Biddle, J. E.; Johnson, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion Deep Learning for Brain Age Prediction and Longitudinal Tracking in Children Through Adulthood
Authors: Zapaishchykova, A.; Tak, D.; Ye, Z.; Liu, K. X.; Likitlersuang, J.; Vajapeyam, S.; Chopra, R. B.; Seidlitz, J.; Bethlehem, R. A.; Lifespan Brain Chart Consortium, ; Mak, R. H.; Mueller, S.; Haas-Kogan, D. A.; Poussaint, T. Y.; Aerts, H. J. W. L.; Kann, B. H.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.17.23297166
Deep learning (DL)-based prediction of biological age in the developing human from a brain magnetic resonance image (MRI) (brain age) may have important diagnostic and therapeutic applications as a non-invasive biomarker of brain health, aging, and neurocognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Reach, adoption, and implementation strategies of a telehealth falls prevention program: perspectives from francophone communities across Canada
Authors: O&amp;#39;Neil, J.; Dionne, N.; Marchand, S.; Cardinal, D.; Handrigan, G.; Savard, J.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23295569
IntroductionA fall may impact a persons physical, emotional, and psychological well-being. Fall prevention programs are being implemented to reduce these negative outcomes. However, linguistic barriers in health services may reduce access to such prevention programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2, influenza A/B and respiratory syncytial virus positivity and association with influenza-like illness and self-reported symptoms, over the 2022/23 winter season in the UK: a longitudinal surveillance cohort
Authors: Dietz, E.; Pritchard, E. E.; Pouwels, K.; Ehsaan, M.; Blake, J.; Gaughan, C.; Haduli, E.; Boothe, H.; Vihta, K.-D.; Peto, T.; Stoesser, N.; Matthews, P.; Taylor, N.; Diamond, I.; Studley, R.; Rourke, E.; Birrell, P.; De Angelis, D.; Fowler, T.; Watson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Studentsourcing - aggregating and re-using data from a practical cell biology course
Authors: Goedhart, J.
Score: 9.4, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.561479
Data that is generated by students during a course is often lost as there is no centrally organized collection and storage of the data. The loss of data prevents its re-use. To provide access to these data, I present an approach that I call studentsourcing. It collects, aggregates and re-uses data that is generated by students in a practical course on cell biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The accuracy of anal self- and companion exams among sexual minority men and transgender women: The Prevent Anal Cancer Palpation Study
Authors: Nyitray, A. G.; McAuliffe, T. L.; Liebert, C.; Swartz, M. D.; Deshmukh, A. A.; Chiao, E. Y.; Weaver, L.; Almirol, E.; Kerman, J.; Schneider, J. A.; Wilkerson, J. M.; Hwang, L.-Y.; Smith, D.; Hazra, A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.23297209
BackgroundSquamous cell carcinoma of the anus (SCCA) annual incidence among sexual minority men (SMM) with and without HIV is 85/100,000 and 19/100,000 persons, respectively, which is significantly higher than the overall incidence (2/100,000).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>A three-node Turing gene circuit forms periodic spatial patterns in bacteria
Authors: Tica, J.; Oliver Huidobro, M.; Zhu, T.; Wachter, G. K. A.; H. Pazuki, R.; Tonello, E.; Siebert, H.; Stumpf, M. P. H.; Endres, R. G.; Isalan, M.
Score: 28.7, Published: 2023-10-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563112
Turing patterns1 are well-known self-organising systems that can form spots, stripes, or labyrinths. They represent a major theory of patterning in tissue organisation, due to their remarkable similarity to some natural patterns, such as skin pigmentation in zebrafish2, digit spacing3,4, and many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>The genetic architecture of protein interaction affinity and specificity
Authors: Bendel, A.; Faure, A.; Klein, D.; Shimada, K.; Kempf, G.; Cavadini, S.; Lehner, B.; Diss, G.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.17.562688
Proteins function in crowded cellular environments in which they must bind to specific target proteins but also avoid binding to many other off-target proteins. In large protein families this task is particularly challenging because many off-target proteins have very similar structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Disturbed sleep is associated with worse patient-reported outcomes and chronic lung allograft dysfunction after lung transplantation
Authors: Singer, J. P.; Prather, A. A.; Betancourt, L.; Kordahl, R. C.; Sriram, A.; Huang, C.-Y.; Hays, S. R.; Kukreja, J.; Calabrese, D. R.; Venado, A.; Greenland, J. R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.23296973
BackgroundMany lung transplant recipients fail to derive substantial improvements in functioning, health-related quality of life (HRQL), or long-term survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Ticks without borders: Microbial communities of immature Neotropical tick species parasitizing migratory landbirds along northern Gulf of Mexico
Authors: Karim, S.; Zenzal, T. J.; Beati, L.; Sen, R.; Adegoke, A.; Kumar, D.; Downs, L.; Keko, M.; Nussbaum, A.; Becker, D.; Moore, F.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.563347
The long-distance, seasonal migrations of birds make them an effective ecological bridge for the movement of ticks. The introduction of exotic tick species to new geographical regions can lead to the emergence of novel tickborne pathogens or the reemergence of previously eradicated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
