<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alcohol use associated alterations in the circulating metabolite profile in the general population and in individuals with major depressive disorder
Authors: Kärkkäinen, O.; Tolmunen, T.; Kivimäki, P.; Kurkinen, K.; Ali-Sisto, T.; Mäntyselkä, P.; Valkonen-Korhonen, M.; Koivumaa-Honkanen, H.; Ruusunen, A.; Velagapudi, V.; Lehto, S. M.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.23289383
Our aim was to evaluate whether alcohol use is associated with changes in the circulating metabolite profile similar to those present in persons with depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>TLR8 escapes X chromosome inactivation in human monocytes and CD4&amp;#43; T cells
Authors: Youness, A.; Cenac, C.; Faz-Lopez, B.; Grunenwald, S.; Barrat, F.; Chaumeil, J.; Mejia, J. E.; Guery, J.-C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.23293823
Human endosomal Toll-like receptors TLR7 and TLR8 recognize self and non-self RNA ligands, and are important mediators of innate immunity and autoimmune pathogenesis. TLR7 and TLR8 are encoded by the adjacent X-linked genes, TLR7 and TLR8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 116.5, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Cryo-EM of soft-landed β-galactosidase: Gas-phase and native structures are remarkably similar
Authors: Esser, T. K.; Boehning, J.; Onur, A.; Chinthapalli, D. K.; Eriksson, L.; Grabarics, M.; Fremdling, P.; Konijnenberg, A.; Makarov, A. A.; Botman, A.; Peter, C.; Benesch, J. L. P.; Robinson, C. V.; Gault, J.; Baker, L.; Bharat, T. A. M.; Rauschenbach, S.
Score: 47.8, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553673
Native mass spectrometry (native MS) is a powerful technique that provides information on stoichiometry, interactions, homogeneity and shape of protein complexes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Transferrin Receptor Targeting Chimeras (TransTACs) for Membrane Protein Degradation
Authors: Zhang, D.; Duque-Jimenez, J.; Brixi, G.; Facchinetti, F.; Rhee, K.; Feng, W. W.; Jänne, P. A.; Zhou, X.
Score: 40.3, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552782
Cancer cells require high levels of iron for rapid proliferation, leading to a significant upregulation of the iron carrier protein Transferrin Receptor (TfR) on their cell surface. Leveraging this phenomenon and the exceptionally fast endocytosis rate of TfR, we introduce Transferrin Receptor TArgeting Chimeras (TransTAC), a novel molecular archetype for membrane protein degradation in cancers and other cell types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>NanoPyx: super-fast bioimage analysis powered by adaptive machine learning
Authors: Saraiva, B. M.; Cunha, I. M.; Brito, A. D.; Follain, G.; Portela, R.; Haase, R.; Pereira, P. M.; Jacquemet, G.; Henriques, R.
Score: 56.6, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553080
To overcome the challenges posed by large and complex microscopy datasets, we have developed NanoPyx, an adaptive bioimage analysis framework designed for high-speed processing. At the core of NanoPyx is the Liquid Engine, an agent-based machine-learning system that predicts acceleration strategies for image analysis tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Glutamate helps unmask the differences in driving forces for phase separation versus clustering of FET family proteins in sub-saturated solutions
Authors: Kar, M.; Vogel, L. T.; Chauhan, G.; Ausserwoger, H.; Welsh, T. J.; Kamath, A. R.; Knowles, T. P. J.; Hyman, A. A.; Seidel, C. A. M.; Pappu, R. V.
Score: 26.1, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.552963
Multivalent proteins undergo coupled segregative and associative phase transitions. Phase separation, a segregative transition, is driven by macromolecular solubility, and this leads to coexisting phases above system-specific saturation concentrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 650.7, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Humans with Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension display a global hypermethylation signature that worsens in patients who have a mutation in the gene encoding the methylation eraser, Tet Methylcytosine Dioxygenase 2 (TET2).
Authors: Hindmarch, C. C.; Potus, F.; Al-Qazazi, R.; Ring, B.; Nichols, W.; Rauh, M.; Archer, S. L.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293846
Epigenetic changes in gene expression due to DNA methylation are important physiologic and pathologic regulators of pulmonary vascular structure and function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>ATG2A-mediated bridge-like lipid transport regulates lipid droplet accumulation
Authors: Korfhage, J. L.; Wan, N.; Elhan, H.; Kauffman, L.; Pineda, M. J.; Fuller, D. M.; Thiam, A. R.; Reinisch, K.; Melia, T.
Score: 18.6, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553257
ATG2 proteins facilitate bulk lipid transport between membranes. ATG2 is an essential autophagy protein, but ATG2 also localizes to lipid droplets (LDs), and genetic depletion of ATG2 increases LD numbers while impairing fatty acid transport from LDs to mitochondria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Nucleotide sharing through gap junctions buffers replication stress
Authors: Boumard, B.; Le Meur, G.; Maalouf, T.; El-Hajj, M.; Bauer, R.; Bardin, A. J.
Score: 16.8, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553366
Cell proliferation underlying tissue growth and homeostasis, requires high levels of metabolites such as deoxynucleotides (dNTPs). The dNTP pool is known to be tightly cell-autonomously regulated through the de novo synthesis and salvage pathways. Here, we reveal that nucleotides can be provided to cells non-autonomously by surrounding cells of the tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Island biogeography theory and the gut: why taller people tend to harbor more diverse gut microbiomes.
Authors: Ramos Sarmiento, K.; Carr, A.; Diener, C.; Locey, K. J.; Gibbons, S. M.
Score: 30.1, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552554
Prior work has shown a positive scaling relationship between vertebrate body size and gut microbiome alpha-diversity. This observation mirrors commonly observed species area relationships (SAR) in many other ecosystems. Here, we show a similar scaling relationship between human height and gut microbiome alpha-diversity across two large, independent cohorts, controlling for a wide range of relevant covariates, such as body mass index, age, sex, and bowel movement frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 24.1, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Long-term Prediction of Severe Hypoglycemia in Type 2 Diabetes Based on Multi-view Co-training
Authors: Agraz, M.; Deng, Y.; Karniadakis, G.; Mantzoros, C.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.23293518
BackgroundPatients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) who have severe hypoglycemia (SH) poses a considerable risk of long-term death, demanding urgent medical attention. Accurate prediction of SH remains challenging due to its multifactorial nature, contributed from factors such as medications, lifestyle choices, and metabolic measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected during a SARS-CoV-2 Omicron wave - Australia, 2022
Authors: Woldegiorgis, M.; Cadby, G.; Ngeh, S.; Korda, R.; Armstrong, P.; Maticevic, J.; Knight, P.; Jardine, A.; Bloomfield, L.; Effler, P.
Score: 2012.2, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293706
ObjectiveTo characterise Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected by Omicron. DesignFollow-up survey of persons testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 in Western Australia, 16 July-3 August 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Opsin gene duplication in Lepidoptera: retrotransposition, sex linkage, and gene expression
Authors: Mulhair, P. O.; Crowley, L.; Boyes, D. H.; Lewis, O. T.; Holland, P. W. H.
Score: 31.6, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.552946
Colour vision in insects is determined by signalling cascades, central to which are opsin proteins, resulting in sensitivity to light at different wavelengths. In certain insect groups, lineage specific evolution of opsin genes, in terms of copy number, shifts in expression patterns, and functional amino acid substitutions, has resulted in changes in colour vision with subsequent behavioural and niche adaptations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Longitudinal Profiling of the Intestinal Microbiome in Children with Cystic Fibrosis Treated with Elexacaftor-Tezacaftor-Ivacaftor
Authors: Reasoner, S. A.; Bernard, R.; Waalkes, A.; Penewit, K.; Lewis, J.; Sokolow, A. G.; Brown, R. F.; Edwards, K. M.; Salipante, S.; Hadjifrangiskou, M.; Nicholson, M. R.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23293949
The intestinal microbiome influences growth and disease progression in children with cystic fibrosis (CF). Elexacaftor-tezacaftor-ivacaftor (ELX/TEZ/IVA), the newest pharmaceutical modulator for CF, restores function of the pathogenic mutated CFTR channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Unique Capabilities of Genome Sequencing for Rare Disease Diagnosis
Authors: Wojcik, M. H.; Lemire, G.; Zaki, M. S.; Wissmann, M.; Win, W.; White, S.; Weisburd, B.; Waddell, L. B.; Verboon, J. M.; VanNoy, G. E.; Topf, A.; Tan, T. Y.; Straub, V.; Stenton, S. L.; Snow, H.; Singer-Berk, M.; Silver, J.; Shril, S.; Seaby, E. G.; Schneider, R.; Sankaran, V. G.; Sanchis-Juan, A.; Russell, K. A.; Reinson, K.; Ravenscroft, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Deletion of Xist upstream sequences alters TAD interactions and leads to defects in Xist coating and expression
Authors: Majumdar, S.; Bammidi, L. S.; Naik, H.; M, A.; Baro, R.; Kalita, A.; Sundarraj, N.; Bariha, G.; Notani, D.; GAYEN, S.
Score: 17.7, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553118
The topological organization of the genome plays an important role in regulating gene expression. However, the connection between the two remains poorly understood. X-chromosome inactivation is a unique model system to explore the interlink between topologically associated domains (TADs) and gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Programmable multi-kilobase RNA editing using CRISPR-mediated trans-splicing
Authors: Borrajo, J.; Javanmardi, K.; Griffin, J.; St. Martin, S. J.; Yao, D.; Hill, K.; Blainey, P.; Al-Shayeb, B.
Score: 74.8, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553620
Current gene editing approaches in eukaryotic cells are limited to single base edits or small DNA insertions and deletions, and remain encumbered by unintended permanent effects and significant challenges in the delivery of large DNA cargo. Here we describe Splice Editing, a generalizable platform to correct gene transcripts in situ by programmable insertion or replacement of large RNA segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The effects of economic difficulties on social and health care costs of children: target trial emulation using complete birth cohort data in Finland
Authors: Hiilamo, A.; Keski-Santti, M.; Juutinen, A.; Makinen, L.; Ristikari, T.; Lallukka, T.
Score: 60.7, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.23293974
It is unclear how much costs economic difficulties incur to the health and social care sector, which is a critical research gap to support the economic case for preventing child poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Identification of Outcome-Oriented Progression Subtypes from Mild Cognitive Impairment to Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease Using Electronic Health Records
Authors: Xu, J.; Yin, R.; Huang, Y.; Gao, H.; Wu, Y.; Guo, J.; Glenn, S.; DeKosky, S.; Wang, F.; Guo, Y.; Bian, J.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.23293270
Alzheimers disease (AD) is a complex heterogeneous neurodegenerative disease that requires an in-depth understanding of its progression pathways and contributing factors to develop effective risk stratification and prevention strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>A Scoping Review of Interventions to De-implement Potentially Harmful Nonsteroidal Anti-inflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs) in Healthcare Settings
Authors: Rockwell, M. S.; Oyese, E. G.; Singh, E.; Vinson, M.; Yim, I.; Turner, J. K.; Epling, J. W.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.23293362
ObjectivesPotentially harmful nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) utilization persists at undesirable rates throughout the world. The purpose of this paper is to review the literature on interventions to de-implement potentially harmful NSAIDs in healthcare settings and to suggest directions for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 infection triggers pro-atherogenic inflammatory 1 responses in human coronary vessels
Authors: Eberhardt, N.; Noval, M. G.; Kaur, R.; Sajja, S.; Amadori, L.; Das, D.; Cilhoroz, B.; Stewart, O. J.; Fernandez, D. M.; Shamailova, R.; Guillen, A. V.; Jangra, S.; Schotsaert, M.; Gildea, M.; Newman, J. D.; Faries, P.; Maldonado, T.; Rockman, C.; Rapkiewicz, A.; Stapleford, K. A.; Narula, N.; Moore, K. J.; Giannarelli, C.
Score: 251.8, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Published benefits of ivermectin use in Itajai, Brazil for COVID-19 infection, hospitalisation, and mortality are entirely explained by statistical artefacts
Authors: Mills, R.; Pecanha Antonio, A. C.; Tucker-Kellogg, G.
Score: 265.2, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.23293924
BackgroundTwo recent publications by Kerr et al. (Cureus 14(1):e21272; Cureus 14(8): e28624) reported dramatic effects of prophylactic ivermectin use for both prevention of COVID-19 and reduction of COVID-19-related hospitalisation and mortality, including a dose-dependent effect of ivermectin prophylaxis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Neutralizing Antibodies Following a Second BA.5 Bivalent Booster
Authors: Wang, Q.; Bowen, A.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R.; Valdez, R.; Stoneman, E.; Gordon, A.; Lihong, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 300.6, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553148
Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA vaccines expressing both the ancestral D614G and Omicron BA.5 spike proteins were introduced in August 2022 with the goal of broadening immunity to emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariants. Subsequent studies on bivalent boosters found neutralizing antibody responses similar to boosters with the original monovalent vaccine, likely the result of immunological imprinting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>The apparent loss of PRC2 chromatin occupancy as an artefact of RNA depletion
Authors: Healy, E.; Zhang, Q.; Gail, E. H.; Agius, S. C.; Sun, G.; Bullen, M.; Pandey, V.; Das, P. P.; Polo, J. M.; Davidovich, C.
Score: 60.0, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.553488
RNA has been implicated in the recruitment of chromatin modifiers, and previous studies have provided evidence in favour and against this idea. RNase treatment of chromatin is a prevalent tool for the study of RNA-mediated regulation of chromatin modifiers, but the limitations of this approach remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Personalized chronic adaptive deep brain stimulation outperforms conventional stimulation in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Oehrn, C. R.; Cernera, S.; Hammer, L. H.; Shcherbakova, M.; Yao, J.; Hahn, A.; Wang, S.; Ostrem, J. L.; Little, S.; Starr, P. A.
Score: 23.0, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293450
1.Deep brain stimulation is a widely used therapy for Parkinsons disease (PD) but currently lacks dynamic responsiveness to changing clinical and neural states. Feedback control has the potential to improve therapeutic effectiveness, but optimal control strategy and additional benefits of &amp;#34;adaptive&amp;#34; neurostimulation are unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neurons in the human entorhinal cortex map abstract emotion space
Authors: Qasim, S. E.; Reinacher, P. C.; Brandt, A.; Schulze-Bonhage, A.; Kunz, L.
Score: 66.4, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552884
When animals move through space, neurons in their entorhinal cortex activate periodically at multiple locations to form a map of the spatial environment. These grid cells may also map non-physical, conceptual spaces to support various other complex behaviors. Here, using intracranial recordings in neurosurgical patients performing an emotional memory task, we find that neurons in the human medial temporal lobe activate in a grid-like pattern across a two-dimensional feature space characterized by emotional valence and arousal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>The plasma proteome of plant-based diets: analyses of 1463 proteins in 50,000 people
Authors: Tong, T. Y.; Smith-Byrne, K.; Papier, K.; Atkins, J. R.; Parsaeian, M.; Key, T. J.; Travis, R. C.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.23294084
Background and objectivesCirculating proteins are integral to many biological processes. We aimed to assess differences in the plasma proteome between people of different dietary groups defined by degree of animal food consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>High 3-hydroxybutyrate concentrations in the placenta-produced amniotic fluid in the human uterus
Authors: Satoh, T.; Shibata, T.; Takata, E.; Takakura, M.; Han, J.; Yamada, S.
Score: 9.4, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293873
In this study, we report first high concentrations of a ketone body, 3-hydroxybutyrate (3HB) in the amniotic fluid in humans. Although 3HB concentrations in the maternal blood are approximately 0.1, those in the amniotic fluid are approximately 0.6 mM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Whole-genome mapping of APOBEC mutagenesis in metastatic urothelial carcinoma identifies driver hotspot mutations and a novel mutational signature
Authors: Nakauma-Gonzalez, J. A.; Rijnders, M.; Noordsij, M. T. W.; Martens, J. W. M.; van der Veldt, A.; Lolkema, M. P.; Boormans, J. L.; van de Werken, H. J. G.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293865
BackgroundIn urothelial carcinoma (UC), apolipoprotein B mRNA-editing enzyme catalytic polypeptide-like (APOBEC) enzymes are major contributors to the mutational burden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Stellate Ganglion Block to Treat Long COVID-19 Syndrome, A 41 Patient Retrospective Cohort Study
Authors: Pearson, L.; Maina, A.; Thompson, L.; Harden, S.; Aaroe, A.; Compratt, T.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.23290338
Post Covid-19 condition (PCC), long COVID-19 syndrome and post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 (PASC) all refer to a constellation of symptoms that are unresolved long after the acute phase of the viral infection. The severity of symptoms can vary from mild and tolerable to severe and debilitating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Longer mandible or nose? Co-evolution of feeding organs in early elephantiforms
Authors: Li, C.; Deng, T.; Wang, Y.; Sun, F.; Wolff, B.; Jiangzuo, Q.; Ma, J.; Xing, L.; Fu, J.; Zhang, J.; Wang, S.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553347
The long-trunked elephantids underwent a significant evolutionary stage characterized by an exceptionally elongated mandible. The initial elongation and subsequent regression of the long mandible, along with its co-evolution with the trunk, present an intriguing issue that remains incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>An end-to-end workflow for non-destructive 3D pathology
Authors: Bishop, K. W.; Barner, L. A. E.; Han, Q.; Baraznenok, E.; Lan, L.; Poudel, C.; Gao, G.; Serafin, R. B.; Chow, S. S. L.; Glaser, A. K.; Janowczyk, A.; Brenes, D.; Huang, H.; Miyasato, D.; True, L. D.; Kang, S.; Vaughan, J. C.; Liu, J. T. C.
Score: 130.1, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551845
Recent advances in 3D pathology offer the ability to image orders-of-magnitude more tissue than conventional pathology while providing a volumetric context that is lacking with 2D tissue sections, all without requiring destructive tissue sectioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Factors associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome-related coronavirus 2 infection in unvaccinated children and young adults
Authors: Silverberg, S. L.; Shulha, H. P.; McMillan, B.; He, G.; Lee, A.; Marquez, A. C.; Bartlett, S. R.; Gill, V.; Abu-Raya, B.; Bettinger, J. A.; Cabrera, A.; Coombs, D.; Gantt, S.; Goldfarb, D. M.; Sauve, L.; Krajden, M.; Morshed, M.; Sekirov, I.; Jassem, A. N.; Sadarangani, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Characterization and Genome Sequencing of a Novel Lytic Bacteriophage Infecting Hospital-Associated Carbapenem-Resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae Strain from Dhaka, Bangladesh
Authors: NSU Genome Research Institute (NGRI), North South University, ; Hossain, M. M.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.23294043
BackgroundMultidrug-resistant bacterial pathogens pose a grave threat to global health, with Klebsiella pneumoniae being a particular concern due to its hypervariable extracellular matrix capsule and frequent development of extended-spectrum {beta}-lactamases and other antibiotic defenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Illuminating the Function of the Orphan Transporter, SLC22A10 in Humans and Other Primates
Authors: Yee, S. W.; Ferrandez-Peral, L.; Alentorn, P.; Fontsere, C.; Ceylan, M.; Koleske, M. L.; Handin, N.; Artegoitia, V. M.; Lara, G.; Chien, H.-C.; Zhou, X.; Dainat, J.; Zalevsky, A.; Sali, A.; Brand, C. M.; Capra, J. A.; Artursson, P.; Newman, J. W.; Marques-Bonet, T.; Giacomini, K. M.
Score: 10.0, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552553
SLC22A10 is classified as an orphan transporter with unknown substrates and function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Auxin Exposure Disrupts Feeding Behavior and Fatty Acid Metabolism in Adult Drosophila
Authors: Fleck, S. A.; Knuteson, R. L.; Dewitt, E. D.; Eisman, R. C.; Nemkov, T.; D&amp;#39;Alessandro, A.; Tennessen, J. M.; Weaver, L. N.
Score: 20.9, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553385
The ease of genetic manipulation in Drosophila melanogaster using the Gal4/UAS system has been beneficial in addressing key biological questions. Current modifications of this methodology to temporally induce transgene expression require temperature changes or exposure to exogenous compounds, both of which have been shown to have detrimental effects on physiological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The Auxin Response Factor ARF27 is required for maize root morphogenesis
Authors: Dash, L.; McReynolds, M. R.; Draves, M. A.; Khangura, R. S.; Muench, R. L.; Khor, J.; Cowling, C. L.; Callwood, J. B.; Mejia, L.; Lang, M.; Dilkes, B. P.; Walley, J. W.; Kelley, D. R.
Score: 14.9, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553439
Crop root systems are central to nutrition acquisition and water usage. Root hairs and lateral roots contribute to fine-scale patterning of root systems and can offer many advantages for improving root function without drastically impacting overall system architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>A sex-stratified analysis of the genetic architecture of human brain anatomy
Authors: Shafee, R.; Moraczewski, D.; Liu, S.; Mallard, T.; Thomas, A. G.; Raznahan, A.
Score: 11.4, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.23293881
Large biobanks have dramatically advanced our understanding of genetic influences on human brain anatomy. However, most studies have combined rather than compared males and females - despite theoretical grounds for potential sex differences. By systematically screening for sex differences in the common genetic architecture of &amp;gt; 1000 neuroanatomical phenotypes in the UK Biobank, we establish a general concordance between males and females in heritability estimates, genetic correlations and variant-level effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 901.4, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Methodological development of molecular endotype discovery from synovial fluid of individuals with knee osteoarthritis: the STEpUP OA Consortium
Authors: Deng, Y.; Perry, T. A.; Hulley, P.; Maciewicz, R. A.; Mitchelmore, J.; Perry, D.; Larsson, S.; Brachat, S.; Struglics, A.; Appleton, C. T.; Kluzek, S.; Arden, N. K.; Felson, D.; Marsden, B.; Tom, B. D. M.; Bondi, L.; Kapoor, M.; Batchelor, V.; Mackay-Alderson, J.; Kumar, V.; Lohmander, L. S.; Welting, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Important enough to show the world&amp;#34;: Using Authentic Research Opportunities and Micropublications to Build Students&amp;#39; Science Identities
Authors: Rubenstein, L. D.; Woodruff, K. A.; Taylor, A. M.; Olesen, J. B.; Smaldino, P. J.; Rubenstein, E. M.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553701
Primarily undergraduate institutions (PUIs) often struggle to provide authentic research opportunities that culminate in peer-reviewed publications due to &amp;#34;recipe-driven&amp;#34; lab courses and the comprehensive body of work necessary for traditional scientific publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Efficient Natural Plasmid Transformation of Vibrio natriegens Enables Zero-capital Molecular Biology
Authors: Specht, D. A.; Sheppard, T. J.; Kennedy, F.; Li, S.; Gadikota, G.; Barstow, B.
Score: 38.6, Published: 2023-08-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.553013
The fast-growing microbe Vibrio natriegens is capable of natural transformation where it draws DNA in from media via an active process under physiological conditions. Using an engineered strain with a genomic copy of the master competence regulator tfoX from Vibrio cholera in combination with a new minimal competence media (MCM) that uses acetate as an energy source, we demonstrate naturally competent cells which are created, transformed, and recovered entirely in the same media, without exchange or addition of new media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence of and gene regulatory constraints on transcriptional adaptation in single cells
Authors: Mellis, I. A.; Bodkin, N.; Goyal, Y.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553318
Cells and tissues have a remarkable ability to adapt to genetic perturbations via a variety of molecular mechanisms. Nonsense-induced transcriptional compensation, a form of transcriptional adaptation, has recently emerged as one such mechanism, in which nonsense mutations in a gene can trigger upregulation of related genes, possibly conferring robustness at cellular and organismal levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Worms on the Cape: an integrative survey of polydorid infestation in wild and cultivated oysters (Crassostrea virginica) from Massachusetts, USA
Authors: Davinack, A. A.; Strong, M.; Brennessel, B.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.12.553105
Polydorid infestations pose a significant challenge to shellfish aquaculture by impacting marketability and profitability of farms. In this study, we investigated the prevalence, intensity, identity and biogeography of shell-boring worms infecting both farmed and wild oysters (Crassostrea virginica) from three sites in Wellfleet Harbor, Massachusetts - an economically important shellfishing region in the northeastern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
