<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Plant-like heliotropism in a photosymbiotic animal
Authors: Lintnerova, E.; Shaw, C.; Keys, M.; Brownlee, C.; Modepalli, V.
Score: 16.9, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565328
Being photosynthetic sessile organisms, plants established heliotropism to track the suns position across the sky and allow their vegetative parts to orient accordingly. Here, we report plant-like heliotropic movement in a photosymbiotic sea anemone Anemonia viridis. Like plants, photosynthesis represents a key energy source in endosymbiotic cnidarians bearing microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Small-molecule binding and sensing with a designed protein family
Authors: Lee, G. R.; Pellock, S. J.; Norn, C.; Tischer, D.; Dauparas, J.; Anishchenko, I.; Mercer, J. A. M.; Kang, A.; Bera, A.; Nguyen, H.; Goreshnik, I.; Vafeados, D.; Roullier, N.; Han, H. L.; Coventry, B.; Haddox, H. K.; Liu, D. R.; Yeh, A. H.-W.; Baker, D.
Score: 24.1, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.565201
Despite transformative advances in protein design with deep learning, the design of small-molecule-binding proteins and sensors for arbitrary ligands remains a grand challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Coordinated differentiation of human intestinal organoids with functional enteric neurons and vasculature
Authors: Childs, C. J.; Poling, H. M.; Chen, K.; Tsai, Y.-H.; Wu, A.; Sweet, C. W.; Vallie, A.; Eiken, M. K.; Huang, S.; Schreiner, R.; Xiao, Z.; Conchola, A. S.; Anderman, M. F.; Holloway, E. M.; Singh, A.; Giger, R.; Mahe, M. M.; Walton, K. D.; Loebel, C.; Helmrath, M. A.; Rafii, S.; Spence, J. R.
Score: 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Structure prediction of protein-ligand complexes from sequence information with Umol
Authors: Bryant, P.; Kelkar, A.; Guljas, A.; Clementi, C.; Noe, F.
Score: 97.5, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.565471
Protein-ligand docking is an established tool in drug discovery and development to narrow down potential therapeutics for experimental testing. However, a high-quality protein structure is required and often the protein is treated as fully or partially rigid. Here we develop an AI system that can predict the fully flexible all-atom structure of protein-ligand complexes directly, given a multiple sequence alignment representation of the protein and a SMILES string representing the ligand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>CryoSTAR: Leveraging Structural Prior and Constraints for Cryo-EM Heterogeneous Reconstruction
Authors: Li, Y.; Zhou, Y.; Yuan, J.; Ye, F.; Gu, Q.
Score: 51.3, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.564872
Resolving conformational heterogeneity in cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) datasets remains a significant challenge in structural biology. Previous methods have often been restricted to working exclusively on volumetric densities, neglecting the potential of incorporating any pre-existing structural knowledge as prior or constraints. In this paper, we present a novel methodology, cryoSTAR, that harnesses atomic model information as structural regularization to elucidate such heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Breast Cancer Macrophage Heterogeneity and Self-renewal are Determined by Spatial Localization
Authors: Ben-Chetrit, N.; Niu, X.; Sotelo, J.; Swett, A. D.; Rajasekhar, V. K.; Jiao, M. S.; Stewart, C. M.; Bhardwaj, P.; Kottapalli, S.; Ganesan, S.; Loyher, P.-L.; Potenski, C.; Hannuna, A.; Brown, K. A.; Iyengar, N. M.; Giri, D. D.; Lowe, S. W.; Healey, J. H.; Geissmann, F.; Sagi, I.; Joyce, J. A.; Landau, D. A.
Score: 31.5, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Drug target Mendelian randomization supports apolipoprotein C3-lowering for lipoprotein-lipid levels reductions and cardiovascular diseases prevention
Authors: Gagnon, E.; Arsenault, B. J.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.23298088
Background and aimsInhibitors of apolipoprotein C-III (apoC3) are currently approved for the reduction of triglyceride levels in patients with Familial Chylomicronemia Syndrome. We used drug target Mendelian randomization (MR) to assess the effect of genetically predicted decrease in APOC3 blood protein levels on cardiometabolic traits and diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Change in RhoGAP and RhoGEF availability drives transitions in cortical patterning and excitability in Drosophila
Authors: Jackson, J. A.; Denk-Lobnig, M.; Kitzinger, K. A.; Martin, A. C.
Score: 22.7, Published: 2023-11-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.565883
Actin cortex patterning and dynamics are critical for cell shape changes. These dynamics undergo transitions during development, often accompanying changes in collective cell behavior. While mechanisms have been established for individual cells dynamic behaviors, mechanisms and specific molecules that result in developmental transitions in vivo are still poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Meta-analysis of RNA sequencing data from 534 skin samples shows substantial IL-17 effects in non-lesional psoriatic skin
Authors: Solvin, A. O.; Chawla, K.; Jenssen, M.; Olsen, L. C.; Furberg, A.-S.; Danielsen, K.; Saunes, M.; Hveem, K.; Saetrom, P.; Loset, M.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.23298021
Psoriasis is a common chronic inflammatory skin disease characterized by disturbed interactions between infiltrating immune cells and keratinocytes. To enhance our understanding of the underlying molecular and cellular mechanisms driving psoriasis pathobiology, and to identify potential biomarkers for disease severity, we conducted RNA sequencing of skin biopsies from 75 patients with psoriasis vulgaris and 46 non-psoriatic controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>TBXT dose sensitivity and the decoupling of nascent mesoderm specification from EMT progression in 2D human gastruloids
Authors: Bulger, E. A.; Muncie-Vasic, I.; Libby, A. R. G.; McDevitt, T. C.; Bruneau, B. G.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2023-11-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.565933
In the nascent mesoderm, levels of Brachyury (TBXT) expression must be precisely regulated to ensure cells exit the primitive streak and pattern the anterior-posterior axis, but how this varying dosage informs morphogenesis is not well understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Environment-organism feedbacks drive changes in ecological interactions
Authors: Meacock, O. J.; Mitri, S.
Score: 29.4, Published: 2023-11-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.565024
Ecological interactions, the impact of one organism on the growth and death of another, underpin our understanding of the long-term composition and the functional properties of communities. Interactions from classical ecology are typically understood to be fixed values, representing for example the per-capita consumption rate of prey by its predator. Yet in many ecosystems, such fixed descriptions are inadequate: interactions can depend on local environmental conditions, the time at which they are measured, and the sampled position in a spatially-structured community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>ASSESSMENT AND CHARACTERIZATION OF COVID-19 RELATED COGNITIVE DECLINE: RESULTS FROM A NATURAL EXPERIMENT
Authors: Sekendiz, Z.; Clouston, S.; Morozova, O.; Carr, M. A.; Fontana, A.; Mehta, N.; Ali, A.; Jiang, E.; Luft, B. J.
Score: 1114.5, Published: 2023-11-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.23298101
BackgroundCognitive impairment is the most common and disabling manifestation of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2. There is an urgent need for the application of more stringent methods for evaluating cognitive outcomes in research studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Fundamental equations linking methylation dynamics to maximum lifespan in mammals
Authors: Horvath, S.; Zhang, J.; Haghani, A.; Lu, A. T.; Fei, Z.
Score: 84.6, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.21.541643
We establish the mathematical foundation that links the rate of change in any molecular biomarker to species lifespan. Specifically, we propose a robust approach that identifies the strong inverse relationship for certain biomarkers using two comprehensive methylation datasets. After examining 54 chromatin states, we found the rates of change of CpG sites in bivalent chromatin states are negatively associated to the lifespans of 90 dog breeds in the first dataset, and the discoveries are further strengthened with 125 mammalian species in the second dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Breathing exercises for the management of gastrointestinal conditions: protocol for a scoping review
Authors: Gholamrezaei, A.; Guadagnoli, L.; Teugels, A.; Peluso, N.; Fung, A.; Van Oudenhove, L.; Van Diest, I.; Vlaeyen, J.; Tack, J.; Vanuytsel, T.; Aziz, Q.; Talley, N. J.; Keefer, L.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297871
1.ObjectivesThis scoping review will identify and map the literature on breathing exercises for the management of gastrointestinal conditions. IntroductionEmerging evidence suggests the potential benefits of breathing exercises for gastrointestinal conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Cost-effective and scalable clonal hematopoiesis assay provides insight into clonal dynamics
Authors: Mack, T.; Vlasschaert, C.; von Beck, K.; Silver, A. J.; Heimlich, J. B.; Poisner, H.; Condon, H. R.; Ulloa, J.; Sochacki, A. L.; Spaulding, T. P.; Kishtagari, A.; Bejan, C. A.; Xu, Y.; Savona, M. R.; Jones, A.; Bick, A. G.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2023-11-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.08.23298270
Clonal hematopoiesis of indeterminate potential (CHIP) is a common age-related phenomenon that occurs when hematopoietic stem cells acquire mutations in a select set of genes commonly mutated in myeloid neoplasia which then expand clonally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Heritability within groups is uninformative about differences among groups: cases from behavioral, evolutionary, and statistical genetics
Authors: Schraiber, J. G.; Edge, M. D.
Score: 74.4, Published: 2023-11-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.565864
Without the ability to control or randomize environments (or genotypes), it is difficult to determine the degree to which observed phenotypic difference between two groups of individuals are due to genetic vs. environmental differences. However, some have suggested that these concerns may be limited to pathological cases, and methods have appeared that seem to give--directly or indirectly--some support to claims that aggregate heritable variation within groups can be related to heritable variation among groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Sources of gene expression variation in a globally diverse human cohort
Authors: Taylor, D. J.; Chhetri, S. B.; Biddanda, A.; Tassia, M. G.; Battle, A.; McCoy, R. C.
Score: 45.2, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.565639
Abstract/SummaryGenetic variation influencing gene expression and splicing is a key source of phenotypic diversity. Though invaluable, studies investigating these links in humans have been strongly biased toward participants of European ancestries, diminishing generalizability and hindering evolutionary research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Height loss in adulthood is associated with health outcomes in later life in men and women enrolled in the 1946 UK Birth Cohort (NSHD)
Authors: Matthes, K. L.; Staub, K.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.23298098
ObjectiveTo investigate the relationship between height in childhood and relative height loss in adult-hood, and to examine the association between height loss and health at age 69. DesignCohort study. SettingData from one of the oldest ongoing cohort studies, the National Survey of Health and Development (NSHD, 1946 UK birth cohort) Participants2,119 study participants who completed the nurse home visit during the 24th and most recent available follow-up examination at age 69.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Blood-based epigenome-wide analyses of chronic low-grade inflammation across diverse population cohorts
Authors: Hillary, R. F.; Ng, H. K.; McCartney, D. L.; Elliott, H. R.; Walker, R. M.; Campbell, A.; Huang, F.; Direk, K.; Welsh, P.; Sattar, N.; Corley, J.; Hayward, C.; McIntosh, A. M.; Sudlow, C.; Evans, K. L.; Cox, S. R.; Chambers, J. C.; Loh, M.; Relton, C. L.; Marioni, R. E.; Yousefi, P. D.; Suderman, M.
Score: 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Real-world effectiveness of non-pharmaceutical interventions in containing COVID-19 pandemic after the roll-out of coronavirus vaccines: A systematic review
Authors: Xiaona, H.; Chen, H.; Zhu, X.; Gao, W.
Score: 24.6, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23297704
BackgroundNon-pharmaceutical interventions (NPIs) have been widely used to control the transmission of infectious diseases. However, the current research evidence on the policy mechanisms of NPIs is still limited. This study aims to systematically identify, describe, and evaluate the existing literature for the real-world effectiveness of NPIs in containing COVID-19 pandemic after the roll-out of coronavirus vaccines, in order to search for optimal strategies for implementing NPIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Crowdsourcing strategies to improve access to HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) in Australia, the Philippines, and China
Authors: Tieosapjaroen, W.; Ongkeko, A. M.; Yin, Z.; Termavanich, K.; Tucker, J. D.; Tang, W.; Li, C.; Zhang, Y.; Castillo-Carandang, N. T.; Ong, J. J.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-10-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.23297686
IntroductionMany Asian countries have yet to scale up HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP). Innovative strategies to increase PrEP uptake are needed. This study examined the use of crowdsourcing to increase PrEP uptake by describing and analysing the experiences of Australia, the Philippines, and China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Mucosal Adenoviral-vectored Vaccine Boosting Durably Prevents XBB.1.16 Infection in Nonhuman Primates
Authors: Gagne, M.; Flynn, B. J.; Andrew, S. F.; Flebbe, D. R.; Mychalowych, A.; Lamb, E.; Davis-Gardner, M. E.; Burnett, M. R.; Serebryannyy, L. A.; Lin, B. C.; Pessaint, L.; Todd, J.-P. M.; Ziff, Z. E.; Maule, E.; Carroll, R.; Naisan, M.; Jethmalani, Y.; Case, J. B.; Dmitriev, I. P.; Kashentseva, E. A.; Ying, B.; Dodson, A.; Kouneski, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>The more symptoms the better? Covid-19 vaccine side effects and long-term neutralizing antibody response
Authors: Dutcher, E. G.; Epel, E. S.; Mason, A. E.; Hecht, F. M.; Robinson, J. E.; Drury, S. S.; Prather, A. A.
Score: 272.0, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296186
Protection against SARS-CoV-2 wanes over time, and booster uptake has been low, in part because of concern about side effects. We examined the relationships between local and systemic symptoms, biometric changes, and neutralizing antibodies (nAB) after mRNA vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Educational Impact of a Research and Mentoring Symposium Emphasizing Formative Feedback for Medical Students and Early Career Doctors in Africa
Authors: Nowbuth, A. A.; Muwowo, M.; Makashinyi, M.; Kumwenda, A.; Mwanamwampula, S. J.; Kaluba, T.; Mazimba, S.; Bloom, S. M.; Asombang, A. W.
Score: 10.8, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.23298036
SummaryResearch training is a core component of medical education, but many African medical schools lack resources to support student research, impeding global health progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical ethics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Fake Publications in Biomedical Science: Red-flagging Method Indicates Mass Production
Authors: Sabel, B. A.; Knaack, E.; Gigerenzer, G.; Bilc, M.
Score: 442.9, Published: 2023-10-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.06.23289563
BackgroundIntegrity of academic publishing is increasingly undermined by fake science publications massively produced by commercial &amp;#34;editing services&amp;#34; (so-called &amp;#34;paper mills&amp;#34;). They use AI-supported, automated production techniques at scale and sell fake publications to students, scientists, and physicians under pressure to advance their careers. Because the scale of fake publications in biomedicine is unknown, we developed a simple method to red-flag them and estimate their number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Observations of Elemental Composition of Enceladus Consistent with Generalized Models of Theoretical Ecosystems
Authors: Muratore, D.; Walker, S. I.; Graham, H.; House, C. H.; Kempes, C. P.
Score: 333.6, Published: 2023-10-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.29.564608
Recent analysis of data from the Cassini Cosmic Dust Analyzer confirm geochemical modeling work that shows that the ocean of Enceladus contains considerable quantities of inorganic phosphorus as well as ammonium [55]. Technological advancement in flight instrumentation will continue to yield increasingly detailed data about the relative elemental and molecular composition of life detection candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>The modified RNA base acp3U is an attachment site for N-glycans in glycoRNA
Authors: Xie, Y.; Hemberger, H.; Till, N. A.; Chai, P.; Watkins, C.; Lebedenko, C. G.; Caldwell, R. M.; George, B.; Bertozzi, C. R.; Garcia, B. A.; Flynn, R. A.
Score: 118.5, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.565735
We recently identified glycoRNA--a previously undescribed glycoconjugate--which consists of RNAs modified with secretory N-glycans and presented on the cell surface. While previous work supported a covalent linkage between RNA and glycans, the direct chemical nature of the RNA-glycan connection was not described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Small Fiber Neuropathy after COVID-19: A Key to Long COVID
Authors: McAlpine, L.; Zubair, A.; Joseph, P.; Spudich, S.
Score: 136.7, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23297764
ObjectivesReport a case series of new onset small fiber neuropathy (SFN) after COVID-19 treated with intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG). SFN is a critical objective finding in long COVID and amenable to treatment. MethodsA retrospective chart review was conducted on patients seen in the NeuroCOVID Clinic at Yale who developed new-onset SFN after a documented COVID-19 illness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>The feature landscape of visual cortex
Authors: Tong, R.; da Silva, R.; Lin, D.; Ghosh, A.; Wilsenach, J.; Cianfarano, E.; Bashivan, P.; Richards, B.; Trenholm, S.
Score: 97.4, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.565500
Understanding computations in the visual system requires a characterization of the distinct feature preferences of neurons in different visual cortical areas. However, we know little about how feature preferences of neurons within a given area relate to that areas role within the global organization of visual cortex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Gestational diabetes as a risk factor for GBS maternal rectovaginal colonization: a systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Mercado-Evans, V.; Zulk, J. J.; Hameed, Z. A.; Patras, K. A.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.23297989
BackgroundMaternal rectovaginal colonization by group B Streptococcus (GBS) increases the risk of perinatal GBS disease that can lead to death or long-term neurological impairment. Factors that increase the risk of rectovaginal GBS carriage are incompletely understood resulting in missed opportunities for detecting GBS in risk-based clinical approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>An elevated rate of whole-genome duplication events in cancers from Black patients
Authors: Brown, L. M.; Hagenson, R. A.; Sheltzer, J. M.
Score: 32.5, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298349
In the United States, Black individuals have higher rates of cancer mortality than any other racial or ethnic group. The sources of these significant racial disparities are not fully understood, and may include social, environmental, and genetic factors that influence cancer onset, diagnosis, and treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Regular Non-steroidal Anti-inflammatory Drug Use Increases Stress Fracture Risk in the General Population: A Retrospective Case-Control Study
Authors: Ciuciu, A.; Mulholland, C.; Bozzi, M. A.; Frymoyer, C. C.; Cavinatto, L.; Yaron, D.; Harwood, M. I.; Close, J. D.; Mehallo, C. J.; Tomlinson, R. E.
Score: 10.9, Published: 2023-10-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.30.23297788
Previous studies have shown that the use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) is associated with increased stress fracture risk, potentially due to diminished skeletal adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Attention and interoception alter perceptual and neural pain signatures
Authors: Niedernhuber, M.; Streicher, J.; Lenggenhager, B.; Bekinschtein, T. A.
Score: 12.1, Published: 2023-11-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.23298049
Fluctuations of chronic pain levels are determined by a complex interplay of cognitive, emotional and perceptual variables. We introduce a pain tracking platform composed of wearable neurotechnology and a smartphone application to measure and predict chronic pain levels. Our method measures, dynamically, pain strength, phenomenal and neural time series collected with an online tool and low-density EEG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Prebiotic membrane structures mimic the morphology of purported early traces of life on Earth
Authors: Jordan, S. F.; van Zuilen, M. A.; Rouillard, J.; Martins, Z.; Lane, N.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.565097
Elucidating the most probable compositions of the first cell membranes prior to the origin of life, within a laboratory setting, requires experiments with organic molecules and chemical conditions representative of those present on the early Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>PAH DEFICIENT PATHOLOGY IN HUMANIZED c.1066-11G&amp;gt;A PHENYLKETONURIA MICE
Authors: Martinez-Pizarro, A.; Pico, S.; Lopez-Marquez, A.; Rodriguez-Lopez, C.; Montalvo, E.; Alvarez, M.; Castro, M.; Ramon-Maiques, S.; Perez, B.; Lucas, J. J.; Richard, E. M.; Desviat, L. R.
Score: 12.7, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.565447
We have generated using CRISPR/Cas9 technology a partially humanized mouse model of the neurometabolic disease phenylketonuria (PKU) carrying the prevalent splice intronic variant PAH c.1066-11G&amp;gt;A. This variant creates a strong alternative splice acceptor site, leading to the inclusion of 9 nucleotides coding for a 3 amino acid insertion between Q355 and Y356 of the phenylalanine hydroxylase (PAH) protein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Sida cordifolia, a medicinal plant is efficacious in models of Huntingtons disease, by reducing ER stress
Authors: Simha, P. K.; Mukherjee, C.; Gupta, V. K. G. K.; Sapariya, N. M.; Nagar, P.; Nazeer, A.; Godbole, A.; Sahu, B. S.; Upadhyay, S.
Score: 9.7, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.565080
Background and aim: Huntington&amp;#39;s Disease is a severe neurodegenerative disorder caused by misfolded mutant huntingtin proteins with expanded stretches of polyglutamines aggregating and destroying cells in the nervous system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Renal mechanotransduction is an essential regulator of renin
Authors: Hill, R. Z.; Shirvan, S.; Burquez, S.; Dubin, A. E.; Servin Vences, M. R.; Miner, J. H.; Patapoutian, A.
Score: 164.3, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.565646
The kidneys tightly control the composition of our internal environment to maintain homeostasis in the face of external variability. The regulation of blood volume begins in the kidneys and is essential for vertebrate life in terrestrial environments where salt and water availability are unpredictable1,2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Chemical inhibition of stomatal differentiation by perturbation of the master-regulatory bHLH heterodimer via an ACT-Like domain
Authors: Nakagawa, A.; Sepuru, K. M.; Yip, S. J. A.; Seo, H.; Coffin, C. M.; Segawa, Y.; Iwasaki, R.; Kato, H.; Kim, S.; Aihara, Y.; Kinoshita, T.; Itami, K.; Han, S.-K.; Murakami, K.; Torii, K. U.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565226
Selective perturbation of protein interactions with chemical compounds enables dissection and control of developmental processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive and inflammatory heterogeneity in severe mental illness: Translating findings from blood to brain
Authors: Saether, L. S.; Szabo, A.; Akkouh, I. A.; Haatveit, B.; Mohn, C.; Vaskinn, A.; Aukrust, P.; Ormerod, M. B. E. G.; Steen, N. E.; Melle, I.; Djurovic, S.; Andreassen, O. A.; Ueland, T.; Ueland, T.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.23297924
Recent findings link cognitive impairment and inflammatory-immune dysregulation in schizophrenia (SZ) and bipolar (BD) spectrum disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Post-Vaccination Syndrome: A Descriptive Analysis of Reported Symptoms and Patient Experiences After Covid-19 Immunization
Authors: Krumholz, H. M.; Wu, Y.; Sawano, M.; Shah, R.; Zhou, T.; Arun, A. S.; Khosla, P.; Kaleem, S.; Vashist, A.; Bhattacharjee, B.; Ding, Q.; Lu, Y.; Caraballo, C.; Warner, F.; Huang, C.; Herrin, J.; Putrino, D.; Hertz, D.; Dressen, B.; Iwasaki, A.
Score: 135.9, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.23298266
Introduction: A chronic post-vaccination syndrome (PVS) after covid-19 vaccination has been reported but has yet to be well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Dissecting unique and common variance across body and brain health indicators using age prediction
Authors: Beck, D.; de Lange, A.-M. G.; Gurholt, T. P.; Voldsbekk, I.; Subramaniapillai, S.; Schindler, L.; Hindley, G.; Leonardsen, E. H.; Rahman, Z.; van der Meer, D.; Korbmacher, M.; Linge, J.; Leinhard, O. D.; Kalleberg, K. T.; Engvig, A.; Sonderby, I.; Andreassen, O. A.; Westlye, L. T.
Score: 7.9, Published: 2023-11-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.03.23298017
Ageing is a heterogeneous multisystem process involving different rates of decline in physiological integrity across biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the perceptions and experiences of community rehabilitation for Long COVID from the perspectives of Scottish General Practitioners and people living with Long COVID: a qualitative study
Authors: Cooper, K.; Duncan, E.; Hart-Winks, E.; Cowie, J.; Shim, J.; Stage, E.; Tooman, T.; Alexander, L.; Love, A.; Morris, J.; Ormerod, J.; Preston, J.; Swinton, P. A.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.23298096
ObjectivesTo explore the experience of accessing Long COVID community rehabilitation from the perspectives of people with Long COVID and General Practitioners (GPs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>MDA5-autoimmunity and Interstitial Pneumonitis Contemporaneous with the COVID-19 Pandemic (MIP-C)
Authors: Iqbal, K.; Sinha, S.; David, P.; De Marco, G.; Taheri, S.; McLaren, E.; MAISURIA, S.; ARUMUGAKANI, G.; Ash, Z.; BUCKLEY, C.; COLES, L.; HETTIARACHCHI, C.; SMITHSON, G.; SLADE, M.; Shah, R.; MARZO-ORTEGA, H.; Keen, M.; Lawson, C.; McLorinan, J.; NIZAM, S.; Reddy, H.; Sharif, O.; Sultan, S.; Tran, G.; WOOD, M.; WOOD, S.; Ghosh, P.; McGonagle, D.
Score: 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Women&amp;#39;s representation in Indian academia and conferences
Authors: Muralidhar, S.; Ananthanarayanan, V.
Score: 61.2, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564078
Abstract/IntroductionIndian science academia has a dearth of women researchers at all levels. Not only are they under-represented, but they are also under-highlighted, under-mentored and overlooked for awards, grants and other career-advancing steps. To effectively address this problem and devise a solution for the inequity, we need data on the proportion of women faculty across multiple STEM institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Neural network extrapolation to distant regions of the protein fitness landscape
Authors: Fahlberg, S. A.; Freschlin, C. R.; Heinzelman, P.; Romero, P. A.
Score: 19.4, Published: 2023-11-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.08.566287
Machine learning (ML) has transformed protein engineering by constructing models of the underlying sequence-function landscape to accelerate the discovery of new biomolecules. ML-guided protein design requires models, trained on local sequence-function information, to accurately predict distant fitness peaks. In this work, we evaluate neural networks&amp;#39; capacity to extrapolate beyond their training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Allometry of cell types in planarians by single cell transcriptomics
Authors: Emili, E.; Perez-Posada, A.; Christodoulou, M. D.; Solana, J.
Score: 64.1, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.01.565140
Allometry explores the relationship between an organisms body size and its various components, offering insights into ecology, physiology, metabolism, and disease. The cell is the basic unit of biological systems, and yet, the study of cell type allometry remains relatively unexplored. Single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) provides a promising tool for investigating cell type allometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Feeding-structure morphogenesis in rhabditid and diplogastrid nematodes is not controlled by a conserved genetic module
Authors: Theska, T.; Sommer, R. J.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-11-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.565949
Disentangling the evolution of the molecular processes and genetic networks that facilitate the emergence of morphological novelties is one of the main objectives in evolutionary developmental biology. Here, we investigated the evolutionary history of a gene regulatory network controlling the development of novel tooth-like feeding-structures in diplogastrid nematodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
