<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omic network analysis identifies dysregulated neurobiological pathways in opioid addiction
Authors: Sullivan, K. A.; Kainer, D.; Lane, M.; Cashman, M.; Miller, J. I.; Garvin, M. R.; Townsend, A.; Quach, B. C.; Willis, C.; Kruse, P.; Gaddis, N. C.; Mathur, R.; Corradin, O.; Maher, B. S.; Scacheri, P. C.; Sanchez-Roige, S.; Palmer, A. A.; Troiani, V.; Chesler, E. J.; Kember, R. L.; Kranzler, H. R.; Justice, A. C.; Xu, K.; Aouizerat, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Human ASXL1 Deficiency Causes Epigenetic Dysfunction, Combined Immunodeficiency and EBV-Associated Hodgkin Lymphoma
Authors: Fu, M. P.; Sharma, M.; Merrill, S. M.; Yousefi, P.; Tan, R.; Modi, B. P.; Del Bel, K.; Deyell, R. J.; Rozmus, J.; Rehmus, W.; Hildebrand, K. J.; James, E.; Blanchard-Rohner, G.; Lin, S.; Shopsowitz, K. E.; Setiadi, A.; Terry, J.; Lee, A. F.; Drogemoller, B. I.; Matthews, A.; Tarailo-Graovac, M.; Sauve, L.; Mitchell, H.; Prendiville, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Conditioned overconsumption is dependent on reinforcer type in lean, but not obese, mice.
Authors: Lewis-Sanders, D.; Bullich, S.; Olvera, M. J.; Vo, J.; Hwang, Y.-S.; Stern, S. A.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2024-01-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.31.573797
Associative learning can drive many different types of behaviors, including food consumption. Previous studies have shown that cues paired with food delivery while mice are hungry will lead increased consumption in the presence of those cues at later times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Viral proteins activate PARIS-mediated tRNA degradation and viral tRNAs rescue infection
Authors: Burman, N.; Belukhina, S.; Depardieu, F.; Wilkinson, R. A.; Skutel, M.; Santiago-Frangos, A.; Graham, A. B.; Livenskyi, A.; Chechenina, A.; Morozova, N.; Zahl, T.; Henriques, W. S.; Buyukyoruk, M.; Rouillon, C.; Shyrokova, L.; Kurata, T.; Hauryliuk, V.; Severinov, K.; Groseille, J.; Thierry, A.; Koszul, R.; Tesson, F.; Bernheim, A.; Bikard, D.; Wiedenheft, B.; Isaev, A.
Score: 60.2, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Antigen-display exosomes provide adjuvant-free protection against SARS-CoV-2 disease at nanogram levels of spike protein
Authors: Guo, C.; Sachithanandham, J.; Zhong, W.; Craney, M.; Villano, J.; Pekosz, A.; Gould, S.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.574272
As the only bionormal nanovesicle, exosomes have high potential as a nanovesicle for delivering vaccines and therapeutics. We show here that the loading of type-1 membrane proteins into the exosome membrane is induced by exosome membrane anchor domains, EMADs, that maximize protein delivery to the plasma membrane, minimize protein sorting to other compartments, and direct proteins into exosome membranes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>PCA-Plus: Enhanced principal component analysis with illustrative applications to batch effects and their quantitation
Authors: Zhang, N.; Casasent, T. D.; Casasent, A. K.; Kumar, S. V.; Wakefield, C.; Broom, B. M.; Weinstein, J. N.; Akbani, R.
Score: 46.6, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.573793
BackgroundPrincipal component analysis (PCA), a standard approach to analysis and visualization of large datasets, is commonly used in biomedical research for detecting similarities and differences among groups of samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Single-molecule detection and super-resolution imaging with a portable and adaptable 3D-printed microscopy platform (Brick-MIC)
Authors: Moya Munoz, G. G.; Brix, O.; Klocke, P.; Wendler, N. D.; Lerner, E.; Zijlstra, N.; Cordes, T.
Score: 15.4, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.573596
Over the past decades, single-molecule spectroscopy and super-resolution microscopy have advanced significantly and by now represent important tools for life science research. Despite rapid progress and ongoing development, there is a growing gap between the state-of-the-art and what is accessible to non-optics specialists, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>CREB activation drives acinar to ductal reprogramming and promote pancreatic cancer progression in animal models of alcoholic chronic pancreatitis
Authors: Srinivasan, S.; Mehra, S.; Bianchi, A.; Singh, S.; Dosch, A. R.; Amirian, H.; Jinka, S.; Krishnamoorthy, V.; Silva, I. D. C.; Box, E. W.; Garrido, V.; Totiger, T. M.; Zhou, Z.; Ban, Y.; Datta, J.; VanSaun, M.; Merchant, N.; Nagathihalli, N.
Score: 11.2, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574376
BACKGROUND AND AIMSIn vivo induction of alcoholic chronic pancreatitis (ACP) causes significant acinar damage, increased fibroinflammatory response, and heightened activation of cyclic response element binding protein 1 (CREB) when compared with alcohol (A) or chronic pancreatitis (CP) mediated pancreatic damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Association between Cardiovascular Disease Risk and long COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis
Authors: Huang, Y.; Wen, Z.; Luo, H.; Liao, Y.; Chen, Z.
Score: 37.4, Published: 2023-12-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300656
ObjectivateTo assess demographic characteristics and investigate the correlation between cardiovascular diseases and long COVID-19 patients. MethodsComprehensive details, encompassing the first authors name, publication year, sample inclusion criteria, sample size, and demographic characteristics, including age and gender of participants, were systematically extracted from all incorporated studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Human cytomegalovirus deploys molecular mimicry to recruit VPS4A to sites of virus assembly
Authors: Butt, B. G.; Fischer, D.; Rep, A. R.; Schauflinger, M.; Read, C.; Bock, T.; Hirner, M.; Graham, S. C.; von Einem, J.
Score: 16.0, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.572781
The AAA-type ATPase VPS4 is recruited by proteins of the endosomal sorting complex required for transport III (ESCRT-III) to catalyse membrane constriction and membrane fission. VPS4A accumulates at the cytoplasmic viral assembly complex (cVAC) of cells infected with human cytomegalovirus (HCMV), the site where nascent virus particles obtain their membrane envelope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell transcriptional dynamics in a living vertebrate
Authors: Eck, E.; Moretti, B.; Schlomann, B. H.; Bragantini, J.; Lange, M.; Zhao, X.; VijayKumar, S.; Valentin, G.; Loureiro, C.; Soroldoni, D.; Royer, L. A.; Oates, A. C.; Garcia, H. H.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574108
The ability to quantify transcriptional dynamics in individual cells via live imaging has revolutionized our understanding of gene regulation. However, such measurements are lacking in the context of vertebrate embryos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Climate change, age acceleration, and the erosion of fitness in polar bears
Authors: Newediuk, L.; Richardson, E. S.; Biddlecombe, B. A.; Kassim, H.; Kathan, L.; Lunn, N.; Rivkin, L. R.; Salama, O. E.; Schmidt, C.; Jones, M. J.; Garroway, C. J.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574416
Rapid climate change is expected to impose strong selective pressures on wild populations, disrupting evolved life history strategies and limiting population viability1. The magnitude and pace at which environments will change means the persistence of wild populations will depend substantially on their ability to adapt genetically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 61.6, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Adverse Events Following SARS-CoV-2 mRNA Vaccination in Adolescents: A Norwegian Nationwide Register-Based Study
Authors: Bergstad Larsen, V.; Gunnes, N.; Gran, J. M.; Boas, H.; Dahl, J.; Viksmoen Watle, S.; Berild, J. D.; Greve-Isdahl, M.; Stoerdal, K.; Gulseth, H.; Karlstad, O.; Lopez-Doriga Ruiz, P.; Tapia, G.
Score: 739.0, Published: 2023-12-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.23299926
BackgroundVaccination of older adolescents against severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) started in the spring of 2021 and continued with younger adolescents throughout the summer and fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA methylation enables recurrent endogenization of giant viruses in an animal relative
Authors: Sarre, L. A.; Kim, I. V.; Ovchinnikov, V.; Olivetta, M.; Suga, H.; Dudin, O.; Sebe-Pedros, A.; de Mendoza, A.
Score: 38.7, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.574619
5-methylcytosine (5mC) is a widespread silencing mechanism that controls genomic parasites. However, in many eukaryotes 5mC has gained complex roles in gene regulation beyond parasite control. Animals are a quintessential case for 5mC evolution, as they show widespread variability across lineages, ranging from gene regulation and transposable element control to loss of this base modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Valid inference for machine learning-assisted GWAS
Authors: Miao, J.; Wu, Y.; Sun, Z.; Miao, X.; Lu, T.; Zhao, J.; Lu, Q.
Score: 20.8, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300779
Machine learning (ML) has revolutionized analytical strategies in almost all scientific disciplines including human genetics and genomics. Due to challenges in sample collection and precise phenotyping, ML-assisted genome-wide association study (GWAS) which uses sophisticated ML to impute phenotypes and then performs GWAS on imputed outcomes has quickly gained popularity in complex trait genetics research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Gene-environment correlation: The role of family environment in academic development
Authors: Zhou, Q.; Gidziela, A.; Allegrini, A. G.; Cheesman, R.; Wertz, J.; Maxwell, J.; Plomin, R.; Rimfeld, K.; Malanchini, M.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574339
Academic achievement is partly heritable and highly polygenic. However, genetic effects on academic achievement are not independent of environmental processes. We investigated whether aspects of the family environment mediated genetic effects on academic achievement across development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive and accurate genome analysis at scale using DRAGEN accelerated algorithms
Authors: Behera, S.; Catreux, S.; Rossi, M.; Truong, S.; Huang, Z.; Ruehle, M.; Visvanath, A.; Parnaby, G.; Roddey, C.; Onuchic, V.; Cameron, D. L.; English, A.; Mehtalia, S.; Han, J.; Mehio, R.; Sedlazeck, F. J.
Score: 54.0, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.573821
Research and medical genomics require comprehensive and scalable solutions to drive the discovery of novel disease targets, evolutionary drivers, and genetic markers with clinical significance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of higher uptake of plant-based diets in England: model-based estimates of health care resource use and health-related quality of life
Authors: Henderson, N.; Sampson, C. J.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300536
Plant-based diets have grown in popularity in recent years, in part because of the perceived health benefits; higher consumption of vegetables and other healthy foods is associated with better nutrition and reduced risk of disease. In this study, we estimate the potential impact of higher uptake of a 100% plant-based (vegan) diet in England from the perspective of the National Health Service (NHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Automated Classification of At-home SARS-CoV-2 Lateral Flow Assay Test Results using Image Matching and Transfer Learning: multiple-pipeline study
Authors: Safarzadeh, M.; Herbert, C.; Wong, S. K.; Stamegna, P.; Guilarte-Walker, Y.; Wright, C.; Suvarna, T.; Nowak, C.; Kheterpal, V.; Pandey, S.; Wang, B.; Lin, H.; O&amp;#39;Connor, L.; Hafer, N.; Luzuriaga, K.; Manabe, Y.; Broach, J.; Zai, A. H.; McManus, D. D.; Du, X.; Soni, A.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Network Modelling for the Clinical Diagnosis of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Bate St Cliere, A.-R.; Fenton, N.
Score: 3.4, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.30.23300452
Alzheimers disease (AD) is a progressively debilitating disease commonly affecting the elderly. Correct diagnosis is important for patients to access suitable therapies and support that can help improve or manage symptoms of the condition. Reports of misdiagnosis and difficulty diagnosing AD highlight existing clinical challenges. Here we propose a Bayesian network as a preliminary model for a complementary clinical diagnostic tool for dementia due to AD and mild cognitive impairment due to AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Gene dysregulation among virally suppressed people living with HIV links to non-AIDS defining cancer pathways
Authors: Quach, B. C.; Earley, E.; Zhou, L.; Willis, C.; Marks, J. A.; Stratford, J. K.; Fang, F.; Bierut, L. J.; Milloy, M.-J. S.; Hayashi, K.; DeBeck, K.; Hancock, D. B.; Xu, K.; Aouizerat, B. E.; Johnson, E. O.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300792
Combination antiretroviral therapy (ART) has changed the landscape of the HIV epidemic by providing an effective means for viral suppression to people living with HIV (PLWH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Engineering self-propelled tumor-infiltrating CAR T cells using synthetic velocity receptors
Authors: Johnston, A. C.; Alicea, G. M.; Lee, C. C.; Patel, P. V.; Hanna, E. A.; Vaz, E.; Forjaz, A.; Wan, Z.; Nair, P. R.; Lim, Y.; Chen, T.; Du, W.; Kim, D.; Nichakawade, T. D.; Rebecca, V. W.; Bonifant, C. L.; Fan, R.; Kiemen, A. L.; Wu, P.-H.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 158.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.13.571595
Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells express antigen-specific synthetic receptors, which upon binding to cancer cells, elicit T cell anti-tumor responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Immunological imprinting shapes the specificity of human antibody responses against SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Johnston, T. S.; Li, S. H.; Painter, M. M.; Atkinson, R. K.; Douek, N. R.; Reeg, D. B.; Doueck, D. C.; Wherry, E. J.; Hensley, S. E.
Score: 24.5, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24301002
The spike glycoprotein of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) continues to accumulate substitutions, leading to breakthrough infections of vaccinated individuals and prompting the development of updated booster vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>UK medical students&amp;#39; self-reported knowledge and harm assessment of psychedelics and their application in clinical research: a cross-sectional study
Authors: Song-Smith, C.; Jacobs, E.; Rucker, J.; Saint, M.; Cooke, J.; Schlosser, M.
Score: 11.1, Published: 2023-12-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300364
ObjectiveTo capture UK medical students self-reported knowledge and harm assessment of psychedelics and to explore the factors associated with support for changing the legal status of psychedelics to facilitate further research. DesignCross-sectional, anonymous online survey of UK medical students using a non-random sampling method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Lethal Infection of Human ACE2-Transgenic Mice Caused by SARS-CoV-2-related Pangolin Coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 1039.7, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) can cause 100% mortality in human ACE2-transgenic mice, potentially attributable to late-stage brain infection. This underscores a spillover risk of GX_P2V into humans and provides a unique model for understanding the pathogenic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2-related viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>A universal molecular mechanism driving aging
Authors: Jin, W.; Zheng, J.; Xiao, Y.; Ju, L.; Chen, F.; Fu, J.; Jiang, H.; Zhang, Y.
Score: 41.4, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.06.574476
How cell replication ultimately results in aging and the Hayflick limit are not fully understood. Here we show that clock-like accumulation of DNA G-quadruplexes (G4s) throughout cell replication drives conserved aging mechanisms. G4 stimulates transcription-replication interactions to delay genome replication and impairs DNA re-methylation and histone modification recovery, leading to loss of heterochromatin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Effects of changes in calculating GFR using KDIGO standards: Discordance in the Staging and Timing of Diagnosis of Chronic Kidney Disease
Authors: Baker, C.; Gratzl, S.; Rodriguez, P. J.; simonov, m.; Cartwright, B.; brar, r.; Stucky, N.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.21.23300415
IntroductionChronic kidney disease (CKD) is a highly prevalent disease with disparities in diagnosis and treatment. Until recently, primary diagnosis for CKD was based on equations that incorporated race and have demonstrated racial bias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Noradrenergic modulation of saccades in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Orlando, I. F.; Hezemans, F. H.; Ye, R.; Murley, A. G.; Holland, N.; Regenthal, R.; Barker, R. A.; Williams Gray, C. H.; Passamonti, L.; Robbins, T.; Rowe, J.; O&amp;#39;Callaghan, C.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.24300879
Noradrenaline is a powerful modulator of cognitive processes, including action-decisions underlying saccadic control. Changes in saccadic eye movements are common across neurodegenerative diseases of ageing, including Parkinsons disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Mitochondrial reverse electron transport in myeloid cells perpetuates neuroinflammation
Authors: Peruzzotti-Jametti, L.; Willis, C. M.; Hamel, R.; Krzak, G.; Reisz, J. A.; Prag, H. A.; Wu, V.; Xiang, Y.; van den Bosch, A.; Nicaise, A. M.; Roth, L.; Bates, G. R.; Huang, H.; Vincent, A. E.; Frezza, C.; Viscomi, C.; Marioni, J. C.; D&amp;#39;Alessandro, A.; Takats, Z.; Murphy, M. P.; Pluchino, S.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574059
Sustained smouldering, or low grade, activation of myeloid cells is a common hallmark of several chronic neurological diseases, including multiple sclerosis (MS)1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>Long-term disgust habituation with limited generalisation in care home workers
Authors: Edgar, C.; Chan, F.; Armstrong, T.; Dalmaijer, E. S.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295198
Countless workers handle bodily effluvia and body envelope violations every working day, and consequentially face deeply unpleasant levels of disgust. Understanding if and how they adapt can help inform policies to improve worker satisfaction and reduce staff turnover. So far, limited evidence exist that self-reported disgust is reduced (or lower to begin with) among those employed in high-disgust environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 61.2, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 157.8, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Heat stress-induced heat shock protein 70 (HSP70) expressions among vulnerable populations in urban and rural areas Klang Valley, Malaysia
Authors: Muhamad, S. N.; how, v.; Md Akim, A.; Lim, F. L.; Mohd Shabri, N. S. A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.23300317
As climate change raises global temperatures, there remains a notable gap in understanding the bodys mechanism of the heat stress defense exhibited by Heat Shock Protein (HSP) within the populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omics profiling with untargeted proteomics for blood-based early detection of lung cancer
Authors: Koh, B.; Liu, M.; Almonte, R.; Ariad, D.; Bundalian, G.; Chan, J.; Choi, J.; Chou, W.-F.; Cuaresma, R.; Hoedt, E.; Hopper, L.; Hu, Y.; Jain, A.; Khaledian, E.; Khin, T.; Kokate, A.; Lee, J.-Y.; Leung, S.; Lin, C.-H.; Marispini, M.; Malekpour, H.; Mora, M.; Mudaliar, N.; Nouri Golmaei, S.; Ramaiah, M.; Ramaswamy, S.; Ranjan, P.; Shu, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>A Novel Fluorescent Immuno-Lectin Assay to Identify Osteoarthritis Associated Glycoforms of Lubricin
Authors: Afshari, A. R.; Thomsson, K. A.; Hoglund, J.; Ryberg, H.; Gidwani, K.; Pettersson, K.; Rolfson, O.; Bjorkman, L. I.; Eisler, T.; Schmidt, T. A.; Jay, G. D.; Karlsson, N. G.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-01-03 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.02.23300279
Lubricin or proteoglycan-4 (PRG-4) is a mucinous glycoprotein lubricating the cartilage and maintaining normal tissue function and cell-homeostasis. Altered O-glycoforms of lubricin has been found in osteoarthritis (OA) synovial fluid (SF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>STAT4 Phosphorylation of T-helper Cells predicts surgical outcomes in Refractory Chronic Rhinosinusitis
Authors: Abidin, M.; Alpan, O.; Plassmeyer, M.; Kozhaya, L.; Loizou, D.; Dogan, M.; Upchurch, Z.; Manes, N.; Nita-Lazar, A.; Unutmaz, D.; Sonder, S. U.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-12-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299743
Objective: Chronic rhinosinusitis (CRS) impacts an estimated 5% to 15% of people worldwide, incurring significant economic healthcare burden. There is a urgent need for the discovery of predictive biomarkers to improve treatment strategies and outcomes for CRS patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The Molecular Signature of Neuropathic Pain in a Human Model System
Authors: Sandy-Hindmarch, O.; Chang, P.-S.; Scheuren, P. S.; De Schoenmacker, I.; Hubli, M.; Loizou, C.; Wirth, S.; Mahadevan, D.; Wiberg, A.; Furniss, D.; Denk, F.; Baskozos, G.; Schmid, A.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.23299847
Peripheral neuropathic pain remains challenging to treat, partly due to our limited understanding of the molecular mechanisms at play in humans. In this multicentre cohort study, we describe the local molecular signature of neuropathic pain at the lesion site, using peripheral nerves of patients with Mortons neuroma as a human model system of neuropathic pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Longer mandible or nose? Co-evolution of feeding organs in early elephantiforms
Authors: Li, C.; Deng, T.; Wang, Y.; Sun, F.; Wolff, B.; Jiangzuo, Q.; Ma, J.; Xing, L.; Fu, J.; Zhang, J.; Wang, S.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2024-01-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.553347
The long-trunked elephantids underwent a significant evolutionary stage characterized by an exceptionally elongated mandible. The initial elongation and subsequent regression of the long mandible, along with its co-evolution with the trunk, present an intriguing issue that remains incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Innate Immune Activation and Mitochondrial ROS Invoke Persistent Cardiac Conduction System Dysfunction after COVID-19
Authors: Ashok, D.; Liu, T.; Criscione, J.; Prakash, M.; Kim, B.; Chow, J.; Craney, M.; Papanicolaou, K.; Sidor, A.; Foster, D. B.; Pekosz, A.; Villano, J.; Kim, D.-H.; O&amp;#39;Rourke, B.
Score: 18.1, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574280
BackgroundCardiac risk rises during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and in long COVID syndrome in humans, but the mechanisms behind COVID-19-linked arrhythmias are unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Agonist efficacy at the B2AR is driven by agonist-induced differences in receptor affinity for the Gs protein, not ligand binding kinetics.
Authors: Harwood, C. R.; Sykes, D. A.; Redfern-Nichols, T.; Ladds, G.; Briddon, S. J.; Veprintsev, D.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2024-01-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574357
IntroductionThe {beta}2-adrenoceptor ({beta}2AR) is a class A G protein-coupled receptor (GPCR). It is therapeutically relevant in asthma, whereby {beta}2AR agonists relieve bronchoconstriction. The {beta}2AR is a prototypical GPCR for structural and biophysical studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Sweet and fatty symbionts: photosynthetic productivity and carbon storage boosted in microalgae within a host
Authors: Catacora Grundy, A.; Chevalier, F.; Yee, D.; LeKieffre, C.; Schieber, N.; Schwab, Y.; Gallet, B.; Jouneau, P.-H.; Curien, G.; Decelle, J.
Score: 25.6, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572971
Symbiosis between a host and intracellular eukaryotic microalgae is a widespread life strategy in aquatic ecosystems. This partnership is considered to be mainly energized by the photosynthetically-derived carbon energy of microalgal symbionts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The origin, deployment, and evolution of a plant-parasitic nematode effectorome
Authors: Molloy, B.; Shin, D. S.; Long, J.; Pellegrin, C.; Senatori, B.; Vieira, P.; Thorpe, P. J.; Damm, A.; Ahmad, M.; Vermeulen, K.; Derevnina, L.; Wei, S.; Sperling, A.; Reyes Estevez, E.; Bruty, S.; de Souza, V. H. M.; Kranse, O. P.; Maier, T.; Baum, T.; Eves-van den Akker, S.
Score: 39.8, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574317
Plant-parasitic nematodes constrain global food security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Risk and early signs of PTSD in people indirectly exposed to October 7 events
Authors: Yamin, D.; Lev-Ari, S.; Mofaz, M.; Elias, R.; Spiegel, D.; Yechezkel, M.; L. Brandeau, M.; Shmueli, E.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-12-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.15.23300048
The coordinated terrorist attacks on October 7, 2023, resulted in catastrophic atrocities, and marked the beginning of the 2023 Israel-Hamas war. The overwhelming coverage by mainstream and social media, characterized by extreme details and graphic images, vividly transported viewers to the horrifying scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Barriers to healthcare access: findings from a co-produced Long Covid case-finding study
Authors: Clutterbuck, D.; Ramasawmy, M.; Pantelic, M.; Hayer, J.; Begum, F.; Faghy, M.; Nasir, N.; Causer, B.; Heightman, M.; Allsopp, G.; Wootton, D.; Khan, M. A.; Hastie, C.; Jackson, M.; Rayner, C.; Brown, D.; Parrett, E.; Jones, G.; Clarke, R.; Mcfarland, S.; Gabbay, M.; Banerjee, A.; Alwan, N. A.; STIMULATE-ICP Consortium, Score: 93.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300767</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 15.9, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Immersive Virtual Reality Games in Neuromotor Rehabilitation with Brain-Computer Interfaces: A Scoping Review
Authors: Gaafer, M. N.; Ahmed, Z. M.; El-Husseiny, A. S.; Youssef, A. R.; Al-Kabbany, A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.08.24300991
The use of immersive virtual reality (VR) is gaining traction among the scientific community as it opens great opportunities in the field of rehabilitation. By making use of video game mechanics and Brain computer interface (BCI) that is based on electroencephalography (EEG) signals, patients undergoing neurorehabilitation can be more engaged in rehabilitation training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Causal Relationships Between Diabetes Mellitus and Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis
Authors: Moss, S. T.; Minelli, C.; Leavy, O. C.; Allen, R. J.; Oliver, N.; Wain, L. V.; Jenkins, R. G.; Stewart, I.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.04.24300827
RationaleIdiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF) is a disease of progressive lung scarring. There is a known association between IPF and diabetes mellitus (DM), but it is unclear whether this association is due to causal relationships between these traits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Best Paper awards lack transparency, inclusivity, and support for Open Science
Authors: Lagisz, M.; Rutkowska, J.; Aich, U.; Ross, R. M.; Santana, M. S.; Wang, J.; Trubanova, N.; Page, M. J.; Pua, A. A. Y.; Yang, Y.; Amin, B.; Martinig, A. R.; Barnett, A.; Surendran, A.; Zhang, J.; Borg, D. N.; Elisee, J.; Wrightson, J. G.; Nakagawa, S.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.571170
Awards can propel academic careers. They also reflect the culture and values of the scientific community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reconstructing cell histories in space with image-readable base editor recording
Authors: Chadly, D. M.; Frieda, K. L.; Gui, C.; Klock, L.; Tran, M.; Sui, M. Y.; Takei, Y.; Bouckaert, R.; Lois, C.; Cai, L.; Elowitz, M. B.
Score: 102.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.573434
Knowing the ancestral states and lineage relationships of individual cells could unravel the dynamic programs underlying development. Engineering cells to actively record information within their own genomic DNA could reveal these histories, but existing recording systems have limited information capacity or disrupt spatial context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open-ST: High-resolution spatial transcriptomics in 3D
Authors: Schott, M.; Leon-Perinan, D.; Splendiani, E.; Strenger, L.; Licha, J. R.; Pentimalli, T. M.; Schallenberg, S.; Alles, J.; Samut Tagliaferro, S.; Boltengagen, A.; Ehrig, S.; Abbiati, S.; Dommerich, S.; Pagani, M.; Ferretti, E.; Macino, G.; Karaiskos, N.; Rajewsky, N.
Score: 78.9, Published: 2023-12-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.22.572554
Spatial transcriptomics (ST) methods have been developed to unlock molecular mechanisms underlying tissue development, homeostasis, or disease. However, there is a need for easy-to-use, high-resolution, cost-efficient, and 3D-scalable methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Wild bird mass mortalities in eastern Canada associated with the Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza A(H5N1) virus, 2022
Authors: Avery-Gomm, S.; Barychka, T.; English, M.; Ronconi, R.; Wilhelm, S. I.; Rail, J.-F.; Cormier, T.; Beaumont, M.; Bowser, C.; Burt, T. V.; Collins, S.; Duffy, S.; Giacinti, J. A.; Gilliland, S.; Giroux, J.-F.; Gjerdrum, C.; Guillemette, M.; Hargan, K. E.; Jones, M.; Kennedy, A.; Kusalik, L.; Lair, S.; Lang, A. S.; Lavoie, R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
