<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Correlation between COVID-19 vaccination and inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders
Authors: Park, Y. H.; Kim, M. H.; Choi, M. G.; Chun, E. M.
Score: 988.2, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298544
ImportanceEarlier research on COVID-19 vaccines identified a range of adverse reactions related to proinflammatory actions that can lead to an excessive immune response and sustained inflammation. However, no study has been conducted on the association between inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders and COVID-19 vaccines. ObjectiveTo investigate the incidence rates of inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders following COVID-19 vaccination and to compare them with those of unvaccinated individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Individual recognition in a jumping spider (Phidippus regius)
Authors: Dahl, C. D.; Cheng, Y.
Score: 47.5, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.567545
Individual recognition is conceptually complex and computationally intense, leading to the general assumption that this social knowledge is solely present in vertebrates with larger brains, while miniature-brained animals in differentiating societies eschew the evolutionary pressure for individual recognition by evolving computationally less demanding class-level recognition, such as kin, social rank, or mate recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Tumor Immune Cell Targeting Chimeras (TICTACs) For Targeted Depletion of Macrophage-Associated Checkpoint Receptors
Authors: Morimoto, M.; Till, N. A.; Bertozzi, C. R.
Score: 33.4, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.570444
Immune cells in the tumor microenvironment are not only powerful regulators of immunosuppression and tumorigenesis, but also represent a dominant cell type, with tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) comprising up to 50% of total cell mass in solid tumors. Immunotherapies such as immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) derive their efficacy from this cancer-immune cell interface, however, immune-related adverse events resulting from systemic blockade remain a significant challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Massively parallel sample preparation for multiplexed single-cell proteomics using nPOP
Authors: Leduc, A.; Koury, L.; Cantlon, J.; Slavov, N.
Score: 37.9, Published: 2023-11-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.27.568927
Single-cell proteomics by mass spectrometry (MS) allows quantifying proteins with high specificity and sensitivity. To increase its throughput, we developed nPOP, a method for parallel preparation of thousands of single cells in nanoliter volume droplets deposited on glass slides. Here, we describe its protocol with emphasis on its flexibility to prepare samples for different multiplexed MS methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>simona: a Comprehensive R package for Semantic Similarity Analysis on Bio-Ontologies
Authors: Gu, Z.
Score: 30.4, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.569758
Bio-ontologies are keys in structuring complex biological information for effective data integration and knowledge representation. In this paper, we present simona, a novel R package for semantic similarity analysis on general bio-ontolgies. Simona implements infrastructures for ontology analysis by offering efficient data structures, fast ontology traversal methods, and elegant visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Interplay between environmental yielding and dynamic forcing regulates bacterial growth
Authors: Hancock, A. M.; Datta, S. S.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.569991
Many bacterial habitats---ranging from gels and tissues in the body to cell-secreted exopolysaccharides in biofilms---are rheologically complex, undergo dynamic external forcing, and have unevenly-distributed nutrients. How do these features jointly influence how the resident cells grow and proliferate? Here, we address this question by studying the growth of Escherichia coli dispersed in granular hydrogel matrices with defined and highly-tunable structural and rheological properties, under different amounts of external forcing imposed by mechanical shaking, and in both aerobic and anaerobic conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Three-dimensional assessments are necessary to determine the true spatial tissue composition of diseased tissues
Authors: Forjaz, A.; Vaz, E.; Romero, V. M.; Joshi, S.; Braxton, A. M.; Jiang, A. C.; Fujikura, K.; Cornish, T.; Hong, S.-M.; Hruban, R. H.; Wu, P.-H.; Wood, L. D.; Kiemen, A. L.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 33.1, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569986
Methods for partially resolved cellular profiling has enabled in-depth quantitative tissue mapping via thinly cut sections to study inter-patient and intra-patient differences in normal human anatomy and disease onset and progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Mechanisms underlying exercise intolerance in Long COVID: an accumulation of multi-system dysfunction
Authors: Jamieson, A.; Al Saikhan, L.; Alghamdi, L.; Hamill Howes, L.; Purcell, H.; Hillman, T.; Heightman, M. J.; Treibel, T. A.; Orini, M.; Bell, R. M.; Scully, M.; Hamer, M.; Chaturvedi, N.; Hughes, A.; Astin, R.; Jones, S.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23299429
The pathogenesis of exercise intolerance and persistent fatigue which can follow an infection with the SARS-CoV-2 virus (&amp;#39;Long COVID&amp;#39;) is not fully understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Universal Cell Embeddings: A Foundation Model for Cell Biology
Authors: Rosen, Y.; Roohani, Y.; Agrawal, A.; Samotorcan, L.; Consortium, T. S.; Quake, S. R.; Leskovec, J.
Score: 83.1, Published: 2023-11-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.28.568918
Developing a universal representation of cells which encompasses the tremendous molecular diversity of cell types within the human body and more generally, across species, would be transformative for cell biology. Recent work using single-cell transcriptomic approaches to create molecular definitions of cell types in the form of cell atlases has provided the necessary data for such an endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Metabolic control of germ layer proportions through regulation of Nodal and Wnt signalling
Authors: Stapornwongkul, K. S.; Hahn, E. M.; Palau, L. S.; Arato, K.; Gritti, N.; Anlas, K.; Polinski, P.; Lopez, M.; Ebisuya, M.; Trivedi, V.
Score: 62.2, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569862
During embryonic development, cells exit pluripotency to give rise to the three germ layers. Metabolic pathways influence cell fate decisions by modulating the epigenetic, transcriptional, and signalling states of cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Seedling microbiota engineering using bacterial synthetic community inoculation on seeds
Authors: Arnault, G.; Marais, C.; Preveaux, A.; Briand, M.; Poisson, A.-S.; Sarniguet, A.; Barret, M.; Simonin, M.
Score: 17.1, Published: 2023-11-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.24.568582
Synthetic Communities (SynComs) are being developed and tested to manipulate plant microbiota and improve plant health. To date, only few studies proposed the use of SynCom on seed despite its potential for plant microbiota engineering. We developed and presented a simple, reproducible and effective seedling microbiota engineering method using SynCom inoculation on seeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical coding of long COVID in primary care 2020-2023 in a cohort of 19 million adults: an OpenSAFELY analysis
Authors: Henderson, A. D.; Butler-Cole, B. F.; Tazare, J.; Tomlinson, L. A.; Marks, M.; Jit, M.; Briggs, A.; Lin, L.-Y.; Carlile, O.; Bates, C.; Parry, J.; Bacon, S. C.; Dillingham, I.; Dennison, W. A.; Costello, R. E.; Wei, Y.; Walker, A. J.; Hulme, W.; Goldacre, B.; Mehrkar, A.; MacKenna, B.; Collaborative, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary change is remarkably constant across timescales
Authors: De Lisle, S.; Svensson, E. I.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-12-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.02.569704
Apparent time-scaling of evolutionary rates presents an evolutionary dilemma; rates of molecular, phenotypic, and lineage diversification scale strongly negatively with timeframe of measurement, raising questions about the processes driving this general pattern. Here we show that much of this apparent temporal scaling is an inevitable outcome of plotting a ratio against its denominator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Proton pump Inhibitor effect on esophageal protein signature of eosinophilic esophagitis, prediction and evaluation of treatment response
Authors: Molina-Jimenez, F.; Ugalde-Trivino, L.; Arias-Gonzalez, L.; Relano-Ruperez, C.; Casabona-Frances, S.; Moreno-Monteagudo, J. A.; Perez-Fernandez, M. T.; Martin-Dominguez, V.; Fernandez-Pacheco, J.; Laserna-Mendieta, E. J.; Munoz-Hernandez, P.; Garcia-Martinez, J.; Munoz, J.; Lucendo, A.; Santander, C.; Majano, P.
Score: 6.2, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298292
BackgroundRecently, we have identified a dysregulated protein signature in the esophageal epithelium of eosinophilic esophagitis (EoE) patients; however, the effect of proton pump inhibitor (PPI) treatment on this signature is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Whole-genome sequencing of half-a-million UK Biobank participants
Authors: The UK Biobank Whole-Genome Sequencing Consortium, ; Li, S.; Carss, K. J.; Halldorsson, B. V.; Cortes, A.
Score: 54.4, Published: 2023-12-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.23299426
Whole-genome sequencing (WGS) provides a comprehensive view of the genome, enabling detection of coding and non-coding genetic variation, and surveying complex regions which are difficult to genotype. Here, we report on whole-genome sequencing of 490,640 UK Biobank participants, building on previous genotyping1 and whole-exome sequencing (WES) efforts2,3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Emergence of RNA-guided transcription factors via domestication of transposon-encoded TnpB nucleases
Authors: Wiegand, T.; Hoffmann, F. T.; Walker, M. W. G.; Tang, S.; Richard, E.; Le, H. C.; Meers, C.; Sternberg, S. H.
Score: 124.6, Published: 2023-11-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.30.569447
Transposon-encoded tnpB genes encode RNA-guided DNA nucleases that promote their own selfish spread through targeted DNA cleavage and homologous recombination1-4. This widespread gene family was repeatedly domesticated over evolutionary timescales, leading to the emergence of diverse CRISPR-associated nucleases including Cas9 and Cas125,6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>The Complete Sequence and Comparative Analysis of Ape Sex Chromosomes
Authors: Makova, K. D.; Pickett, B. D.; Harris, R. S.; Hartley, G. A.; Cechova, M.; Pal, K.; Nurk, S.; Yoo, D.; Li, Q.; Hebbar, P.; McGrath, B. C.; Antonacci, F.; Aubel, M.; Biddanda, A.; Borchers, M.; Bornberg, E.; Bouffard, G. G.; Brooks, S. Y.; Carbone, L.; Carrel, L.; Carroll, A.; Chang, P.-C.; Chin, C.-S.; Cook, D. E.; Craig, S. J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Treating Rheumatoid Arthritis in Zanzibar: a cost effectiveness study comparing conventional, biologic, and targeted-synthetic disease modifying anti-rheumatic drugs
Authors: Said, S. S.; Kühl, M.-J.; Fevang, B.-T. S.; Nystad, T. W.; Johansson, K. A.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299489
To evaluate the cost effectiveness of six disease modifying anti-rheumatic drug (DMARD) treat-to-target treatment strategies for patients with rheumatoid arthritis in Zanzibar. A Markov model was used to calculate the cost-effectiveness of various DMARD strategies in the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis over a three-year period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Infection is Associated with an Increase in New Diagnoses of Schizophrenia Spectrum and Psychotic Disorder: A Study Using the US National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C)
Authors: Rahman, A.; Russell, M.; Zheng, W.; Eckrich, D.; Ahmed, I.; on behalf of the N3C Consortium, Score: 680.9, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299473
Amid the ongoing global repercussions of SARS-CoV-2, its crucial to comprehend its potential long-term psychiatric effects. Several recent studies have suggested a link between COVID-19 and subsequent mental health disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 1103.1, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Hematologic abnormalities after COVID-19 vaccination: A large Korean population-based cohort study
Authors: CHOI, H. S.; KIM, M.-H.; CHOI, M. G.; PARK, J. H.; CHUN, E. M.
Score: 1629.5, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298565
Adverse hematologic events have been reported after COVID-19 vaccination. The objective of this study was to investigate whether hematologic abnormalities develop after COVID-19 vaccination. Retrospective cohort analyses of data from the Korean National Health Insurance Service (KNHIS) database were conducted from July 2022 to August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 JN.1 variant
Authors: Kaku, Y.; Okumura, K.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Kosugi, Y.; Uriu, K.; Hinay, A. A.; Chen, L.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Kobiyama, K.; Ishii, K. J.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Zahradnik, J.; Ito, J.; Sato, K.
Score: 190.7, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570782
The SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 lineage, first identified in August 2023, is phylogenetically distinct from the currently circulating SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB lineages, including EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of key residues in MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 main proteases for resistance against clinically applied inhibitors nirmatrelvir and ensitrelvir
Authors: Krismer, L.; Schoeppe, H.; Rauch, S.; Bante, D.; Sprenger, B.; Naschberger, A.; Costacurta, F.; Fuerst, A.; Sauerwein, A.; Rupp, B.; Kaserer, T.; von Laer, D.; Heilmann, E.
Score: 30.7, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569917
The Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) is an epidemic, zoonotically emerging pathogen initially reported in Saudi Arabia in 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The virtual multiple sclerosis patient: on the clinical-radiological paradox
Authors: Sorrentino, P.; Pathak, A.; Ziaeemehr, A.; Troisi Lopez, E.; Cipriano, L.; Romano, A.; Sparaco, M.; Quarantelli, M.; Banerjee, A.; Sorrentino, G.; Hashemi, M.; Jirsa, V.
Score: 19.7, Published: 2023-12-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.01.23299274
Multiple sclerosis (MS) is typically diagnosed based on the clinical presentation, the presence of structural MRI lesions, and a &amp;#34;no better explanation&amp;#34; criterion. The structural lesions, disseminated in time and space, are a consequence of autoimmune processes leading to the damage of the myelin sheath in the central nervous system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Network-level encoding of local neurotransmitters in cortical astrocytes
Authors: Cahill, M. K.; Collard, M.; Tse, V.; Reitman, M. E.; Etchenique, R.; Kirst, C.; Poskanzer, K. E.
Score: 59.3, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.01.568932
Summary ParagraphAstrocytes--the most abundant non-neuronal cell type in the mammalian brain--are crucial circuit components that respond to and modulate neuronal activity via calcium (Ca2&amp;#43;) signaling1-8. Astrocyte Ca2&amp;#43; activity is highly heterogeneous and occurs across multiple spatiotemporal scales: from fast, subcellular activity3,4 to slow, synchronized activity that travels across connected astrocyte networks9-11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>Influence of Nursing Explanation Skills on Incident Occurrence
Authors: Fujimoto, M.; Shimamura, M.; Yuki, F.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-11-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298399
OBJECTIVESIn routine nursing tasks, providing accurate explanations is vital for the quality of healthcare and patient safety, but empirical data on this are scarce. This study aimed to create a psychological scale and investigate how nursing explanation skills affect healthcare incidents. DESIGNThe study involved psychological scale development and questionnaire surveys based on psychological paradigms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Maternal Fortified Balanced Energy-Protein Supplementation on the Mother-Infant Gut Microbiome: A Sub-Study of the MISAME-III Randomized Controlled Trial
Authors: Deng, L.; Taelman, S.; Olm, M. R.; Toe, L. C.; Balini, E.; Ouedraogo, L.; Bastos-Moreira, Y.; Argaw, A.; Tesfamariam, K.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Ouedraogo, M.; Ganaba, R.; Criekinge, W. v.; Kolsteren, P.; Stock, M.; Lachat, C.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Dailey-Chwalibog, T.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2023-11-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.24.23298964
Biological pathways, including individual gut microbiome are potential barriers for maternal nutritional supplementation to improvement in infant growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A Video Intervention to Improve Patient Understanding of Tumor Genomic Testing in Patients with Cancer
Authors: Veney, D.; Wei, L.; Toland, A. E.; Presley, C. J.; Hampel, H.; Padamsee, T. J.; Lee, C. N.; Irvin, W. J.; Bishop, M.; Kim, J.; Hovick, S. R.; Senter, L.; Stover, D.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299443
BackgroundTumor genomic testing (TGT) has become standard-of-care for most patients with advanced/metastatic cancer. Despite established guidelines, patient education prior to TGT is variable or frequently omitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>Audiovestibular adverse events following COVID-19 vaccinations
Authors: Shetty, A. N.; Morgan, H. J.; Phuong, L. K.; Mallard, J.; Vlasenko, D.; Pearce, C.; Crawford, N. W.; Buttery, J. P.; Clothier, H. J.
Score: 12.0, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298435
ImportanceEvidence regarding audiovestibular adverse events post COVID-19 vaccination to date has been inconclusive regarding a potential etiological association. This study used a multi-data source approach to assess incidence of these events following COVID-19 vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Nanoscale Imaging and Microanalysis of Ice Age Bone Offers New Perspective on &amp;#39;Subfossils&amp;#39; and Fossilization
Authors: Anderson, L. A.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570041
The 3-D structure and organization of type-1 collagen protein and vasculature for a set of ancient permafrost bones is extensively documented at the nanoscale (up to 150,000x magnification) for the first time. The chemical mapping technique ToF-SIMS is additionally used to directly localize chemical signal to these structures; C:N and isotope measurements are also reported for the bulk organic bone matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Disease progression modelling reveals heterogeneity in trajectories of Lewy-type alpha-synuclein pathology
Authors: Mastenbroek, S. E.; Vogel, J. W.; Collij, L. E.; Serrano, G. E.; Tremblay, C.; Young, A. L.; Arce, R. A.; Shill, H. A.; Driver-Dunckley, E. D.; Mehta, S. H.; Belden, C. M.; Atri, A.; Choudhury, P.; Barkhof, F.; Adler, C. H.; Ossenkoppele, R.; Beach, T. G.; Hansson, O.
Score: 12.8, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.569878
Lewy body (LB) disorders, characterized by the aggregation of misfolded -synuclein proteins, exhibit notable clinical heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Dysregulated Platelet Function in Patients with Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19
Authors: Aggarwal, A.; Singh, T. K.; Pham, M.; Godwin, M.; Chen, R.; McIntyre, T. M.; Chung, M. K.; Jennings, C.; Ali, M.; Park, H.; Englund, K.; Khorana, A. A.; Svensson, L.; Kapadia, S. R.; McCrae, K. R.; Cameron, S. J.
Score: 58.6, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545507
BackgroundPost-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC), also referred as Long-COVID, sometimes follows COVID-19, a disease caused by SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Human Heart Failure Alters Mitochondria and Fiber 3D Structure Triggering Metabolic Shifts
Authors: Vue, Z.; Ajayi, P. T.; Neikirk, K.; Murphy, A.; Prasad, P.; Jenkins, B. C.; Vang, L.; Garza-Lopez, E.; Mungai, M.; Marshall, A. G.; Beasley, H. K.; Killion, M.; Parker, R.; Anukodem, J.; Lavine, K.; Ajijola, O.; Mobley, B.; Dai, D.-F.; Exil, V.; Kirabo, A.; Ru Su, Y.; Tomasek, K.; Zhang, X.; Wanjalla, C. N.; Hubert, D. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Characterization of DNA methylation reader proteins of Arabidopsis thaliana
Authors: Cahn, J.; Lloyd, J. P. B.; Karemaker, I. D.; Jansen, P. W.; Pflueger, J.; Duncan, O.; Petereit, J.; Bogdanovic, O.; Millar, H.; Vermeulen, M.; Lister, R.
Score: 33.5, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570080
In plants, cytosine DNA methylation (mC) is largely associated with transcriptional repression of transposable elements, but it can also be found in the body of expressed genes, referred to as gene body methylation (GbM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Comparative Effectiveness of Semaglutide and Tirzepatide for Weight Loss in Adults with Overweight and Obesity in the US: A Real-World Evidence Study
Authors: Rodriguez, P. J.; Cartwright, B.; Gratzl, S.; Baker, C.; Brar, R.; Gluckman, T. J.; Stucky, N.
Score: 485.5, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298775
BackgroundBoth tirzepatide and semaglutide have been shown to reduce weight for patients with overweight or obesity in randomized controlled trials (RCTs). While tirzepatide appears to provide greater weight loss than semaglutide in this population, head-to-head RCTs are not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID is associated with severe cognitive slowing
Authors: Zhao, S.; Martin, E. M.; Reuken, P. A.; Scholcz, A.; Ganse-Dumrath, A.; Srowig, A.; Utech, I.; Kozik, V.; Radscheidt, M.; Brodoehl, S.; Stallmach, A.; Schwab, M.; Fraser, E.; Finke, K.; Husain, M.
Score: 529.9, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.23299331
BackgroundCOVID-19 survivors may suffer from a wide range of chronic cognitive symptoms for months or years as part of post-COVID-19 conditions (PCC). To date, there is no definitive objective cognitive marker for PCC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1087.3, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
Introduction: The two messenger RNA (mRNA) vaccines (Pfizer/BioNTech (BNT162B2) and Moderna (mRNA-1273)) have worldwide been administered in children from 6 months of age and older. Vaccines may have non-specific effects on the risk of other infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Supraspinal control of motoneurons after paralysis enabled by spinal cord stimulation
Authors: Balaguer, J.-M.; Prat-Ortega, G.; Verma, N.; Yadav, P.; Sorensen, E.; de Freitas, R.; Ensel, S.; Borda, L.; Donadio, S.; Liang, L.; Ho, J.; Damiani, A.; Grigsby, E.; Fields, D. P.; Gonzalez-Martinez, J. A.; Gerszten, P. C.; Weber, D. J.; Pirondini, E.; Capogrosso, M.
Score: 16.5, Published: 2023-12-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.29.23298779
Spinal cord stimulation (SCS) restores motor control after spinal cord injury (SCI) and stroke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effect of mRNA vaccination on pulmonary sequelae after mild COVID-19
Authors: Gagiannis, D.; Hackenbroch, C.; Zech, F.; Kirchhoff, F.; Bloch, W.; Junghans, K.; Steinestel, K.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.23299330
BackgroundPrevious studies indicate a protective role for SARS-CoV-2 vaccination against development of pulmonary post-acute sequelae of COVID (PASC). We compared clinical, imaging, histopathology and ultrastructural features of pulmonary PASC with and without prior vaccination in a consecutive cohort of 54 unvaccinated, 17 partially vaccinated and 28 fully vaccinated patients who presented with dyspnea on exertion after mild COVID-19 (without hospitalization).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>A genome-wide association study suggests new susceptibility loci for primary antiphospholipid syndrome
Authors: Casares-Marfil, D.; Martinez-Bueno, M.; Borghi, M. O.; Pons-Estel, G.; PRECISESADS Clinical Consortium, ; Reales, G.; Zuo, Y.; Espinosa, G.; Radstake, T. R. D. J.; van den Hoogen, L. L.; Wallace, C.; Guthridge, J.; James, J.; Cervera, R.; Luigi Meroni, P. L.; Martin, J.; Knight, J.; Alarcon-Riquelme, M.; Sawalha, A. H.
Score: 6.0, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299396</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Evolving patterns of extremely productive publishing behavior across science
Authors: Ioannidis, J.; Collins, T. A.; Baas, J.
Score: 15.5, Published: 2023-11-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.23.568476
We aimed to evaluate how many authors are extremely productive and how their presence across countries and scientific fields has changed during 2000-2022. Extremely productive (EP) authors were defined as those with &amp;gt;60 full papers (articles, reviews, conference papers) published in a single calendar year and indexed in Scopus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A within person randomised trial to investigate the effects of a rigid cervical collar on three-dimensional angular movement and angular acceleration during emergency spinal immobilisation and extrication procedures in elite football (soccer) players: The RESTRICT study.
Authors: Callaghan, M. J.; Hughes, T.; Davin, J.; Hayes, R.; Hough, N.; Torpey, D.; Dawson, S.; Murray, E.; Perry, D.; Lancett, M.; Liu, A.; Jones, R.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-11-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.22.23298822
ObjectiveTo determine the effects of rigid collars on cervical movement and acceleration during triple spinal immobilisation and extrication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Validation of cell-free protein synthesis aboard the International Space Station
Authors: Kocalar, S.; Miller, B. M.; Huang, A.; Gleason, E.; Martin, K.; Foley, K.; Copeland, D. S.; Jewett, M.; Saavedra, E. A.; Kraves, S.
Score: 18.8, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.570403
Cell-free protein synthesis (CFPS) is a rapidly maturing in vitro gene expression platform that can be used to transcribe and translate nucleic acids at the point of need, enabling on-demand synthesis of peptide-based vaccines and biotherapeutics, as well as the development of diagnostic tests for environmental contaminants and infectious agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>A foundational atlas of autism protein interactions reveals molecular convergence
Authors: Wang, B.; Vartak, R.; Zaltsman, Y.; Naing, Z. Z. C.; Hennick, K. M.; Polacco, B. J.; Bashir, A.; Eckhardt, M.; Bouhaddou, M.; Xu, J.; Sun, N.; Lasser, M.; Zhou, Y.; Guiley, K. Z.; Chan, U.; Kaye, J. A.; Khare, P.; Drake, S.; Drury, V.; Burke, D. F.; Gonzalez, S.; Alkhairy, S.; Morris, M.; Baum, T.; Krasnoff, R.; Wang, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Acoustic enrichment of heterogenous circulating tumor cells and clusters from patients with metastatic prostate cancer
Authors: Magnusson, C.; Augustsson, P.; Undvall Anand, E.; Lenshof, A.; Josefsson, A.; Welen, K.; Bjartell, A.; Ceder, Y.; Lilja, H.; Laurell, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.23299128
BackgroundThere are important unmet clinical needs to develop cell enrichment technologies to enable unbiased label-free isolation of both single cell and clusters of circulating tumor cells (CTCs) manifesting heterogeneous lineage specificity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Wolf-dog hybrids arise: new insight into the eastern fringe of the Northern European wolf population
Authors: Tirronen, K. F.; Kuznetsova, A. S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569906
In study, tissue samples of 35 wolves hunted in Russian Karelia and 12 specimens of dogs were used in 2012-2022 for genetic analysis. Among wolves four individuals (11%) were recognized as wolf-dog hybrids (WDH) according to phenotypic characteristics. The analysis of 11 autosomal STR confirmed the hybrid origin of three, and allowed us to exclude one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
