<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Plant-like heliotropism in a photosymbiotic animal
Authors: Lintnerova, E.; Shaw, C.; Keys, M.; Brownlee, C.; Modepalli, V.
Score: 56.9, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565328
Being photosynthetic sessile organisms, plants established heliotropism to track the suns position across the sky and allow their vegetative parts to orient accordingly. Here, we report plant-like heliotropic movement in a photosymbiotic sea anemone Anemonia viridis. Like plants, photosynthesis represents a key energy source in endosymbiotic cnidarians bearing microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>A double-ring of human RAD52 remodels replication forks restricting fork reversal
Authors: Honda, M.; Razzaghi, M.; Gaur, P.; Malacaria, E.; Di Biagi, L.; Aiello, F. A.; Paintsil, E. A.; Stanfield, A.; Deppe, B. J.; Gakhar, L.; Schnicker, N. J.; Spies, M. A.; Pichierri, P.; Spies, M.
Score: 23.4, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566657
Human RAD521,2 is a multifunctional DNA repair protein involved in several cellular events that support genome stability including protection of stalled DNA replication forks from excessive degradation3-7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Lung and liver editing by lipid nanoparticle delivery of a stable CRISPR-Cas9 RNP
Authors: Chen, K.; Han, H.; Zhao, S.; Xu, B.; Yin, B.; Trinidad, M.; Burgstone, B. W.; Murthy, N.; Doudna, J. A.
Score: 25.7, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.566339
Lipid nanoparticle (LNP) delivery of CRISPR ribonucleoproteins (RNPs) has the potential to enable high-efficiency in vivo genome editing with low toxicity and an easily manufactured technology, if RNP efficacy can be maintained during LNP production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Deep generative model deciphers derailed trajectories in acute myeloid leukemia
Authors: Nazaret, A.; Fan, J. L.; Lavallee, V.-P.; Cornish, A. E.; Kiseliovas, V.; Masilionis, I.; Chun, J.; Bowman, R. L.; Eisman, S. E.; Wang, J.; Shi, L.; Levine, R. L.; Mazutis, L.; Blei, D.; Pe&amp;#39;er, D.; Azizi, E.
Score: 56.3, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.566719
Single-cell genomics has the potential to map cell states and their dynamics in an unbiased way in response to perturbations like disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Connecting Chromatin Structures to Gene Regulation Using Dynamic Polymer Simulations
Authors: Fu, Y.; Clark, F. T.; Nomikou, S.; Tsirigos, A.; Lionnet, T.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.566032
The transfer of regulatory information between distal loci on chromatin is thought to involve physical proximity, but key biophysical features of these contacts remain unclear. For instance, it is unknown how close and for how long two loci need to be in order to productively interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic heritability of cell plasticity drives cancer drug resistance through one-to-many genotype to phenotype mapping
Authors: Fernandez-Mateos, J.; Milite, S.; Oliveira, E.; Vlachogiannis, G.; Chen, B.; Yara, E.; Cresswell, G. D.; James, C.; Patruno, L.; Ascolani, G.; Acar, A.; Heide, T.; Spiteri, I.; Graudenzi, A.; Caravagna, G.; Graham, T.; Magnani, L.; Valeri, N.; Sottoriva, A.
Score: 42.9, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567140
Drug resistance is a largely unsolved problem in oncology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Cardiovascular and Neurological Outcomes in Patients Treated with Edoxaban for Atrial Fibrillation and Characteristics in Patients with Cancer
Authors: Cheng, K.-H.; Tu, H.-P.; Cheng, K.-C.; Scherrer-Crosbie, M.; Hsu, T.-Y.
Score: 9.8, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.23297577
BACKGROUNDDirect oral anticoagulants (DOACs) outperform warfarin in vascular and bleeding events in atrial fibrillation (AF) patients. Yet, effects of DOACs on congestive heart failure (CHF) and Alzheimers disease (AD) remain less explored. METHODSUsing the Taiwan National Health Insurance Research Database, a nationwide retrospective cohort study was conducted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic label-free analysis of SARS-CoV-2 infection reveals virus-induced subcellular remodeling.
Authors: Saunders, N.; Monel, B.; Cayet, N.; Archetti, L.; Moreno, H.; Jeanne, A.; Marguier, A.; Wai, T.; Schwartz, O.; Frechin, M.
Score: 72.1, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.567378
Assessing the impact of SARS-CoV-2 on organelle dynamics allows a better understanding of the mechanisms of viral replication. We combine label-free holo-tomographic microscopy (HTM) with Artificial Intelligence (AI) to visualize and quantify the subcellular changes triggered by SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Approach to Measure Alveolar Bone Loss After COVID-19
Authors: Lee, S. W.; Huz, K.; Gorelick, K.; Bina, T.; Matsumura, S.; Yin, N.; Zhang, N.; Naa Ardua Anang, Y.; Li, J.; Servin-DeMarrais, H. I.; McMahon, D. J.; Yin, M. T.; Wadhwa, S.; Lu, H.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298788
Severity of periodontal disease may be determined by measurement of alveolar crestal height (ACH) on dental bitewing radiographs; however, the prevailing method of assessment is through visualization which is time consuming and not a direct measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell spatial proteomics identifies the JAK/STAT pathway as an actionable therapeutic target in lethal cutaneous drug reactions
Authors: Nordmann, T.; Anderton, H.; Hasegawa, A.; Schweizer, L.; Zhang, P.; Stadler, P.-C.; Sinha, A.; Metousis, A.; Rosenberger, F. A.; Zwiebel, M.; Satoh, T. K.; Anzengruber, F.; Tanzer, M. C.; Saito, Y.; Gong, T.; Thielert, M.; Kimura, H.; Silke, N.; Rodriguez, E. H.; Gaetana, R.; Nguyen, H. H.; Gross, A.; Levesque, M. P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Genetically encoded affinity reagents (GEARs): A toolkit for visualizing and manipulating endogenous protein function in vivo.
Authors: Boswell, C. W.; Hoppe, C.; Sherrard, A.; Miao, L.; Kojima, M. L.; Krishna, S.; Musaev, D.; Zhao, N.; Stasevich, T. J.; Giraldez, A. J.
Score: 40.1, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567075
Probing endogenous protein localization and function in vivo remains challenging due to laborious gene targeting and monofunctional alleles. Here, we develop a multifunctional, universal, and adaptable toolkit based on genetically encoded affinity reagents (GEARs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Co-habiting ants and silverfish display a converging feeding ecology
Authors: Parmentier, T.; Baltanas, R. M.; Valdivia, C.; Gaju-Ricart, M.; Boeckx, P.; Lukasik, P.; Wybouw, N.
Score: 12.3, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.567524
O_LISpecies from a great number of animal taxa have specialized to living with social hosts. Depending on their level of specialization, these symbiotic animals are characterized by distinct behavioural, chemical, and morphological traits that enable close heterospecific interactions. Despite its functional importance, our understanding of the feeding ecology of specialized animals living with social hosts remains limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Impact of Mask Mandates on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission: A Case Study of Utah
Authors: Horn, A. C.; Shoemaker, H. E.; Keegan, L. T.
Score: 140.6, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298464
BackgroundThroughout the COVID-19 pandemic, the effectiveness of face masks mandates has been intensely debated. Many methods have been used to demonstrate mask effectiveness, including one that compares the change in reproduction number following implementing and removing face mask mandates1. MethodsUsing data from Utah, we calculated the effect of mask mandates (EFm) in each local health district from before and after three key mandates: the Salt Lake and Summit County (SLSC) mask mandates enacted; the Utah statewide mask mandate enacted; and the Utah statewide mandate was lifted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A non-adaptive explanation for macroevolutionary patterns in the evolution of complex multicellularity
Authors: Bingham, E. P.; Ratcliff, W. C.
Score: 92.1, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.566713
&amp;#34;Complex multicellularity&amp;#34;, conventionally defined as large organisms with many specialized cell types, has evolved five times independently in eukaryotes, but never within prokaryotes. A number hypotheses have been proposed to explain this phenomenon, most of which posit that eukaryotes evolved key traits (e.g., dynamic cytoskeletons, alternative mechanisms of gene regulation, or subcellular compartments) which were a necessary prerequisite for the evolution of complex multicellularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Human enteric nervous system progenitor transplantation restores functional responses in Hirschsprung Disease patient-derived tissue
Authors: Jevans, B.; Cooper, F.; Fatieieva, Y.; Gogolou, A.; Kang, Y.-N.; Restuadi, R.; Vanden Berghe, P.; Adameyko, I.; Thapar, N.; Andrews, P. W.; De Coppi, P.; Tsakiridis, A.; McCann, C. J.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298455
ObjectiveHirschsprung disease (HSCR) is a severe congenital disorder affecting 1:5000 live births. HSCR results from failure of enteric nervous system (ENS) progenitors to fully colonise the gastrointestinal tract during embryonic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Polygenic burden of short tandem repeat expansions promote risk for Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Guo, M. H.; Lee, W.-P.; Vardarajan, B. N.; Schellenberg, G. D.; Phillips-Cremins, J. E.
Score: 27.2, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298623
Studies of the genetics of Alzheimers disease (AD) have largely focused on single nucleotide variants and short insertions/deletions. However, most of the disease heritability has yet to be uncovered, suggesting that there is substantial genetic risk conferred by other forms of genetic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Causal interpretations of family GWAS in the presence of heterogeneous effects
Authors: Veller, C.; Przeworski, M.; Coop, G.
Score: 51.0, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566950
Family-based genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have emerged as a gold standard for assessing causal effects of alleles and polygenic scores. Notably, family studies are often claimed to provide an unbiased estimate of the average causal effect (or average treatment effect; ATE) of an allele, on the basis of an analogy between the random transmission of alleles from parents to children and a randomized controlled trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>An encyclopedia of enhancer-gene regulatory interactions in the human genome
Authors: Gschwind, A. R.; Mualim, K. S.; Karbalayghareh, A.; Sheth, M. U.; Dey, K. K.; Jagoda, E.; Nurtdinov, R. N.; Xi, W.; Tan, A. S.; Jones, H.; Ma, X. R.; Yao, D.; Nasser, J.; Avsec, Z.; James, B. T.; Shamim, M. S.; Durand, N. C.; Rao, S. S. P.; Mahajan, R.; Doughty, B. R.; Andreeva, K.; Ulirsch, J. C.; Fan, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Cost-effective boosting allocations in the post-Omicron era of COVID-19 management
Authors: Le, T. P.; Conway, E.; Akpan, E.; Abell, I.; Abraham, P.; Baker, C. M.; Campbell, P. T.; Cromer, D.; Lydeamore, M. J.; McDonough, Y.; Mueller, I.; Ryan, G.; Walker, C.; Wang, Y.; Carvalho, N.; McVernon, J.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298536
BackgroundFollowing widespread exposure to Omicron variants, COVID-19 has transitioned to endemic circulation. Populations now have diverse infection and vaccination histories, resulting in heterogeneous immune landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>The application of Large Language Models to the phenotype-based prioritization of causative genes in rare disease patients
Authors: KAFKAS, S.; Abdelhakim, M.; Althagafi, A.; Toonsi, S.; Alghamdi, M.; SCHOFIELD, P.; Hoehndorf, R.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298615
Computational methods for identifying gene-disease associations can use both genomic and phenotypic information to prioritize genes and variants that may be associated with genetic diseases. Phenotype-based methods commonly rely on comparing phenotypes observed in a patient with a database of genotype-to-phenotype associations using a measure of semantic similarity, and are primarily limited by the quality and completeness of this database as well as the quality of phenotypes assigned to a patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Exploring virtual funding committee practices in the allocation of National Institute for Health and Care Research funding: A netnographic study
Authors: Blatch-Jones, A. J.; Boxall, C.; Asante, E.; Meadmore, K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23298707
ObjectivesFunding committees, comprising members with a range of knowledge, skills, and experience, are considered integral to the decision-making process of funding organisations for recommending or allocating research funding. However, there is limited research investigating the decision-making processes, the role of members and their social interactions during funding committee meetings conducted both virtually and face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>UBTF Tandem Duplications in Pediatric MDS and AML: Implications for Clinical Screening and Diagnosis
Authors: Barajas, J. M.; Umeda, M.; Contreras, L.; Khanlari, M.; Westover, T.; Walsh, M. P.; Xiong, E.; Yang, C.; Otero, B.; Arribas-Layton, M.; Abdelhamed, S.; Song, G.; Ma, X.; Thomas, M. E.; Ma, J.; Klco, J. M.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298320
Recent genomic studies in adult and pediatric acute myeloid leukemia (AML) demonstrated recurrent in-frame tandem duplications (TD) in exon 13 of upstream binding transcription factor (UBTF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Fast evolution of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 to JN.1 under heavy immune pressure
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Xu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Wang, P.; Wang, J.; Liu, J.; Yu, L.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Wang, Y.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y.
Score: 220.2, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566860
While the BA.2.86 variant demonstrated significant antigenic drift and enhanced ACE2 binding affinity, its ability to evade humoral immunity was relatively moderate compared to dominant strains like EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Post-pandemic memory T-cell response to SARS-CoV-2 is durable, broadly targeted and cross-reactive to hypermutated BA.2.86
Authors: Nesamari, R.; Omondi, M. A.; Hoft, M. A.; Ngomti, A.; Baguma, R.; Nkayi, A. A.; Besethi, A. S.; Magugu, S. F.; Mosala, P.; Walters, A.; Clark, G. M.; Mennen, M.; Skelem, S.; Adriaanse, M.; Grifoni, A.; Sette, A.; Keeton, R. S.; Ntusi, N. A.; Riou, C.; Burgers, W. A.
Score: 31.9, Published: 2023-10-30 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Association Between Beta Blocker and Clinical Outcome in Adult Patients with Sepsis or Septic Shock: Protocol of a Systematic Review and Meta- Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials
Authors: Bhattacharjee, S.; Ernest, E. E.; Maitra, S.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298548
Use of beta-blockers as a part of heart rate control strategy is sepsis and septic shock patients is of great debate. Despite of early encouraging results, no large trial was performed and several subsequent small studies reported conflicting results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>MedEdMENTOR AI: Can artificial intelligence help medical education researchers select theoretical constructs?
Authors: Ow, G.; Rodman, A.; Stetson, G. V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298661
INTRODUCTIONMedical education scholarship often lacks a strong theoretical underpinning, with this gap most often affecting early-career researchers and researchers in the Global South. Large language models (LLMs) have shown considerable promise to augment human writing and creativity in a variety of settings. In this study, we describe the development of MedEdMENTOR -- an online platform for medical education research with a library of over 250 theories -- and the development and evaluation of MedEdMENTOR AI, an LLM containing knowledge from MedEdMENTOR and the first AI mentor for medical education research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron HK.3 variant harboring the &amp;#34;FLip&amp;#34; substitution
Authors: Kosugi, Y.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Putri, O.; Uriu, K.; Kaku, Y.; Hinay, A. A.; Chen, L.; Kuramochi, J.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Ito, J.; Sato, K.
Score: 185.6, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566985
In November 2023, SARS-CoV-2 XBB descendants, including EG.5.1 (XBB.1.9.2.5.1), the currently predominant lineage, are circulating worldwide according to Nextstrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Creation of de novo cryptic splicing for ALS/FTD precision medicine
Authors: Wilkins, O. G.; Chien, M. Z. Y. J.; Wlaschin, J. J.; Pisliakova, M.; Thompson, D.; Digby, H.; Simkin, R. L.; Diaz, J. A.; Mehta, P. R.; Keuss, M. J.; Zanovello, M.; Brown, A.-L.; Harley, P.; Darbey, A.; Karda, R.; Fisher, E. M. C.; Cunningham, T. J.; Le Pichon, C. E.; Ule, J.; Fratta, P.
Score: 47.2, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>A limbic-predominant amnestic neurodegenerative syndrome associated with TDP-43 pathology
Authors: Corriveau-Lecavalier, N.; Botha, H.; Graff-Radford, J.; Switzer, A. R.; Przybelski, S. A.; Wiste, H. J.; Murray, M. E.; Reichard, R. R.; Dickson, D. W.; Nguyen, A.; Ramanan, V.; McCarter, S. J.; Boeve, B. F.; Machulda, M. M.; Fields, J. A.; Stricker, N. S.; Nelson, P. T.; Grothe, M. J.; Knopman, D. S.; Lowe, V. J.; Petersen, R. C.; Jack, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Tonic dopamine and biases in value learning linked through a biologically inspired reinforcement learning model
Authors: Romero Pinto, S.; Uchida, N.
Score: 83.3, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.566580
A hallmark of various psychiatric disorders is biased future predictions. Here we examined the mechanisms for biased value learning using reinforcement learning models incorporating recent findings on synaptic plasticity and opponent circuit mechanisms in the basal ganglia. We show that variations in tonic dopamine can alter the balance between learning from positive and negative reward prediction errors, leading to biased value predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>FooDOxS: A Database of Oxidized Sterols Content in Foods
Authors: Medina-Meza, I. G.; Vaidya, Y.; Barnaba, C.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298592
This research addresses the knowledge gap regarding dietary oxidized lipids (DOxS) in foods classified under the NOVA and WWEIA systems. We present the FooDOxS database, a comprehensive compilation of DOxS content in over 1,680 food items from 120 publications across 25 countries, augmented by internal lab data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Maternal cardiovascular and haematological complications alter the risk associations between environmental exposure and adverse pregnancy outcomes
Authors: Sun, H. Z.; Tang, H.; Zhao, H.; Xiang, Q.; Tian, Y.; van Daalen, K. R.; Tang, K.; Loo, E. X.-L.; Shek, L. P.; Archibald, A. T.; Xu, W.; Guo, Y.; Bai, X.; Zhejiang Environmental and Birth Health Research Alliance (ZEBRA) Collaborative Group, Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298338
Given Chinas recent introduction of the &amp;#34;three-child policy&amp;#34; in response to population ageing1, safeguarding perinatal health has become an urgent priority2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary dynamics of 1,976 lymphoid malignancies predict clinical outcome
Authors: Gabbutt, C.; Duran-Ferrer, M.; Grant, H.; Mallo, D.; Nadeu, F.; Househam, J.; Villamor, N.; Krali, O.; Nordlund, J.; Zenz, T.; Campo, E.; Lopez-Guillermo, A.; Fitzgibbon, J.; Barnes, C. P.; Shibata, D.; Martin-Subero, J. I.; Graham, T. A.
Score: 42.8, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298336
Cancer development, progression, and response to treatment are evolutionary processes, but characterising the evolutionary dynamics at sufficient scale to be clinically-meaningful has remained challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Unsupervised subgrouping of chronic low back pain patients treated in a specialty clinic
Authors: Torres Espin, A.; Keller, A.; Ewing, S.; Bishara, A.; Takegami, N.; Ferguson, A. R.; Scheffler, A.; Hue, T.; Lotzs, J.; Peterson, T.; Zheng, P.; O&amp;#39;Neill, C.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-11-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.04.23298104
BackgroundChronic low back pain (cLBP) is the leading cause of disability worldwide. Current treatments have minor or moderate effects, partly because of the idiopathic nature of most cLBP cases, the complexity of its presentation, and heterogeneity in the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>CCR5/CXCR3 antagonist TAK-779 prevents diffuse alveolar damage of the lung in murine model of the SARS-CoV-2-related acute respiratory distress syndrome
Authors: Chernov, A.; Rodionov, M.; Kazakov, V.; Ivanova, K.; Mesheryakov, F.; Kudriaeva, A.; Gabibov, A.; Telegin, G.; Belogurov, A.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.567145
The acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) secondary to viral pneumonitis is one of the main causes of high mortality in patients with COVID-19 (novel coronavirus disease 2019) - ongoing SARS-CoV-2 infection, reached more than 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Increased Severity of New-onset Type 1 Diabetes in Children and Adolescents during the COVID-19 Pandemic: Experience from a Tertiary Care Center in Serbia
Authors: Jovanovic, D.; Blagojevic, J.; Stanisavljevic, D.; Jesic, M.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2023-11-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.20.23298741
Background and objectives: Public health measures, parental fear of infection, and redeployment of medical resources in response to the COVID-19 pandemic might have led to a decrease in pediatric healthcare access. As a result, a delay in type 1 diabetes diagnosis might have occurred, leading to the worsening of its clinical presentation in the pediatric population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Effects of testosterone and metformin on the GlycanAge index of biological age and the composition of the IgG glycome
Authors: Vinicki, M.; Pribic, T.; Vuckovic, F.; Frkatovic-Hodzic|, A.; Plaza-Andrade, I.; Tinahones, F.; Raffaele, J.; Fernandez-Garcia, J. C.; Lauc, G.
Score: 5.8, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298497
With aging, there is a correlation between a decline in the bodys ability to maintain regular functioning and greater susceptibility to age-related diseases. Therapeutic interventions targeting the underlying biological changes of aging hold promise for preventing or delaying multiple age-related diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>The in vitro functional profiles of fentanyl and nitazene analogs at the μ-opioid receptor - high efficacy is dangerous regardless of signaling bias
Authors: Tsai, M.-H. M.; Chen, L.; Baumann, M. H.; Canals, M.; Javitch, J. A.; Lane, J. R.; Shi, L.
Score: 5.3, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.566672
Novel synthetic opioids (NSOs), including both fentanyl and non-fentanyl analogs that act as the -opioid receptor (MOR) agonists, are associated with serious intoxication and fatal overdose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Fibre-specific mitochondrial protein abundance is linked to resting and post-training mitochondrial content in human muscle.
Authors: Reisman, E.; Botella Ruiz, J.; Huang, C.; Schittenhelm, R. B.; Stroud, D. A.; Granata, C.; Chandrasiri, S.; Ramm, G.; Oorschot, V.; Caruana, N. J.; Bishop, D. J.
Score: 36.4, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2022.10.23.512956
Analyses of mitochondrial adaptations in human skeletal muscle have mostly used whole-muscle samples, where results may be confounded by the presence of a mixture of type I and II muscle fibres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Plant pathogenic fungi hijack phosphate starvation signaling with conserved enzymatic effectors
Authors: McCombe, C. L.; Wegner, A.; Zamora, C. S.; Casanova, F.; Aditya, S.; Greenwood, J. R.; Wirtz, L.; de Paula, S.; England, E.; Shang, S.; Ericsson, D. J.; Oliveira-Garcia, E.; Williams, S. J.; Schaffrath, U.
Score: 26.8, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566975
Phosphate availability modulates plant immune function and regulates interactions with beneficial, phosphate-providing, microbes. Here, we describe the hijacking of plant phosphate sensing by a family of Nudix hydrolase effectors from pathogenic Magnaporthe oryzae and Colletotrichum fungi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Management of Antipsychotics in Primary Care: Insights from Healthcare Professionals and Policy Makers in the UK
Authors: Woodall, A. A.; Abuzour, A. S.; Wilson, S. A.; Mair, F. S.; Buchan, I.; Sheard, S. B.; Atkinson, P.; Joyce, D. W.; Symon, P.; Walker, L. E.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298487
IntroductionAntipsychotic medication is increasingly prescribed to patients with serious mental illness. Patients with serious mental illness often have cardiovascular and metabolic comorbidities, and antipsychotics independently increase the risk of cardiometabolic disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Hidden Toll of Drug-Induced Impulsivity: A Network Analysis of the FDA Adverse Event Reporting System.
Authors: Fusaroli, M.; Polizzi, S.; Menestrina, L.; Giunchi, V.; Pellegrini, L.; Raschi, E.; Weintraub, D.; Recanatini, M.; Castellani, G.; De Ponti, F.; Poluzzi, E.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23298635
IntroductionAdverse drug reactions significantly impact patients lives, yet their influence is often underestimated in treatment decisions and monitoring. Impulsivity induced by dopaminergic agents can lead to impaired social functioning and quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Post-Vaccination Syndrome: A Descriptive Analysis of Reported Symptoms and Patient Experiences After Covid-19 Immunization
Authors: Krumholz, H. M.; Wu, Y.; Sawano, M.; Shah, R.; Zhou, T.; Arun, A. S.; Khosla, P.; Kaleem, S.; Vashist, A.; Bhattacharjee, B.; Ding, Q.; Lu, Y.; Caraballo, C.; Warner, F.; Huang, C.; Herrin, J.; Putrino, D.; Hertz, D.; Dressen, B.; Iwasaki, A.
Score: 708.9, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.23298266
IntroductionA chronic post-vaccination syndrome (PVS) after covid-19 vaccination has been reported but has yet to be well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Spot the Difference: Can ChatGPT4-Vision Transform Radiology Artificial Intelligence?
Authors: Kelly, B. S. S.; Duignan, S.; Mathur, P.; Dillon, H.; Lee, E.; Yeom, K. W.; Keane, P.; Killeen, R. P.; Lawlor, A.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298499
OpenAIs flagship Large Language Model ChatGPT can now accept image input (GPT4V). &amp;#34;Spot the Difference&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;Medical&amp;#34; have been suggested as emerging applications. The interpretation of medical images is a dynamic process not a static task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The effects of inhaled corticosteroids on healthy airways
Authors: Marchi, E.; Hinks, T. S. C.; Richardson, M.; Khalfaoui, L.; Symon, F.; Rajasekar, P.; Clifford, R.; Hagardon, B.; Austin, C. D.; MacIsaac, J.; Kobor, M. S.; Siddiqui, S.; Mar, J. S.; Arron, J. R.; Choy, D.; Bradding, P. H.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298442
RationaleThe effects of inhaled corticosteroids (ICS) on healthy airways are poorly defined. ObjectivesTo delineate the effects of ICS on gene expression in healthy airways, without confounding caused by changes in disease-related genes and disease-related alterations in ICS-responsiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Connectome reorganization associated with temporal lobe pathology and its surgical resection
Authors: Lariviere, S.; Park, B.-y.; Royer, J.; DeKraker, J.; Ngo, A.; Sahlas, E.; Chen, J.; Rodriguez-Cruces, R.; Weng, Y.; Frauscher, B.; Wang, Z.; Misic, B.; Shafiei, G.; Bernasconi, A.; Bernasconi, N.; Fox, M. D.; Zhang, Z.; Bernhardt, B.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298482
Network neuroscience offers a unique framework to understand the organizational principles of the human brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Continuous evolution of user-defined genes at 1-million-times the genomic mutation rate
Authors: Rix, G.; Williams, R. L.; Spinner, H.; Hu, V. J.; Marks, D. S.; Liu, C. C.
Score: 56.5, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566922
When nature maintains or evolves a genes function over millions of years at scale, it produces a diversity of homologous sequences whose patterns of conservation and change contain rich structural, functional, and historical information about the gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Proteome-wide base editor screens to assess phosphorylation site functionality in high-throughput
Authors: Kennedy, P. H.; Deh Sheikh, A. A.; Balakar, M.; Jones, A. C.; Olive, M. E.; Hedge, M.; Matias, M. I.; Pirete, N.; Burt, R.; Levy, J.; Little, T.; Hogan, P. G.; Liu, D. R.; Doench, J. G.; Newton, A. C.; Gottschalk, R. A.; de Boer, C.; Alarcon, S.; Newby, G.; Myers, S. A.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>In situ observation and range extension of the first monoplacophoran Neopilina galatheae
Authors: Chen, C.; Jamieson, J. W.
Score: 58.6, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.08.566290
Monoplacophoran molluscs have been dubbed living fossils due to their absence in the fossil record for about 375 million years, until Neopilina galatheae Lemche, 1957 was trawled off Costa Rica in 1952. Since then, over 35 species of living monoplacophorans have been discovered. Nevertheless, in situ observations of these rare deep-sea animals remain scant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
