<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 61.4, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>DNA end sensing and cleavage by the Shedu anti-phage defense system
Authors: Loeff, L.; Walter, A.; Rosalen, G. T.; Jinek, M.
Score: 29.8, Published: 2023-08-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.552762
The detection of molecular patterns associated with invading pathogens is a hallmark of innate immune systems. Prokaryotes deploy sophisticated host-defense mechanisms in innate anti-phage immunity. Shedu is a single-component defense system comprising a putative nuclease SduA. Here we report cryo-EM structures of apo- and dsDNA-bound tetrameric SduA assemblies, revealing that the N-terminal domains of SduA form a clamp that recognizes free DNA ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>SonoPrint: Acoustically Assisted Volumetric 3D Printing for Composites
Authors: Agrawal, P.; Zhuang, S.; Dreher, S.; Mitter, S.; Ahmed, D.
Score: 9.6, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552292
Advancements in additive manufacturing in composites have transformed various fields in aerospace, medical devices, tissue engineering, and electronics, enabling fine-tuning material properties by reinforcing internal particles and adjusting their type, orientation, and volume fraction. This capability opens new possibilities for tailoring materials to specific applications and optimizing the performance of 3D-printed objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Benchmarking computational methods for single-cell chromatin data analysis
Authors: Luo, S.; Germain, P.-L.; Robinson, M. D.; von Meyenn, F.
Score: 22.2, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.552046
Single-cell chromatin accessibility assays, such as scATAC-seq, are increasingly employed in individual and joint multi-omic profiling of single cells. As the accumulation of scATAC-seq and multi-omics datasets continue, challenges in analyzing such sparse, noisy, and high-dimensional data become pressing. Specifically, one challenge relates to optimizing the processing of chromatin-level measurements and efficiently extracting information to discern cellular heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Approximating conformational Boltzmann distributions with AlphaFold2 predictions
Authors: Brown, B. P.; Stein, R. A.; Meiler, J.; Mchaourab, H.
Score: 24.6, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.552168
Protein dynamics are intimately tied to biological function and can enable processes such as signal transduction, enzyme catalysis, and molecular recognition. The relative free energies of conformations that contribute to these functional equilibria are evolved for the physiology of the organism. Despite the importance of these equilibria for understanding biological function and developing treatments for disease, the computational and experimental methods capable of quantifying them are limited to systems of modest size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 643.5, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Influenza Vaccination and Major Cardiovascular Risk: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Clinical Trials Studies
Authors: Omidi, F.; Zangiabadian, M.; Shahidi Bonjar, A. H.; Nasiri, M. J.; Sarmastzadeh, T.
Score: 5.7, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.23293585
BackgroundCardiovascular events remain a substantial global health concern, necessitating innovative strategies for prevention. This study aims to assess the potential impact of influenza vaccination on major cardiovascular events. MethodsA search of the medical English literature was conducted using PubMed/MEDLINE, EMBASE, and the Cochrane CENTRAL up to 1 August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>The actin binding protein profilin 1 is critical for mitochondria function
Authors: Read, T.-A.; Cisterna, B. A.; Skruber, K.; Ahmadieh, S.; Lindamood, H. L.; Vitriol, J.; Shi, Y.; Lefebvre, A. E. Y. T.; Black, J. B.; Butler, M. T.; Bear, J. E.; Cherezova, A.; Ilatovskaya, D. V.; Weintraub, N. L.; Vitriol, E. A.
Score: 35.2, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552354
Profilin 1 (PFN1) is an actin binding protein that is vital for the polymerization of monomeric actin into filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reversal of Biological Age in Multiple Rat Organs by Young Porcine Plasma Fraction
Authors: Horvath, S.; Singh, K.; Raj, K.; Khairnar, S.; Sanghavi, A.; Shrivastava, A.; Zoller, J. A.; Li, C. Z.; Herenu, C. B.; Canatelli-Mallat, M.; Lehmann, M.; Habazin, S.; Vuckovic, F.; Solberg-Woods, L.; Garcia Martinez, A.; Wang, T.; Chiavellini, P.; Levine, A. J.; Chen, H.; Brooke, R. T.; Gordevicius, J.; Lauc, G.; Goya, R. G.; Katcher, H. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Local climate change velocities explain multidirectional range shifts in a North American butterfly assemblage
Authors: da Silva, C. R. B.; Diamond, S. E.
Score: 6.0, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.551397
Species are often expected to shift their distributions poleward to evade warming climates. However, from 18 years of fixed transect monitoring data on 88 species of butterfly in the midwestern United States, we show that butterflies are shifting their centroids in all directions, except towards regions that are becoming warmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Phenotype-based targeted treatment of SGLT2 inhibitors and GLP-1 receptor agonists in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Cardoso, P.; Young, K. G.; Nair, A. T. N.; Hopkins, R.; McGovern, A. P.; Haider, E.; Karunaratne, P.; Donnelly, L.; Mateen, B. A.; Sattar, N.; Holman, R. R.; Bowden, J.; Hattersley, A.; Pearson, E. R.; Jones, A. G.; Shields, B.; McKinley, T. J.; Dennis, J. M.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.23293636
A precision medicine approach in type 2 diabetes (T2D) could enhance targeting specific glucose-lowering therapies to individual patients most likely to benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected during a SARS-CoV-2 Omicron wave - Australia, 2022
Authors: Woldegiorgis, M.; Cadby, G.; Ngeh, S.; Korda, R.; Armstrong, P.; Maticevic, J.; Knight, P.; Jardine, A.; Bloomfield, L.; Effler, P.
Score: 1366.1, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293706
ObjectiveTo characterise Long COVID in a highly vaccinated population infected by Omicron. DesignFollow-up survey of persons testing positive for SARS-CoV-2 in Western Australia, 16 July-3 August 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Functional Adaptations of Endogenous Retroviruses to the Drosophila Host Underlie their Evolutionary Diversification
Authors: Senti, K.-A.; Handler, D.; Rafanel, B.; Kosiol, C.; Schloetterer, C.; Brennecke, J.
Score: 52.7, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551782
Transposable elements profoundly affect the biology and evolution of their hosts, yet their own evolutionary dynamics remain poorly understood. Here, we investigate insect endogenous retroviruses (iERVs), a monophyletic group of LTR retrotransposons that have acquired the trait of infectivity, likely through capture of a Baculovirus envelope gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Copy-number variants as modulators of common disease susceptibility
Authors: Auwerx, C.; Joeloo, M.; Sadler, M. C.; Tesio, N.; Ojavee, S. E.; Clark, C. J.; Mägi, R.; Estonian Biobank Research Team, ; Reymond, A.; Kutalik, Z.
Score: 16.5, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293408
BackgroundCopy-number variations (CNVs) have been associated with rare and debilitating genomic syndromes but their impact on health later in life in the general population remains poorly described. MethodsAssessing four modes of CNV action, we performed genome-wide association scans (GWASs) between the copy-number of CNV-proxy probes and 60 curated ICD-10 based clinical diagnoses in 331,522 unrelated white UK Biobank participants with replication in the Estonian Biobank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Broad functional profiling of fission yeast proteins using phenomics and machine learning
Authors: Rodriguez-Lopez, M.; Bordin, N.; Lees, J.; Scholes, H.; Hassan, S.; Saintain, Q.; Kamrad, S.; Orengo, C.; Bähler, J.
Score: 68.9, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.05.535764
Many proteins remain poorly characterized even in well-studied organisms, presenting a bottleneck for research. We applied phenomics and machine-learning approaches with Schizosaccharomyces pombe for broad cues on protein functions. We assayed colony-growth phenotypes to measure the fitness of deletion mutants for 3509 non-essential genes in 131 conditions with different nutrients, drugs, and stresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Phage-plasmids promote genetic exchanges between phages and plasmids and create novel ones.
Authors: Pfeifer, E.; Rocha, E. P. C.
Score: 27.5, Published: 2023-08-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552325
Phages and plasmids have key roles in bacterial evolution and are usually very different. Yet, they must recombine, since they sometimes carry nearly identical accessory genes. Phage-plasmids are both plasmids and phages and we found they connect them by being at their interface in the network of gene repertoire relatedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The experience of family carers for people with moderate to advanced dementia within a domestic home setting: a systematically constructed narrative synthesis
Authors: James, C.; Walshe, C.; Swarbrick, C.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293402
BackgroundCaring for someone with moderate to advanced dementia within a domestic home setting can be burdensome and time-consuming. To ensure the effectiveness of care planning and delivery, especially towards the end of life, understanding the nature and impact of such caregiving on the family carer is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Coding Inequity: Assessing GPT-4&amp;#39;s Potential for Perpetuating Racial and Gender Biases in Healthcare
Authors: Zack, T.; Lehman, E.; Suzgun, M.; Rodriguez, J. A.; Celi, L. A.; Gichoya, J.; Jurafsky, D.; Szolovits, P.; Bates, D. W.; Abdulnour, R.-E. E.; Butte, A. J.; Alsentzer, E.
Score: 20.4, Published: 2023-07-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292577
BackgroundLarge language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 hold great promise as transformative tools in healthcare, ranging from automating administrative tasks to augmenting clinical decision- making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Measuring Mental Health in a Cost-of-Living Crisis: a rapid review
Authors: England, C.; Jarrom, D.; Washington, J.; Hasler, E.; Batten, L.; Lewis, R.; Edwards, R. T.; Davies, J.; Collins, B.; Cooper, A.; Edwards, A. G.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293078
Since 2021 the UK has experienced a sharp rise in inflation. For many, wages and welfare payments have not kept up with rising costs, leading to a cost of living crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Study Protocol for the Intraoperative Complications Assessment and Reporting with Universal Standards (ICARUS) Global Cross-Specialty Surveys Among Surgeons, Anesthesiologists, Nurses, Interventional Cardiologists, and Interventional Radiologists
Authors: Cacciamani, G. E.; Sholklapper, T.; Eppler, M. B.; Sayegh, A.; Storino Ramacciotti, L.; Abreu, A. L.; Sotelo, R.; Desai, M. M.; Gill, I. S.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.23293789
Every year, approximately 200 million surgeries are performed worldwide, and intraoperative adverse events (iAEs) have a significant impact on patients and surgeons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Vascular injury markers associated with cognitive impairment in people with HIV on suppressive antiretroviral therapy
Authors: Guha, D.; Misra, V.; Yin, J.; Horiguchi, M.; Uno, H.; Gabuzda, D.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23293053
ObjectiveHuman immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-associated neurocognitive disorders (HAND) remain prevalent despite viral suppression on antiretroviral therapy (ART). Vascular disease contributes to HAND, but peripheral markers that distinguish vascular cognitive impairment (VCI) from HIV-related etiologies remain unclear. DesignCross-sectional study of vascular injury, inflammation, and central nervous system (CNS) injury markers in relation to HAND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Megakaryocyte infection by SARS-CoV-2 drives the formation of pathogenic afucosylated IgG antibodies in mice
Authors: Mabrouk, M.; Jalali, F.; Zaid, N.; Naya, A.; Khyatti, M.; Khalki, L.; Guessous, F.; Zaid, Y.
Score: 697.3, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549113
More than 90% of total human plasma immunoglobulin G (IgG) is found in a fucosylated form, but specific IgGs with low core fucosylation (afucosylated IgGs) are found in response to infections with enveloped viruses and to alloantigens on blood cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Antiviral efficacy of the SARS-CoV-2 XBB breakthrough infection sera against Omicron subvariants including EG.5
Authors: Kaku, Y.; Kosugi, Y.; Uriu, K.; Ito, J.; Kuramochi, J.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Sato, K.
Score: 940.4, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552415
As of July 2023, EG.5.1 (a.k.a. XBB.1.9.2.5.1), a XBB subvariant bearing the S:Q52H and S:F456L substitutions, alongside the S:F486P substitution (Figure S1A), has rapidly spread in some countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Eukaryotic RNA-guided endonucleases evolved from a unique clade of bacterial enzymes
Authors: Yoon, P. H.; Skopintsev, P.; Shi, H.; Chen, L.-X.; Adler, B. A.; Al-Shimary, M.; Craig, R. J.; Li, Z.; Amerasekera, J.; Trinidad, M.; Nisonoff, H.; Chen, K.; Lahiri, A.; Boger, R.; Jacobsen, S.; Banfield, J. F.; Doudna, J. A.
Score: 51.5, Published: 2023-08-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.09.552727
RNA-guided endonucleases form the crux of diverse biological processes and technologies, including adaptive immunity, transposition, and genome editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Personalized chronic adaptive deep brain stimulation outperforms conventional stimulation in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Oehrn, C. R.; Cernera, S.; Hammer, L. H.; Shcherbakova, M.; Yao, J.; Hahn, A.; Wang, S.; Ostrem, J. L.; Little, S.; Starr, P. A.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293450
1.Deep brain stimulation is a widely used therapy for Parkinsons disease (PD) but currently lacks dynamic responsiveness to changing clinical and neural states. Feedback control has the potential to improve therapeutic effectiveness, but optimal control strategy and additional benefits of &amp;#34;adaptive&amp;#34; neurostimulation are unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Learning produces a hippocampal cognitive map in the form of an orthogonalized state machine
Authors: Sun, W.; Winnubst, J.; Natrajan, M.; Lai, C.; Kajikawa, K.; Michaelos, M.; Gattoni, R.; Fitzgerald, J. E.; Spruston, N.
Score: 83.5, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551900
Cognitive maps confer animals with flexible intelligence by representing spatial, temporal, and abstract relationships that can be used to shape thought, planning, and behavior. Cognitive maps have been observed in the hippocampus, but their algorithmic form and the processes by which they are learned remain obscure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Evidence-Based Practice Competencies among Nutrition Professionals and Students: A Systematic Review
Authors: Ghosh, N. R.; Esmaeilinezhad, Z.; Zajac, J.; Creasy, R. A.; Lorenz, S. G.; Crews, M.; Beathard, K. M.; Bala, M. M.; Klatt, K. C.; Johnston, B. C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.23293580
BackgroundEvidence-based practice (EBP) promotes shared decision-making between clinicians and patients and has been widely adopted by various health professions including nutrition &amp;amp; dietetics, medicine and nursing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Validation of Automated Visual Evaluation (AVE) on Smartphone Images for Cervical Cancer Screening in a Prospective Study in Zambia
Authors: Hu, L.; Mwanahamuntu, M. H.; Sahasrabuddhe, V. V.; Barrett, C.; Horning, M. P.; Shah, I.; Laverriere, Z.; Banik, D.; Ji, Y.; Shibemba, A. L.; Chisele, S.; Munalula, M. K.; Kaunga, F.; Musonda, F.; Malyangu, E.; Hariharan, K. M.; Parham, G. P.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292888
I.ObjectivesVisual inspection with acetic acid (VIA) is a low-cost approach for cervical cancer screening in most low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) but lacks objectivity and requires sustained training and quality assurance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Large language models approach expert-level clinical knowledge and reasoning in ophthalmology: A head-to-head cross-sectional study
Authors: Thirunavukarasu, A. J.; Mahmood, S.; Malem, A.; Foster, W. P.; Sanghera, R.; Hassan, R.; Zhou, S.; Wong, S. W.; Wong, Y. L.; Chong, Y. J.; Shakeel, A.; Chang, Y.-H.; Tan, B. K. J.; Jain, N.; Tan, T. F.; Rauz, S.; Ting, D. S. W.; Ting, D. S. J.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Lack of early animal fossils: insights from taphonomic experiments on placozoans and their traces
Authors: Naimark, E.; Lyupina, Y. V.; Nikitin, M. A.; Finoshin, A. D.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551688
Placozoa are simple two-layered multicellular animals. Can such a simple animal preserve in the fossil record? The results of our taphonomic experiments showed that it is chemically possible; however, the chances of the presevation are negligible for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>An end-to-end workflow for non-destructive 3D pathology
Authors: Bishop, K. W.; Barner, L. A. E.; Han, Q.; Baraznenok, E.; Lan, L.; Poudel, C.; Gao, G.; Serafin, R. B.; Chow, S. S. L.; Glaser, A. K.; Janowczyk, A.; Brenes, D.; Huang, H.; Miyasato, D.; True, L. D.; Kang, S.; Vaughan, J. C.; Liu, J. T. C.
Score: 126.0, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551845
Recent advances in 3D pathology offer the ability to image orders-of-magnitude more tissue than conventional pathology while providing a volumetric context that is lacking with 2D tissue sections, all without requiring destructive tissue sectioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>RNA splicing modulator induces peripheral neuropathy with increased neurofilament light chain levels via p53 signaling
Authors: Krach, F.; Boerstler, T.; Reischl, S.; Krumm, L.; Regensburger, M.; Winkler, J.; Winner, B.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-08-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.551640
RNA splicing modulators are a new class of small molecules with the potential to modify the expression levels of proteins. A recent clinical trial investigating the splicing modulator branaplam for Huntingtons disease to lower huntingtin levels was terminated due to the development of peripheral neuropathy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Inflammation causes insulin resistance via interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF3)-mediated reduction in FAHFA levels
Authors: Yan, S.; Santoro, A.; Niphakis, M. J.; Pinto, A. M.; Jacobs, C. L.; Ahmad, R.; Suciu, R. M.; Fonslow, B. R.; Herbst-Graham, R. B.; Ngo, N.; Henry, C. L.; Herbst, D. M.; Saghatelian, A.; Kahn, B. B.; Rosen, E. D.
Score: 6.0, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552481
Obesity-induced inflammation causes metabolic dysfunction, but the mechanisms remain elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Mucilage produced by sorghum (Sorghum bicolor) aerial roots supports a nitrogen-fixing community
Authors: Venado, R. E.; Wilker, J.; Pankievicz, V.; Infante, V.; MacIntyre, A.; Wolf, E.; Vela, S.; Robbins, F. A.; Fernandes-Junior, P. I.; Vermerris, W.; Ane, J.-M.
Score: 74.6, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.05.552127
O_LISorghum (Sorghum bicolor) is gaining popularity as a sustainable energy crop due to its high biomass and potential for biofuel production. Some rare sorghum accessions develop many aerial roots that produce viscous carbohydrate-rich mucilage after rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Examining Differences in the Genetic and Functional Architecture of ADHD Diagnosed in Childhood and Adulthood
Authors: Breunig, S.; Lawrence, J. M.; Foote, I. F.; Gebhardt, H. J.; Willcutt, E. G.; Grotzinger, A. D.
Score: 22.3, Published: 2023-08-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.02.23293439
BackgroundAttention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) is a neurodevelopmental disorder that is diagnosed when symptoms onset in childhood. Here we investigate whether individuals who are diagnosed as children differ from those who are diagnosed in adulthood with respect to shared and unique architecture at the genome-wide, functional, and gene expression level of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Digital Exclusion as a barrier to accessing healthcare: A summary composite indicator and online tool to explore and quantify local differences in levels of exclusion.
Authors: Mee, P.; Gussy, M.; Huntley, P.; Kenny, A.; Jarratt, T.; Kenward, N.; Ward, D.; Vaughan, A.
Score: 15.4, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292547
Digital exclusion leads to marginalization and inequality. A lack of tools to measure local exclusion hampers targeted interventions. In this study a composite indicator for digital exclusion and associated toolkit was developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>The predictive role of pain catastrophising following genicular arterial embolisation for the treatment of mild and moderate knee osteoarthritis
Authors: Harrison, R.; Salomons, T.; MacGill, S.; Little, M.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23290995
Knee osteoarthritis (OA) is the most common form of OA and is not currently considered to be a curable disease. Specifically, mild-to-moderate knee OA that is resistant to conservative treatment, but does not warrant joint replacement, poses a significant clinical problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Randomized attention-placebo controlled trial of a digital self-management platform for adult asthma
Authors: Kandola, A.; Edwards, K.; Straatman, J.; Duehrkoop, B.; Hein, B.; Hayes, J. F.
Score: 53.3, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292865
BackgroundAsthma is one of the most common chronic conditions worldwide, with a substantial individual, societal and healthcare burden. Digital apps hold promise as a highly accessible, low-cost method of enhancing self-management in asthma, which is critical to effective asthma control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Somatic TET2 Mutations are Associated with Giant Cell Arteritis
Authors: Robinette, M. L.; Weeks, L. D.; Kramer, R. J.; Agrawal, M.; Gibson, C. J.; Yu, Z.; Sekar, A.; Mehta, A.; Niroula, A.; Brown, J. T.; McDermott, G. C.; Reshef, E. R.; Lu, J. E.; Liou, V. D.; Chiou, C. A.; Natarajan, P.; Freitag, S. K.; Rao, D. A.; Ebert, B. A.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23292945
ObjectiveGiant cell arteritis (GCA) is an age-related vasculitis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Purchases dominate the carbon footprint of research laboratories
Authors: De Paepe, M.; Jeanneau, L.; Mariette, J.; Aumont, O.; Estevez-Torres, A.
Score: 33.7, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.04.535626
Despite increasing interest for the carbon footprint of higher education institutions, little is known about the carbon footprint associated to research activities. Air travel and attendance to conferences concentrate recent data and debates but purchases have attracted little attention. Here we develop a hybrid method to estimate the greenhouse gas emissions (GHG) associated to research purchases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Scoping Review of One-Dimension Statistical Parametric Mapping in Lower Limb Biomechanical Analysis
Authors: Yona, T.; Kamel, N.; Cohen-Eick, G.; Ovadia, I.; Fischer, A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.06.23293709
BackgroundBiomechanics is crucial in enhancing sports performance and preventing injury. Traditionally, discrete point analysis is used to analyze important kinetic and kinematic data points, reducing continuous data to a single point. One-dimensional Statistical Parametric Mapping (spm1d) offers a more comprehensive approach by assessing entire movement curves instead of isolated peak values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Machine-guided design of synthetic cell type-specific cis-regulatory elements
Authors: Gosai, S. J.; Castro, R. I.; Fuentes, N.; Butts, J. C.; Kales, S.; Noche, R. R.; Mouri, K.; Sabeti, P. C.; Reilly, S. K.; Tewhey, R.
Score: 55.9, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.08.552077
Cis-regulatory elements (CREs) control gene expression, orchestrating tissue identity, developmental timing, and stimulus responses, which collectively define the thousands of unique cell types in the body. While there is great potential for strategically incorporating CREs in therapeutic or biotechnology applications that require tissue specificity, there is no guarantee that an optimal CRE for an intended purpose has arisen naturally through evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic discovery of protein interaction interfaces using AlphaFold and experimental validation
Authors: Lee, C. Y.; Hubrich, D.; Varga, J. K.; Schäfer, C.; Welzel, M.; Schumbera, E.; Đokic, M.; Strom, J. M.; Schönfeld, J.; Geist, J. L.; Polat, F.; Gibson, T. J.; Keller Valsecchi, C. I.; Kumar, M.; Schueler-Furman, O.; Luck, K.
Score: 45.9, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552219
Structural resolution of protein interactions enables mechanistic and functional studies as well as interpretation of disease variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms in a prospective cohort of COVID-19 survivors
Authors: Gomes, C. M.; Hisano, M.; Souza, J. D.; Henriques, J. V. T.; De Bessa, J.; Moromizato, J.; Bosi, T.; Mazoni, R.; Gismondi, J.; Camargo, B.; Sammour, Z. M.; Bruschini, H.; Battistella, L. R.; Nahas, W. C.
Score: 29.1, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.01.23293500
PurposeTo analyze the prevalence of lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in patients who survived moderate and severe forms of COVID-19 and the risk factors for LUTS six months after hospital discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Primed and ready: Nanopore metabarcoding can now recover highly accurate consensus barcodes that are generally indel-free
Authors: Chang, J. J. M.; Ip, Y. C. A.; Neo, W. L.; Mowe, M. A. D.; Jaafar, Z.; Huang, D.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.04.552069
BackgroundDNA metabarcoding applies high-throughput sequencing approaches to generate numerous DNA barcodes from mixed sample pools for mass species identification and community characterisation. To date, however, most metabarcoding studies employ second-generation sequencing platforms like Illumina, which are limited by short read lengths and longer turnaround times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
