<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Rhinovirus infection of airway epithelial cells uncovers the non-ciliated subset as a likely driver of genetic susceptibility to childhood-onset asthma
Authors: Djeddi, S.; Fermandez-Salinas, D.; Huang, G.; Aguiar, V.; Mohanty, C.; Kendziorski, C.; Gazal, S.; Boyce, J.; Ober, C.; Gern, J.; Barrett, N.; Gutierrez-Arcelus, M.
Score: 18.3, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302068
Asthma is a complex disease caused by genetic and environmental factors. Epidemiological studies have shown that in children, wheezing during rhinovirus infection (a cause of the common cold) is associated with asthma development during childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Tap Dancing Frogs: Posterior Toe Tapping and Feeding Behavior in Dendrobates tinctorius
Authors: Parrish, T. Q.; Fischer, E. K.
Score: 36.6, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.558032
Animals have myriad adaptations to help them hunt and feed in the most efficient and effective manner. One mysterious behavior related to hunting and feeding is the posterior toe tapping behavior of some frogs. Biologists and hobbyists alike have long noticed this behavior, but there is little empirical data to explain its causes and consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Mechanism of degrader-targeted protein ubiquitinability
Authors: Crowe, C.; Nakasone, M.; Chandler, S.; Tatham, M. H.; Makukhin, N.; Hay, R. T.; Ciulli, A.
Score: 59.7, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.578957
Small molecule degraders of disease-driving proteins offer a clinically proven modality with enhanced therapeutic efficacy and the potential to tackle previously undrugged targets. Thermodynamically stable and kinetically long-lived degrader-mediated ternary complexes can drive faster, more profound and durable target degradation, however the mechanistic features by which they impact on target ubiquitination remain elusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Feature Reuse and Scaling: Understanding Transfer Learning with Protein Language Models
Authors: Li, F.-Z.; Amini, A. P.; Yue, Y.; Yang, K. K.; Lu, A. X.
Score: 87.1, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.578959
Large pretrained protein language models (PLMs) have improved protein property and structure prediction from sequences via transfer learning, in which weights and representations from PLMs are repurposed for downstream tasks. Although PLMs have shown great promise, currently there is little understanding of how the features learned by pretraining relate to and are useful for downstream tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>edgeR 4.0: powerful differential analysis of sequencing data with expanded functionality and improved support for small counts and larger datasets
Authors: Chen, Y.; Chen, L.; Lun, A. T. L.; Baldoni, P. L.; Smyth, G. K.
Score: 142.2, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.576131
edgeR is an R/Bioconductor software package for differential analyses of sequencing data in the form of read counts for genes or genomic features. Over the past 15 years, edgeR has been a popular choice for statistical analysis of data from sequencing technologies such as RNA-seq or ChIP-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Small LEA proteins as an effective air-water interface protectant for fragile samples during cryo-EM grid plunge freezing
Authors: Abe, K. M.; Lim, C. J.
Score: 54.1, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579238
Sample loss due to air-water interface (AWI) interactions is a significant challenge during cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) sample grid plunge freezing. We report that small Late Embryogenesis Abundant (LEA) proteins, which naturally bind to AWI, can protect samples from AWI damage during plunge freezing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>αKG-mediated carnitine synthesis promotes homologous recombination via histone acetylation
Authors: Uboveja, A.; Huang, Z.; Buj, R.; Amalric, A.; Wang, H.; Tangudu, N. K.; Cole, A. R.; Megill, E.; Kantner, D.; Chatoff, A.; Ahmad, H.; Marcinkiewicz, M. M.; Disharoon, J. A.; Graff, S.; Dahl, E. S.; Hempel, N.; Stallaert, W.; Sidoli, S.; Bitler, B. G.; Long, D. T.; Snyder, N. W.; Aird, K. M.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.578742</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Development and validation of imaging-free myocardial fibrosis prediction models, association with outcomes, and sample size estimation for phase 3 trials
Authors: Black, N.; Bradley, J.; Lewis, G.; Lagan, J.; Orsborne, C.; Soltani, F.; Farrant, J. P.; McDonagh, T.; Schmitt, M.; Cavalcante, J.; Ugander, M.; Butler, J.; Petrie, M. C.; Miller, C.; Schelbert, E.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2024-02-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.24302443
Background and AimsPhase 3 trials testing whether pharmacologic interventions targeting myocardial fibrosis (MF) improve outcomes require MF measurement that does not rely on tomographic imaging with intravenous contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cryosectioning-enabled super-resolution microscopy for studying nuclear architecture at the single protein level
Authors: Stein, J.; Ericsson, M.; Nofal, M.; Magni, L.; Aufmkolk, S.; McMillan, R. B.; Breimann, L.; Herlihy, C. P.; Lee, S. D.; Willemin, A.; Wohlmann, J.; Arguedas-Jimenez, L.; Yin, P.; Pombo, A.; Church, G. M.; Wu, C.-t.
Score: 47.5, Published: 2024-02-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.576943
DNA-PAINT combined with total Internal Reflection Fluorescence (TIRF) microscopy enables the highest localization precisions, down to single nanometers in thin biological samples, due to TIRFs unique method for optical sectioning and attaining high contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Induction and in silico staging of human gastruloids with neural tube, segmented somites &amp;amp; advanced cell types
Authors: Hamazaki, N.; Yang, W.; Kubo, C.; Qiu, C.; Martin, B. K.; Garge, R. K.; Regalado, S. G.; Nichols, E.; Lee, C.; Daza, R. M.; Srivatsan, S.; Shendure, J.
Score: 41.9, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579769
Embryonic organoids are emerging as powerful models for studying early mammalian development. For example, stem cell-derived &amp;#39;gastruloids&amp;#39; form elongating structures containing all three germ layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Geographically widespread and novel hemotropic mycoplasmas and bartonellae in Mexican free-tailed bats and sympatric North American bat species
Authors: Becker, D.; Dyer, K.; Lock, L.; Pladas, S.; Sukhadia, A.; Demory, B.; Nunes Batista, J.; Pineda, M.; Simmons, N.; Adams, A.; Frick, W.; O&amp;#39;Mara, T.; Volokhov, D.
Score: 13.5, Published: 2024-02-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.577874
Bacterial pathogens remain poorly characterized in bats, especially in North America. We describe novel (and in some cases panmictic) hemoplasmas (12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2--Reactive Salivary Antibody Detection in South Carolina Emergency Healthcare Workers: September 2019 -- March 2020
Authors: Meltzer, H. C.; Goodwin, J. L.; Fowler, L. A.; Britt, T. W.; Pirrallo, R. G.; Grier, J. T.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.31.24301668
BackgroundOn 19 January 2020, the first case of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection was identified in the US, with the first cases in South Carolina (SC) confirmed on 06 March 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>A prognostic molecular signature of hepatic steatosis is spatially heterogeneous and dynamic in human liver
Authors: Perry, A. S.; Hadad, N.; Chatterjee, E.; Jimenez Ramos, M.; Farber-Eger, E.; Roshani, R.; Stolze, L.; Zhao, S.; Martens, L.; Kendall, T.; Thone, T.; Amancherla, K.; Bailin, S.; Gabriel, C.; Koethe, J.; Carr, J. J.; Terry, J. G.; Freedman, J.; Tanriverdi, K.; Alsop, E.; Van Keuren-Jensen, K.; Sauld, J.; Mahajan, G.; Khan, S.; Colangelo, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Unreliability in Simulations of COVID-19 Cases and Deaths Based on Transmission Models
Authors: Kakeya, H.; Itoh, M.; Kamijima, Y.; Nitta, T.; Umeno, Y.
Score: 401.3, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.02.24302123
Two papers authored by the same research group were published in academic journals in October 2023, both of which simulate counterfactual COVID-19 cases and deaths using transmission models. One paper estimates that the COVID-19 cases and deaths from Feb 17 to Nov 30, 2021 in Japan would have been as many as 63.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Effect of iris pigmentation of blue and brown eyed individuals with European ancestry on ability to see in low light conditions after a short-term dark adaption period.
Authors: Cain, F. E.; Yamaguchi, K.
Score: 147.0, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576074
The effect of iris depigmentation on ability to see in low light conditions has not been thoroughly investigated as an adaptive advantage that could have contributed to the evolution and persistence of blue eyes in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Novel syndromic neurodevelopmental disorder caused by de novo deletion of CHASERR, a long noncoding RNA
Authors: Ganesh, V. S.; Riquin, K.; Chatron, N.; Lamar, K.-M.; Aziz, M.; Monin, P.; O&amp;#39;Leary, M.; Goodrich, J. K.; Garimella, K. V.; England, E.; Yoon, E.; Weisburd, B.; Aguet, F.; Bacino, C. A.; Murdock, D. R.; Dai, H.; Rosenfeld, J. A.; Emrick, L. T.; Ketkar, S.; Sarusi, Y.; Sanlaville, D.; Kayani, S.; Broadbent, B.; Isidor, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Developmental disruption of the mitochondrial fissiongene drp-1 extends the longevity of daf-2 insulin/IGF-1 receptor mutant
Authors: Traa, A.; Van Raamsdonk, J.
Score: 21.4, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.579360
The dynamic nature of the mitochondrial network is regulated by mitochondrial fission and fusion, allowing for re-organization of mitochondria to adapt to the cells ever-changing needs. As organisms age, mitochondrial fission and fusion become dysregulated and mitochondrial networks become increasingly fragmented. Modulation of mitochondrial dynamics has been shown to affect longevity in fungi, yeast, Drosophila and C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Unifying approaches from statistical genetics and phylogenetics for mapping phenotypes in structured populations
Authors: Schraiber, J. G.; Edge, M. D.; Pennell, M.
Score: 32.9, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579721
In both statistical genetics and phylogenetics, a major goal is to identify correlations between genetic loci or other aspects of the phenotype or environment and a focal trait. In these two fields, there are sophisticated but disparate statistical traditions aimed at these tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Missing the vulnerable - Inequalities in social protection among the general population, people living with HIV, and adolescent girls and young women in 13 sub-Saharan African countries: Analysis of population-based surveys
Authors: Chipanta, D.; Amo-Agyei, S.; Hertzog, L.; Hosseinpoor, A. R.; Smith, M. J.; Mahoney, C.; Jaramillo Meija, J. G.; Keiser, O.; Estill, J.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2024-02-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302524
Inequality in access to services is a global problem mainly impacting the poorest populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Retrieval Augmented Generation Enabled Generative Pre-Trained Transformer 4 (GPT-4) Performance for Clinical Trial Screening
Authors: Unlu, O.; Shin, J.; Mailly, C. J.; Oates, M. F.; Tucci, M. R.; Varugheese, M.; Wagholikar, K.; Wang, F.; Scirica, B. M.; Blood, A. J.; Aronson, S. J.
Score: 62.3, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302376
BackgroundSubject screening is a key aspect of all clinical trials; however, traditionally, it is a labor-intensive and error-prone task, demanding significant time and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>TP53 mutation screening for patients at risk of myeloid malignancy
Authors: Mukherjee, D.; Lawal, R. A.; Fitzhugh, C. D.; Hourigan, C. S.; Dillon, L. W.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.24302401
There is increasing recognition of the risk of developing therapy-related myeloid malignancy, including after cellular therapy. While retrospective studies have implicated pre-existing TP53 mutated hematopoietic clones as a common causative mechanism, no prospective screening to identify those patients at greatest risk is currently possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Prescribing pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) for HIV prevention: A cross-sectional survey of General Practitioners in Australia
Authors: Wu, J.; Fairley, C. K.; Grace, D.; Bavinton, B. R.; Fraser, D.; Chan, C.; Chow, E. P. F.; Ong, J. J.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301757
BackgroundPre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) is a safe and effective medication for preventing HIV acquisition. We examined Australian general practitioners (GP) knowledge of PrEP efficacy, characteristics associated with ever prescribing PrEP, and barriers to prescribing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent booster improves antibody binding and neutralization against emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variants
Authors: Jain, S.; Kumar, S.; Lai, L.; Linderman, S.; Malik, A. A.; Ellis, M. L.; Godbole, S.; Solis, D.; Sahoo, M. K.; Bechnak, K.; Paredes, I.; Tanios, R.; Kazzi, B.; Dib, S. M.; Litvack, M. B.; Wimalsena, S. T.; Ciric, C.; Rostad, C.; West, R.; Teng, I.-T.; Wang, D.; Kwong, P. D.; Rouphael, N.; Pinsky, B. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Blood transcriptomics reveal persistent SARS-CoV-2 RNA and candidate biomarkers in Long COVID patients
Authors: MENEZES, S. M.; JAMOULLE, M.; Carletto, M. P.; Van Holm, B.; Moens, L.; Meyts, I.; Maes, P.; Van Weyenbergh, J.
Score: 458.2, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.24301293
With an estimated 65 million individuals suffering from Long COVID, validated therapeutic strategies as well as non-invasive biomarkers are direly needed to guide clinical management. We used blood digital transcriptomics in search of viral persistence and Long COVID diagnostic biomarkers in a real-world, general practice-based setting with a long clinical follow-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Can unguided machine learning re-discover physiologic signatures of neonatal sepsis?
Authors: Sullivan, B. A.; Mesner, I. G.; Fairchild, K. D.; Lake, D. E.; Moorman, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.03.24302230
BackgroundCardiorespiratory deterioration due to sepsis is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality for extremely premature infants with very low birth weight (VLBW, birthweight &amp;lt;1500g). Abnormal heart rate (HR) patterns precede the clinical diagnosis of late-onset sepsis in this population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Perceptions, attitudes, and challenges regarding continuing professional development among Ethiopian Medical Laboratory professionals: A mixed-method study
Authors: Gudeta, A. N.; Sisay, A.; Shibabaw, A.; Kebede, E.; Tesfaye, F.; Kedida, G.; Deneke, N.; Teklu, T.; Cheneke, W.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.04.24302318
BackgroundMedical laboratory professionals play vital role in healthcare. The growing demand for quality laboratory services and emerging technologies underscore the crucial need for Continuing Professional Development (CPD). However, there is limited information on CPD programs in Ethiopia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Viroid-like colonists of human microbiomes
Authors: Zheludev, I. N.; Edgar, R. C.; Galiano, M. J. L.; De la Pena, M.; Babaian, A.; Bhatt, A. S.; Fire, A. Z.
Score: 829.4, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.576352
Here, we describe the &amp;#34;Obelisks,&amp;#34; a previously unrecognised class of viroid-like elements that we first identified in human gut metatranscriptomic data. &amp;#34;Obelisks&amp;#34; share several properties: (i) apparently circular RNA [~]1kb genome assemblies, (ii) predicted rod-like secondary structures encompassing the entire genome, and (iii) open reading frames coding for a novel protein superfamily, which we call the &amp;#34;Oblins&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Interplay of condensation and chromatin binding underlies BRD4 targeting
Authors: Strom, A. R.; Eeftens, J. M.; Polyachenko, Y.; Weaver, C. J.; Watanabe, H.-F.; Bracha, D.; Orlovsky, N. D.; Jumper, C. C.; Jacobs, W. M.; Brangwynne, C. P.
Score: 26.8, Published: 2024-02-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.579384
Nuclear compartments form via biomolecular phase separation, mediated through multivalent properties of biomolecules concentrated within condensates. Certain compartments are associated with specific chromatin regions, including transcriptional initiation condensates, which are composed of transcription factors and transcriptional machinery, and form at acetylated regions including enhancer and promoter loci.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Acute kidney injury outcomes of COVID-19 confirmed patients in a Philippine tertiary hospital: A retrospective study
Authors: Sayson, J.; Kalaw, R.; Ordona, B. E.; Lim, M. E.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302369
The novel coronavirus (COVID-19) is known to be the fifth pandemic causing massive deaths worldwide. This virus has not only been deeply associated with acute respiratory distress, but also acute kidney injury (AKI). This study describes the baseline characteristics and various outcomes of AKI based on the KDIGO 2012 Clinical Practice Guidelines in patients hospitalized with COVID-19 at a Philippine tertiary hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Evidence for trans-synaptic propagation of oligomeric tau in Progressive Supranuclear Palsy
Authors: McGeachan, R.; Keavey, L.; Rose, J. L.; Simzer, E. M.; Chang, Y. Y.; Spires-Jones, M. P.; Gillmore, M.; Ravingerova, N.; Scutariu, C.; Taylor, L.; Rose, J.; King, D.; Tzioras, M.; Tulloch, J.; Booker, S.; Liaquat, I.; Hindley-Pollock, N.; Geary, B.; Smith, C.; Brennan, P. M.; Durrant, C. S.; Spires-Jones, T. L.
Score: 20.6, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2022.09.20.22280086</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-COV-2 induces blood-brain barrier and choroid plexus barrier impairments and vascular inflammation in mice
Authors: Qiao, H.; Deng, X.; Qiu, L.; Qu, Y.; Chiu, Y.; Chen, F.; Xia, S.; Muenzel, C.; Ge, T.; Song, P.; Bonnin, A.; Zhao, Z.; Yuan, W.
Score: 208.8, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579589
The coronavirus disease of 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic that has led to more than 700 million confirmed cases and near 7 million deaths. Although Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) virus mainly infects the respiratory system, neurological complications are widely reported in both acute infection and long-COVID cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Associations between genetically predicted iron status and cardiovascular disease risk: A Mendelian randomization study
Authors: Barad, A.; Clark, A. G.; O&amp;#39;Brien, K. O.; Pressman, E. K.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302373
BackgroundMendelian randomization (MR) studies suggest a causal effect of iron (Fe) status on cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk, but it is unknown if these associations are confounded by pleiotropic effects of the instrumental variables (IV) on CVD risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of cancer incidence among Marines and Navy personnel and civilian workers exposed to contaminated drinking water at USMC Base Camp Lejeune
Authors: Bove, F. J.
Score: 93.2, Published: 2024-01-29 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.27.24301873
BackgroundDrinking water at U.S. Marine Corps Base Camp Lejeune, North Carolina was contaminated with trichloroethylene and other industrial solvents from 1953 to 1985. MethodsA cohort cancer incidence study was conducted of Marines/Navy personnel who, between 1975 and 1985, began service and were stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina (N=154,821) or Camp Pendleton, California (N=163,484), and civilian workers employed at Camp Lejeune (N=6,494) or Camp Pendleton (N=5,797) between October 1972 and December 1985.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>British Oncology Pharmacy Association Delphi Consensus Guidelines: co-infusion of trometamol-containing calcium folinate (leucovorin) with Systemic Anti-Cancer Treatments
Authors: Polwart, C.; Root, T.; Tezcan, S.; Meehan, S.; Wetherill, B.; Waterson, C.; Burnett, B.; Chauhan, R.; Al-Modaris, I.; Walters-Davies, R.; British Oncology Pharmacy Association, Score: 5.6, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.24302100
Drug stability and compatibility are critical factors influencing cost and logistics of treatment delivery, therapeutic effectiveness, and patient safety. This is particularly significant in the realm of cancer chemotherapeutics, where stability and compatibility studies play a vital role in ensuring rational and safe medicine administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Digital PCR-based deep quantitative profiling delineates heterogeneity and evolution of uveal melanoma
Authors: Nell, R. J.; Versluis, M.; Menger, N. V.; Verdijk, R. M.; Kroes, W. G. M.; Kapiteijn, E. H. W.; Luyten, G. P. M.; Jager, M. J.; van der Velden, P. A.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-02-02 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.30.24301871
Uveal melanoma is an aggressive intraocular tumour characterised by a limited number of genetic alterations. However, the evolution of this malignancy remains enigmatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Neuropsychology of chronic back pain managed with long-term opioid use.
Authors: Baliki, M. N.; Vigotsky, A. D.; Rached, G.; Jabakhanji, R.; Huang, L.; Branco, P.; Cong, O.; Griffith, J. W.; Wasan, A.; Schnitzer, T.; Apkarian, A. V.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.24302408
Chronic pain is commonly treated with long-term opioids, but the neuropsychological outcomes associated with stable long-duration opioid use remain unclear. Here, we contrasted the psychological profiles, brain activity, and brain structure of 70 chronic back pain patients on opioids (CBP&amp;#43;O, average opioid exposure 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Loss of endogenous estrogen alters mitochondrial metabolism and muscle clock-related protein Rbm20 in female mdx mice
Authors: Timpani, C. A.; Debrincat, D.; Kourakis, S.; Boyer, R.; Formosa, L. E.; Steele, J. R.; Zhang, H.; Schittenhelm, R. B.; Russell, A. P.; Rybalka, E.; Lindsay, A.
Score: 5.4, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.579567
Female carriers of a Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) gene mutation manifest exercise intolerance and metabolic anomalies that may be exacerbated following menopause due to the loss of estrogen, a known regulator of skeletal muscle function and metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Cell circuits underlying nanomaterial specific respiratory toxicology
Authors: Voss, C.; Han, L.; Ansari, M.; Strunz, M.; Haefner, V.; Ballester-Lopez, C.; Angelidis, I.; Mayr, C. H.; Berthing, T.; Conlon, T.; Liu, Q.; Ren, H.; Zhou, Q.; Schmid, O.; Yildirim, A. O.; Rehberg, M.; Vogel, U.; Gothe-Schniering, J.; Theis, F. J.; Schiller, H. B.; Stoeger, T.
Score: 4.5, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579746
Nanomaterials emerged as boundless resource of innovation, but their shape and biopersistence related to respiratory toxicology raise longstanding concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Anti-diuretic hormone ITP signals via a guanylate cyclase receptor to modulate systemic homeostasis in Drosophila
Authors: Gera, J.; Agard, M.; Nave, H.; Sajadi, F.; Thorat, L.; Kondo, S.; Nassel, D.; Paluzzi, J.-P. V.; Zandawala, M.
Score: 16.5, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.579245
Insects have evolved a variety of neurohormones that enable them to maintain their nutrient and osmotic homeostasis. While the identities and functions of various insect metabolic and diuretic hormones have been well-established, the characterization of an anti-diuretic signaling system that is conserved across most insects is still lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 260.9, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Report: GLP-1 RA Prescribing Trends - December 2023 Data
Authors: Gratzl, S.; Rodriguez, P. J.; Cartwright, B. M. G.; Baker, C.; Stucky, N.
Score: 14.0, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301500
BackgroundLimited recent data exist on prescribing patterns and patient characteristics for glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonists (GLP-1 RAs), an important drug class used as anti-diabetic medication (ADM) for patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2D) and/or anti-obesity medication (AOM) in patients with overweight or obesity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Distinguishing different psychiatric disorders using DDx-PRS
Authors: Peyrot, W. J.; Panagiotaropoulou, G.; Olde Loohuis, L. M.; Adams, M.; Awasthi, S.; Ge, T.; McIntosh, A. M.; Mitchell, B. L.; Mullins, N.; O&amp;#39;Connell, K. S.; Penninx, B. W. J. H.; Posthuma, D.; Ripke, S.; Ruderfer, D. M.; Uffelmann, E.; Vilhjalmsson, B. J.; Zhu, Z.; Schizophrenia Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Bipolar Disorder Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Major Depressive Disorder Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium, ; Smoller, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Ecological impacts of climate change will transform public health priorities for zoonotic and vector-borne disease
Authors: Redding, D. W.; Gibb, R.; Jones, K. E.
Score: 54.3, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.24302575
Climate change impacts on zoonotic/vector-borne diseases pose significant threats to humanity1 but these links are, in general, poorly understood2. Here, we project present and future geographical risk patterns for 141 infectious agents to understand likely climate change impacts, by integrating ecological models of infection hazard (climate-driven host/vector distributions and dispersal3,4) with exposure (human populations) and vulnerability (poverty prevalence).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Brain 3T magnetic resonance imaging in neonates: features and incidental findings from a research cohort enriched for preterm birth
Authors: Sullivan, G.; Choi, S.; Quigley, A. J.; Teed, R.; Blesa Cabez, M.; Vaher, K.; Corrigan, A. E.; Stoye, D. Q.; Thrippleton, M. J.; Bastin, M.; Boardman, J. P.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.24302207
Background and objectivesThe survival rate and patterns of brain injury after very preterm birth are evolving with changes in clinical practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Physiotherapy Under Pressure: A Cross-Sectional Study on The Interplay Between Perfectionism, Moral Injury, and Burnout
Authors: Biggs, D.; Blackburn, L.; Black, C.; Shanmugam, S.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.24302501
Background: Given the escalating challenges for UK-based physiotherapists in workload pressures, budget constraints, staff shortages and patient wait times, the profession (of 65,000 registered physiotherapists) requires immediate care and review of therapist health. This pioneering study aims to examine perfectionism, moral injury, and burnout among UK-based physiotherapists across the NHS, private practice, sports, and academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Structured Peer Review: Pilot results from 23 Elsevier Journals
Authors: Malicki, M.; Mehmani, B.
Score: 26.1, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.578440
BackgroundReviewers rarely comment on the same aspects of a manuscript, making it difficult to properly assess manuscripts quality and the quality of the peer review process. It was the goal of this pilot study to evaluate structured peer review implementation by: 1) exploring if and how reviewers answered structured peer review questions, 2) analysing reviewer agreement, 3) comparing that agreement to agreement before implementation of structured peer review, and 4) further enhancing the piloted set of structured peer review questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Indexing Healthcare Access and Quality for Surgically Amenable Conditions: A Global Analysis of 204 Countries and Territories from 1990 to 2019
Authors: Zadey, S.; Smith, E. R.; Staton, C. A.; Fitzgerald, T. N.; Nickenig Vissoci, J. R.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.04.24302290
IntroductionBuilding on past frameworks, our aim was to systematically analyze the healthcare access and quality (HAQ) index for surgically treatable conditions, its progress over time, and the gap compared to non-surgical HAQ across 204 countries and territories from 1990 to 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>DNA representations and generalization performance of sequence-to-expression models
Authors: Shen, Y.; Kudla, G.; Oyarzun, D. A.
Score: 10.0, Published: 2024-02-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579067
The increasing demand for biological products drives many efforts to engineer cells that produce heterologous proteins at maximal yield. Recent advances in massively parallel reporter assays can deliver data suitable for training machine learning models and sup-port the design of microbial strains with optimized protein expression phenotypes. The best performing sequence- to-expression models have been trained on one-hot encodings, a mechanism-agnostic representation of nucleotide sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Spatially Exploring RNA Biology in Archival Formalin-Fixed Paraffin-Embedded Tissues
Authors: Bai, Z.; Zhang, D.; Gao, Y.; Tao, B.; Bao, S.; Enninful, A.; Zhang, D.; Su, G.; Tian, X.; Zhang, N.; Xiao, Y.; Liu, Y.; Gerstein, M.; Li, M.; Xing, Y.; Lu, J.; Xu, M. L.; Fan, R.
Score: 76.4, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.579143
Spatial transcriptomics has emerged as a powerful tool for dissecting spatial cellular heterogeneity but as of today is largely limited to gene expression analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Molecular signatures of chronic antibody-mediated rejection in human liver transplants
Authors: Engel, B.; Alaswad, A.; Campos-Murguia, A.; Zoodsma, M.; Klingbeil, A.; Chihab, K.; Bosselmann, E. A.; Heinrich, S.; Hartleben, B.; Jonigk, D. D.; Verboom, M.; Hallensleben, M.; Geffers, R.; Wedemeyer, H.; Xu, C.; Jaeckel, E.; Li, Y.; Taubert, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302515
Background&amp;amp;AimsThe role of antibody-mediated rejection (ABMR) after liver transplantation (LT) remains controversial. Chronic ABMR (cABMR) is often subclinical and potentially missed without surveillance biopsies (svLbx) which are not established in most LT centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of genetic associations with clinical phenotypes of kidney stone disease
Authors: Hsi, R. S.; Zhang, S.; Xu, Y.; Triozzi, J. L.; Hung, A. M.; Bejan, C. A.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301501
Introduction and ObjectiveWe sought to replicate and discover genetic associations of kidney stone disease within a large-scale electronic health record (EHR) system. MethodsWe performed genome-wide association studies (GWASs) for nephrolithiasis from genotyped samples of 5,571 cases and 83,692 controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>The highly repetitive genome of Myxobolus rasmusseni n. sp, a myxozoan parasite of fathead minnows
Authors: Muthye, V. R.; Leon Coria, A.; Liu, H.; Finney, C. A. M.; Goater, C. P.; Wasmuth, J. D.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579586
Background The Myxozoa is a group of at least 2,400 endoparasites within the phylum Cnidaria. All myxozoans have greatly reduced in size and morphology compared to free-living members of the phylum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
