<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Correlation between COVID-19 vaccination and inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders
Authors: Park, Y. H.; Kim, M. H.; Choi, M. G.; Chun, E. M.
Score: 987.3, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298544
ImportanceEarlier research on COVID-19 vaccines identified a range of adverse reactions related to proinflammatory actions that can lead to an excessive immune response and sustained inflammation. However, no study has been conducted on the association between inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders and COVID-19 vaccines. ObjectiveTo investigate the incidence rates of inflammatory musculoskeletal disorders following COVID-19 vaccination and to compare them with those of unvaccinated individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A female-biased gene expression signature of dominance in cooperatively breeding meerkats
Authors: Campbell, C. R.; Manser, M.; Shiratori, M.; Williams, K.; Barreiro, L.; Clutton-Brock, T. H.; Tung, J.
Score: 21.0, Published: 2023-12-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.01.569325
Dominance is a primary determinant of social dynamics and resource access in social animals. Recent studies show that dominance is also reflected in the gene regulatory profiles of peripheral immune cells. However, the strength and direction of this relationship differs across the species and sex combinations investigated, potentially due to variation in the predictors and energetic consequences of dominant status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Tumor Immune Cell Targeting Chimeras (TICTACs) For Targeted Depletion of Macrophage-Associated Checkpoint Receptors
Authors: Morimoto, M.; Till, N. A.; Bertozzi, C. R.
Score: 34.5, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.570444
Immune cells in the tumor microenvironment are not only powerful regulators of immunosuppression and tumorigenesis, but also represent a dominant cell type, with tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) comprising up to 50% of total cell mass in solid tumors. Immunotherapies such as immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) derive their efficacy from this cancer-immune cell interface, however, immune-related adverse events resulting from systemic blockade remain a significant challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Massively parallel sample preparation for multiplexed single-cell proteomics using nPOP
Authors: Leduc, A.; Koury, L.; Cantlon, J.; Slavov, N.
Score: 38.4, Published: 2023-11-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.27.568927
Single-cell proteomics by mass spectrometry (MS) allows quantifying proteins with high specificity and sensitivity. To increase its throughput, we developed nPOP, a method for parallel preparation of thousands of single cells in nanoliter volume droplets deposited on glass slides. Here, we describe its protocol with emphasis on its flexibility to prepare samples for different multiplexed MS methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>simona: a Comprehensive R package for Semantic Similarity Analysis on Bio-Ontologies
Authors: Gu, Z.
Score: 29.8, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.569758
Bio-ontologies are keys in structuring complex biological information for effective data integration and knowledge representation. In this paper, we present simona, a novel R package for semantic similarity analysis on general bio-ontolgies. Simona implements infrastructures for ontology analysis by offering efficient data structures, fast ontology traversal methods, and elegant visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>A Fast Interferometric Beam Shaper for Multi-Emitter 3D MINFLUX
Authors: Geismann, M. K.; Gomez-Segalas, A.; Passera, A.; Shirzadian, M.; Balzarotti, F.
Score: 20.3, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.570565
Displacing beams of light in a controlled manner is integral to a wide range of optical methods such as scanning microscopes and optical tweezers. Optical super-resolution techniques like STED and RESOLFT, as well as localization techniques like MINFLUX and MINSTED rely on accurate and fast beam displacements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Three-dimensional assessments are necessary to determine the true spatial tissue composition of diseased tissues
Authors: Forjaz, A.; Vaz, E.; Romero, V. M.; Joshi, S.; Braxton, A. M.; Jiang, A. C.; Fujikura, K.; Cornish, T.; Hong, S.-M.; Hruban, R. H.; Wu, P.-H.; Wood, L. D.; Kiemen, A. L.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569986
Methods for partially resolved cellular profiling has enabled in-depth quantitative tissue mapping via thinly cut sections to study inter-patient and intra-patient differences in normal human anatomy and disease onset and progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Mechanisms underlying exercise intolerance in Long COVID: an accumulation of multi-system dysfunction
Authors: Jamieson, A.; Al Saikhan, L.; Alghamdi, L.; Hamill Howes, L.; Purcell, H.; Hillman, T.; Heightman, M. J.; Treibel, T. A.; Orini, M.; Bell, R. M.; Scully, M.; Hamer, M.; Chaturvedi, N.; Hughes, A.; Astin, R.; Jones, S.
Score: 34.2, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23299429
The pathogenesis of exercise intolerance and persistent fatigue which can follow an infection with the SARS-CoV-2 virus (Long COVID) is not fully understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Endoplasmic reticulum exit sites are segregated for secretion based on cargo size
Authors: Saxena, S.; Foresti, O.; Liu, A.; Androulaki, S.; Rodriguez, M. P.; Raote, I.; Cui, B.; Aridor, M.; Malhotra, V.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-12-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.570627
TANGO1-family proteins (TANGO1, TANGO1S and cTAGE5) form stable complexes at the Endoplasmic Reticulum Exit Sites (ERES) and mediate export of bulky cargoes. The C-terminal proline rich domain (PRD) of these proteins binds Sec23A and affects COPII assembly at ERES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Metabolic control of germ layer proportions through regulation of Nodal and Wnt signalling
Authors: Stapornwongkul, K. S.; Hahn, E. M.; Palau, L. S.; Arato, K.; Gritti, N.; Anlas, K.; Polinski, P.; Lopez, M.; Ebisuya, M.; Trivedi, V.
Score: 66.6, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569862
During embryonic development, cells exit pluripotency to give rise to the three germ layers. Metabolic pathways influence cell fate decisions by modulating the epigenetic, transcriptional, and signalling states of cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Climate change has desynchronized insect and vegetation phenologies across Europe
Authors: Huang, Y.; Yu, C.; Huang, W.; Liu, Y.; Qi, M.; Bai, J.; Dong, Y.; Gascoigne, S.; Ciais, P.; Penuelas, J.; Salguero-Gomez, R.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.571152
Climate change is drastically affecting the phenologies of species worldwide, including shifts in development. The potential impact of climate change on the synchronicity of plant-insect phenology is particularly concerning since the stability of pollination networks and food chains depends on their tight temporal dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Impact of COVID-19 on mental illness in vaccinated and unvaccinated people: a population-based cohort study in OpenSAFELY
Authors: Walker, V.; Patalay, P.; Cuitin Coronado, J. I.; Denholm, R.; Forbes, H.; Stafford, J.; Moltrecht, B.; Palmer, T.; Walker, A.; Thompson, E. J.; Taylor, K.; Cezard, G.; Horne, E. M.; Wei, Y.; Al Arab, M.; Knight, R.; Fisher, L.; Massey, J.; Davy, S.; Mehrkar, A.; Bacon, S.; Goldacre, B.; Wood, A.; Chaturvedi, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Allelic gene conversion softens selective sweeps
Authors: Schrider, D. R.
Score: 20.2, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570141
The prominence of positive selection, in which beneficial mutations are favored by natural selection and rapidly increase in frequency, is a subject of intense debate. Positive selection can result in selective sweeps, in which the haplotype(s) bearing the adaptive allele &amp;#34;sweep&amp;#34; through the population, thereby removing much of the genetic diversity from the region surrounding the target of selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>From Text to Tables: A Local Privacy Preserving Large Language Model for Structured Information Retrieval from Medical Documents
Authors: Wiest, I. C.; Ferber, D.; Zhu, J.; Van Treeck, M.; Meyer, S. K.; Juglan, R.; Carrero, Z. I.; Paech, D.; Kleesiek, J.; Ebert, M. P.; Truhn, D.; Kather, J. N.
Score: 18.1, Published: 2023-12-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23299648
Background and AimsMost clinical information is encoded as text, but extracting quantitative information from text is challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Whole-genome sequencing of half-a-million UK Biobank participants
Authors: The UK Biobank Whole-Genome Sequencing Consortium, ; Li, S.; Carss, K. J.; Halldorsson, B. V.; Cortes, A.
Score: 65.3, Published: 2023-12-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.23299426
Summary ParagraphWhole-genome sequencing (WGS) provides a comprehensive view of the genome, enabling detection of coding and non-coding genetic variation, and surveying complex regions which are difficult to genotype. Here, we report on whole-genome sequencing of 490,640 UK Biobank participants, building on previous genotyping1 and whole-exome sequencing (WES) efforts2,3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>pIGLET: Safe harbor landing sites for reproducible and efficient transgenesis in zebrafish
Authors: Lalonde, R. L.; Wells, H. H.; Kemmler, C. L.; Nieuwenhuize, S.; Lerma, R.; Burger, A.; Mosimann, C.
Score: 47.3, Published: 2023-12-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570868
Standard methods for transgenesis in zebrafish depend on random transgene integration into the genome followed by resource-intensive screening and validation. Targeted vector integration into validated genomic loci using phiC31 integrase-based attP/attB recombination has transformed mouse and Drosophila transgenesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Rapid and Quantitative Functional Interrogation of Human Enhancer Variant Activity in Live Mice
Authors: Hollingsworth, E. W.; Liu, T. A.; Jacinto, S. H.; Chen, C. X.; Alcantara, J. A.; Kvon, E. Z.
Score: 25.3, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.10.570890
Functional analysis of non-coding variants associated with human congenital disorders remains challenging due to the lack of efficient in vivo models. Here we introduce dual-enSERT, a robust Cas9-based two-color fluorescent reporter system which enables rapid, quantitative comparison of enhancer allele activities in live mice of any genetic background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Associations of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease with inpatient hospital costs and with quality-adjusted life years: Evidence from conventional and Mendelian randomization analyses in the UK Biobank
Authors: Dixon, P.; Anderson, E. L.
Score: 1.4, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.23299763
BACKGROUNDAlzheimers disease and other dementias are progressive neurodegenerative disorders with profound impacts on cognitive function. There is a shortage of economic evidence relating to the impact Alzheimers disease on healthcare costs and quality-adjusted life-years (QALYs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Infection is Associated with an Increase in New Diagnoses of Schizophrenia Spectrum and Psychotic Disorder: A Study Using the US National COVID Cohort Collaborative (N3C)
Authors: Rahman, A.; Russell, M.; Zheng, W.; Eckrich, D.; Ahmed, I.; on behalf of the N3C Consortium, Score: 701.6, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299473
Amid the ongoing global repercussions of SARS-CoV-2, its crucial to comprehend its potential long-term psychiatric effects. Several recent studies have suggested a link between COVID-19 and subsequent mental health disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>A rapid review of physical health risks associated with special procedures (tattooing, body piercing, acupuncture, electrolysis)
Authors: Kiseleva, M.; Csontos, J.; Edwards, D.; Gillen, E.; Mann, M.; Searchfield, L.; Sha&amp;#39;aban, A.; Lewis, R.; Cooper, A.; Edwards, A. G.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.11.23299649
Special procedures, such as tattooing (including semi-permanent make-up), body piercing, acupuncture and electrolysis involve piercing the skin and carry a potential risk of infection and other complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>XBB.1.5 monovalent mRNA vaccine booster elicits robust neutralizing antibodies against emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Bowen, A.; Mellis, I. A.; Valdez, R.; Gherasim, C.; Gordon, A.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 1143.0, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.26.568730
COVID-19 vaccines have recently been updated with the spike protein of SARS-CoV-2 XBB.1.5 subvariant alone, but their immunogenicity in humans has yet to be fully evaluated and reported, particularly against emergent viruses that are rapidly expanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Hematologic abnormalities after COVID-19 vaccination: A large Korean population-based cohort study
Authors: CHOI, H. S.; KIM, M.-H.; CHOI, M. G.; PARK, J. H.; CHUN, E. M.
Score: 1666.4, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298565
Adverse hematologic events have been reported after COVID-19 vaccination. The objective of this study was to investigate whether hematologic abnormalities develop after COVID-19 vaccination. Retrospective cohort analyses of data from the Korean National Health Insurance Service (KNHIS) database were conducted from July 2022 to August 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical students&amp;#39; perceptions towards artificial intelligence in education and practice: A multinational, multicenter cross-sectional study
Authors: Busch, F.; Hoffmann, L.; Truhn, D.; Ortiz-Prado, E.; Makowski, M. R.; Bressem, K. K.; Adams, L. C.; COMFORT Consortium, Score: 4.8, Published: 2023-12-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.09.23299744
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) is anticipated to fundamentally change the educational and professional landscape for the next generation of physicians, but its successful integration depends on the global perspectives of all stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 JN.1 variant
Authors: Kaku, Y.; Okumura, K.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Kosugi, Y.; Uriu, K.; Hinay, A. A.; Chen, L.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Kobiyama, K.; Ishii, K. J.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Zahradnik, J.; Ito, J.; Sato, K.
Score: 613.3, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570782
The SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 lineage, first identified in August 2023, is phylogenetically distinct from the currently circulating SARS-CoV-2 Omicron XBB lineages, including EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>snPATHO-seq: unlocking the pathology archives
Authors: Wang, T.; Harvey, K.; Escudero Morales, J.; Kiedik, B.; Al-Eryani, G.; Greenwald, A. C.; Kalavros, N.; SegatovDezem, F.; Ma, Y.; Pita-Juarez, Y.; Wise, K.; Degletagne, C.; Elz, A.; Johanneson, J.; Pakiam, F.; Ryu, H.; Newell, E. W.; Tonon, L.; Kohlway, A.; Drennon, T.; Hadadianpour, A.; Abousoud, J.; Scott, R.; Lund, P.; Durruthy, J.; Vallejos, A. F.; Kaczorowski, D.; Warren, J.; Butler, L. M.; O&amp;#39;Toole, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Neuronal avalanches in temporal lobe epilepsy as a diagnostic tool: a noninvasive investigation of intrinsic resting state dynamics
Authors: Corsi, M.-C.; Lopez, E. T.; Sorrentino, P.; Danieli, A.; Cuozzo, S.; Bonanni, P.; Duma, G. M.
Score: 7.1, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.23299589
Background and ObjectivesThe epilepsy diagnosis still represents a complex process, with misdiagnosis reaching 40%. Here, we aimed at building an automatable workflow, to help the clinicians in the diagnostic process, differentiating between controls and a population of patients with temporal lobe epilepsy (TLE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Connectivity underlying motor cortex activity during naturalistic goal-directed behavior
Authors: Finkelstein, A.; Daie, K.; Rozsa, M.; Darshan, R.; Svoboda, K.
Score: 48.7, Published: 2023-12-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.25.568673
Neural representations of information are shaped by local network interactions. Previous studies linking neural coding and cortical connectivity focused on stimulus selectivity in the sensory cortex 1-4. Here we study neural activity in the motor cortex during naturalistic behavior in which mice gathered rewards with multidirectional tongue reaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nursing</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nursing/</guid>
      <description>Influence of Nursing Explanation Skills on Incident Occurrence
Authors: Fujimoto, M.; Shimamura, M.; Yuki, F.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-11-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298399
OBJECTIVESIn routine nursing tasks, providing accurate explanations is vital for the quality of healthcare and patient safety, but empirical data on this are scarce. This study aimed to create a psychological scale and investigate how nursing explanation skills affect healthcare incidents. DESIGNThe study involved psychological scale development and questionnaire surveys based on psychological paradigms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Imprecision nutrition? Duplicate meals result in unreliable individual glycemic responses measured by continuous glucose monitors across four dietary patterns in adults without diabetes
Authors: Hengist, A.; Ong, J. A.; McNeel, K.; Guo, J.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 173.2, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.23291406
Background: Continuous glucose monitors (CGMs) are being used to characterize postprandial glycemic responses and thereby provide personalized dietary advice to minimize glycemic excursions. However, the efficacy of such advice depends on reliable CGM responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A Video Intervention to Improve Patient Understanding of Tumor Genomic Testing in Patients with Cancer
Authors: Veney, D.; Wei, L.; Toland, A. E.; Presley, C. J.; Hampel, H.; Padamsee, T. J.; Lee, C. N.; Irvin, W. J.; Bishop, M.; Kim, J.; Hovick, S. R.; Senter, L.; Stover, D.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299443
BackgroundTumor genomic testing (TGT) has become standard-of-care for most patients with advanced/metastatic cancer. Despite established guidelines, patient education prior to TGT is variable or frequently omitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Nanoscale Imaging and Microanalysis of Ice Age Bone Offers New Perspective on &amp;#39;Subfossils&amp;#39; and Fossilization
Authors: Anderson, L. A.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570041
The 3-D structure and organization of type-1 collagen protein and vasculature for a set of ancient permafrost bones is extensively documented at the nanoscale (up to 150,000x magnification) for the first time. The chemical mapping technique ToF-SIMS is additionally used to directly localize chemical signal to these structures; C:N and isotope measurements are also reported for the bulk organic bone matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Disease progression modelling reveals heterogeneity in trajectories of Lewy-type alpha-synuclein pathology
Authors: Mastenbroek, S. E.; Vogel, J. W.; Collij, L. E.; Serrano, G. E.; Tremblay, C.; Young, A. L.; Arce, R. A.; Shill, H. A.; Driver-Dunckley, E. D.; Mehta, S. H.; Belden, C. M.; Atri, A.; Choudhury, P.; Barkhof, F.; Adler, C. H.; Ossenkoppele, R.; Beach, T. G.; Hansson, O.
Score: 16.6, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.569878
Lewy body (LB) disorders, characterized by the aggregation of misfolded -synuclein proteins, exhibit notable clinical heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Dysregulated Platelet Function in Patients with Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19
Authors: Aggarwal, A.; Singh, T. K.; Pham, M.; Godwin, M.; Chen, R.; McIntyre, T. M.; Chung, M. K.; Jennings, C.; Ali, M.; Park, H.; Englund, K.; Khorana, A. A.; Svensson, L.; Kapadia, S. R.; McCrae, K. R.; Cameron, S. J.
Score: 60.4, Published: 2023-11-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.18.545507
BackgroundPost-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC), also referred as Long-COVID, sometimes follows COVID-19, a disease caused by SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Human Heart Failure Alters Mitochondria and Fiber 3D Structure Triggering Metabolic Shifts
Authors: Vue, Z.; Ajayi, P. T.; Neikirk, K.; Murphy, A.; Prasad, P.; Jenkins, B. C.; Vang, L.; Garza-Lopez, E.; Mungai, M.; Marshall, A. G.; Beasley, H. K.; Killion, M.; Parker, R.; Anukodem, J.; Lavine, K.; Ajijola, O.; Mobley, B.; Dai, D.-F.; Exil, V.; Kirabo, A.; Ru Su, Y.; Tomasek, K.; Zhang, X.; Wanjalla, C. N.; Hubert, D. L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Characterization of DNA methylation reader proteins of Arabidopsis thaliana
Authors: Cahn, J.; Lloyd, J. P. B.; Karemaker, I. D.; Jansen, P. W.; Pflueger, J.; Duncan, O.; Petereit, J.; Bogdanovic, O.; Millar, H.; Vermeulen, M.; Lister, R.
Score: 33.5, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.570080
In plants, cytosine DNA methylation (mC) is largely associated with transcriptional repression of transposable elements, but it can also be found in the body of expressed genes, referred to as gene body methylation (GbM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Comparative Effectiveness of Semaglutide and Tirzepatide for Weight Loss in Adults with Overweight and Obesity in the US: A Real-World Evidence Study
Authors: Rodriguez, P. J.; Cartwright, B.; Gratzl, S.; Baker, C.; Brar, R.; Gluckman, T. J.; Stucky, N.
Score: 487.2, Published: 2023-11-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.21.23298775
BackgroundBoth tirzepatide and semaglutide have been shown to reduce weight for patients with overweight or obesity in randomized controlled trials (RCTs). While tirzepatide appears to provide greater weight loss than semaglutide in this population, head-to-head RCTs are not yet available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Long COVID is associated with severe cognitive slowing
Authors: Zhao, S.; Martin, E. M.; Reuken, P. A.; Scholcz, A.; Ganse-Dumrath, A.; Srowig, A.; Utech, I.; Kozik, V.; Radscheidt, M.; Brodoehl, S.; Stallmach, A.; Schwab, M.; Fraser, E.; Finke, K.; Husain, M.
Score: 534.3, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.03.23299331
BackgroundCOVID-19 survivors may suffer from a wide range of chronic cognitive symptoms for months or years as part of post-COVID-19 conditions (PCC). To date, there is no definitive objective cognitive marker for PCC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1154.9, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
ImportancePhase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects; this is not assessed within the current regulatory framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Genetic Polymorphisms and Post-Stroke Upper Limb Motor Improvement A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Subramanian, S. K.; Morgan, R. T.; Rasmusson, C.; Shepherd, K.; Li, C. L.
Score: 4.0, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.23299579
BackgroundPost-stroke upper limb (UL) motor improvement is associated with adaptive neuroplasticity and motor learning. Both intervention-related (including provision of intensive, variable, and task-specific practice) and individual-specific factors (including the presence of genetic polymorphisms) influence improvement. In individuals with stroke, most commonly, polymorphisms are found in Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF), Apolipoprotein (APOE) and catechol-O-methyltransferase (COMT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Pulmonary microbiome and transcriptome signatures reveal distinct pathobiologic states associated with mortality in two cohorts of pediatric stem cell transplant patients.
Authors: Zinter, M. S.; Dvorak, C. C.; Mayday, M. Y.; Reyes, G.; Simon, M. R.; Pearce, E. M.; Kim, H.; Shaw, P. J.; Rowan, C. M.; Auletta, J. J.; Martin, P. L.; Godder, K.; Duncan, C. N.; Lalefar, N. R.; Kreml, E. M.; Hume, J. R.; Abdel-Azim, H.; Hurley, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>A genome-wide association study suggests new susceptibility loci for primary antiphospholipid syndrome
Authors: Casares-Marfil, D.; Martinez-Bueno, M.; Borghi, M. O.; Pons-Estel, G.; PRECISESADS Clinical Consortium, ; Reales, G.; Zuo, Y.; Espinosa, G.; Radstake, T. R. D. J.; van den Hoogen, L. L.; Wallace, C.; Guthridge, J.; James, J.; Cervera, R.; Luigi Meroni, P. L.; Martin, J.; Knight, J.; Alarcon-Riquelme, M.; Sawalha, A. H.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2023-12-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.05.23299396</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Rendering protein structures inside cells at the atomic level with Unreal Engine
Authors: Chen, M.
Score: 76.4, Published: 2023-12-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.08.570879
While the recent development of cryogenic electron tomography (CryoET) makes it possible to identify various macromolecules inside cells and determine their structure at near-atomic resolution, it remains challenging to visualize the complex cellular environment at the atomic level. One of the main hurdles in cell visualization is to render the millions of molecules in real time computationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Multi-phase, multi-ethnic GWAS uncovers putative loci in predisposition to human sprint performance, health and disease
Authors: Wang, G.; Fuku, N.; Miyamoto-Mikami, E.; Tanaka, M.; Miyachi, M.; Murakami, H.; Cheng, Y.-C.; Mitchell, B. D.; Morrison, E.; Austin, K. G.; Ahmetov, I. I.; Sportgene Research Group, ; Generozov, E. V.; Filipenko, M. L.; Gilep, A. A.; Gineviciene, V.; Moran, C. N.; Venckunas, T.; Cieszczyk, P.; Derave, W.; Papadimitriou, I.; Garton, F. C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>ProteinNPT: Improving Protein Property Predictionand Design with Non-Parametric Transformers
Authors: Notin, P.; Weitzman, R.; Marks, D. S.; Gal, Y.
Score: 23.3, Published: 2023-12-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.06.570473
Protein design holds immense potential for optimizing naturally occurring proteins, with broad applications in drug discovery, material design, and sustainability. How-ever, computational methods for protein engineering are confronted with significant challenges, such as an expansive design space, sparse functional regions, and a scarcity of available labels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Remodeling of the protein ubiquitylation landscape in the aging vertebrate brain
Authors: Marino, A.; Di Fraia, D.; Panfilova, D.; Sahu, A. K.; Ori, A.
Score: 18.6, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.02.569713
Post-translational modifications (PTMs) regulate protein homeostasis and function. How aging affects the landscape of PTMs remains largely elusive. Here, we reveal changes in hundreds of protein ubiquitylation, acetylation, and phosphorylation sites in the aging brain of mice. We show that aging has a major impact on protein ubiquitylation and that 29% of the ubiquitylation sites are affected independently of protein abundance, indicating altered PTM stoichiometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Acoustic enrichment of heterogenous circulating tumor cells and clusters from patients with metastatic prostate cancer
Authors: Magnusson, C.; Augustsson, P.; Undvall Anand, E.; Lenshof, A.; Josefsson, A.; Welen, K.; Bjartell, A.; Ceder, Y.; Lilja, H.; Laurell, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.23299128
BackgroundThere are important unmet clinical needs to develop cell enrichment technologies to enable unbiased label-free isolation of both single cell and clusters of circulating tumor cells (CTCs) manifesting heterogeneous lineage specificity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Wolf-dog hybrids arise: new insight into the eastern fringe of the Northern European wolf population
Authors: Tirronen, K. F.; Kuznetsova, A. S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-12-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.04.569906
In study, tissue samples of 35 wolves hunted in Russian Karelia and 12 specimens of dogs were used in 2012-2022 for genetic analysis. Among wolves four individuals (11%) were recognized as wolf-dog hybrids (WDH) according to phenotypic characteristics. The analysis of 11 autosomal STR confirmed the hybrid origin of three, and allowed us to exclude one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
