<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Gene expression differences associated with alcohol use disorder in human brain
Authors: Willis, C.; White, J. D.; Minto, M. S.; Quach, B. C.; Han, S.; Tao, R.; Shin, J. H.; Deep-Soboslay, A.; Hyde, T.; Mayfield, R. D.; Webb, B. T.; Johnson, E. O.; Kleinman, J. E.; Bierut, L. J.; Hancock, D. B.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24301386
Excessive alcohol consumption is a leading cause of preventable death worldwide. Neurobiological mechanisms associated with alcohol use disorder (AUD) remain poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Repeated Hand Grip Strength is an Objective Marker for Disability and Severity of Key Symptoms in Post-COVID ME/CFS
Authors: Paffrath, A.; Kim, L.; Kedor, C.; Stein, E.; Rust, R.; Freitag, H.; Hoppmann, U.; Hanitsch, L. G.; Bellmann-Strobl, J.; Wittke, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Sotzny, F.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301776
Post-COVID Syndrome (PCS) refers to a diverse array of symptoms that persist beyond 3 months of the acute phase of a SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Noxious stimulation induces self-protective behaviour in bumblebees
Authors: Gibbons, M.; Pasquini, E.; Kowalewska, A.; Read, E.; Gibson, S.; Crump, A.; Solvi, C.; Versace, E.; Chittka, L.
Score: 72.7, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575734
Self-grooming directed towards a noxiously-stimulated body part is one indicator that an animal may feel pain. In insects, the lack of evidence for such behaviour has been widely argued to reflect the absence of pain experiences. Here, we tested whether bumblebees (Bombus terrestris) selectively groom one of their antennae that was touched with a noxiously-heated (65 {square}C) probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Design of a Cereblon construct for crystallographic and biophysical studies of protein degraders
Authors: Kroupova, A.; Spiteri, V. A.; Furihata, H.; Darren, D.; Ramachandran, S.; Rutter, Z.; Chakraborti, S.; Haubrich, K.; Pethe, J.; Gonzales, D.; Wijaya, A.; Rodriguez-Rios, M.; Lynch, D. M.; Farnaby, W.; Nakasone, M.; Zollman, D.; Ciulli, A.
Score: 25.5, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.575503
The ubiquitin E3 ligase cereblon (CRBN) is the target of therapeutic drugs thalidomide and lenalidomide and is recruited by most targeted protein degraders (PROTACs and molecular glues) in clinical development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Surface Patterned Omniphobic Tiles (SPOTs): a versatile platform for scalable liquid handling
Authors: Shiri, S.; Qazi, M. J.; Tan, S.; Albo, J.; Chen, A.; Fukuda, R.; Jain, M. S.; Menesses, M.; Nchinda, N.; Ahmed, G.; Gallegos, A.; Gangishetty, M.; Congreve, D.; Cira, N. J.
Score: 23.9, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.575712
Manipulating liquids is a ubiquitous need for experiments across numerous scientific disciplines. To overcome limitations of current methods, we introduce Surface Patterned Omniphobic Tiles (SPOTs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>edgeR 4.0: powerful differential analysis of sequencing data with expanded functionality and improved support for small counts and larger datasets
Authors: Chen, Y.; Chen, L.; Lun, A. T. L.; Baldoni, P. L.; Smyth, G. K.
Score: 78.5, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.576131
edgeR is an R/Bioconductor software package for differential analyses of sequencing data in the form of read counts for genes or genomic features. Over the past 15 years, edgeR has been a popular choice for statistical analysis of data from sequencing technologies such as RNA-seq or ChIP-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>PatternJ: an ImageJ toolset for the automated and quantitative analysis of regular spatial patterns found in sarcomeres, axons, somites, and more
Authors: Baheux Blin, M.; Loreau, V.; Schnorrer, F.; Mangeol, P.
Score: 21.1, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576053
Regular spatial patterns are ubiquitous forms of organization in nature. In animals, regular patterns can be found from the cellular scale to the tissue scale, and from early stages of development to adulthood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Discovery of Highly Active Kynureninases for Cancer Immunotherapy through Protein Language Model
Authors: Eom, H.; Cho, K. S.; Lee, J.; Kim, S.; Park, S.; Kim, H.; Yang, J.; Han, Y.-H.; Lee, J.; Seok, C.; Lee, M. S.; Song, W. J.; Steinegger, M.
Score: 27.1, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575968
Overcoming the immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment is a promising strategy in anticancer therapy. L-kynurenine, a strong immunosuppressive metabolite can be degraded through kynureninases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>THE IMPACT OF ROUTINE CARDIAC TROPONIN I-BASED CARDIOTOXICITY SCREENING ON CLINICAL OUTCOMES IN PATIENTS ON CANCER IMMUNOTHERAPY
Authors: Ivanovic, M.; Chan, A.; Cheng, E.; Xu, S.; Le, C.; Franquiz, M.; You, J.; Fazal, M.; Batchelder, R.; Reddy, S. A.; Katsumoto, T. R.; Ramchandran, K.; Colevas, A. D.; Khan, S.; Fan, A.; Cheng, P.; Wakelee, H.; Wu, S. M.; Witteles, R. M.; Neal, J. W.; Waliany, S.; Zhu, H.
Score: 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Optogenetic generation of leader cells reveals a force-velocity relation for collective cell migration
Authors: Rossetti, L.; Grosser, S.; Abenza, J. F.; Valon, L.; Roca-Cusachs, P.; Alert, R.; Trepat, X.
Score: 46.8, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576733
The front of migratory cellular clusters during development, wound healing and cancer invasion is typically populated with highly protrusive cells that are called leader cells. Leader cells are thought to physically pull and direct their cohort of followers, but how leaders and followers are mechanically organized to migrate collectively remains controversial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating the Diagnostic and Treatment Recommendation Capabilities of GPT-4 Vision in Dermatology
Authors: Pillai, A.; Parappally-Joseph, S.; Hardin, J.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301743
Background: The integration of artificial intelligence (AI) in dermatology presents a promising frontier for enhancing diagnostic accuracy and treatment planning. However, general purpose AI models require rigorous evaluation before being applied to real-world medical cases. Objective: This project specifically evaluates GPT-4V&amp;#39;s performance in accurately diagnosing and generating treatment plans for common dermatological conditions, comparing its assessment of textual versus image data and its performance with multimodal inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A new genetically tractable non-vertebrate system to study complete camera-type eye regeneration
Authors: Accorsi, A.; Pardo, B.; Ross, E.; Corbin, T. J.; McClain, M.; Weaver, K.; Delventhal, K.; Morrison, J. A.; McKinney, M. C.; McKinney, S. A.; Sanchez Alvarado, A.
Score: 42.9, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.26.577494
Camera-type eyes are complex sensory organs susceptible to irreversible damage. Their repair is difficult to study due to the paucity of camera-type eye regeneration models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Sonic restoration: Acoustic stimulation enhances soil fungal biomass and activity of plant growth-promoting fungi
Authors: Robinson, J. M.; Cando-Dumancela, C.; Breed, M. F.
Score: 19.4, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575298
Ecosystem restoration interventions often utilise visible elements to restore an ecosystem (e.g., replanting native plant communities and reintroducing lost species). However, using acoustic stimulation to restore ecosystems has received little attention. Our study aimed to (a) investigate the potential effects of acoustic stimulation on fungal biomass and organic matter decomposition, which are both crucial components of ecosystem functioning and (b) assess the effect of acoustic stimulation on the growth rate and sporulation of the plant growth-promoting fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Deaths induced by compassionate use of hydroxychloroquine during the first COVID-19 wave: the devil is in the details.
Authors: Beaudart, C.; Douxfils, J.; Musuamba, F.; Dogne, J.-M.
Score: 165.0, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301464
Several trials of different designs were conducted to investigate the efficacy and safety of hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) for the prevention and/or the treatment of COVID-19 patients. Recently, it has been reported that HCQ might have been associated with an excess of 16,990 deaths during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic in 6 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Changes in the cellular makeup of motor patterning circuits drive courtship song evolution in Drosophila
Authors: Ye, D.; Walsh, J. T.; Junker, I. P.; Ding, Y.
Score: 16.9, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576861
How evolutionary changes in genes and neurons encode species variation in complex motor behaviors are largely unknown. Here, we develop genetic tools that permit a neural circuit comparison between the model species Drosophila melanogaster and the closely-related species D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Metagenomic analysis of colonic tissue and stool microbiome in patients with colorectal cancer in a South Asian population
Authors: Gamage, B.; Ranasinghe, D.; Sahankumari, P.; Malavige, G. N.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.24301775
Objective: The gut microbiome is thought to play an important role in the development of colorectal cancer (CRC). However, as the gut microbiome varies widely based on diet, we sought to investigate the gut microbiome changes in patients with CRC in a South Asian population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Early detection of malignant and pre-malignant peripheral nerve tumors using cell-free DNA fragmentomics
Authors: Sundby, R. T.; Szymanski, J. J.; Pan, A.; Jones, P. A.; Mahmood, S. Z.; Reid, O. H.; Srihari, D.; Armstrong, A. E.; Chamberlain, S.; Burgic, S.; Weekley, K.; Murray, B.; Patel, S.; Lucas, A. N.; Fagan, M.; Dufek, A.; Meyer, C. F.; Collins, N. B.; Van Tine, B. A.; Dombi, E.; Gross, A. M.; Kim, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Accurate inference of population history in the presence of background selection
Authors: Cousins, T.; Tabin, D.; Patterson, N.; Reich, D.; Durvasula, A.
Score: 34.3, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576291
1All published methods for learning about demographic history make the simplifying assumption that the genome evolves neutrally, and do not seek to account for the effects of natural selection on patterns of variation. This is a major concern, as ample work has demonstrated the pervasive effects of natural selection and in particular background selection (BGS) on patterns of genetic variation in diverse species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Randomizing the human genome by engineering recombination between repeat elements
Authors: Koeppel, J.; Ferreira, R.; Vanderstichele, T.; Riedmayr, L. M.; Peets, E. M.; Girling, G.; Weller, J.; Liberante, F. G.; Ellis, T.; Church, G. M.; Parts, L.
Score: 97.3, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.576745
While protein-coding genes are characterized increasingly well, 99% of the human genome is non-coding and poorly understood. This gap is due to a lack of tools for engineering variants that affect sequence to the necessary extent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>The impact of higher uptake of plant-based diets in England: model-based estimates of health care resource use and health-related quality of life
Authors: Henderson, N.; Sampson, C. J.
Score: 11.8, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300536
Plant-based diets have grown in popularity in recent years, in part because of the perceived health benefits; higher consumption of vegetables and other healthy foods is associated with better nutrition and reduced risk of disease. In this study, we estimate the potential impact of higher uptake of a 100% plant-based (vegan) diet in England from the perspective of the National Health Service (NHS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Predicting Adverse Behavior in Individuals with Autism Spectrum Disorder Through Off-body Sleep Analysis
Authors: Kiarashi, Y.; Suresha, P. B.; Bahrami Rad, A.; Reyna, M.; Anderson, C.; Foster, J.; Lantz, J.; Villavicencio, T.; Hamlin, T.; Clifford, G. D.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301681
Poor sleep quality in Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) individuals is linked to severe daytime behaviors. This study explores the relationship between a prior night&amp;#39;s sleep structure and its predictive power for next-day behavior in ASD individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Are socio-demographic factors associated with electronic Health Information System utilization? A cross sectional study of the District Health Information System -2 (DHIS-2) in Burundi
Authors: Yandemye, I.; Nimubona, A.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-01-05 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.24300804
The utilization of Electronic Health Information System is crucial in informing credible decision-making process, especially in developing countries. We aimed to investigate the socio-demographic factors of Health workers that are associated with their utilization of the DHIS-2 platform in Burundi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>A Randomised Clinical Trial of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of VRC07-523LS Administered via Different Routes and Doses (HVTN 127/HPTN 087)
Authors: Walsh, S. R.; Gay, C. L.; Karuna, S. T.; Hyrien, O.; Skalland, T.; Mayer, K. H.; Sobieszczyk, M. E.; Baden, L. R.; Goepfert, P. A.; del Rio, C.; Pantaleo, G.; Andrew, P.; Karg, C.; He, Z.; Lu, H.; Paez, C. A.; Baumblatt, J. A. G.; Polakowski, L. L.; Chege, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>In silico assessment of immune cross protection between BCoV and SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Beirao, B. C. B.; Querne, L. B.; Zettel Bastos, F.; Adur, M. d. A.; Cavalheiro, V. L.
Score: 140.2, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577193
Background: Humans have long shared infectious agents with cattle, and the bovine-derived human common cold OC-43 CoV is a not-so-distant example of cross-species viral spill over of coronaviruses. Human exposure to the Bovine Coronavirus (BCoV) is certainly common, as the virus is endemic in most high-density cattle-raising regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Altered IgG4 Antibody Response to Repeated mRNA versus Protein COVID Vaccines
Authors: Kalkeri, R.; Zhu, M.; Cloney-Clark, S.; Plested, J. S.; Parekh, A.; Gorinson, D.; Cai, R.; Mahato, S.; Ramanathan, P.; Aurelia, L. C.; John Selva, K.; Marchese, A. M.; Fries, L.; Chung, A. W.; Dunkle, L. M.
Score: 283.3, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301374
Repeated mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination has been associated with increases in the proportion of IgG4 in spike-specific antibody responses and concurrent reductions in Fc{gamma}-mediated effector functions that may limit control of viral infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive ML-based Respiratory Monitoring System for Physiological Monitoring &amp;amp; Resource Planning in the ICU
Authors: Hüser, M.; Lyu, X.; Faltys, M.; Pace, A.; Hoche, M.; Hyland, S. L.; Yeche, H.; Burger, M.; Merz, T. M.; Rätsch, G.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301516
Respiratory failure (RF) is a frequent occurrence in critically ill patients and is associated with significant morbidity and mortality as well as resource use. To improve the monitoring and management of RF in intensive care unit (ICU) patients, we used machine learning to develop a monitoring system covering the entire management cycle of RF, from early detection and monitoring, to assessment of readiness for extubation and prediction of extubation failure risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>An infection and pathogenesis mouse model of SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 4266.1, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) is highly attenuated, but can cause mortality in a specifically designed human ACE2-transgenic mouse model, making it an invaluable surrogate model for evaluating the efficacy of drugs and vaccines against SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cryo-EM analysis on magnetic beads for scarce macromolecules in heterogeneous samples
Authors: Arimura, Y.; Konishi, H. A.; Funabiki, H.
Score: 53.3, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.21.576499
Here, we introduce Magnetic Isolation and Concentration (MagIC)-cryo-EM, a technique enabling direct structural analysis of targets captured on nanomagnetic beads, thereby reducing the targets concentration requirement to &amp;lt; 0.0005 mg/ml, which is 100 to 1000-fold lower than conventional cryo-EM methods. Using MagIC-cryo-EM, we characterized structural variations of oocyte-specific linker histone H1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The effects of intermittent or continuous exercise on renal haemodynamics during moderate-intensity exercise
Authors: Kawakami, S.; Yasuno, T.; Kawakami, S.; Ito, A.; Fujimi, K.; Matsuda, T.; Nakashima, S.; Masutani, K.; Uehara, Y.; Higaki, Y.; Michishita, R.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-26 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.24301695
Purpose Moderate-intensity exercise has beneficial effects for individuals with CKD. However, it is unclear whether intermittent exercise (IE) has a different effect on renal haemodynamics compared to continuous exercise (CE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating GPT-4 as a Clinical Decision Support Tool in Ischemic Stroke Management
Authors: Haim, A.; Katson, M.; Cohen-Shelly, M.; Peretz, S.; Aran, D.; Shelly, S.
Score: 11.3, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301409
Cerebrovascular diseases are the second most common cause of death worldwide and one of the major causes of disability burden. Advancements in artificial intelligence (AI) have the potential to revolutionize healthcare delivery, particularly in critical decision-making scenarios such as ischemic stroke management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Sensory Input, Sex, and Function Shape Hypothalamic Cell Type Development
Authors: Kaplan, H. S.; Logeman, B. L.; Zhang, K.; Santiago, C.; Sohail, N.; Naumenko, S.; Ho Sui, S. J.; Ginty, D. D.; Ren, B.; Dulac, C.
Score: 40.7, Published: 2024-01-23 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.23.576835
Mammalian behavior and physiology undergo dramatic changes in early life. Young animals rely on conspecifics to meet their homeostatic needs, until weaning and puberty initiate nutritional independence and sex-specific social interactions, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Healthy Japanese Dietary Pattern Is Associated with Slower Biological Aging in Older Men: WASEDA&amp;#39;S Health Study
Authors: Kawamura, T.; Higuchi, M.; Ito, T.; Kawakami, R.; Usui, C.; McGreevy, K. M.; Horvath, S.; Radak, Z.; Torii, S.; Suzuki, K.; Ishii, K.; Sakamoto, S.; Oka, K.; Muraoka, I.; Tanisawa, K.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24300981
Aging is the greatest risk factor for numerous diseases and mortality, and establishing geroprotective interventions targeting aging is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 176.7, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Automation risk and subjective wellbeing in the UK
Authors: Zheng, J.; Rohenkohl, B.; Barahona, M.; Clarke, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301484
The personal well-being of workers may be influenced by the risk of job automation brought about by technological innovation. Here we use data from the Understanding Society survey in the UK and a fixed-effects model to examine associations between working in a highly automatable job and life and job satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Use of tryptic peptide MALDI mass spectrometry imaging to identify the spatial proteomic landscape of colorectal cancer liver metastases.
Authors: Li, C. M. Y.; Briggs, M.; Lee, Y. R.; Tin, T.; Young, C.; Pierides, J.; Kaur, G.; Drew, P.; Maddern, G.; Hoffman, P.; Klinger-Hoffman, M.; Fenix, K.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-01-25 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.24.24301748
Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the second leading cause of cancer-related deaths worldwide. CRC liver metastases (CRLM) are often resistant to conventional treatments, with high rates of recurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the Adequacy of Morphological Models used in Palaeobiology
Authors: Mulvey, L. P. A.; May, M. R.; Brown, J. M.; Hoehna, S.; Wright, A. M.; Warnock, R. C. M.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2024-01-27 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.25.577179
Reconstructing the evolutionary history of different groups of organisms provides insight into how life originated and diversified on Earth. Phylogenetic trees are commonly used to estimate this evolutionary history, providing a hypothesis of the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>The SUbventral-Gland master Regulator (SUGR) of nematode virulence
Authors: Pellegrin, C.; Damm, A.; Sperling, A. L.; Molloy, B.; Shin, D. S.; Long, J.; Brett, P.; Bravo, A. D.-T.; Lynch, S. J.; Senatori, B.; Vieira, P.; Mejias, J.; Kumar, A.; Masonbrink, R. E.; Maier, T. R.; Baum, T. J.; Eves-van den Akker, S.
Score: 35.6, Published: 2024-01-24 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.22.576598
All pathogens must tailor their gene expression to their environment. Therefore, targeting host:parasite biology that regulates these changes in gene expression could open up routes to pathogen control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>A Non-targeted Proteomics Newborn Screening Platform for Genetic Disorders
Authors: Shibata, H.; Nakajima, D.; Konno, R.; Hijikata, A.; Higashiguchi, M.; Nihira, H.; Shimodera, S.; Miyamoto, T.; Nishitani-Isa, M.; Hiejima, E.; Izawa, K.; Takita, J.; Heike, T.; Okamura, K.; Ohnishi, H.; Ishimura, M.; Okada, S.; Yamashita, M.; Morio, T.; Kanegane, H.; Imai, K.; Nakamura, Y.; Nonoyama, S.; Uchiyama, T.; Onodera, M.; Nishikomori, R.; Ohara, O.; Kawashima, Y.; Yasumi, T.
Score: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Pharmacogenomics Guided Spaceflight: the intersection between space-flown drugs and space genes
Authors: Nelson, T. M.; Rose, J. K.; Walter, C. E.; Cervantes-Navarro, G. L.; Schmidt, C. M.; Lin, R.; Alexander, E.; Zheng, J. T.; Glicksberg, B. S.; Schmidt, J. C.; Overbey, E.; Rana, B.; Patel, H.; Schmidt, M. A.; Mason, C. E.
Score: 11.0, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575951
Ten years ago, it was predicted that the multi-omics revolution would also revolutionize space pharmacogenomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Intestinal barrier function in the naked mole-rat: an emergent model for gastrointestinal insights
Authors: Aguilera-Lizarraga, J.; Ritoux, A.; Bulmer, D.; Smith, E. S. J.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.576063
The intestinal barrier plays a crucial role in homeostasis, both by facilitating absorption of nutrients and providing a tight shield to prevent the invasion by either pathogen or commensal microorganisms. Intestinal barrier malfunction is associated with systemic inflammation, oxidative stress, and decreased insulin sensitivity, which may lead to the dysregulation of other tissues such as the liver, fat, skeletal muscle, and brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>FROM DUST TO SEED: A LUNAR CHICKPEA STORY
Authors: Atkin, J.; Oliveira Pedro dos Santos, S.
Score: 75.7, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576311
Food sustainability is one of the most significant barriers to long-term space travel. Providing resources from Earth is not cost-efficient, and resupply missions are not viable to meet the needs of long-term life in deep space conditions. Plants in space can provide a source of nutrition and oxygen, reducing the reliance on packaged foods, reducing resupply needs, and extending the duration of missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Major depressive disorder, neuroticism, suicidal behaviors, and depression severity are all associated with neurotoxic immune networks and their intricate interactions with metabolic syndrome.
Authors: Maes, M.; Jirakran, K.; Vasupanrajit, A.; Zhou, B.; Tunvirachaisakul, C.; Almulla, A. F.
Score: 10.5, Published: 2024-01-21 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.20.24301553
BackgroundMajor depressive disorder (MDD) is considered to be a neuroimmune disorder. However, there are no data regarding the association between comprehensive immune profiles and their interactions with the metabolic syndrome (MetS) in predicting neuroticism, suicidal behaviors, and severity of outpatient MDD (OMDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1353.8, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
ImportancePhase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects. ObjectiveConduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of the phase 3 trials to assess overall and non-specific health effects of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 20.7, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Pathogenic autoantibody internalization in myositis
Authors: Pinal-Fernandez, I.; Munoz-Braceras, S.; Casal-Dominguez, M.; Pak, K.; Torres-Ruiz, J.; Musai, J.; Dell&amp;#39;Orso, S.; Naz, F.; Islam, S.; Gutierrez-Cruz, G.; Dolores Cano, M.; Matas-Garcia, A.; Padrosa, J.; Tobias-Baraja, E.; Garrabou, G.; Aldecoa, I.; Espinosa, G.; Simeon-Aznar, C. P.; Guillen-Del-Castillo, A.; Gil-Vila, A.; Trallero-Araguas, E.; Christopher-Stine, L.; Lloyd, T. E.; Liewluck, T.; Naddaf, E.; Stenzel, W.; Greenberg, S. A.; Maria Grau, J.; Selva-O&amp;#39;Callaghan, A.; Milisenda, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Orthogonalized human protease control of secreted signals
Authors: Aldrete, C. A.; Vlahos, A. E.; Pei, J.; Cong, Q.; Gao, X. J.
Score: 12.1, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576308
Synthetic circuits that regulate protein secretion in human cells could support cell-based therapies by enabling control over local environments. While protein-level circuits enable such potential clinical applications, featuring orthogonality and compactness, their non-human origin poses a potential immunogenic risk. Here, we developed Humanized Drug Induced Regulation of Engineered CyTokines (hDIRECT) as a platform to control cytokine activity exclusively using human-derived proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Statistical inference with a manifold-constrained RNA velocity model uncovers cell cycle speed modulations
Authors: Lederer, A. R.; Leonardi, M.; Talamanca, L.; Herrera, A.; Droin, C.; Khven, I.; Carvalho, H. J.; Valente, A.; Dominguez Mantes, A.; Mulet Arabi, P.; Pinello, L.; Naef, F.; La Manno, G.
Score: 40.1, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.576093
Across a range of biological processes, cells undergo coordinated changes in gene expression, resulting in transcriptome dynamics that unfold within a low-dimensional manifold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>MRI-Targeted Prostate Biopsy Introduces Grade Inflation and Overtreatment
Authors: Batouche, A. O.; Czeizler, E.; Lehto, T.-P.; Erickson, A.; Shadbahr, T.; Laajala, T. D.; Pohjonen, J.; Vickers, A. J.; Mirtti, T.; Rannikko, A. S.
Score: 6.2, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.10.24300922
PurposeThe use of MRI-targeted biopsies has led to lower detection of Gleason Grade Group 1 (GG1) prostate cancer and increased detection of GG2 disease. Although this finding is generally attributed to improved sensitivity and specificity of MRI for aggressive cancers, it might also be explained by grade inflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Wild bird mass mortalities in eastern Canada associated with the Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza A(H5N1) virus, 2022
Authors: Avery-Gomm, S.; Barychka, T.; English, M.; Ronconi, R.; Wilhelm, S. I.; Rail, J.-F.; Cormier, T.; Beaumont, M.; Bowser, C.; Burt, T. V.; Collins, S.; Duffy, S.; Giacinti, J. A.; Gilliland, S.; Giroux, J.-F.; Gjerdrum, C.; Guillemette, M.; Hargan, K. E.; Jones, M.; Kennedy, A.; Kusalik, L.; Lair, S.; Lang, A. S.; Lavoie, R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
