<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Chronic Pain, Cannabis Legalization and Cannabis Use Disorder in Veterans Health Administration Patients, 2005 to 2019
Authors: Hasin, D. S.; Wall, M. M.; Alschuler, D.; Mannes, Z. L.; Malte, C.; Olfson, M.; Keyes, K. M.; Gradus, J. L.; Cerda, M.; Maynard, C. C.; Keyhani, S.; Martins, S. S.; Fink, D. S.; Livne, O.; McDowell, Y.; Sherman, S.; Saxon, A. J.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292453
Abstract/SummaryO_ST_ABSBackgroundC_ST_ABSThe risk for cannabis use disorder (CUD) is elevated among U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Prebiotic Supplements Correct Oral Probiotic Deficiency for Lasting Allergy Relief
Authors: Han, C.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23291433
Allergic rhinitis has increased in the last fifty years from affecting less than a percent to more than twenty-six percent of the population[1]. Today, more than one hundred million people in the US suffer from these seasonal or yearlong allergies[2]. The hygiene hypothesis was proposed 30 years ago as a potential explanation for this phenomenon[3], and we built on that with the specific oral hygiene hypothesis[4].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Four Individually Identified Paired Dopamine Neurons Signal Taste Punishment in Larval Drosophila
Authors: Weber, D.; Vogt, K.; Miroschnikow, A.; Pankratz, M. J.; Thum, A. S.
Score: 8.2, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550661
Dopaminergic neurons (DANs) carry out multiple tasks in the brain, including the transmission of information related to rewards and punishments across various animal species. They are responsible for evaluating sensory input, storing resultant associations as memory, and continuously updating them based on their relevance and reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Targeted protein editing with an antibody-based system
Authors: Rimon, O.; Konc, J.; Roy Chowdhury, V.; Bernardes, G. J. L.; Vendruscolo, M.
Score: 18.8, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.551006
The chemical modification of proteins is one of the major mechanisms used to regulate the trafficking and function of these macromolecules in the cell. It is therefore of great interest to develop tools to exploit this type of modifications for applications in molecular biology, medicine and biotechnology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Flow in fetoplacental microvessels in vitro enhances perfusion, barrier function, and matrix stability
Authors: Cherubini, M.; Erickson, S.; Padmanaban, P.; Haberkant, P.; Stein, F.; Sastre, V. B.; Haase, K.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2023-07-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549736
Proper placental vascularization is vital for pregnancy outcomes, but assessing it with animal models and human explants has limitations. Here, we present a 3D in vitro model of human placenta terminal villi that includes fetal mesenchyme and vascular endothelium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Unified fate mapping in multiview single-cell data
Authors: Weiler, P.; Lange, M.; Klein, M.; Pe&amp;#39;er, D.; Theis, F.
Score: 119.9, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.549685
Single-cell RNA sequencing allows us to model cellular state dynamics and fate decisions using expression similarity or RNA velocity to reconstruct state-change trajectories. However, trajectory inference does not incorporate valuable time point information or utilize additional modalities, while methods that address these different data views cannot be combined and do not scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Disease-specific tau filaments assemble via polymorphic intermediates
Authors: Lövestam, S.; Li, D.; Wagstaff, J. L.; Kotecha, A.; Kimanius, D.; McLaughlin, S. H.; Murzin, A. G.; Freund, S. M. V.; Goedert, M.; Scheres, S. H. W.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550295
Intermediate species in the assembly of amyloid filaments are believed to play a central role in neurodegenerative diseases and may constitute important targets for therapeutic intervention. However, structural information about intermediate species has been scarce and the molecular mechanisms by which amyloids assemble remain largely unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Drug screening in human physiologic medium identifies uric acid as an inhibitor of rigosertib efficacy
Authors: Rawat, V.; DeLear, P.; Prashanth, P.; Ozgurses, M. E.; Tebeje, A.; Burns, P. A.; Conger, K. O.; Solis, C.; Hasnain, Y.; Novikova, A.; Endress, J. E.; Gonzalez-Sanchez, P.; Dong, W.; Stephanopoulos, G.; DeNicola, G. M.; Harris, I. S.; Sept, D. S.; Mason, F. M.; Coloff, J. L.
Score: 31.7, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550731</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The persistent underrepresentation of patients with chronic kidney disease in cardiovascular trials: a systematic review and evidence map of exclusion and outcomes
Authors: Colombijn, J. M. T.; Idema, D. L.; van Beem, S.; Blokland, A. M.; van der Braak, K.; Handoko, M. L.; Huis in&amp;#39;t Veld, L. F.; Kaul, T.; Kolagasigil-Akdemir, N.; Kusters, M. P. T.; Meijvis, S. C. A.; Oosting, I. J.; Spijker, R.; Bots, M.; Hooft, L.; Verhaar, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>An mTOR/RNA pol I axis shapes chromatin architecture in response to fasting
Authors: Al-Refaie, N.; Padovani, F.; Binando, F.; Hornung, J.; Zhao, Q.; Towbin, B. D.; Sarinay Cenik, E.; Stroustrup, N.; Schmoller, K. M.; Cabianca, D. S.
Score: 33.6, Published: 2023-07-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.22.550032
Chromatin architecture is a fundamental mediator of genome function. Fasting is a major environmental cue across the animal kingdom. Yet, how it impacts on 3D genome organization is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Oral health vulnerability and its associated risk factors among tribal elderly people in Bangladesh: a pilot study
Authors: Barua, S.; Bosu, S.; Haque, M. F.; Bosak, L.; Rashid, M. R.; Zaman, S. R.; Rahman, M. F.; Rahman, M. M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293159
BackgroundTribal elderly is a vulnerable population due to their geographic location and lack of access to healthcare services. This study aims to assess the oral health status of tribal elderly in Bangladesh and identify any associated risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A conserved fertilization complex of Izumo1, Spaca6, and Tmem81 mediates sperm-egg interaction in vertebrates
Authors: Deneke, V. E.; Blaha, A.; Lu, Y.; Draper, J. M.; Phan, C. S.; Panser, K.; Schleiffer, A.; Jacob, L.; Humer, T.; Stejskal, K.; Krssakova, G.; Handler, D.; Kamoshita, M.; Vance, T. D. R.; Roitinger, E.; Lee, J. E.; Ikawa, M.; Pauli, A.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550750
Fertilization, the fusion of sperm and egg, is essential for sexual reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Contribution of carbon inputs to soil carbon accumulation cannot be neglected
Authors: He, X.; Abramoff, R.; Abs, E.; Georgiou, K.; Zhang, H.; Goll, D. S.
Score: 17.9, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549330
In a recently published paper (1), the authors report that microbial carbon use efficiency (CUE) is the primary determinant of global soil organic carbon (SOC) storage and that the relative impact of plant carbon inputs on SOC is minor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Decrease in multiple complement protein levels is associated with the development of islet autoimmunity and type 1 diabetes
Authors: Webb-Robertson, B.-J. M.; Nakayasu, E. S.; Dong, F.; Waugh, K.; Flores, J.; Bramer, L.; Schepmoes, A.; Gao, Y.; Fillmore, T.; Onengut-Gumuscu, S.; Frazer-Abel, A.; Rich, S.; Holers, M.; Metz, T.; Rewers, M.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-07-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.13.23292628
Type 1 diabetes (T1D) is a chronic condition caused by autoimmune destruction of the insulin-producing pancreatic {beta}-cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic prediction of common and rare diseases
Authors: Carrasco-Zanini, J.; Pietzner, M.; Davitte, J.; Surendran, P.; Croteau-Chonka, D. C.; Robins, C.; Torralbo, A.; Tomlinson, C.; Fitzpatrick, N.; Ytsma, C.; Kanno, T.; Gade, S.; Freitag, D.; Ziebell, F.; Denaxas, S.; Betts, J. C.; Wareham, N. J.; Hemingway, H.; Scott, R. A.; Langenberg, C.
Score: 33.0, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292811
BackgroundFor many diseases there are delays in diagnosis due to a lack of objective biomarkers for disease onset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Venom tradeoff shapes interspecific interactions, physiology and reproduction
Authors: Surm, J. M.; Birch, S. J.; Macrander, J.; Jaimes-Becerra, A.; Fridrich, A.; Aharoni, R.; Rozenblat, R.; Sharabany, J.; Appelbaum, L.; Reitzel, A. M.; Moran, Y.
Score: 29.6, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550294
The ability of an animal to effectively capture prey and defend against predators is pivotal for its survival. Venom, a mixture of many toxin proteins, shapes predator-prey interactions. Here, we use the sea anemone Nematostella vectensis to test how toxin genotypes impact predator-prey interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Federated analysis of the contribution of recessive coding variants to 29,745 developmental disorder patients from diverse populations
Authors: Chundru, V. K.; Zhang, Z.; Walter, K.; Lindsay, S.; Danecek, P.; Eberhardt, R. Y.; Gardner, E. J.; Malawsky, D. S.; Wigdor, E. M.; Torene, R.; Retterer, K.; Wright, C. F.; McWalter, K.; Sheridan, E.; Firth, H. V.; Hurles, M. E.; Samocha, K. E.; Ustach, V. D.; Martin, H. C.
Score: 27.6, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic Age Acceleration in Surviving versus Deceased COVID-19 Patients with Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome following Hospitalization
Authors: Bejaoui, Y.; Humaira Amanullah, F.; Saad, M.; Taleb, S.; Bradic, M.; Megarbane, A.; Ait Hssain, A.; Abi Khalil, C.; El Hajj, N.
Score: 400.9, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549478
Aging has been reported as a major risk factor for severe symptoms and higher mortality rates in COVID-19 patients. Molecular hallmarks such as epigenetic alterations and telomere attenuation reflect the biological process of aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent profiling of multiscale 3D genome organization and gene expression in single mammalian cells
Authors: Zhou, T.; Zhang, R.; Jia, D.; Doty, R. T.; Munday, A. D.; Gao, D.; Xin, L.; Abkowitz, J. L.; Duan, Z.; Ma, J.
Score: 48.7, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549578
The organization of mammalian genomes within the nucleus features a complex, multiscale three-dimensional (3D) architecture. The functional significance of these 3D genome features, however, remains largely elusive due to limited single-cell technologies that can concurrently profile genome organization and transcriptional activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Uncertainty in serious illness: A national interdisciplinary consensus exercise to identify clinical research priorities
Authors: Etkind, S. N.; Barclay, S.; Spathis, A.; Hopkins, S.; Bowers, B.; Koffman, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.23293007
BackgroundSerious illness is characterised by uncertainty, particularly in older age groups. Uncertainty may be experienced by patients, family carers, and health professionals about a broad variety of issues. There are many evidence gaps regarding the experience and management of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the hype: large language models propagate race-based medicine
Authors: Omiye, J. A.; Lester, J.; Spichak, S.; Rotemberg, V.; Daneshjou, R.
Score: 66.7, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292192
ImportanceLarge language models (LLMs) are being integrated into healthcare systems; but these models recapitulate harmful, race-based medicine. ObjectiveThe objective of this study is to assess whether four commercially available large language models (LLMs) propagate harmful, inaccurate, race-based content when responding to eight different scenarios that historically included race-based medicine or widespread misconceptions around race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The Introduction of Social Health Insurance and Health Care Seeking Behavior in Urban Ethiopia
Authors: Zarepour, Z.; Mebratie, A.; Shamebo, D.; Shigute, Z.; Alemu, G.; Bedi, A. S.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292262
ObjectivesIn recent years, to enhance access to and use of health care the government of Ethiopia has introduced voluntary Community Based Health Insurance (CBHI) schemes for the rural and informal sectors of the economy. After years of planning and the ratification of a legal framework the government proposes to introduce a compulsory Social Health Insurance (SHI) program for formal sector employees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence in Biomedicine: Systematic Review
Authors: Gabashvili, I. S.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292672
Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a rapidly progressing technology with its applications expanding exponentially over the past decade. While initial breakthroughs predominantly focused on deep learning and computer vision, recent advancements have facilitated a shift towards natural language processing and beyond. This includes generative models, like ChatGPT, capable of understanding the grammar of software code, analog signals, and molecular structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Do people with disabilities have the same level of HIV knowledge and access to testing? Evidence from 513,252 people across 37 Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys
Authors: Rotenberg, S.; Chen, S.; Hanass-Hancock, J.; Davey, C.; Banks, L. M.; Kuper, H.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292845
BackgroundDisability and HIV are intricately linked, as people with disabilities are at higher risk of contracting HIV and HIV can lead to impairments and disability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Megakaryocyte infection by SARS-CoV-2 drives the formation of pathogenic afucosylated IgG antibodies in mice
Authors: Mabrouk, M.; Jalali, F.; Zaid, N.; Naya, A.; Khyatti, M.; Khalki, L.; Guessous, F.; Zaid, Y.
Score: 675.3, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549113
More than 90% of total human plasma immunoglobulin G (IgG) is found in a fucosylated form, but specific IgGs with low core fucosylation (afucosylated IgGs) are found in response to infections with enveloped viruses and to alloantigens on blood cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of the analytical and clinical sensitivity of thirty-four rapid antigen tests with the most prevalent SARS-CoV-2 variants of concern during the COVID-19 pandemic in the UK
Authors: Byrne, R. L.; Aljayyoussi, G.; Greenland - Bews, C.; Kontogianni, K.; Wooding, D.; Williams, C. T.; de Vos, M.; Body, R.; Adams, E. R.; Escadafel, C.; Edwards, T. R.; Cubas Atienzar, A. I.
Score: 74.4, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293072
BackgroundThe continued emergence of SARS-CoV-2 variants of concern (VOC) requires timely analytical and clinical evaluation of antigen-based rapid diagnostic tests (Ag-RDTs) especially those that are recommended for at home use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical Students&amp;#39; Attitudes toward AI in Medicine and their Expectations for Medical Education
Authors: Kimmerle, J.; Timm, J.; Festl-Wietek, T.; Cress, U.; Herrmann-Werner, A.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292877
Artificial intelligence (AI) is used in a variety of contexts in medicine. This involves the use of algorithms and software that analyze digital information to make diagnoses and suggest adapted therapies. It is unclear, however, what medical students know about AI in medicine, how they evaluate its application, and what they expect from their medical training accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Bacterial cGAS-like enzymes produce 2&amp;#39;,3&amp;#39;-cGAMP to activate an ion channel that restricts phage replication
Authors: Tak, U.; Walth, P.; Whiteley, A. T.
Score: 43.7, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550367
The mammalian innate immune system uses cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) to synthesize the cyclic dinucleotide 2&amp;#39;,3&amp;#39;-cGAMP during antiviral and antitumor immune responses. 2&amp;#39;,3&amp;#39;-cGAMP is a nucleotide second messenger that initiates inflammatory signaling by binding to and activating the stimulator of interferon genes (STING) receptor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic assessment of ISWI subunits reveals that NURF creates local accessibility for proper CTCF function
Authors: Iurlaro, M.; Masoni, F.; Wirbelauer, C.; Iskar, M.; Burger, L.; Schuebeler, D.
Score: 20.6, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.550466
Catalytic activity of the ISWI family of remodelers is critical for nucleosomal organization and DNA binding of transcription factors, including the insulator protein CTCF. To define which subcomplex mediates these diverse functions, we derived a panel of isogenic mouse stem cell lines each lacking one of six ISWI accessory subunits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence and characteristics of monogenic disease in adult kidney stone formers
Authors: Anderegg, M. A.; Olinger, E. G.; Bargagli, M.; Geraghty, R.; Pohlmeier, L.; Nater, A.; Bruggmann, R.; Sayer, J. A.; Vogt, B.; Schaller, A.; Fuster, D. G.
Score: 5.5, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292924
Molecular mechanisms of kidney stone formation remain unknown in most patients. Previous studies showed a high heritability of nephrolithiasis, but data on prevalence and characteristics of monogenic disease in unselected adults with nephrolithiasis are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The coupling between brain connectivity and heartbeat dynamics unveils the altered interoceptive mechanisms in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Candia-Rivera, D.; Vidailhet, M.; Chavez, M.; de Vico Fallani, F.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23292942
Parkinsons disease (PD) is often known for its classical motor symptoms, but non-motor symptoms are often reported including interoceptive and autonomic dysfunctions. Autonomic dysfunctions, such as cardiovascular, urinary, or thermoregulatory abnormalities, are more prone to be associated with motor and cognitive decline, as well as increase the risk of mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Three-dimensional single-cell transcriptome imaging of thick tissues
Authors: Fang, R.; Halpern, A. R.; Rahman, M. M.; Huang, Z.; Lei, Z.; Hell, S. J.; Dulac, C.; Zhuang, X.
Score: 63.1, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.550124
Multiplexed error-robust fluorescence in-situ hybridization (MERFISH) allows genome-scale imaging of RNAs in individual cells in intact tissues. To date, MERFISH has been applied to image thin tissue samples of [~]10-{micro}m thickness. Here, we present a method to enable three-dimensional (3D) single-cell transcriptome imaging of thick tissue specimens by integrating MERFISH with confocal microscopy for optical sectioning and deep learning for increasing imaging speed and quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic studies of human placentas reveal partnerships associated with preeclampsia, diabetes, gravidity, and labor.
Authors: Ho, S. J.; Chaput, D.; Sinkey, R. G.; Garces, A.; New, E. P.; Okuka, M.; Sang, P.; Arlier, S.; Semerci, N.; Steffensen, T. S.; Rutherford, T. J.; Alsina, A. E.; Cai, J.; Anderson, M. L.; Magness, R. R.; Uversky, V. N.; Cummings, D. A. T.; Tsibris, J. C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292673</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge and practice of road safety measures among motor-bikers in Bangladesh: a cross-sectional study
Authors: Das, S. K.; Tamannur, T.; Nesa, A.; Al Noman, A.; Dey, P.; Kundu, S. K.; Sultana, H.; Riaz, B. K.; ANM, S. I.; Sharower, G.; Dhar, B. K.; Rahman, M. M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293162
Introduction Road traffic accidents (RTAs) including motorbike accidents are the leading cause of death for teenagers between 15 and 29 and have been a serious concern in low- and middle-income countries like Bangladesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>An updated PREDICT breast cancer prognostic model including the benefits and harms of radiotherapy
Authors: Grootes, I.; Wishart, G. C.; Pharoah, P. D. P.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292777
BackgroundPredict Breast (www.breast.predict.nhs.uk) is an online prognostication and treatment benefit tool for early invasive breast cancer. However, the most recent version of PREDICT Breast (v2.2) was based on data for breast cancer cases diagnosed from 1999 to 2003 and did not incorporate the benefits of radiotherapy or the harms associated with theray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Industry payments to anesthesiologists in the United States between 2014 and 2022
Authors: Murayama, A.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293096
BackgroundFinancial relationships between physicians and the healthcare industry could be beneficial to improve patient care, but could lead to conflicts of interest. However, there was no study specifically evaluating the extent of financial relationships between anesthesiologists and the healthcare industry in the United States. MethodsUsing the Open Payments Database between 2014 and 2022, this longitudinal cross-sectional study examined the size, prevalence and trends of general (non-research) payments made by the healthcare industry to all anesthesiologists in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of Late Pleistocene and Holocene fossil lizards from Hall&amp;#39;s Cave and a primer on morphological variation in North American lizard skulls
Authors: Ledesma, D. T.; Scarpetta, S. G.; Jacisin, J. J.; Meza, A.; Kemp, M. E.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.549934
Fossil identification practices have a profound effect on our interpretation of the past because these identifications form the basis for downstream analyses. Therefore, well-supported fossil identifications are paramount for examining the impact of past environmental changes on populations and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Self-Supervised Learning for Histopathology with Masked Image Modeling
Authors: Filiot, A.; Ghermi, R.; Olivier, A.; Jacob, P.; Fidon, L.; Mac Kain, A.; Saillard, C.; Schiratti, J.-B.
Score: 8.0, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.23292757
Computational pathology is revolutionizing the field of pathology by integrating advanced computer vision and machine learning technologies into diagnostic workflows. It offers unprecedented opportunities for improved efficiency in treatment decisions by allowing pathologists to achieve higher precision and objectivity in disease classification, tumor microenvironment description and identification of new biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>One-Year Follow-up of Young People with ME/CFS Following Infectious Mononucleosis by Epstein-Barr Virus
Authors: Pricoco, R.; Meidel, P.; Hofberger, T.; Zietemann, H.; Mueller, Y.; Wiehler, K.; Michel, K.; Paulick, J.; Leone, A.; Haegele, M.; Mayer-Huber, S.; Gerrer, K.; Mittelstrass, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Renz-Polster, H.; Mihatsch, L.; Behrends, U.
Score: 45.1, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293082
BackgroundInfectious mononucleosis, caused by the Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV-IM), has been linked to the development of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue-syndrome (ME/CFS) in children, adolescents, and young adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Optical Control of G-Actin with a Photoswitchable Latrunculin
Authors: Veprek, N. A.; Cooper, M. H.; Laprell, L.; Yang, E. J.-N.; Folkerts, S.; Bao, R.; Oertner, T. G.; Pon, L. A.; Zuchero, J. B.; Trauner, D. H.
Score: 20.5, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.17.549222
Actin is one of the most abundant proteins in eukaryotic cells and a key component of the cytoskeleton. A range of small molecules have emerged that interfere with actin dynamics by either binding to polymeric F-actin or monomeric G-actin to stabilize or destabilize filaments or prevent their formation and growth, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 43.0, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The WY domain of an RxLR effector drives interactions with a host target phosphatase to mimic host regulatory proteins and promote Phytophthora infestans infection.
Authors: Bentham, A. R.; Wang, W.; Trusch, F.; Varden, F.; Birch, P. R.; Banfield, M. J.
Score: 24.7, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550319
Plant pathogens manipulate the cellular environment of the host to facilitate infection and colonization, often leading to plant diseases. To accomplish this, many specialized pathogens secrete virulence proteins called effectors into the host cell, which subvert processes such as immune signalling, gene transcription, and host metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>You can change your life through sports: Physical activity interventions to improve the health and wellbeing of adults experiencing homelessness: a mixed methods systematic review
Authors: Dawes, J. F.; Rogans-Watson, R.; Broderick, J.
Score: 10.9, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293203
ObjectivesSystematically synthesise evidence of physical activity interventions for people experiencing homelessness (PEH). DesignMixed-methods systematic review. Data sourcesEMBASE, Web of Science, CINAHL, PubMed (MEDLINE), PsycINFO, SPORTDiscus, and Cochrane Library, searched from inception to October 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Reactivation of herpesvirus type-6 and IgA/IgM-mediated responses to activin-A underpin Long COVID, including affective symptoms and chronic fatigue syndrome.
Authors: Vojdani, A.; Almulla, A. F.; Zhou, B.; Al-Hakeim, H. F.; Maes, M.
Score: 56.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23293046
AbstractO_ST_ABSBackgroundC_ST_ABSPersistent infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), reactivation of dormant viruses, and immune-oxidative responses are involved in Long COVID. ObjectivesTo investigate whether Long COVID and depressive, anxiety and chronic fatigue syndrome (CFS) symptoms, are associated with IgA/IgM/IgG to SARS-CoV-2, human Herpesvirus type 6 (HHV-6), Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV), and immune-oxidative biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 607.9, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
Background: Use of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 14.5, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in serotype distribution and disease severity in adults hospitalised with Streptococcus pneumoniae infection in Bristol and Bath: a retrospective cohort study, 2006-2022
Authors: Hyams, C.; Challen, R.; Hettle, D.; Amin-Chowdhury, Z.; Grimes, C.; Ruffino, G.; Conway, R.; Heath, R.; North, P.; Malin, A.; Maskell, N. A.; Williams, P.; Williams, O. M.; Ladhani, S. N.; Danon, L.; Finn, A.
Score: 4.1, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.30.23287917
BackgroundPaediatric pneumococcal conjugate vaccination (PCV) has reduced adult PCV-serotype disease: PCV7 has greater indirect effects than PCV13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omics analysis in primary T cells elucidates mechanisms behind disease associated genetic loci
Authors: Shi, C.; Zhao, D.; Rossi, S.; Frantzeskos, A.; Ding, J.; Ferrazzano, C.; Wynn, C.; Hum, R.; Richards, E.; Gupta, M.; Yap, C. F.; Plant, D.; Grencis, R.; Martin, P.; Adamson, A.; Eyre, S.; Bowes, J.; Barton, A.; Ho, P.; Rattray, M.; Orozco, G.
Score: 13.6, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292550
In this study, we present the most extensive dataset of chromatin conformation data with matching gene expression and chromatin accessibility from primary T cells to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT identifies gender disparities in scientific peer review
Authors: Verharen, J. P. H.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549552
The peer review process is a critical step in ensuring the quality of scientific research. However, its subjectivity has raised concerns. To investigate this issue, I examined over 500 publicly available peer review reports from 200 published neuroscience papers in 2022-2023. OpenAIs generative artificial intelligence ChatGPT was used to analyze language use in these reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Interdisciplinary Inquiry via PanelGPT: Application to Explore Chatbot Application in Sports Rehabilitation
Authors: McBee, J. C.; Han, D. Y.; Liu, L.; Ma, L.; Adjeroh, D. A.; Xu, D.; Hu, G.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292452
BackgroundChatGPT showcases exceptional conversational capabilities and extensive cross-disciplinary knowledge. In addition, it possesses the ability to perform multiple roles within a single chat session. This unique multi-role-playing feature positions ChatGPT as a promising tool to explore interdisciplinary subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>xTrimoPGLM: Unified 100B-Scale Pre-trained Transformer for Deciphering the Language of Protein
Authors: Chen, B.; Cheng, X.; Gengyang, L.-a.; Li, S.; Zeng, X.; Wang, B.; Gong, J.; Liu, C.; Zeng, A.; Dong, Y.; Tang, J.; Song, L.
Score: 98.1, Published: 2023-07-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.547496
Protein language models have shown remarkable success in learning biological information from protein sequences. However, most existing models are limited by either autoencoding or autoregressive pre-training objectives, which makes them struggle to handle protein understanding and generation tasks concurrently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive atlas of the aging vertebrate brain reveals signatures of progressive proteostasis dysfunction
Authors: Di Fraia, D.; Marino, A.; Lee, J. H.; Kelmer Sacramento, E.; Baumgart, M.; Bagnoli, S.; Tomaz da Silva, P.; Kumar Sahu, A.; Siano, G.; Tiessen, M.; Gagneur, J.; Frydman, J.; Cellerino, A.; Ori, A.
Score: 33.4, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549210
Protein homeostasis is disrupted in aging and neurodegenerative diseases, yet, the specific impact of aging on brain proteostasis remains poorly understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
