<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Early Urinary Markers of Kidney Injury in Adult People with Cystic Fibrosis Correlate with Neutrophil Activation and Lung Infection
Authors: Rosner, G. M.; Goswami, H. B.; Sessions, K.; Mendyka, L. K.; Kerin, B.; Vlasac, I.; Mellinger, D.; Gwilt, L.; Hampton, T. H.; Graber, M.; Ashare, A.; Harris, W. T.; Christensen, B.; Swiatecka-Urban, A.; Stanton, B. A.; Skopelja-Gardner, S.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-11-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298378
BackgroundAdult people with cystic fibrosis (PwCF) have a higher risk of end-stage kidney disease than the general population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Plant-like heliotropism in a photosymbiotic animal
Authors: Lintnerova, E.; Shaw, C.; Keys, M.; Brownlee, C.; Modepalli, V.
Score: 48.9, Published: 2023-11-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.02.565328
Being photosynthetic sessile organisms, plants established heliotropism to track the suns position across the sky and allow their vegetative parts to orient accordingly. Here, we report plant-like heliotropic movement in a photosymbiotic sea anemone Anemonia viridis. Like plants, photosynthesis represents a key energy source in endosymbiotic cnidarians bearing microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>A double-ring of human RAD52 remodels replication forks restricting fork reversal
Authors: Honda, M.; Razzaghi, M.; Gaur, P.; Malacaria, E.; Di Biagi, L.; Aiello, F. A.; Paintsil, E. A.; Stanfield, A.; Deppe, B. J.; Gakhar, L.; Schnicker, N. J.; Spies, M. A.; Pichierri, P.; Spies, M.
Score: 23.2, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566657
Human RAD521,2 is a multifunctional DNA repair protein involved in several cellular events that support genome stability including protection of stalled DNA replication forks from excessive degradation3-7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Ultrasonic reporters of calcium for deep tissue imaging of cellular signals
Authors: Jin, Z.; Lakshmanan, A.; Zhang, R.; Tran, T. A.; Rabut, C.; Dutka, P.; Duan, M.; Hurt, R. C.; Malounda, D.; Yao, Y.; Shapiro, M. G.
Score: 76.6, Published: 2023-11-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.566364
Calcium imaging has enabled major biological discoveries. However, the scattering of light by tissue limits the use of standard fluorescent calcium indicators in living animals. To address this limitation, we introduce the first genetically encoded ultrasonic reporter of calcium (URoC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Deep generative model deciphers derailed trajectories in acute myeloid leukemia
Authors: Nazaret, A.; Fan, J. L.; Lavallee, V.-P.; Cornish, A. E.; Kiseliovas, V.; Masilionis, I.; Chun, J.; Bowman, R. L.; Eisman, S. E.; Wang, J.; Shi, L.; Levine, R. L.; Mazutis, L.; Blei, D.; Pe&amp;#39;er, D.; Azizi, E.
Score: 56.3, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.566719
Single-cell genomics has the potential to map cell states and their dynamics in an unbiased way in response to perturbations like disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>The mechanism of mRNA activation
Authors: Gentry, R. C.; Ide, N. A.; Comunale, V. M.; Hartwick, E. W.; Kinz-Thompson, C. D.; Gonzalez, R. L.
Score: 21.9, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567265
During translation initiation, messenger RNA molecules must be identified and activated for loading into a ribosome. In this rate-limiting step, the heterotrimeric protein eukaryotic initiation factor eIF4F must recognize and productively interact with the 7-methylguanosine cap at the 5&amp;#39; end of the messenger RNA and subsequently activate the message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic heritability of cell plasticity drives cancer drug resistance through one-to-many genotype to phenotype mapping
Authors: Fernandez-Mateos, J.; Milite, S.; Oliveira, E.; Vlachogiannis, G.; Chen, B.; Yara, E.; Cresswell, G. D.; James, C.; Patruno, L.; Ascolani, G.; Acar, A.; Heide, T.; Spiteri, I.; Graudenzi, A.; Caravagna, G.; Graham, T.; Magnani, L.; Valeri, N.; Sottoriva, A.
Score: 40.2, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567140
Drug resistance is a largely unsolved problem in oncology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Cardiovascular risk prediction using metabolomic biomarkers and polygenic risk scores: A cohort study and modelling analyses
Authors: Ritchie, S. C.; Jiang, X.; Pennells, L.; Xu, Y.; Coffey, C.; Liu, Y.; Surendran, P.; Karthikeyan, S.; Lambert, S. A.; Danesh, J.; Butterworth, A. S.; Wood, A.; Kaptoge, S.; Di Angelantonio, E.; Inouye, M.
Score: 27.9, Published: 2023-11-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.31.23297859
Metabolomic platforms using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy can now rapidly quantify many circulating metabolites which are potential biomarkers of cardiovascular disease (CVD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic label-free analysis of SARS-CoV-2 infection reveals virus-induced subcellular remodeling.
Authors: Saunders, N.; Monel, B.; Cayet, N.; Archetti, L.; Moreno, H.; Jeanne, A.; Marguier, A.; Wai, T.; Schwartz, O.; Frechin, M.
Score: 62.8, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.567378
Assessing the impact of SARS-CoV-2 on organelle dynamics allows a better understanding of the mechanisms of viral replication. We combine label-free holo-tomographic microscopy (HTM) with Artificial Intelligence (AI) to visualize and quantify the subcellular changes triggered by SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell spatial proteomics identifies the JAK/STAT pathway as an actionable therapeutic target in lethal cutaneous drug reactions
Authors: Nordmann, T.; Anderton, H.; Hasegawa, A.; Schweizer, L.; Zhang, P.; Stadler, P.-C.; Sinha, A.; Metousis, A.; Rosenberger, F. A.; Zwiebel, M.; Satoh, T. K.; Anzengruber, F.; Tanzer, M. C.; Saito, Y.; Gong, T.; Thielert, M.; Kimura, H.; Silke, N.; Rodriguez, E. H.; Gaetana, R.; Nguyen, H. H.; Gross, A.; Levesque, M. P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Genetically encoded affinity reagents (GEARs): A toolkit for visualizing and manipulating endogenous protein function in vivo.
Authors: Boswell, C. W.; Hoppe, C.; Sherrard, A.; Miao, L.; Kojima, M. L.; Krishna, S.; Musaev, D.; Zhao, N.; Stasevich, T. J.; Giraldez, A. J.
Score: 35.4, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.567075
Probing endogenous protein localization and function in vivo remains challenging due to laborious gene targeting and monofunctional alleles. Here, we develop a multifunctional, universal, and adaptable toolkit based on genetically encoded affinity reagents (GEARs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>The evolutionary age-range size relationship is modulated by insularity and dispersal in plants and animals
Authors: Alzate, A.; Rozzi, R.; Velasco, J. A.; Robertson, D. R.; Zizka, A.; Tobias, J. A.; Hill, A.; Bacon, C. D.; Janzen, T.; Pellissier, L.; van der Plas, F.; Rosindell, J.; Onstein, R. E.
Score: 15.6, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.566377
Earth is home to millions of plant and animal species, with more than 40 thousand species facing extinction worldwide (Diaz et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>ASSESSMENT AND CHARACTERIZATION OF COVID-19 RELATED COGNITIVE DECLINE: RESULTS FROM A NATURAL EXPERIMENT
Authors: Sekendiz, Z.; Clouston, S.; Morozova, O.; Carr, M. A.; Fontana, A.; Mehta, N.; Ali, A.; Jiang, E.; Luft, B. J.
Score: 1190.1, Published: 2023-11-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.23298101
BackgroundCognitive impairment is the most common and disabling manifestation of post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2. There is an urgent need for the application of more stringent methods for evaluating cognitive outcomes in research studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A non-adaptive explanation for macroevolutionary patterns in the evolution of complex multicellularity
Authors: Bingham, E. P.; Ratcliff, W. C.
Score: 91.6, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.11.566713
&amp;#34;Complex multicellularity&amp;#34;, conventionally defined as large organisms with many specialized cell types, has evolved five times independently in eukaryotes, but never within prokaryotes. A number hypotheses have been proposed to explain this phenomenon, most of which posit that eukaryotes evolved key traits (e.g., dynamic cytoskeletons, alternative mechanisms of gene regulation, or subcellular compartments) which were a necessary prerequisite for the evolution of complex multicellularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Human enteric nervous system progenitor transplantation restores functional responses in Hirschsprung Disease patient-derived tissue
Authors: Jevans, B.; Cooper, F.; Fatieieva, Y.; Gogolou, A.; Kang, Y.-N.; Restuadi, R.; Vanden Berghe, P.; Adameyko, I.; Thapar, N.; Andrews, P. W.; De Coppi, P.; Tsakiridis, A.; McCann, C. J.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298455
ObjectiveHirschsprung disease (HSCR) is a severe congenital disorder affecting 1:5000 live births. HSCR results from failure of enteric nervous system (ENS) progenitors to fully colonise the gastrointestinal tract during embryonic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Polygenic burden of short tandem repeat expansions promote risk for Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Guo, M. H.; Lee, W.-P.; Vardarajan, B. N.; Schellenberg, G. D.; Phillips-Cremins, J. E.
Score: 18.3, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298623
Studies of the genetics of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease (AD) have largely focused on single nucleotide variants and short insertions/deletions. However, most of the disease heritability has yet to be uncovered, suggesting that there is substantial genetic risk conferred by other forms of genetic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Causal interpretations of family GWAS in the presence of heterogeneous effects
Authors: Veller, C.; Przeworski, M.; Coop, G.
Score: 48.7, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566950
Family-based genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have emerged as a gold standard for assessing causal effects of alleles and polygenic scores. Notably, family studies are often claimed to provide an unbiased estimate of the average causal effect (or average treatment effect; ATE) of an allele, on the basis of an analogy between the random transmission of alleles from parents to children and a randomized controlled trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>An encyclopedia of enhancer-gene regulatory interactions in the human genome
Authors: Gschwind, A. R.; Mualim, K. S.; Karbalayghareh, A.; Sheth, M. U.; Dey, K. K.; Jagoda, E.; Nurtdinov, R. N.; Xi, W.; Tan, A. S.; Jones, H.; Ma, X. R.; Yao, D.; Nasser, J.; Avsec, Z.; James, B. T.; Shamim, M. S.; Durand, N. C.; Rao, S. S. P.; Mahajan, R.; Doughty, B. R.; Andreeva, K.; Ulirsch, J. C.; Fan, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Autophagy gene expression in skeletal muscle of older individuals is associated with physical performance, muscle volume and mitochondrial function in the Study of Muscle, Mobility and Aging (SOMMA)
Authors: Coen, P. M.; Huo, Z.; Tranah, G. J.; Barnes, H. N.; Cawthon, P. M.; Hepple, R. T.; Toledo, F. G.; Evans, D. S.; Fernandez, O. S.; Cuervo, A. M.; Kritchevsky, S. B.; Newman, A. B.; Cummings, S. R.; Esser, K. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>The application of Large Language Models to the phenotype-based prioritization of causative genes in rare disease patients
Authors: KAFKAS, S.; Abdelhakim, M.; Althagafi, A.; Toonsi, S.; Alghamdi, M.; SCHOFIELD, P.; Hoehndorf, R.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.16.23298615
Computational methods for identifying gene-disease associations can use both genomic and phenotypic information to prioritize genes and variants that may be associated with genetic diseases. Phenotype-based methods commonly rely on comparing phenotypes observed in a patient with a database of genotype-to-phenotype associations using a measure of semantic similarity, and are primarily limited by the quality and completeness of this database as well as the quality of phenotypes assigned to a patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Real-world effectiveness of non-pharmaceutical interventions in containing COVID-19 pandemic after the roll-out of coronavirus vaccines: A systematic review
Authors: Xiaona, H.; Chen, H.; Zhu, X.; Gao, W.
Score: 27.1, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23297704
BackgroundNon-pharmaceutical interventions (NPIs) have been widely used to control the transmission of infectious diseases. However, the current research evidence on the policy mechanisms of NPIs is still limited. This study aims to systematically identify, describe, and evaluate the existing literature for the real-world effectiveness of NPIs in containing COVID-19 pandemic after the roll-out of coronavirus vaccines, in order to search for optimal strategies for implementing NPIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Exploring virtual funding committee practices in the allocation of National Institute for Health and Care Research funding: A netnographic study
Authors: Blatch-Jones, A. J.; Boxall, C.; Asante, E.; Meadmore, K.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.17.23298707
Objectives: Funding committees, comprising members with a range of knowledge, skills, and experience, are considered integral to the decision-making process of funding organisations for recommending or allocating research funding. However, there is limited research investigating the decision-making processes, the role of members and their social interactions during funding committee meetings conducted both virtually and face-to-face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>UBTF Tandem Duplications in Pediatric MDS and AML: Implications for Clinical Screening and Diagnosis
Authors: Barajas, J. M.; Umeda, M.; Contreras, L.; Khanlari, M.; Westover, T.; Walsh, M. P.; Xiong, E.; Yang, C.; Otero, B.; Arribas-Layton, M.; Abdelhamed, S.; Song, G.; Ma, X.; Thomas, M. E.; Ma, J.; Klco, J. M.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298320
Recent genomic studies in adult and pediatric acute myeloid leukemia (AML) demonstrated recurrent in-frame tandem duplications (TD) in exon 13 of upstream binding transcription factor (UBTF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Fast evolution of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 to JN.1 under heavy immune pressure
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Xu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Wang, P.; Wang, J.; Liu, J.; Yu, L.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Wang, Y.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y.
Score: 177.7, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566860
While the BA.2.86 variant demonstrated significant antigenic drift and enhanced ACE2 binding affinity, its ability to evade humoral immunity was relatively moderate compared to dominant strains like EG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Synergistic Role of NK Cells and Monocytes in Promoting Atherogenesis in Severe COVID-19 Patients.
Authors: Gunasena, M.; Alles, M.; Wijewantha, Y.; Mulhern, W.; Bowman, E.; Gabriel, J.; Kettelhut, A.; Kumar, A.; Weragalaarachchi, K.; Kasturiratna, D.; Horowitz, J. C.; Scrape, S.; Pannu, S. R.; Liu, S.-L.; Vilgelm, A.; Wijeratne, S.; Bednash, J. S.; Demberg, T.; Funderburg, N. T.; Liyanage, N.
Score: 36.4, Published: 2023-11-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298322
Clinical data demonstrate an increased predisposition to cardiovascular disease (CVD) following severe COVID-19 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Association Between Beta Blocker and Clinical Outcome in Adult Patients with Sepsis or Septic Shock: Protocol of a Systematic Review and Meta- Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials
Authors: Bhattacharjee, S.; Ernest, E. E.; Maitra, S.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298548
Use of beta-blockers as a part of heart rate control strategy is sepsis and septic shock patients is of great debate. Despite of early encouraging results, no large trial was performed and several subsequent small studies reported conflicting results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron HK.3 variant harboring the &amp;#34;FLip&amp;#34; substitution
Authors: Kosugi, Y.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Putri, O.; Uriu, K.; Kaku, Y.; Hinay, A. A.; Chen, L.; Kuramochi, J.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; The Genotype to Phenotype Japan (G2P-Japan) Consortium, ; Ito, J.; Sato, K.
Score: 180.6, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566985
In November 2023, SARS-CoV-2 XBB descendants, including EG.5.1 (XBB.1.9.2.5.1), the currently predominant lineage, are circulating worldwide according to Nextstrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>De novo basecalling of m6A modifications at single molecule and single nucleotide resolution
Authors: Cruciani, S.; Delgado Tejedor, A.; Pryszcz, L.; Medina, R.; Llovera, L.; Novoa, E. M.
Score: 47.5, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566801
RNA modifications hold pivotal roles in shaping the fate and function of RNA molecules. Although nanopore sequencing technologies have proven successful at transcriptome-wide detection of RNA modifications, current algorithms are limited to predicting modifications at a per-site level rather than within individual RNA molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>A systematic review of quantitative EEG findings in Long COVID, Fibromyalgia and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome
Authors: Silva-Passadouro, B.; Tamasauskas, A.; Khoja, O.; Casson, A. J.; Delis, I.; Brown, C.; Sivan, M.
Score: 42.8, Published: 2023-11-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.06.23298171
Long COVID (LC) is a multisymptom clinical syndrome with similarities to Fibromyalgia Syndrome (FMS) and Chronic Fatigue Syndrome/Myalgic Encephalomyelitis (CFS/ME). All these conditions are believed to be associated with centrally driven mechanisms such as central sensitisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Tonic dopamine and biases in value learning linked through a biologically inspired reinforcement learning model
Authors: Romero Pinto, S.; Uchida, N.
Score: 83.3, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.566580
A hallmark of various psychiatric disorders is biased future predictions. Here we examined the mechanisms for biased value learning using reinforcement learning models incorporating recent findings on synaptic plasticity and opponent circuit mechanisms in the basal ganglia. We show that variations in tonic dopamine can alter the balance between learning from positive and negative reward prediction errors, leading to biased value predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>FooDOxS: A Database of Oxidized Sterols Content in Foods
Authors: Medina-Meza, I. G.; Vaidya, Y.; Barnaba, C.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-11-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298592
This research addresses the knowledge gap regarding dietary oxidized lipids (DOxS) in foods classified under the NOVA and WWEIA systems. We present the FooDOxS database, a comprehensive compilation of DOxS content in over 1,680 food items from 120 publications across 25 countries, augmented by internal lab data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Maternal cardiovascular and haematological complications alter the risk associations between environmental exposure and adverse pregnancy outcomes
Authors: Sun, H. Z.; Tang, H.; Zhao, H.; Xiang, Q.; Tian, Y.; van Daalen, K. R.; Tang, K.; Loo, E. X.-L.; Shek, L. P.; Archibald, A. T.; Xu, W.; Guo, Y.; Bai, X.; Zhejiang Environmental and Birth Health Research Alliance (ZEBRA) Collaborative Group, Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.15.23298338
Given China&amp;#39;s recent introduction of the &amp;#34;three-child policy&amp;#34; in response to population ageing, safeguarding perinatal health has become an urgent priority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary dynamics of 1,976 lymphoid malignancies predict clinical outcome
Authors: Gabbutt, C.; Duran-Ferrer, M.; Grant, H.; Mallo, D.; Nadeu, F.; Househam, J.; Villamor, N.; Krali, O.; Nordlund, J.; Zenz, T.; Campo, E.; Lopez-Guillermo, A.; Fitzgibbon, J.; Barnes, C. P.; Shibata, D.; Martin-Subero, J. I.; Graham, T. A.
Score: 42.8, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298336
Cancer development, progression, and response to treatment are evolutionary processes, but characterising the evolutionary dynamics at sufficient scale to be clinically-meaningful has remained challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Elevated Plasma Complement Factors in CRB1-associated Inherited Retinal Dystrophies
Authors: Moekotte, L.; Boer, J. H.; Hiddingh, S.; Ligt, A.; Nguyen, X.-T.-A.; Hoyng, C. B.; Inglehearn, C. F.; McKibbin, M.; Lamey, T. M.; Thompson, J. A.; Chen, F. K.; McLaren, T. L.; AlTalbishi, A.; Panneman, D. M.; Boonen, E. G. M.; Banfi, S.; Bocquet, B.; Meunier, I.; Baere, E.; Koenekoop, R.; Oldak, M.; Rivolta, C.; Roberts, L.; Ramesar, R.; Strupaite-Sileikiene, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>CCR5/CXCR3 antagonist TAK-779 prevents diffuse alveolar damage of the lung in murine model of the SARS-CoV-2-related acute respiratory distress syndrome
Authors: Chernov, A.; Rodionov, M.; Kazakov, V.; Ivanova, K.; Mesheryakov, F.; Kudriaeva, A.; Gabibov, A.; Telegin, G.; Belogurov, A.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2023-11-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.567145
The acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) secondary to viral pneumonitis is one of the main causes of high mortality in patients with COVID-19 (novel coronavirus disease 2019) - ongoing SARS-CoV-2 infection, reached more than 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Admissions to paediatric medical wards with a primary mental health diagnosis: a systematic review of the literature
Authors: Vazquez-Vazquez, A.; Smith, A.; Gibson, F.; Roberts, H.; Mathews, G.; Ward, J.; Viner, R. M.; Nicholls, D.; Cornaglia, F.; Roland, D.; Phillips, K.; Hudson, L. D.
Score: 7.7, Published: 2023-11-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298368
ObjectiveTo systematically review the literature describing children and young people (CYP) admissions to paediatric general wards because of primary mental health reasons, particularly in MH crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Effects of testosterone and metformin on the GlycanAge index of biological age and the composition of the IgG glycome
Authors: Vinicki, M.; Pribic, T.; Vuckovic, F.; Frkatovic-Hodzic|, A.; Plaza-Andrade, I.; Tinahones, F.; Raffaele, J.; Fernandez-Garcia, J. C.; Lauc, G.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-11-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.23298497
With aging, there is a correlation between a decline in the body&amp;#39;s ability to maintain regular functioning and greater susceptibility to age-related diseases. Therapeutic interventions targeting the underlying biological changes of aging hold promise for preventing or delaying multiple age-related diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Feasibility of intranasal delivery of thin-film freeze-dried monoclonal antibodies
Authors: Yu, Y.-S.; Xu, H.; AboulFotouh, K.; Williams, G.; Suman, J.; Sahakijpijarn, S.; Cano, C.; Warnken, Z.; Wu, K. C.- W.; Williams, R. O.; Cui, Z.
Score: 143.5, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563139
Monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) administered intranasally as dry powders can be potentially applied for the treatment or pre-exposure prevention of viral infections in the upper respiratory tract. However, a method to transform the mAbs from liquid to dry powders suitable for intranasal administration and a device that can spray the dry powders to the desired region of the nasal cavity are needed to fully realize the potentials of the mAbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Quantification of healthspan in aging mice: Introducing FAMY and GRAIL
Authors: Lamming, D. W.
Score: 23.9, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.566044
The population around the world is graying, and as many of these individuals will spend years suffering from the burdens of age associated diseases, understanding how to increase healthspan, defined as the period of life free from disease and disability, is an urgent priority of geroscience research. The lack of agreed-upon quantitative metrics for measuring healthspan in aging mice has slowed progress in identifying interventions that do not simply increase lifespan, but also healthspan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Plant pathogenic fungi hijack phosphate starvation signaling with conserved enzymatic effectors
Authors: McCombe, C. L.; Wegner, A.; Zamora, C. S.; Casanova, F.; Aditya, S.; Greenwood, J. R.; Wirtz, L.; de Paula, S.; England, E.; Shang, S.; Ericsson, D. J.; Oliveira-Garcia, E.; Williams, S. J.; Schaffrath, U.
Score: 25.5, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.14.566975
Phosphate availability modulates plant immune function and regulates interactions with beneficial, phosphate-providing, microbes. Here, we describe the hijacking of plant phosphate sensing by a family of Nudix hydrolase effectors from pathogenic Magnaporthe oryzae and Colletotrichum fungi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Management of Antipsychotics in Primary Care: Insights from Healthcare Professionals and Policy Makers in the UK
Authors: Woodall, A. A.; Abuzour, A. S.; Wilson, S. A.; Mair, F. S.; Buchan, I.; Sheard, S. B.; Atkinson, P.; Joyce, D. W.; Symon, P.; Walker, L. E.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298487
IntroductionAntipsychotic medication is increasingly prescribed to patients with serious mental illness. Patients with serious mental illness often have cardiovascular and metabolic comorbidities, and antipsychotics independently increase the risk of cardiometabolic disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Brain-wide Disruptions of Anatomical Connectivity in Antipsychotic-Naive First Episode Psychosis
Authors: Chopra, S.; Levi, P. T.; Holmes, A.; Orchard, E. R.; Segal, A.; Francey, S. M.; ODonoghue, B.; Cropley, V.; Nelson, B.; Graham, J.; Baldwin, L.; Yuen, H. P.; Allott, K.; Alvarez-Jimenez, M.; Harrigan, S.; Pantelis, C.; Wood, S. J.; McGorry, P.; Fornito, A.
Score: 14.1, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.10.23298391
OBJECTIVEDisruptions of axonal connectivity are thought to be a core pathophysiological feature of psychotic illness, but whether they are present early in the illness, prior to antipsychotic exposure, and whether they can predict clinical outcome remains unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Post-Vaccination Syndrome: A Descriptive Analysis of Reported Symptoms and Patient Experiences After Covid-19 Immunization
Authors: Krumholz, H. M.; Wu, Y.; Sawano, M.; Shah, R.; Zhou, T.; Arun, A. S.; Khosla, P.; Kaleem, S.; Vashist, A.; Bhattacharjee, B.; Ding, Q.; Lu, Y.; Caraballo, C.; Warner, F.; Huang, C.; Herrin, J.; Putrino, D.; Hertz, D.; Dressen, B.; Iwasaki, A.
Score: 343.9, Published: 2023-11-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.09.23298266
IntroductionA chronic post-vaccination syndrome (PVS) after covid-19 vaccination has been reported but has yet to be well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Automated quantitative evaluation of thymic involution and hyperplasia on plain chest CT
Authors: Okamura, Y. T.; Endo, K.; Toriihara, A.; Fukuda, I.; Isogai, J.; Sato, Y.; Yasuoka, K.; Kagami, S.-I.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298440
ObjectiveTo establish an automatic method to quantify thymic involution and hyperplasia based on plain chest computed tomography (CT). MethodsWe defined the thymic region for quantification (TRQ) as the target region. We manually segmented the TRQ in 135 CT studies, followed by construction of segmentation neural network (NN) models based on the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of 245,368 diverse individuals from the NIH All of Us Cohort identifies incomplete penetrance of the VEXAS-defining UBA1 p.M41L somatic mutation
Authors: Corty, R. W.; Byram, K. W.; Springer, J. M.; Grayson, P. C.; Bick, A. G.
Score: 8.4, Published: 2023-11-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.07.23298212
ObjectiveSomatic mutations in UBA1 cause the recently described systemic auto-inflammatory syndrome, VEXAS. Study of this disease has largely been limited to highly symptomatic patients. We sought to determine the prevalence of VEXAS-associated somatic mutations and their disease penetrance in a diverse, unselected population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>surgery</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/surgery/</guid>
      <description>Connectome reorganization associated with temporal lobe pathology and its surgical resection
Authors: Lariviere, S.; Park, B.-y.; Royer, J.; DeKraker, J.; Ngo, A.; Sahlas, E.; Chen, J.; Rodriguez-Cruces, R.; Weng, Y.; Frauscher, B.; Wang, Z.; Misic, B.; Shafiei, G.; Bernasconi, A.; Bernasconi, N.; Fox, M. D.; Zhang, Z.; Bernhardt, B.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.23298482
Network neuroscience offers a unique framework to understand the organizational principles of the human brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Continuous evolution of user-defined genes at 1-million-times the genomic mutation rate
Authors: Rix, G.; Williams, R. L.; Spinner, H.; Hu, V. J.; Marks, D. S.; Liu, C. C.
Score: 54.5, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.13.566922
When nature maintains or evolves a genes function over millions of years at scale, it produces a diversity of homologous sequences whose patterns of conservation and change contain rich structural, functional, and historical information about the gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Proteome-wide base editor screens to assess phosphorylation site functionality in high-throughput
Authors: Kennedy, P. H.; Deh Sheikh, A. A.; Balakar, M.; Jones, A. C.; Olive, M. E.; Hedge, M.; Matias, M. I.; Pirete, N.; Burt, R.; Levy, J.; Little, T.; Hogan, P. G.; Liu, D. R.; Doench, J. G.; Newton, A. C.; Gottschalk, R. A.; de Boer, C.; Alarcon, S.; Newby, G.; Myers, S. A.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-11-14 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>In situ observation and range extension of the first monoplacophoran Neopilina galatheae
Authors: Chen, C.; Jamieson, J. W.
Score: 57.8, Published: 2023-11-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.11.08.566290
Monoplacophoran molluscs have been dubbed living fossils due to their absence in the fossil record for about 375 million years, until Neopilina galatheae Lemche, 1957 was trawled off Costa Rica in 1952. Since then, over 35 species of living monoplacophorans have been discovered. Nevertheless, in situ observations of these rare deep-sea animals remain scant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
