<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Extracellular Matrix Abnormalities in the Hippocampus of Subjects with Substance Use Disorder
Authors: Valeri, J.; Stiplosek, C.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, S. M.; Sinclair, D.; Grant, K. A.; Bollavarapu, R.; Platt, D. M.; Stockmeier, C. A.; Gisabella, B.; Pantazopoulos, H.
Score: 4.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295222
Contextual triggers are significant factors contributing to relapse in substance use disorders (SUD). Emerging evidence points to a critical role of extracellular matrix (ECM) molecules as mediators of reward memories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 405.5, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>African elephants address one another with individually specific calls
Authors: Pardo, M. A.; Fristrup, K.; Lolchuragi, D. S.; Poole, J.; Granli, P.; Moss, C.; Douglas-Hamilton, I.; Wittemyer, G.
Score: 124.1, Published: 2023-08-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.25.554872
Personal names are a universal feature of human language, yet few analogs exist in other species. While dolphins and parrots address conspecifics by imitating the calls of the addressee 1,2, human names are not imitations of the sounds typically made by the names owner 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>The potential of plasma HLA peptides beyond neoepitopes
Authors: Wahle, M.; Thielert, M.; Zwiebel, M.; Skowronek, P.; Zeng, W.-F.; Mann, M.
Score: 27.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.556309
Distinction of non-self from self is the major task of the immune system. Immunopeptidomics studies the peptide repertoire presented by the human leukocyte antigen (HLA) protein, usually on tissues. However, HLA peptides are also bound to plasma soluble HLA (sHLA), but little is known about their origin and potential for biomarker discovery in this readily available biofluid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Human gut metagenomic mining reveals an untapped source of peptide antibiotics
Authors: Torres, M. D. T.; Brooks, E. F.; Cesaro, A.; Sberro, H.; Nicolaou, C.; Bhatt, A. S.; de la Fuente, C.
Score: 32.0, Published: 2023-09-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.555711
Drug-resistant bacteria are outpacing traditional antibiotic discovery efforts. Here, we computationally mined 444,054 families of putative small proteins from 1,773 human gut metagenomes, identifying 323 peptide antibiotics encoded in small open reading frames (smORFs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Accurate human genome analysis with Element Avidity sequencing
Authors: Carroll, A.; Kolesnikov, A.; Cook, D. E.; Brambrink, L.; Wiseman, K. N.; Billings, S. M.; Kruglyak, S.; Lajoie, B. R.; Zhao, J.; Levy, S. E.; McLean, C. Y.; Shafin, K.; Nattestad, M.; Chang, P.-C.
Score: 543.5, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.11.553043
We investigate the new sequencing technology Avidity from Element Biosciences. We show that Element whole genome sequencing achieves higher mapping and variant calling accuracy compared to Illumina sequencing at the same coverage, with larger differences at lower coverages (20x-30x).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>In situ cryoET reveals inhibitor-induced perturbations in Pf80S GTPase interactions
Authors: Anton, L.; Cheng, W.; Haile, M.; Cobb, D. W.; Zhu, X.; Han, L.; Li, E.; Nair, A.; Lee, C. L.; Ke, H.; Zhang, G.; Doud, E. H.; Ho, C.-M.
Score: 103.9, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.03.556115
Malaria parasites rely heavily on rapid, high fidelity protein synthesis to infect and replicate in human erythrocytes, making translation an attractive target for new antimalarials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Glioblastoma is spatially organized by neurodevelopmental programs and a glial-like wound healing response
Authors: Mossi Albiach, A.; Janusauskas, J.; Kapustova, I.; Kvedaraite, E.; Codeluppi, S.; Munting, J. B.; Borm, L. E.; Kjaer Jacobsen, J.; Shamikh, A.; Persson, O.; Linnarsson, S.
Score: 48.0, Published: 2023-09-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555882
Glioblastoma is the deadliest brain cancer, characterized by great cellular diversity and unique histology. To understand the spatial organization of transcriptional cell states, we mapped the expression of 888 genes in centimeter-scaletissuesectionsfromalargepatientcohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Distinct biological signature and modifiable risk factors underly the comorbidity between major depressive disorder and cardiovascular disease
Authors: Bergstedt, J.; Pasman, J. A.; Ma, Z.; Harder, A.; Yao, S.; Parker, N.; Treur, J. L.; Smit, D. J. A.; Frei, O.; Shadrin, A.; Meijsen, J. J.; Shen, Q.; Tornvall, P.; Buil, A.; Werge, T.; Hjerling-Leffler, J.; Als, T. D.; Borglum, A. D.; Lewis, C. M.; McIntosh, A. M.; Valdimarsdottir, U. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>The anti-SARS-CoV-2 BNT162b2 vaccine suppresses mithramycin-induced erythroid differentiation and expression of embryo-fetal globin genes in human erythroleukemia K562 cells
Authors: Zurlo, M.; Gasparello, J.; Verona, M.; Papi, C.; Cosenza, L. C.; Finotti, A.; Marzaro, G.; Gambari, R.
Score: 905.2, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556634
The COVID-19 severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) the ongoing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic. The SARS-CoV-2 Spike protein (S-protein) plays an important role in the early phase of SARS-CoV2 infection through efficient interaction with ACE2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>PUFFFIN: A novel, ultra-bright, customisable, single plasmid system for labelling cell neighbourhoods
Authors: Lebek, T.; Malaguti, M.; Elfick, A.; Lowell, S.
Score: 36.3, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.556381
Cell communication orchestrates development, homeostasis, and disease. Understanding these processes depends on effective methods to study how cells influence their neighbours. Here, we present Positive Ultra-bright Fluorescent Fusion For Identifying Neighbours (PUFFFIN), a novel cell neighbour-labelling system based upon secretion and uptake of a positively supercharged fluorescent protein s36GFP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Neonicotinoids, more than herbicides, land use, and climate, drive recent butterfly declines in the American Midwest
Authors: Van Deynze, B.; Swinton, S. M.; Hennessy, D. A.; Haddad, N.; Ries, L.
Score: 51.2, Published: 2023-08-26 DOI: 10.1101/2022.07.29.502042
Mounting evidence shows insects are in decline globally. Habitat loss, climate change, and pesticides have all been implicated, but their relative effects have never been evaluated in a comprehensive large-scale study. We harmonized 17 years of land use, climate, multiple classes of pesticides and butterfly data across 60 counties in five states in the US Midwest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Attacks on Ukrainian healthcare facilities during the first year of the full-scale Russian invasion of Ukraine
Authors: Barten, D.; Tin, D.; Granholm, F.; Rusnak, D.; van Osch, F.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294763
BackgroundAlthough the Geneva Conventions and Rome Statute demand protections for healthcare facilities during war, breaches of these protections are frequently reported. The ongoing war in Ukraine is no exception, with several healthcare attacks eliciting widespread condemnation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Morning exercise and pre-breakfast metformin interact to reduce glycaemia in people with Type 2 Diabetes: a randomized crossover trial
Authors: Pena Carrillo, B. J.; Cope, E.; Gurel, S.; Traslosheros, A.; Kenny, A.; Mody, N.; Delibegovic, M.; Philip, S.; Thies, F.; Blana, D.; Gabriel, B. M.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295059
Exercise is recommended in the treatment of Type 2 Diabetes and can improve insulin sensitivity [1]. However, previous evidence suggests that exercise at different times of the day in people with type 2 diabetes may have opposing outcomes on glycaemia [2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Serological outcomes of SARS-CoV-2 infection by vaccination status and variant in England
Authors: Quinot, C.; Lunt, R.; Kirsebom, F.; Andrews, N.; Whitaker, H.; Skarnes, C.; Letley, L.; Haskins, D.; Angel, C.; Firminger, S.; Ratcliffe, K.; Sheridan, A.; Rajan, S.; Akindele, L.; Ijaz, S.; Zambon, M.; Brown, K.; Ramsay, M.; Lopez Bernal, J.
Score: 136.2, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295073
BackgroundThroughout the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, several vaccines have been rolled out and distinct variants with different severity and immune profiles emerged in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Quantitative Genetic Model of Background Selection in Humans
Authors: Buffalo, V.; Kern, A. D.
Score: 27.2, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556762
Across the human genome, there are large-scale fluctuations in genetic diversity caused by the indirect effects of selection. This &amp;#34;linked selection signal&amp;#34; reflects the impact of selection according to the physical placement of functional regions and recombination rates along chromosomes. Previous work has shown that purifying selection acting against the steady influx of new deleterious mutations at functional portions of the genome shapes patterns of genomic variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Utility of EsoGuard as a Triage Test for Endoscopy to Identify Barrett&amp;#39;s Esophagus in Fire Fighters
Authors: Hamblin, R.; Lee, V. T.; deGuzman, B. J.; Verma, S.; Aklog, L.
Score: 243.7, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294176
BackgroundFirefighters have frequent exposure to smoke and compounds that have been shown to increase the risk of developing esophageal neoplasia. EsoGuard(R) is a DNA biomarker assay that can be utilized with efficiency and high tolerability as a triage test in the diagnosis of patients with Barretts Esophagus (BE) and/or esophageal adenocarcinoma (EAC) in this population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell RNA sequencing reveals dysregulated cellular programmes in the inflamed epithelium of Crohn&amp;#39;s disease patients.
Authors: Krzak, M.; Alegbe, T.; Taylor, D. L.; Ghouraba, M. H.; Strickland, M.; Satti, R.; Thompson, T.; Arestang, K.; Przybilla, M. J.; Ramirez-Navarro, L.; Harris, B. T.; Cheam, K. A. X.; Noell, G.; Leonard, S.; Petrova, V.; Jones-Bell, C.; James, K. R.; Wana, N.; Hu, M. X.; Skelton, J.; Ostermayer, J.; Gu, Y.; Dawson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>The simplicity of protein sequence-function relationships
Authors: Park, Y.; Metzger, B. P. H.; Thornton, J. W.
Score: 30.5, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.02.556057
How complicated is the relationship between a proteins sequence and its function? High-order epistatic interactions among residues are thought to be pervasive, making a proteins function difficult to predict or understand from its sequence. Most prior studies, however, used methods that misinterpret measurement errors, small local idiosyncracies around a designated wild-type sequence, and global nonlinearity in the sequence-function relationship as rampant high-order interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Regulatory Transposable Elements in the Encyclopedia of DNA Elements
Authors: Du, A. Y.; Chobirko, J. D.; Zhuo, X.; Feschotte, C.; Wang, T.
Score: 51.5, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.556380
Transposable elements (TEs) make up about half of the human genome and many have the biochemical hallmarks of tissue- or cell type-specific cis-regulatory elements. While some TEs have been rigorously documented to contribute directly to host gene regulation, we still have a very partial view of their regulatory landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>A Literature Review and Meta-Analysis of the Effects of Lockdowns on COVID-19 Mortality - II
Authors: Herby, J.; Jonung, L.; Hanke, S.
Score: 216.5, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294845
The purpose of this systematic review and meta-analysis is to determine the effect of lockdowns on COVID-19 mortality based on available empirical evidence. Lockdowns are defined as the imposition of at least one compulsory, non-pharmaceutical intervention (NPI). We employ a systematic search and screening procedure in which 19,646 studies are identified that could potentially address the purpose of our study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>A Network Analysis of Molecular Interactions to Study the Development of New-onset Diabetes and Hypertension after COVID-19 Infection Using Bioinformatics Tools.
Authors: de Oliveira Andrade, L. J.; Matos de Oliveira, L. C.; Matos de Oliveira, G. C.; Matos de Oliveira, L.
Score: 26.7, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.10.23295323
Introduction: The association between COVID-19 infection and the development of new-onset diabetes and hypertension is an emerging area of research. However, a comprehensive understanding of the underlying molecular mechanisms is still lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Ischemic Stroke after COVID-19 Bivalent Booster Vaccination in an Integrated Health System
Authors: Sharff, K.; Tandy, T. K.; Lewis, P. F.; Johnson, E. S.
Score: 6.4, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295368
Abstract: Purpose: What is the absolute occurrence of ischemic stroke and transient ischemic attack after a COVID-19 bivalent vaccination? Methods: We conducted a retrospective cohort study of Kaiser Permanente Northwest (KPNW) patients 18 years and older who were vaccinated with either the Pfizer or Moderna formulation of the COVID19 bivalent vaccine between September 1, 2022 and March 1st 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Cellular aging is accelerated in the malignant clone of myeloproliferative neoplasms
Authors: Vieri, M.; Tharmapalan, V.; Kalmer, M.; Baumeister, J.; Nikolic, M.; Schnitker, M.; Kirschner, M.; Flosdorf, N.; Szymanski de Toledo, M. A.; Zenke, M.; Koschmieder, S.; Brummendorf, T. H.; Beier, F.; Wagner, W.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295349
Myeloproliferative neoplasms (MPNs) are caused by somatic driver mutations, such as JAK2V617F, which might also affect cellular aging and senescence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Antigenicity and infectivity characterization of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Chen, X.; Xu, Y.; Wang, P.; Yu, L.; Wang, J.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Xiao, T.; An, R.; Wang, Y.; Gu, Q.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Shen, Z.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y. R.
Score: 549.1, Published: 2023-09-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555815
The recently identified SARS-CoV-2 variant, BA.2.86, which carries a substantial number of Spike mutations, has raised a global alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Wu, K.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 2549.4, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Neutralization Escape by SARS-CoV-2 Omicron Subvariant BA.2.86
Authors: Lasrado, N.; Collier, A.-r.; Hachmann, N.; Miller, J.; Rowe, M.; Schonberg, E.; Rodrigues, S.; LaPiana, A.; Patio, R.; Anand, T.; Fisher, J.; Mazurek, C.; Guan, R.; Wagh, K.; Theiler, J.; Korber, B.; Barouch, D. H.
Score: 698.2, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.556272
The continued evolution of SARS-CoV-2 may lead to evasion of vaccine immunity and natural immunity. A highly mutated Omicron variant BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>High-confidence 3D template matching for cryo-electron tomography
Authors: Cruz-Leon, S.; Majtner, T.; Hoffmann, P. C.; Kreysing, J. P.; Tuijtel, M. W.; Schaefer, S. L.; Geissler, K.; Beck, M.; Turonova, B.; Hummer, G.
Score: 40.1, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.556310
Cryo-electron tomography (CryoET) resolves individual macromolecules inside living cells. However, the complex composition and high density of cells challenge the faithful identification of features in tomograms. Here, we capitalize on recent advances in electron tomography and demonstrate that 3D template matching (TM) localizes a wide range of structures inside crowded eukaryotic cells with confidence 10 to 100-fold above the noise level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The citrate transporter SLC13A5 as a therapeutic target for kidney disease: evidence from Mendelian randomization to inform drug development
Authors: Gill, D.; Zagkos, L.; Gill, R.; Benzing, T.; Jordan, J.; Birkenfeld, A.; Burgess, S.; Zahn, G.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.29.23294760
BackgroundSolute carrier family 13 member 5 (SLC13A5) is a Na -coupled citrate co-transporter that mediates the entry of extracellular citrate into the cytosol. SLC13A5 inhibition has been proposed as a therapeutic target for reducing progression of kidney disease via its effects on citrate metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Diminished utility of fMRI subsequent memory models with increasing severity across the Alzheimer&amp;#39;s disease risk spectrum
Authors: Soch, J.; Richter, A.; Kizilirmak, J. M.; Schütze, H.; Altenstein, S.; Dechent, P.; Fliessbach, K.; Glanz, W.; Herrera, A. L.; Hetzer, S.; Incesoy, E. I.; Kilimann, I.; Kimmich, O.; Lammerding, D.; Laske, C.; Lohse, A.; Lüsebrink, F.; Munk, M. H.; Peters, O.; Preis, L.; Priller, J.; Rostamzadeh, A.; Roy-Kluth, N.; Scheffler, K.; Schneider, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Translocation of gut commensal bacteria to the brain
Authors: Thapa, M.; Kumari, A.; Chin, C.-Y.; Choby, J.; Jin, F.; Bogati, B.; Chopyk, D.; Koduri, N.; Pahnke, A.; Elrod, E.; Burd, E. M.; Weiss, D. S.; Grakoui, A.
Score: 727.4, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.555630
The gut-brain axis, a bidirectional signaling network between the intestine and the central nervous system, is crucial to the regulation of host physiology and inflammation. Recent advances suggest a strong correlation between gut dysbiosis and neurological diseases, however, relatively little is known about how gut bacteria impact the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Dietary sulfur amino acid restriction in humans with overweight and obesity: a translational randomized controlled trial
Authors: Olsen, T.; Stolt, E.; Ovrebo, B.; Elshorbagy, A.; Tore, E. C.; Lee-Oedegard, S.; Troensegaard, H.; Johannessen, H.; Doeland, B.; Vo, A. A. D.; Dahl, A. F.; Svendsen, K.; Thoresen, M.; Refsum, H.; Rising, R.; Barvikova, K.; Greevenbroek, M. v.; Kozich, V.; Retterstol, K.; Vinknes, K. J.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295155</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Disruption of maternal IgA by prenatal antibiotics precedes intestinal E. coli colonization and late-onset sepsis in neonates
Authors: McDonald, K.; Browning, D.; Greenfield, K.; Lin, K.; Meier, J.; Sasaki, A.; Megli, C.; Knoop, K.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.23295031
Neonates, most notably prematurely born neonates, are particularly vulnerable to enteric pathogens. It is recommended that all pregnant patients receive antibiotics following Preterm Premature Rupture of Membranes (PPROM) to prolong pregnancy, yet not all antibiotic regimens have been studied for efficacy, especially when considering neonatal outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Long-read RNA sequencing redefines the clear cell renal cell carcinoma transcriptome and reveals novel genes and transcripts associated with disease recurrence and immune evasion
Authors: Lee, J.; Snell, E. A.; Brown, J.; Banks, R. E.; Turner, D. J.; Vasudev, N. S.; Lagos, D.
Score: 13.6, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295204
BackgroundLong-read direct RNA sequencing (DRS) and PCR cDNA sequencing (PCS) of tumour samples could lead to discovery of novel transcript isoforms, novel genes, and transcriptomic co-dependencies missed by conventional short-read sequencing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Savoring Meditation on Positive Emotions and Pain-Related Brain Function: A Mechanistic Randomized Controlled Trial in People With Rheumatoid Arthritis
Authors: Finan, P.; Hunt, C.; Keaser, M. L.; Smith, K.; Lerman, S.; Bingham, C. O.; Barrett, F.; Garland, E. L.; Zeidan, F.; Seminowicz, D. A.
Score: 1.9, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23294949
Positive emotions are a promising target for intervention in chronic pain, but mixed findings across trials to date suggest that existing interventions may not be optimized to efficiently engage the target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Characterizing the phenotypic and genetic structure of psychopathology in UK Biobank
Authors: Williams, C. M.; Peyre, H.; Wolfram, T.; Lee, Y. H.; Ge, T.; Smoller, J. W.; Mallard, T. T.; Ramus, F.
Score: 22.1, Published: 2023-09-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23295086
Mental conditions exhibit a higher-order transdiagnostic factor structure which helps to explain the widespread comorbidity observed in psychopathology. However, the phenotypic and genetic structures of psychopathology may differ, raising questions about the validity and utility of these factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular Basis of Human Trace Amine-Associated Receptor 1 Activation
Authors: Zilberg, G.; Parpounas, A. K.; Warren, A. L.; Yang, S.; Wacker, D.
Score: 8.8, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.556555
The human trace amine-associated receptor 1 (hTAAR1, hTA1) is a key regulator of monoaminergic neurotransmission and the actions of psychostimulants. Despite preclinical research demonstrating its tractability as a drug target, its molecular mechanisms of activation remain unclear. Moreover, poorly understood pharmacological differences between rodent and human TA1 complicate the translation of findings from preclinical disease models into novel pharmacotherapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Myosin Heavy Chains: Ribosomal Specialization Drives Human Skeletal Muscle Fiber Heterogeneity
Authors: Moreno-Justicia, R.; Van der Stede, T.; Stocks, B.; Laitila, J.; Seaborne, R. A.; Van de Loock, A.; Lievens, E.; Marin-Arraiza, L.; Van Vossel, K.; Yigit, N.; Anckaert, J.; Weyns, A.; Van Thienen, R.; Sahl, R. E.; Zanoteli, E.; Lawlor, M. W.; Mestdagh, P.; Vandesompele, J.; Ochala, J.; Hostrup, M.; Derave, W.; Deshmukh, A. S.
Score: 41.6, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Retrotransposon-driven environmental regulation of FLC leads to adaptive response to herbicide
Authors: Raingeval, M.; Leduque, B.; Baduel, P.; Edera, A.; Roux, F.; Colot, V.; Quadrana, L.
Score: 32.2, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.556499
The mobilization of retrotransposons yields major-effect mutations. Here, we report an adaptive retrotransposon insertion within the first intron of the Arabidopsis floral-repressor locus FLOWERING LOCUS C (FLC). The insertion-mutation augments the environmental sensitivity of FLC by affecting the balance between coding and non-coding transcript isoforms in response to environmental threads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>The Sensation and Pain Rating Scale: easy to use, clear to interpret, and responsive to clinical change
Authors: Madden, V. J.; Kamerman, P.; Leake, H. B.; Catley, M. J.; Heathcote, L. C.; Moseley, L. G.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-09-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295128
The Sensation and Pain Rating Scale (SPARS) allows rating of non-painful as well as painful percepts. Although it performs well in the experimental context, its clinical utility has not been tested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>MDMA Assisted Psychotherapy Decreases PTSD Symptoms, Dissociation, Functional Disability, and Depression: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Green, W. M.; Raut, S. B.; James, F. L. J.; Benedek, D. M.; Ursano, R. J.; Johnson, L. R.
Score: 11.9, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23293955
Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) causes broad impairments affecting quality of life. However, despite current treatment many people with PTSD do not fully recover. MDMA assisted psychotherapy has emerged as a new therapy for PTSD and its comorbidities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Genomic epidemiology of the cholera outbreak in Malawi 2022-2023
Authors: Chabuka, L.; Choga, W. T.; Mavian, C. N.; Moir, M.; Tegally, H.; Wilkinson, E.; Naidoo, Y.; Inward, R.; Morgenstern, C.; Bhatt, S.; Wint, W. G. R.; Khan, K.; Bogoch, I. I.; Kraemer, M. U. G.; Baxter, C.; Tagliamonte, M.; Salemi, M.; Lessells, R.; Mitambo, C.; Chitatanga, R.; Bango, J. B.; Chiwaula, M.; Chavula, Y.; Bukhu, M.; Manda, H.; Chitenje, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>A Mutual Knowledge Distillation-Empowered AI Framework for Early Detection of Alzheimer&amp;#39;s Disease Using Incomplete Multi-Modal Images
Authors: Kwak, M. G.; Su, Y.; Chen, K.; Weidman, D.; Wu, T.; Lure, F.; Li, J.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294574
Early detection of Alzheimers Disease (AD) is crucial to ensure timely interventions and optimize treatment outcomes for patients. While integrating multi-modal neuroimages, such as MRI and PET, has shown great promise, limited research has been done to effectively handle incomplete multi-modal image datasets in the integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>HEART rate variability biofeedback breathing programme for LOng Covid dysautonomia (HEARTLOC): results of a feasibility study
Authors: Corrado, J.; Iftekhar, N.; Halpin, S.; Li, M.; Tarrant, R.; Grimaldi, J.; Simms, A.; O&amp;#39;Connor, R. J.; Casson, A.; Sivan, M.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295208
Introduction Post-covid-19 syndrome, or Long covid (LC) refers to symptoms persisting 12 weeks after Covid-19 infection. LC comprises a wide range of dysautonomia symptoms, including fatigue, breathlessness, palpitations, dizziness, pain and brain fog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Being responsible for COPD - lung disease as a manifestation of structural violence.
Authors: Williams, P. J.; Buttery, S. C.; Laverty, A. A.; Hopkinson, N. S.
Score: 7.2, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.06.23295021
Lung health, the development of lung disease, and how well a person with lung disease is able to live, all depend on a wide range of societal factors. Considering COPD as a manifestation of structural violence, something that continues to be done to people, despite it being largely preventable, makes the causal processes more apparent and the responsibility to interrupt or alleviate these clearer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Characterising the neurobiological mechanisms of action of exercise and cognitive behavioural interventions for rheumatoid arthritis fatigue: an MRI brain study
Authors: Dehsarvi, A.; Al-Wasity, S.; Stefanov, K.; Wiseman, S.; Ralston, S.; Wardlaw, J. M.; Emsley, R.; Bachmair, E.-m.; Cavanagh, J.; Waiter, G. D.; Basu, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.23294366
BackgroundChronic Fatigue is a major clinical unmet need among patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). Current therapies are limited to non-pharmacological interventions, such as personalised exercise programmes (PEP) and cognitive behavioural approaches (CBA), however, still most patients continue to report severe fatigue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>You do not receive enough recognition for your influential science
Authors: Arabi, S.; Ni, C.; Hutchins, B. I.
Score: 35.7, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556750
During career advancement and funding allocation decisions in biomedicine, reviewers have traditionally depended on journal-level measures of scientific influence like the impact factor. Prestigious journals are thought to pursue a reputation of exclusivity by rejecting large quantities of papers, many of which may be meritorious. It is possible that this process could create a system whereby some influential articles are prospectively identified and recognized by journal brands but most influential articles are overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review on the Effects of Exercise on Gut Microbial Diversity, Taxonomic Composition, and Microbial Metabolites: Identifying Research Gaps and Future Directions
Authors: Cullen, J.; Shahzad, S.; Dhillon, J.
Score: 39.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.05.23294991
The gut microbiome, hosting a diverse microbial community, plays a pivotal role in metabolism, immunity, and digestion. While the potential of exercise to influence this microbiome has been increasingly recognized, findings remain incongruous. This systematic review examined the effects of exercise on the gut microbiome of human and animal models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Engineering synthetic phosphorylation signaling networks in human cells
Authors: Yang, X.; Rocks, J. W.; Jiang, K.; Walters, A. J.; Rai, K.; Liu, J.; Nguyen, J.; Olson, S. D.; Mehta, P.; Collins, J. J.; Daringer, N. M.; Bashor, C. J.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.557100
Protein phosphorylation signaling networks play a central role in how cells sense and respond to their environment. Here, we describe the engineering of artificial phosphorylation networks in which &amp;#34;push-pull&amp;#34; motifs-reversible enzymatic phosphorylation cycles consisting of opposing kinase and phosphatase activities-are assembled from modular protein domain parts and then wired together to create synthetic phosphorylation circuits in human cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Correlation of myeloid-derived suppressor cell expansion with upregulated transposable elements in severe COVID-19 unveiled in single-cell RNA sequencing reanalysis
Authors: Farahmandnejad, M.; Mosadeghi, P.; Dorvash, M.; Sakhteman, A.; Faridi, P.; Negahdaripour, M.
Score: 19.2, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.556192
Some studies investigated the potential role of transposable elements (TEs) in COVID-19 pathogenesis and complications. However, to the best of our knowledge, there is no study to examine the possible association of TEs expression in cell functions and its potential role in COVID-19 immune response at the single-cell level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>An integrative taxonomic treatment of the Mycetophilidae (Diptera: Bibionomorpha) from Singapore reveals 115 new species on 730km2
Authors: Amorim, D. d. S.; Oliveira, S. S.; Balbi, M. I. P. A.; Ang, Y.; Yeo, D.; Srivathsan, A.; Meier, R.
Score: 42.8, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.02.555672
&amp;#34;Open ended&amp;#34; or &amp;#34;dark taxa&amp;#34; are species-rich clades that are so abundant and diverse that conventional taxonomic methods tend to struggle with the onslaught of specimens and species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
