<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>The contribution of movement to social network structure and spreading dynamics under simple and complex transmission
Authors: Chimento, M.; Farine, D. R.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579705
The structure of social networks fundamentally influences spreading dynamics. In general, the more contact between individuals, the more opportunity there is for transmission to take place. Yet, contact between individuals, and any resulting transmission events, are determined by a combination of spatial (where individuals choose to move) and social rules (who they choose to interact with or learn from).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structural basis for the inhibition of PRC2 by active transcription histone posttranslational modifications
Authors: Cookis, T.; Lydecker, A.; Sauer, P. V.; Kasinath, V.; Nogales, E.
Score: 25.2, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579730
Polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) is an epigenetic regulator essential for embryonic development and maintenance of cell identity that trimethylates histone H3 at lysine 27 (H3K27me3) leading to gene silencing. PRC2 is regulated by association with protein cofactors and crosstalk with histone posttranslational modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Far-red chemigenetic biosensors for multi-dimensional and super-resolved kinase activity imaging
Authors: Frei, M. S.; Sanchez, S. A.; Liu, L.; Schneider, F.; Wang, Z.; Hakozaki, H.; Li, Y.; Lyons, A. C.; Rohm, T. V.; Olefsky, J. M.; Shi, L.; Schöneberg, J.; Fraser, S. E.; Mehta, S.; Wang, Y.; Zhang, J.
Score: 35.1, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579766
Fluorescent biosensors revolutionized biomedical science by enabling the direct measurement of signaling activities in living cells, yet the current technology is limited in resolution and dimensionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Cellpose3: one-click image restoration for improved cellular segmentation
Authors: Stringer, C.; Pachitariu, M.
Score: 106.0, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579780
Generalist methods for cellular segmentation have good out-of-the-box performance on a variety of image types. However, existing methods struggle for images that are degraded by noise, blurred or undersampled, all of which are common in microscopy. We focused the development of Cellpose3 on addressing these cases, and here we demonstrate substantial out-of-the-box gains in segmentation and image quality for noisy, blurry or undersampled images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Low-dose cryo-electron ptychography of proteins at sub-nanometer resolution
Authors: Kucukoglu, B.; Mohammed, I.; Guerrero-Ferreira, R. C.; Ribet, S.; Varnavides, G.; Leidl, M. L.; Lau, K.; Nazarov, S.; Myasnikov, A.; Sachse, C.; Mueller-Caspary, K.; Ophus, C.; Stahlberg, H.
Score: 42.9, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.12.579607
Cryo-transmission electron microscopy (cryo-EM) of frozen hydrated specimens is an efficient method for the structural analysis of purified biological molecules. However, for particles smaller than 50kDa, single particle cryo-EM often fails due to the limited imaging contrast of individual micrographs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Gene regulatory network landscape of Group 3/4 medulloblastoma
Authors: Joshi, P.; Stelzer, T.; Okonechnikov, K.; Sarropoulos, I.; Sepp, M.; Pour-Jamnani, M. V.; Rademacher, A.; Yamada-Saito, T.; Schneider, C.; Schmidt, J.; Schaefer, P.; Leiss, K.; Bortolomeazzi, M.; Mallm, J.-P.; da Silva, P. B. G.; Statz, B.; Wittmann, A.; Schramm, K.; Blattner-Johnson, M.; Fiesel, P.; Jones, B.; Milde, T.; Pajtler, K.; van Tilburg, C. M.; Witt, O.; Rippe, K.; Korshunov, A.; Jones, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Stressor-evoked brain activity, cardiovascular reactivity, and subclinical atherosclerosis in midlife adults.
Authors: Rasero, J.; Verstynen, T. D.; DuPont, C. M.; Kraynak, T. E.; Barinas-Mitchell, E.; Scudder, M. R.; Kamarck, T. W.; Sentis, A. I.; Leckie, R. L.; Gianaros, P. J.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-02-06 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.05.24302236
BackgroundCardiovascular responses to psychological stressors have been separately associated with preclinical atherosclerosis and hemodynamic brain activity patterns across different studies and cohorts; however, what has not been established is whether cardiovascular stress responses reliably link indicators of stressor-evoked brain activity and preclinical atherosclerosis that have been measured in the same individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single molecule imaging of the central dogma reveals myosin-2A gene expression is regulated by contextual translational buffering
Authors: Wiggan, O.; Stasevich, T. J.
Score: 92.3, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.11.579797
While protein homeostasis is a hallmark of gene regulation, unraveling the hidden regulatory mechanisms that maintain homeostasis is difficult using traditional methods. To confront this problem, we CRISPR engineered a human cell line with multiple tags in the endogenous MYH9 gene, which encodes the essential and ubiquitous myosin-2A cytoskeletal motor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Induction and in silico staging of human gastruloids with neural tube, segmented somites &amp;amp; advanced cell types
Authors: Hamazaki, N.; Yang, W.; Kubo, C.; Qiu, C.; Martin, B. K.; Garge, R. K.; Regalado, S. G.; Nichols, E.; Lee, C.; Daza, R. M.; Srivatsan, S.; Shendure, J.
Score: 43.4, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579769
Embryonic organoids are emerging as powerful models for studying early mammalian development. For example, stem cell-derived gastruloids form elongating structures containing all three germ layers1-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Global niche partitioning of purine and pyrimidine cross-feeding among ocean microbes
Authors: Braakman, R.; Satinsky, B.; O&amp;#39;Keefe, T. J.; Longnecker, K.; Becker, J. W.; Dooley, K.; Hogle, S. L.; Arellano, A.; Kido Soule, M. C.; Kujawinski, E. B.; Chisholm, S. W.
Score: 16.9, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579562
Characterizing the diversity of cross-feeding pathways in ocean microbes illuminates forces shaping co-evolution, ecosystem self-assembly and carbon cycling. Here we uncover a purine and pyrimidine cross-feeding network in globally abundant groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Incidence of Mortality and Predictors Among Patients with Shock Managed in the Emergency Room of a Large Tertiary Referral Hospital in Ethiopia
Authors: Asfaw (MD), K. G.; Adugna (MD, A. G.; Mekonen (MD), N. M.; Leulseged (MD, MPH), T. W.; Merahi (MD, MPH), M. K.; Kejela (MD), S.; Moges (MD), F. H.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.24302628
BackgroundShock is a common emergency condition which can lead to organ failure and death if not diagnosed and managed timely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Serum proteomic profiling of physical activity reveals CD300LG as a novel exerkine with a potential causal link to glucose homeostasis
Authors: Lee-Odegard, S.; Hjorth, M.; Olsen, T.; Moen, G.-H.; Daubney, E.; Evans, D. M.; Hevener, A. L.; Lusis, A. J.; Zhou, M.; Seldin, M. M.; Allayee, H.; Viken, J. K.; Gulseth, H.; Norheim, F.; Drevon, C. A.; Birkeland, K. I.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.24302626
BackgroundPhysical activity has been associated with preventing the development of type 2 diabetes and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Differential associations between SARS-CoV-2 infection, perceived burden of the pandemic and mental health in the German population-based cohort for digital health research
Authors: Steinmann, L. A.; Claass, L. V.; Rau, M.; Massag, J.; Diexer, S.; Klee, B.; Gottschick, C.; Binder, M.; Sedding, D.; Frese, T.; Girndt, M.; Hoell, J.; Moor, I.; Rosendahl, J.; Gekle, M.; Mikolajczyk, R.; Opel, N.
Score: 18.7, Published: 2024-02-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.14.24302768
IntroductionUnderstanding the potential adverse effects of the Covid-19-pandemic remains a challenge for public mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>50,000 years of Evolutionary History of India: Insights from ~2,700 Whole Genome Sequences
Authors: Kerdoncuff, E.; Skov, L.; Patterson, N.; Zhao, W.; Lueng, Y. Y.; Schellenberg, G. D.; Smith, J. A.; Dey, S.; Ganna, A.; Dey, A.; Kardia, S. L. R.; Lee, J.; Moorjani, P.
Score: 116.3, Published: 2024-02-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.15.580575
India has been underrepresented in whole genome sequencing studies. We generated 2,762 high coverage genomes from India - including individuals from most geographic regions, speakers of all major languages, and tribal and caste groups - providing a comprehensive survey of genetic variation in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>forensic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/forensic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/forensic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 vaccination was a rare potential etiology for cause of death after medicolegal autopsy. A Finnish nationwide study.
Authors: Pakanen, L.; Nieminen, T.; Kuvaja, P.; Nohynek, H.; Goebeler, S.; Artama, M.; Hovi, P.
Score: 38.3, Published: 2024-02-14 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.13.24302742
COVID-19 vaccinations began globally at the end of 2020. By the end of 2021, 9.8 million doses were given in Finland. Regarding safety, most vaccine-related adverse reactions have been mild, but serious and lethal ones have also occurred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A rare splice-site variant in cardiac troponin-T (TNNT2): The need for ancestral diversity in genomic reference datasets
Authors: Butters, A.; Thomson, K.; Harrington, F.; Henden, N.; McGuire, K.; Byrne, A.; Bryen, S.; Leask, M.; Ackerman, M. J.; Atherton, J. J.; Bos, J. M.; Caleshu, C.; Parikh, V. N.; Day, S.; Tardiff, J. C.; Dunn, K.; Hayes, I.; Juang, J.; McGaughran, J.; Nowak, N.; Ronan, A.; Semsarian, C.; Tiemensma, M.; Merriman, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Controlling for polygenic genetic confounding in epidemiologic association studies
Authors: Zhao, Z.; Yang, X.; Miao, J.; Dorn, S.; Barcellos, S.; Fletcher, J.; Lu, Q.
Score: 12.4, Published: 2024-02-14 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.12.579913
Epidemiologic associations estimated from observational data are often confounded by genetics due to pervasive pleiotropy among complex traits. Many studies either neglect genetic confounding altogether or rely on adjusting for polygenic scores (PGS) in regression analysis. In this study, we unveil that the commonly employed PGS approach is inadequate for removing genetic confounding due to measurement error and model misspecification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Unifying approaches from statistical genetics and phylogenetics for mapping phenotypes in structured populations
Authors: Schraiber, J. G.; Edge, M. D.; Pennell, M.
Score: 36.5, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579721
In both statistical genetics and phylogenetics, a major goal is to identify correlations between genetic loci or other aspects of the phenotype or environment and a focal trait. In these two fields, there are sophisticated but disparate statistical traditions aimed at these tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Retrieval Augmented Generation Enabled Generative Pre-Trained Transformer 4 (GPT-4) Performance for Clinical Trial Screening
Authors: Unlu, O.; Shin, J.; Mailly, C. J.; Oates, M. F.; Tucci, M. R.; Varugheese, M.; Wagholikar, K.; Wang, F.; Scirica, B. M.; Blood, A. J.; Aronson, S. J.
Score: 62.9, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302376
BackgroundSubject screening is a key aspect of all clinical trials; however, traditionally, it is a labor-intensive and error-prone task, demanding significant time and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>TP53 mutation screening for patients at risk of myeloid malignancy
Authors: Mukherjee, D.; Lawal, R. A.; Fitzhugh, C. D.; Hourigan, C. S.; Dillon, L. W.
Score: 16.6, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.06.24302401
There is increasing recognition of the risk of developing therapy-related myeloid malignancy, including after cellular therapy. While retrospective studies have implicated pre-existing TP53 mutated hematopoietic clones as a common causative mechanism, no prospective screening to identify those patients at greatest risk is currently possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Mild HIV-specific selective forces overlaying natural CD4&amp;#43; T cell dynamics explain the clonality and decay dynamics of HIV reservoir cells
Authors: Reeves, D. B.; Rigau, D. N.; Romero, A.; Zhang, H.; Simonetti, F. R.; Varriale, J.; Hoh, R.; Zhang, L.; Smith, K. N.; Montaner, L. J.; Rubin, L. H.; Gange, S. J.; Roan, N. R.; Tien, P. C.; Margolick, J. B.; Peluso, M. J.; Deeks, S. G.; Schiffer, J. T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>A Broad-Spectrum Multi-Antigen mRNA/LNP-Based Pan-Coronavirus Vaccine Induced Potent Cross-Protective Immunity Against Infection and Disease Caused by Highly Pathogenic and Heavily Spike-Mutated SARS-CoV-2 Variants of Concern in the Syrian Hamster Model
Authors: Prakash, S.; Dhanushkodi, N. R.; Singer, M.; Quadiri, A.; Zayou, L.; Vahed, H.; Coulon, P.-G.; El Babsiri, A.; Gil, D.; Ulmer, J. B.; BENMOHAMED, L.
Score: 34.4, Published: 2024-02-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.14.580225
The first-generation Spike-alone-based COVID-19 vaccines have successfully contributed to reducing the risk of hospitalization, serious illness, and death caused by SARS-CoV-2 infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Restrained memory CD8&amp;#43; T cell responses favors viral persistence and elevated IgG responses in patients with severe Long COVID.
Authors: Rodriguez, L.; Tan, Z.; Tadepally, L. K.; Wang, J.; Barcenilla, H.; Swank, Z.; Zuo, F.; Abolhassani, H.; Pavlovitch-Bedzyk, A. J.; Wang, C.; Gonzalez, L.; Habimana Mugabo, C.; Johnsson, A.; Chen, Y.; James, A.; Mikes, J.; Kleberg, L.; Sundling, C.; Bjornson, M.; Nygren-Bonnier, M.; Stahlberg, M.; Runold, M.; Bjorkander, S.; Melen, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical ethics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Improving research transparency with individualized report cards: A feasibility study in clinical trials at a large university medical center
Authors: Franzen, D. L.; Salholz-Hillel, M.; Müller-Ohlraun, S.; Strech, D.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.24302619
Research transparency is crucial for ensuring the relevance, integrity, and reliability of scientific findings. However, previous work indicates room for improvement across transparency practices. The primary objective of this study was to develop an extensible tool to provide individualized feedback and guidance for improved transparency across phases of a study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 serosurvey of healthy, privately owned cats presenting to a New York City animal hospital in the early phase of the COVID-19 pandemic (2020-2021)
Authors: Choi, A.; Stout, A. E.; Rollins, A.; Wang, K.; Guo, Q.; Jaimes, J. A.; Kennedy, M.; Wagner, B.; Whittaker, G. R.
Score: 241.6, Published: 2024-02-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.13.580068
Both domestic and non-domestic cats are now established to be susceptible to infection by SARS-CoV-2, the cause of the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Structure-based design of a soluble human cytomegalovirus glycoprotein B antigen stabilized in a prefusion-like conformation
Authors: Sponholtz, M. R.; Byrne, P. O.; Lee, A. G.; Ramamohan, A. R.; Goldsmith, J. A.; McCool, R. S.; Zhou, L.; Johnson, N. V.; Hsieh, C.-L.; Connors, M.; Karthigeyan, K.; Campbell, J. D.; Permar, S. R.; Maynard, J. A.; Yu, D.; Bottomley, M. J.; McLellan, J. S.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579772
Human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) glycoprotein B (gB) is a class III membrane fusion protein required for viral entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Evidence for trans-synaptic propagation of oligomeric tau in Progressive Supranuclear Palsy
Authors: McGeachan, R.; Keavey, L.; Rose, J. L.; Simzer, E. M.; Chang, Y. Y.; Spires-Jones, M. P.; Gillmore, M.; Ravingerova, N.; Scutariu, C.; Taylor, L.; Rose, J.; King, D.; Tzioras, M.; Tulloch, J.; Booker, S.; Liaquat, I.; Hindley-Pollock, N.; Geary, B.; Smith, C.; Brennan, P. M.; Durrant, C. S.; Spires-Jones, T. L.
Score: 23.0, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2022.09.20.22280086</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>SARS-COV-2 induces blood-brain barrier and choroid plexus barrier impairments and vascular inflammation in mice
Authors: Qiao, H.; Deng, X.; Qiu, L.; Qu, Y.; Chiu, Y.; Chen, F.; Xia, S.; Muenzel, C.; Ge, T.; Song, P.; Bonnin, A.; Zhao, Z.; Yuan, W.
Score: 213.0, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.579589
The coronavirus disease of 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic that has led to more than 700 million confirmed cases and near 7 million deaths. Although Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) virus mainly infects the respiratory system, neurological complications are widely reported in both acute infection and long-COVID cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 infection and Pregnancy outcome: A cross-sectional study from Eastern U.P. Population, India
Authors: Rai, S.; Ashish, A.; Mishra, S.; Kumar, B.; Kusum, K.; Singh, R.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-02-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.15.24302882
Pregnant women with coronavirus infection are at a higher risk for severe diseases. In the present study, we evaluated and compared clinical characteristics and outcomes in pregnancy of normal females and females with SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our study was a cross-sectional study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Biological Factors Influencing Individual Responses to Propylene Oxide: A Systematic Review
Authors: Gabashvili, I. S.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2024-02-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.15.24302622
Objective: This systematic review aims to synthesize current knowledge on Propylene Oxide (PO) in human exhaled breath, examining its presence across various biological matrices and exploring methodologies for its analysis. It seeks to elucidate the sources of PO in the human body and understand individual variability in detoxification processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>British Oncology Pharmacy Association Delphi Consensus Guidelines: co-infusion of trometamol-containing calcium folinate (leucovorin) with Systemic Anti-Cancer Treatments
Authors: Polwart, C.; Root, T.; Tezcan, S.; Meehan, S.; Wetherill, B.; Waterson, C.; Burnett, B.; Chauhan, R.; Al-Modaris, I.; Walters-Davies, R.; British Oncology Pharmacy Association, Score: 6.1, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.24302100
Drug stability and compatibility are critical factors influencing cost and logistics of treatment delivery, therapeutic effectiveness, and patient safety. This is particularly significant in the realm of cancer chemotherapeutics, where stability and compatibility studies play a vital role in ensuring rational and safe medicine administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Myopia and hyperopia are associated with opposite chronotypes in a sample of 71,016 individuals
Authors: Palumaa, T.; Taba, N.; Teder-Laving, M.; Kivi, K.-L.; Reis, K.; Vosa, U.; Research Team, E. B.; Esko, T.; Abner, E.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-02-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.13.24302718
Myopia, projected to affect half of the global population by 2050, is a growing healthcare concern. Chronotype, an output of the human biological clock, and sleep parameters have been associated with several diseases, including myopia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Optical photothermal infrared spectroscopy (O-PTIR): a promising new tool for bench-top analytical palaeontology at the sub-micron scale
Authors: Loron, C. C.; Borondics, F.
Score: 16.5, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.579492
The identification of preserved organic material within fossils is challenging. Well-established vibrational spectroscopy techniques, such as micro-FTIR (Fourier Transform Infra-Red spectroscopy), have been widely used to investigate organic fossils molecular composition. However, even when well-adapted to study objects several tens of micrometre across, they still suffer from limitations, notably regarding resolution and sample preparation requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Loss of endogenous estrogen alters mitochondrial metabolism and muscle clock-related protein Rbm20 in female mdx mice
Authors: Timpani, C. A.; Debrincat, D.; Kourakis, S.; Boyer, R.; Formosa, L. E.; Steele, J. R.; Zhang, H.; Schittenhelm, R. B.; Russell, A. P.; Rybalka, E.; Lindsay, A.
Score: 6.4, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.579567
Female carriers of a Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) gene mutation manifest exercise intolerance and metabolic anomalies that may be exacerbated following menopause due to the loss of estrogen, a known regulator of skeletal muscle function and metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Cell circuits underlying nanomaterial specific respiratory toxicology
Authors: Voss, C.; Han, L.; Ansari, M.; Strunz, M.; Haefner, V.; Ballester-Lopez, C.; Angelidis, I.; Mayr, C. H.; Berthing, T.; Conlon, T.; Liu, Q.; Ren, H.; Zhou, Q.; Schmid, O.; Yildirim, A. O.; Rehberg, M.; Vogel, U.; Gothe-Schniering, J.; Theis, F. J.; Schiller, H. B.; Stoeger, T.
Score: 9.0, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.10.579746
Nanomaterials emerged as boundless resource of innovation, but their shape and biopersistence related to respiratory toxicology raise longstanding concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Anti-diuretic hormone ITP signals via a guanylate cyclase receptor to modulate systemic homeostasis in Drosophila
Authors: Gera, J.; Agard, M.; Nave, H.; Sajadi, F.; Thorat, L.; Kondo, S.; Nassel, D.; Paluzzi, J.-P. V.; Zandawala, M.
Score: 17.8, Published: 2024-02-10 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.07.579245
Insects have evolved a variety of neurohormones that enable them to maintain their nutrient and osmotic homeostasis. While the identities and functions of various insect metabolic and diuretic hormones have been well-established, the characterization of an anti-diuretic signaling system that is conserved across most insects is still lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Bioengineering secreted proteases converts divergent Rcr3 orthologs and paralogs into extracellular immune co-receptors
Authors: Kourelis, J.; Schuster, M.; Demir, F.; Mattinson, O.; Krauter, S.; Kahlon, P. S.; O&amp;#39;Grady, R.; Royston, S.; Bravo-Cazar, A. L.; Mooney, B. C.; Huesgen, P. F.; Kamoun, S.; van der Hoorn, R. A. L.
Score: 30.7, Published: 2024-02-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.14.580413
Secreted immune proteases Rcr3 and Pip1 of tomato are both inhibited by Avr2 from the fungal plant pathogen Cladosporium fulvum but only Rcr3 act as a decoy co-receptor that detects Avr2 in the presence of the Cf-2 immune receptor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Sub-second and multi-second dopamine dynamics underlie variability in human time perception
Authors: Sadibolova, R.; DiMarco, E. K.; Jiang, A.; Maas, B.; Tatter, S. B.; Laxton, A.; Kishida, K. T.; Terhune, D. B.
Score: 8.5, Published: 2024-02-09 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.24302276
Timing behaviour and the perception of time are fundamental to cognitive and emotional processes in humans. In non-human model organisms, the neuromodulator dopamine has been associated with variations in timing behaviour, but the connection between variations in dopamine levels and the human experience of time has not been directly assessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Ecological impacts of climate change will transform public health priorities for zoonotic and vector-borne disease
Authors: Redding, D. W.; Gibb, R.; Jones, K. E.
Score: 57.4, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.24302575
Climate change impacts on zoonotic/vector-borne diseases pose significant threats to humanity1 but these links are, in general, poorly understood2. Here, we project present and future geographical risk patterns for 141 infectious agents to understand likely climate change impacts, by integrating ecological models of infection hazard (climate-driven host/vector distributions and dispersal3,4) with exposure (human populations) and vulnerability (poverty prevalence).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>First positronium image of the human brain in vivo
Authors: Moskal, P.; Baran, J.; Bass, S.; Choinski, J.; Chug, N.; Curceanu, C.; Czerwinski, E.; Dadgar, M.; Das, M.; Dulski, K. Ł; Eliyan, K. V.; Fronczewska, K.; Gajos, A.; Kacprzak, K.; Kajetanowicz, M.; Kaplanoglu, T.; Kaplon, L.; Klimaszewski, K.; Kobylecka, M.; Korcyl, G.; Kozik, T.; Krzemien, W.; Kubat, K.; Kumar, D.; Kunikowska, J.; Maczewska, J.; Migdal, W.; Moskal, G.; Mryka, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Physiotherapy Under Pressure: A Cross-Sectional Study on The Interplay Between Perfectionism, Moral Injury, and Burnout
Authors: Biggs, D.; Blackburn, L.; Black, C.; Shanmugam, S.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.09.24302501
BackgroundGiven the escalating challenges for UK-based physiotherapists in workload pressures, budget constraints, staff shortages and patient wait times, the profession (of 65,000 registered physiotherapists) requires immediate care and review of therapist health. This pioneering study aims to examine perfectionism, moral injury, and burnout among UK-based physiotherapists across the NHS, private practice, sports, and academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Structured Peer Review: Pilot results from 23 Elsevier Journals
Authors: Malicki, M.; Mehmani, B.
Score: 28.3, Published: 2024-02-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.01.578440
BackgroundReviewers rarely comment on the same aspects of a manuscript, making it difficult to properly assess manuscripts quality and the quality of the peer review process. It was the goal of this pilot study to evaluate structured peer review implementation by: 1) exploring if and how reviewers answered structured peer review questions, 2) analysing reviewer agreement, 3) comparing that agreement to agreement before implementation of structured peer review, and 4) further enhancing the piloted set of structured peer review questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>Frequency and spectrum of mutations in human sperm measured using duplex sequencing correlate with trio-based de novo mutation analyses
Authors: Axelsson, J.; LeBlanc, D.; Shojaeisaadi, H.; Meier, M. J.; Fitzgerald, D. M.; Nachmanson, D.; Carlson, J.; Golubeva, A.; Higgins, J.; Smith, T.; Lo, F. Y.; Pilsner, R.; Williams, A.; Salk, J.; Marchetti, F.; Yauk, C.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-02-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.13.24302689
De novo mutations (DNMs) are drivers of genetic disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough in Dicot Prime Editing: Enabling Heritable Desired Edits in Tomato and Arabidopsis
Authors: Vu, T. V.; Nguyen, N. T.; Kim, J.; Song, Y. J.; Nguyen, T. H.; Kim, J.-Y.
Score: 12.4, Published: 2024-02-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.11.579803
Prime editing (PE) enables almost all types of precise genome editing in animals and plants. It has been successfully adapted to edit several plants at variable efficiency and versatility. However, this technique is inefficient for dicots for unknown reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>An Organism-Level Quantitative Flux Model of Mammalian Energy Metabolism
Authors: Yuan, B.; Inouye, K. E.; Hotamisligil, G.; Hui, S.
Score: 37.5, Published: 2024-02-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.11.579776
Mammalian tissues feed on nutrients in the blood circulation. At the organism-level, mammalian energy metabolism comprises of oxidation, interconverting, storing and releasing of circulating nutrients. Though much is known about the individual processes and nutrients, a holistic and quantitative model describing these processes for all major circulating nutrients is lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Molecular signatures of chronic antibody-mediated rejection in human liver transplants
Authors: Engel, B.; Alaswad, A.; Campos-Murguia, A.; Zoodsma, M.; Klingbeil, A.; Chihab, K.; Bosselmann, E. A.; Heinrich, S.; Hartleben, B.; Jonigk, D. D.; Verboom, M.; Hallensleben, M.; Geffers, R.; Wedemeyer, H.; Xu, C.; Jaeckel, E.; Li, Y.; Taubert, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2024-02-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.02.08.24302515
Background&amp;amp;AimsThe role of antibody-mediated rejection (ABMR) after liver transplantation (LT) remains controversial. Chronic ABMR (cABMR) is often subclinical and potentially missed without surveillance biopsies (svLbx) which are not established in most LT centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/urology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of genetic associations with clinical phenotypes of kidney stone disease
Authors: Hsi, R. S.; Zhang, S.; Xu, Y.; Triozzi, J. L.; Hung, A. M.; Bejan, C. A.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2024-01-22 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301501
Introduction and ObjectiveWe sought to replicate and discover genetic associations of kidney stone disease within a large-scale electronic health record (EHR) system. MethodsWe performed genome-wide association studies (GWASs) for nephrolithiasis from genotyped samples of 5,571 cases and 83,692 controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>West Nile virus is transmitted within mosquito populations through infectious mosquito excreta
Authors: Hamel, R.; Narpon, Q.; Serrato-Pomar, I.; Gauliard, C.; Berthomieu, A.; Wichit, S.; Misse, D.; Sofonea, M. T.; Pompon, J.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2024-01-31 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.29.577888
Understanding transmission routes of arboviruses is key to control their epidemiology and global health burden. Using West Nile virus and Culex mosquitoes, we tested whether arboviruses are transmitted through mosquito excreta. First, we determined the presence of infectious virions in excreta and quantified a high concentration of infectious units per excreta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
