<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Suppressed IgG4 class switching in dupilumab- and TNF inhibitor-treated patients after repeated SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccination
Authors: Valk, A. M.; Keijser, J. B. D.; Dam, K. v.; Stalman, E.; Wieske, L.; Steenhuis, M.; Kummer, L. Y. L.; Spuls, P. I.; Bekkenk, M. W.; Musters, A. H.; Post, N. F.; Bosma, A. L.; Horvath, B.; Hijnen, D.; Schreurs, C. R. G.; van Kempen, Z.; Killestein, J.; Volkers, A. G.; Tas, S.; Boekel, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Multi-attribute decision-making in macaques relies on direct attribute comparisons
Authors: Perkins, A. Q.; Gillis, Z. S.; Rich, E. L.
Score: 9.5, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.563329
In value-based decisions, there are frequently multiple attributes, such as cost, quality, or quantity, that contribute to the overall goodness of an option. Since one option may not be better in all attributes at once, the decision process should include a means of weighing relevant attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structure of the yeast ceramide synthase
Authors: Schäfer, J.-H.; Clausmeyer, L.; Körner, C.; Esch, B. M.; Wolf, V. N.; Walter, S.; Januliene, D.; Moeller, A.; Fröhlich, F.
Score: 16.5, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563787
Ceramides play a pivotal role as essential lipids, serving as foundational components for complex sphingolipids and potent signaling molecules. Ceramides are the products of the N-acylation of a sphingoid base and a CoA-activated fatty acid. This reaction is catalyzed by the enzymes of the evolutionarily conserved ceramide synthase (CerS) family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Designer Fat Cells: Adipogenic Differentiation of CRISPR-Cas9 Genome-Engineered Induced Pluripotent Stem Cells
Authors: Ely, E. V.; Kapinski, A. T.; Paradi, S. G.; Tang, R.; Guilak, F.; Collins, K. H.-M.
Score: 10.9, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564206
Adipose tissue is an active endocrine organ that can signal bidirectionally to many tissues and organ systems in the body. With obesity, adipose tissue is a source of low-level inflammation that contributes to various co-morbidities and damage to downstream effector tissues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>OMICmAge: An integrative multi-omics approach to quantify biological age with electronic medical records
Authors: Chen, Q.; Dwaraka, V. B.; Carreras-Gallo, N.; Mendez, K.; Chen, Y.; Kachroo, P.; Prince, N.; Went, H.; Mendez, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Moqri, M.; Chu, S. H.; Kelly, R. S.; Weiss, S. T.; Rattray, N. J.; Gladyshev, V. N.; Karlson, E.; Wheelock, C.; Mathe, E. A.; Dahlin, A.; McGeachie, M. J.; Smith, R.; Lasky-Su, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Multi-pass, single-molecule nanopore reading of long protein strands with single-amino acid sensitivity
Authors: Motone, K.; Kontogiorgos-Heintz, D.; Wee, J.; Kurihara, K.; Yang, S.; Roote, G.; Fang, Y.; Cardozo, N.; Nivala, J.
Score: 168.6, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563182
The ability to sequence single protein molecules in their native, full-length form would enable a more comprehensive understanding of proteomic diversity. Current technologies, however, are limited in achieving this goal. Here, we establish a method for long-range, single-molecule reading of intact protein strands on a commercial nanopore sensor array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Ataxia-telangiectasia mutated (Atm) disruption sensitizes spatially-directed H3.3K27M/TP53 diffuse midline gliomas to radiation therapy
Authors: Mangoli, A.; Wu, S.; Liu, H. Q.; Aksu, M.; Jain, V. J.; Foreman, B. E.; Regal, J. A.; Weidenhammer, L. B.; Stewart, C. E.; Guerra Garcia, M. E.; Hocke, E.; Abramson, K.; Williams, N. T.; Luo, L.; Deland, K.; Attardi, L.; Abe, K.; Hashizume, R.; Ashley, D. M.; Becher, O. J.; Kirsch, D. G.; Gregory, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Deep neural network for identification of impaired microvascular and vasomotor function from stress electrocardiography
Authors: Moody, J. B.; Poitrasson-Riviere, A.; Renaud, J. M.; Hagio, T.; Alahdab, F.; Al-Mallah, M. H.; Vanderver, M. D.; Ficaro, E. P.; Murthy, V. L.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.23297552
Background: Impaired microvascular and vasomotor function is a common consequence of aging, diabetes, and other risk factors, and is associated with adverse cardiac outcomes. Such impairments are not readily identified by standard clinical methods of cardiovascular testing such as coronary angiography and noninvasive single photon emission tomography (SPECT) myocardial perfusion imaging (MPI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Diatom pyrenoids are encased in a protein shell that enables efficient CO2 fixation
Authors: Shimakawa, G.; Demulder, M.; Flori, S.; Kawamoto, A.; Tsuji, Y.; Nawaly, H.; Tanaka, A.; Tohda, R.; Ota, T.; Matsui, H.; Morishima, N.; Okubo, R.; Wietrzynski, W.; Lamm, L.; Righetto, R. D.; Uwizeye, C.; Gallet, B.; Jouneau, P.-H.; Gerle, C.; Kurisu, G.; Finazzi, G.; Engel, B. D.; Matsuda, Y.
Score: 51.0, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.25.564039
Pyrenoids are subcompartments of algal chloroplasts that concentrate Rubisco enzymes and their CO2 substrate, thereby increasing the efficiency of carbon fixation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular basis for positional memory and its reprogrammability in limb regeneration
Authors: Otsuki, L.; Plattner, S. A.; Taniguchi-Sugiura, Y.; Tanaka, E. M.
Score: 42.9, Published: 2023-10-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.27.564423
Upon limb amputation in salamanders, anterior and posterior connective tissue cells form distinct signalling centres that together fuel successful regeneration. The molecular properties that distinguish anterior and posterior cells prior to injury, which enable them to initiate different signalling centres after amputation, are not known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>The Moa the Merrier: Resolving When the Dinornithiformes Went Extinct
Authors: Foxon, F.
Score: 43.4, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.552261
The Moa (Aves: Dinornithiformes) are an extinct group of the ratite clade from New Zealand. The overkill hypothesis asserts that the first New Zealand settlers hunted the Moa to extinction by 1450 CE, whereas the staggered survival hypothesis allows for Moa survival until after Europeans began to arrive on New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Threat awareness and counter-terrorism preparedness of Dutch hospitals: a cross-sectional survey
Authors: Barten, D.; Janssen, M.; De Cauwer, H.; Keereweer, D.; Tan, E.; van Osch, F.; Mortelmans, L.
Score: 4.8, Published: 2023-10-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.14.23297038
BackgroundWorkplace violence, including violent extremism, is a growing concern in the healthcare environment. Furthermore, there has been a disproportionate rise in the rate of terrorist attacks on hospitals during the past two decades. Hospitals are vulnerable targets due to their easy accessibility and their high density of patients, staff and visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of Stroke Risk Following COVID-19 mRNA Bivalent Vaccines Among U.S. Adults Aged &amp;gt;=65 Years
Authors: Lu, Y.; Matuska, K.; Nadimpalli, G.; Ma, Y.; Duma, N.; Zhang, H.; Chiang, Y.; Lyu, H.; Chillarige, Y.; Forshee, R. A.; Anderson, S. A.
Score: 970.9, Published: 2023-10-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.10.23296624
In January 2023, the United States Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention noted a safety concern for ischemic stroke in adults [&amp;amp;ge;]65 years receiving the BNT162b2; WT/OMI BA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A systematic screen for co-option of transposable elements across the fungal kingdom
Authors: Oggenfuss, U.; Badet, T.; Croll, D.
Score: 38.9, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.563377
How novel protein functions are acquired is a central question in molecular biology. Key paths to novelty include gene duplications, recombination or horizontal acquisition. Transposable elements (TEs) are increasingly recognized as a major source of novel domain-encoding sequences. However, the impact of TE coding sequences on the evolution of the proteome remains understudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Microbiome-based risk prediction in incident heart failure: a community challenge
Authors: Erawijantari, P. P.; Kartal, E.; Linares-Blanco, J.; Laajala, T. D.; Feldman, L. E.; The FINRISK Microbiome DREAM Challenge and ML4Microbiome Communities, ; Carmona-Saez, P.; Shigdel, R.; Claesson, M. J.; Bertelsen, R. J.; Gomez-Cabrero, D.; Minot, S.; Albrecht, J.; Chung, V.; Inouye, M.; Jousilahti, P.; Schultz, J.-H.; Friederich, H.-C.; Knight, R.; Salomaa, V.; Niiranen, T.; Havulinna, A. S.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Prospective analysis of incident disease among individuals of diverse ancestries using genetic and conventional risk factors
Authors: Wang, W.; Eriksson, N.; McIntyre, M.; Bagur Quetglas, R.; Koelsch, B. L.; Hinds, D. A.; Aslibekyan, S.; Auton, A.; Holmes, M. V.; Shringarpure, S. S.
Score: 34.2, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.23297414
BackgroundHuman genetics provides opportunities for enhancing disease prediction through polygenic risk scores (PRS). MethodWe used a dataset from 23andMe (6.77M European, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Transcription factor stoichiometry, motif affinity and syntax regulate single-cell chromatin dynamics during fibroblast reprogramming to pluripotency
Authors: Nair, S.; Ameen, M.; Sundaram, L.; Pampari, A.; Schreiber, J.; Balsubramani, A.; Wang, Y. X.; Burns, D.; Blau, H. M.; Karakikes, I.; Wang, K. C.; Kundaje, A.
Score: 35.2, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.04.560808
Ectopic expression of OCT4, SOX2, KLF4 and MYC (OSKM) transforms differentiated cells into induced pluripotent stem cells. To refine our mechanistic understanding of reprogramming, especially during the early stages, we profiled chromatin accessibility and gene expression at single-cell resolution across a densely sampled time course of human fibroblast reprogramming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>A Deep Dive into Single-Cell RNA Sequencing Foundation Models
Authors: Boiarsky, R.; Singh, N. M.; Buendia, A.; Getz, G.; Sontag, D.
Score: 26.8, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563100
Large-scale foundation models, which are pre-trained on massive, unlabeled datasets and subsequently fine-tuned on specific tasks, have recently achieved unparalleled success on a wide array of applications, including in healthcare and biology. In this paper, we explore two foundation models recently developed for single-cell RNA sequencing data, scBERT and scGPT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of the updated COVID-19 mRNA Autumn 2023 vaccines in Germany
Authors: Joshi, K.; Scholz, S.; Maschio, M.; Kohli, M.; Lee, A.; Fust, K.; Ultsch, B.; van de Velde, N.; Beck, E.
Score: 38.8, Published: 2023-10-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.09.23296505
ObjectivesTo assess the potential clinical impact and cost-effectiveness of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mRNA vaccines updated for Autumn 2023 in adults aged [&amp;amp;ge;]60 years and high-risk persons aged 30-59 years in Germany over a 1-year analytic time horizon (September 2023--August 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>DiabetIA: Building Machine Learning Models for Type 2 Diabetes Complications
Authors: Tripp, J.; Santana-Quinteros, D.; Perez-Estrada, R.; Rodriguez-Moran, M. F.; Arcos-Gonzalez, C.; Mercado-Rios, J.; Cristobal-Perez, F.; Hernandez-Martinez, B. R.; Nava-Aguilar, M. A.; Gonzalez-Arroyo, G.; Salazar-Fernandez, E. P.; Quiroz-Armada, P. S.; Cortes-Vieyra, R.; Noriega-Cisneros, R.; Zinzun-Ixta, G.; Maldonado-Pichardo, M. C.; Flores-Alvarez, L. J.; Reyes-Granados, S. C.; Chagolla-Morales, R.; Paredes-Saralegui, J. G.; Flores-Garrido, M.; Garcia-Velazquez, L. M.; Figueroa-Mora, K. M.; Gomez-Garcia, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>Factors Influencing the Trajectory of COVID-19 Evolution: A Longitudinal Study of 12 Asian Countries
Authors: He, X.; Liu, H.; Zeng, F.; Gao, W.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.23297319
BackgroundThe effectiveness of different strategies in addressing the COVID-19 pandemic has been assessed, but there is still not enough evidence in Asian countries. This study aims to examine the factors influencing the trajectory of COVID-19 evolution in Asia, to provide insights for optimizing public health policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>The influence of skin pigmentation on pulse oximetry readings: a protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Ahmed, S.; Afrin, S.; Hasan, S. M.; Sarker, S. S.; Azrin, F.; Jahan, E.; Rahman, A. E.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-10-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.18.23297133
BackgroundPulse oximeters are widely used crucial devices to triage and monitor sign of diseases and make informed decisions on patients health. Various studies have found a bias in pulse oximetry readings based on skin pigmentation/ ethnicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Effects of COVID-19 mRNA vaccination on HIV viremia and reservoir size
Authors: Duncan, M. C.; Omondi, F. H.; Kinloch, N. N.; Lapointe, H. R.; Speckmaier, S.; Moran Garcia, N.; Lawson, T.; DeMarco, M. L.; Simons, J.; Holmes, D. T.; Lowe, C. F.; Bacani, N.; Sereda, P.; Barrios, R.; Harris, M.; Romney, M. G.; Montaner, J. S. G.; Brumme, C. J.; Brockman, M. A.; Brumme, Z. L.
Score: 14.9, Published: 2023-10-09 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Heterotypic responses against nsp12/nsp13 from prior SARS-CoV-2 infection associates with lower subsequent endemic coronavirus incidence
Authors: Bean, D. J.; Monroe, J.; Liang, Y. M.; Borberg, E.; Senussi, Y.; Swank, Z.; Chalise, S.; Walt, D.; Weinberg, J.; Sagar, M.
Score: 143.7, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563621
Immune responses from prior SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19 vaccination do not prevent re-infections and may not protect against future novel coronaviruses (CoVs). We examined the incidence of and immune differences against human endemic CoVs (eCoV) as a proxy for response against future emerging CoVs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Plasma-based antigen persistence in the post-acute phase of SARS-CoV-2 infection
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Swank, Z. N.; Goldberg, S. A.; Lu, S.; Dalhuisen, T.; Borberg, E.; Senussi, Y.; Luna, M. A.; Chang Song, C.; Clark, A.; Zamora, A.; Lew, M.; Viswanathan, B.; Huang, B.; Anglin, K.; Hoh, R.; Hsue, P. Y.; Durstenfeld, M. S.; Spinelli, M. A.; Glidden, D. V.; Henrich, T. J.; Kelly, J. D.; Deeks, S. G.; Walt, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Virological characteristics of the SARS-CoV-2 Omicron EG.5.1 variant
Authors: Tsujino, S.; Deguchi, S.; Nomai, T.; Padilla-Blanco, M.; Plianchaisuk, A.; Wang, L.; Begum, M. M.; Uriu, K.; Mizuma, K.; Nao, N.; Kojima, I.; Tsubo, T.; Li, J.; Matsumura, Y.; Nagao, M.; Oda, Y.; Tsuda, M.; Anraku, Y.; Kita, S.; Yajima, H.; Tabata, K.; Guo, Z.; Hinay, A. A.; Yoshimatsu, K.; Yamamoto, Y.; Nagamoto, Y.; Asakura, H.; Nagashima, M.; Sadamasu, K.; Yoshimura, K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-locus CRISPRi targeting with a single truncated guide RNA
Authors: Moore, M. M.; Wekhande, S.; Issner, R.; Collins, A.; Liu, Y.; Javed, N.; Buenrostro, J. D.; Epstein, C. B.; Mattei, E.; Doench, J. G.; Bernstein, B. E.; Shoresh, N.; Najm, F. J.
Score: 18.9, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.563306
A critical goal in functional genomics is evaluating which non-coding elements contribute to gene expression, cellular function, and disease. Functional characterization remains a challenge due to the abundance and complexity of candidate elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Peripheral Transcriptomics in Acute and Long-Term Kidney Dysfunction in SARS-CoV2 Infection
Authors: Jayaraman, P.; Rajagopal, M.; Paranjpe, I.; Liharska, L.; Suarez-Farinas, M.; Thompson, R.; Del Valle, D. M.; Beckmann, N.; Oh, W.; Gulamali, F. F.; Kauffman, J.; Gonzalez-Kozlova, E.; Dellepiane, S.; Vasquez-Rios, G.; Vaid, A.; Jiang, J.; Chen, A.; Sakhuja, A.; Chen, S.; Kenigsberg, E.; He, J. C.; Coca, S. G.; Chan, L.; Schadt, E.; Merad, M.; Kim-Schulze, S.; Gnjatic, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Pathways linking pulse pressure to dementia in adults with Down syndrome
Authors: Rizvi, B.; Lao, P. J.; Sathishkumar, M.; Taylor, L.; Queder, N.; McMillan, L.; Edwards, N.; Keator, D. B.; Doran, E.; Hom, C.; Nguyen, D.; Rosas, H. D.; Lai, F.; Schupf, N.; Guiterrez, J.; Silverman, W.; Lott, I. T.; Mapstone, M.; Wilcock, D. M.; Head, E.; Yassa, M. A.; Brickman, A. M.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.23297625</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuroinflammation in post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) as assessed by PBR28 PET correlates with vascular disease measures
Authors: VanElzakker, M. B.; Bues, H. F.; Brusaferri, L.; Kim, M.; Saadi, D.; Ratai, E.-M.; Dougherty, D. D.; Loggia, M. L.
Score: 1039.2, Published: 2023-10-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563117
The COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 has triggered a consequential public health crisis of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC), sometimes referred to as long COVID. The mechanisms of the heterogeneous persistent symptoms and signs that comprise PASC are under investigation, and several studies have pointed to the central nervous and vascular systems as being potential sites of dysfunction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Edematous Type of Malnutrition Takes Longer Recovery Time Compared to Severe Wasting (Marasmus): Findings on 6-59 months old children treated for Severe Acute Malnutrition After the War in Northern Ethiopia, 2023: Prospective Longitudinal Study
Authors: Abay, M.; Tesfay, W.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.23297307
BackgroundSevere acute malnutrition (SAM) is still having public health significance by attributing almost fifty percent of the estimated ten to eleven million deaths encountered in less than five-years old children, imposing nine-fold likelihood of death compared with well-nourished children of similar age group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Disruption of maternal IgA by prenatal antibiotics precedes intestinal E. coli colonization and late-onset sepsis in neonates
Authors: McDonald, K.; Browning, D.; Greenfield, K.; Lin, K.; Meier, J.; Butoryak, M.; Sasaki, A.; Hand, T.; Megli, C.; Knoop, K.
Score: 16.4, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.04.23295031
Neonates, most notably prematurely born neonates, are particularly vulnerable to enteric pathogens. It is recommended that all pregnant patients receive antibiotics following Preterm Premature Rupture of Membranes (PPROM) to prolong pregnancy, yet not all antibiotic regimens have been studied for efficacy, especially when considering neonatal outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Light exposure during sleep is associated with irregular sleep timing: the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis (MESA)
Authors: Wallace, D. A.; Qiu, X.; Schwartz, J.; Scheer, F. A.; Redline, S.; Sofer, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.11.23296889
ObjectiveExposure to light at night (LAN) may influence sleep timing and regularity. Here, we test whether greater light exposure during sleep (LEDS) associates with greater irregularity in sleep onset timing in a large cohort of older adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Low Booster uptake in cancer patients despite health benefits
Authors: Figueiredo, J. C.; Levy, J. A.; Choi, S. Y.; Xu, A. M.; Merin, N. M.; Hamid, O.; Lemos, T.; Nguyen, N.; Nadri, M.; Gonzalez, A.; Mahov, S.; Darrah, J. M.; Gong, J.; Paquette, R. L.; Mita, A. C.; Vescio, R. A.; Salvy, S. J.; Mehmi, I.; Hendifar, A. E.; Natale, R. B.; Tourtellotte, W. G.; Ramanujan, V. K.; Huynh, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Isotopia: a stable isotope database for Classical Antiquity
Authors: Formichella, G.; Soncin, S.; Lubritto, C.; Tafuri, M. A.; Fernandes, R.; Cocozza, C.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-10-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.19.563074
We present Isotopia, an open-access database compiling over 36,000 stable isotope measurements ({delta}13C, {delta}15N, {delta}18O, {delta}34S, 87Sr/86Sr, 206Pb/204Pb, 207Pb/204Pb, 208Pb/204Pb, 207Pb/206Pb, and 208Pb/206Pb) on human, animal, and plant bioarchaeological remains dating to Classical Antiquity (approximately 800 BCE - 500 CE). These were recovered from different European regions, particularly from the Mediterranean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Platelet proteo-transcriptomic profiling validates mediators of thrombosis and proteostasis in patients with myeloproliferative neoplasms
Authors: Kelliher, S.; Gamba, S.; Weiss, L.; Shen, Z.; Marchetti, M.; Schieppati, F.; Scaife, C.; Madden, S.; Bennett, K.; Fortune, A.; Maung, S.; Fay, M.; Ni Ainle, F.; Maguire, P.; Falanga, A.; Kevane, B.; Krishnan, A.
Score: 3.7, Published: 2023-10-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563619
Patients with chronic Myeloproliferative Neoplasms (MPN) including polycythemia vera (PV) and essential thrombocythemia (ET) exhibit unique clinical features, such as a tendency toward thrombosis and hemorrhage, and risk of disease progression to secondary bone marrow fibrosis and/or acute leukemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Safety of Monovalent BNT162b2 (Pfizer-BioNTech), mRNA-1273 (Moderna), and NVX-CoV2373 (Novavax) COVID-19 Vaccines in US Children Aged 6 months to 17 years
Authors: Lloyd, P. C.; Hu, M.; Shoaibi, A.; Feng, Y.; Wong, H. L.; Smith, E. R.; Amend, K. L.; Kline, A.; Beachler, D. C.; Gruber, J. F.; Mitra, M.; Seeger, J. D.; Harris, C.; Secora, A.; Obidi, J.; Wang, J.; Song, J.; McMahill-Walraven, C. N.; Reich, C.; McEvoy, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Discovery of Ancestry-Specific Variants Associated with Clopidogrel Response among Caribbean Hispanics.
Authors: Yang, G.; Gonzalez, P.; Monero, M.; Carrasquillo, K.; Renta, J. Y.; Hernandez-Suarez, D. F.; Botton, M. R.; Melin, K.; Scott, S.; Ruano, G.; Roche-Lima, A.; Alarcon, C.; Ritchie, M.; Perara, M.; Duconge, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.29.23296372
BackgroundHigh on-treatment platelet reactivity (HTPR) with clopidogrel is predictive of ischemic events in adults with coronary artery disease. Despite strong data suggesting HTPR varies with ethnicity, including clinical and genetic variables, no genome-wide association study (GWAS) of clopidogrel response has been performed among Caribbean Hispanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Targeting cancer with small molecule pan-KRAS degraders
Authors: Popow, J.; Farnaby, W.; Gollner, A.; Kofink, C.; Fischer, G.; Wurm, M.; Zollman, D.; Wijaya, A.; Mischerikow, N.; Hasenoehrl, C.; Prokofeva, P.; Arnhof, H.; Arce-Solano, S.; Bell, S.; Boeck, G.; Diers, E.; Frost, A. B.; Goodwin-Tindall, J.; Karolyi-Oezguer, J.; Khan, S.; Klawatsch, T.; Koegl, M.; Kousek, R.; Kratochvil, B.; Kropatsch, K.; Lauber, A. A.; McLennan, R.; Olt, S.; Peter, D.; Petermann, O.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Intrinsic properties of spinal motoneurons degrade ankle torque control in humans
Authors: Beauchamp, J. A.; Pearcey, G. E. P.; Khurram, O. U.; Negro, F.; Dewald, J. P. A.; Heckman, C.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-10-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.23.563670
Motoneurons are the final common pathway for all motor commands and possess intrinsic electrical properties that must be tuned to control muscle across the full range of motor behaviors. Neuromodulatory input from the brainstem is likely essential for adapting motoneuron properties to match this diversity of motor tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Single nuclei sequencing reveals C4 photosynthesis is based on rewiring of ancestral cell identity networks
Authors: Swift, J.; Luginbuehl, L. H.; Schreier, T.; Donald, R. M.; Lee, T.; Nery, J.; Ecker, J. R.; Hibberd, J. M.
Score: 43.7, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.562893
In multicellular systems changes to the patterning of gene expression drive modifications in cell function and trait evolution. One striking example is found in more than sixty plant lineages where compartmentation of photosynthesis between cell types allowed evolution of the efficient C4 pathway from the ancestral C3 state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Sex differences in ADHD diagnosis and clinical care: A national study of population healthcare records in Wales
Authors: Martin, J.; Langley, K.; Cooper, M.; Rouquette, O. Y.; John, A.; Sayal, K.; Ford, T.; Thapar, A.
Score: 11.8, Published: 2023-10-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.20.23297324
BackgroundPopulation-based studies have observed sex biases in the diagnosis and treatment of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD). Females are less likely to be diagnosed or prescribed ADHD medication. This study uses national healthcare records, to investigate sex differences in diagnosis and clinical care in young people with ADHD, particularly regarding recognition and treatment of other mental health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Reduced risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection among household contacts with recent vaccination and past COVID-19 infection: results from two multi-site case-ascertained household transmission studies
Authors: Rolfes, M. A.; Talbot, H. K.; Morrissey, K. G.; Stockwell, M. S.; Maldonado, Y.; McLean, H. Q.; Lutrick, K.; Bowman, N. M.; Rao, S.; Izurieta, H. S.; Zhu, Y.; Chappell, J.; Battan-Wraith, S.; Merrill, L. S.; McLaren, S. H.; Sano, E.; Biddle, J. E.; Johnson, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Parental education and income are linked to offspring cortical brain structure and psychopathology at 9-11 years
Authors: Norbom, L. B.; Rokicki, J.; Eilertsen, E. M.; Wiker, T.; Hanson, J.; Dahl, A.; Alnaes, D.; Fernandez-Cabello, S.; Beck, D.; Agartz, I.; Andreassen, O. A.; Westlye, L. T.; Tamnes, C. K.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.02.16.23286027
BackgroundA childs socioeconomic environment can shape central aspects of their life, including vulnerability to mental disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Performance of next-generation molecular methods in the diagnosis of pleural space infections and their aetiology
Authors: Bell, P. T.; Baird, T.; Goddard, J.; Olagoke, O. S.; Burke, A.; Subedi, S.; Davey, T. R.; Anderson, J.; Sarovich, D. S.; Price, E. P.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-10-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.23297281
Pleural space infections (PSIs) are common and associated with substantial healthcare cost, morbidity, and mortality. Accurate PSI diagnosis remains challenging due to low culture positivity rates, frequent polymicrobial involvement, and non-specific diagnostic biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Women&amp;#39;s representation in Indian academia and conferences
Authors: Muralidhar, S.; Ananthanarayanan, V.
Score: 17.7, Published: 2023-10-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.26.564078
Indian science academia has a dearth of women researchers at all levels. Not only are they under-represented, but they are also under-highlighted, under-mentored and overlooked for awards, grants and other career-advancing steps. To effectively address this problem and devise a solution for the inequity, we need data on the proportion of women faculty across multiple STEM institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Tuning and minimizing lipidome composition in Mycoplasma mycoides and the Minimal Cell JCVI-Syn3A
Authors: Justice, I. G.; Saenz, J. P.
Score: 28.4, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.24.563757
All cells are encapsulated by a lipid membrane which facilitates the interaction between life and its environment. The property and function of the cell membrane is critically dependent on its lipidome composition which can range from 10s to 100s of unique lipid structures. How life has evolved to exploit such diverse mixtures of lipids has been experimentally challenging to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>DrugMap: A quantitative pan-cancer analysis of cysteine ligandability
Authors: Takahashi, M.; Chong, H. B.; Zhang, S.; Lazarov, M.; Harry, S.; Maynard, M.; White, R.; Hilbert, B.; Gohar, M.; Ge, M.; Zhang, J.; Durr, B. R.; Kryukov, G.; Tsou, C.-C.; Brooijmans, N.; Alghali, A.; Rubio, K.; Vilanueva, A.; Harrison, D.; Koglin, A.-S.; Ojeda, S.; Karakyriakou, B.; Healy, A.; Assaad, J.; Makram, F.; Rachimin, I.; Khandelwal, N.; Tien, P.-C.; Popoola, G.; Chen, N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Disturbed sleep is associated with worse patient-reported outcomes and chronic lung allograft dysfunction after lung transplantation
Authors: Singer, J. P.; Prather, A. A.; Betancourt, L.; Kordahl, R. C.; Sriram, A.; Huang, C.-Y.; Hays, S. R.; Kukreja, J.; Calabrese, D. R.; Venado, A.; Greenland, J. R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-10-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.12.23296973
BackgroundMany lung transplant recipients fail to derive substantial improvements in functioning, health-related quality of life (HRQL), or long-term survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Ticks without borders: Microbial communities of immature Neotropical tick species parasitizing migratory landbirds along northern Gulf of Mexico
Authors: Karim, S.; Zenzal, T. J.; Beati, L.; Sen, R.; Adegoke, A.; Kumar, D.; Downs, L.; Keko, M.; Nussbaum, A.; Becker, D.; Moore, F.
Score: 5.6, Published: 2023-10-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.10.22.563347
The long-distance, seasonal migrations of birds make them an effective ecological bridge for the movement of ticks. The introduction of exotic tick species to new geographical regions can lead to the emergence of novel tick-borne pathogens or the re-emergence of previously eradicated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
