<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Polymerized type I collagen down-regulates STAT-1 phosphorylation through engagement to LAIR-1 in M1-macrophages avoiding long COVID
Authors: Olivares Martinez, E.; Hernandez-Ramirez, D. F.; Nunez-Alvarez, C. A.; Chapa-Ibarguengoitia, M.; Mendez-Flores, S.; Priego-Ranero, A.; Azamar-Llamas, D.; Olvera-Prado, H.; Rivas-Redonda, K. I.; Ochoa-Hein, E.; Lopez-Mosqueda, L. G.; Rojas-Castaneda, E.; Urbina-Teran, S.; Septien-Stute, L.; Hernandez-Gilsoul, T.; Aguilar-Leon, D.; Torres-Villalobos, G.; Furuzawa-Carballeda, J.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-07-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292108
BackgroundThe polymerized type I collagen (PTIC) is a {gamma}-irradiated mixture of pepsinized porcine type I collagen and polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A densely sampled and richly annotated acoustic dataset from a wild bird population
Authors: Merino Recalde, N.; Estandia, A.; Pichot, L.; Vansse, A.; Cole, E. F.; Sheldon, B. C.
Score: 49.6, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.547484
We present a high-resolution, densely-sampled dataset of wild bird songs collected over multiple years from a single population of Great Tits (Parus major) in the UK. The dataset includes over 1,100,000 individual acoustic units from 109,963 richly annotated songs, sung by more than 400 individual birds, and provides unprecedented detail on the vocal behaviour of wild birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Bifunctional small molecules that induce nuclearlocalization and targeted transcriptional regulation
Authors: Gibson, W. J.; Sadagopan, A.; Shoba, V. M.; Choudhary, A.; Meyerson, M. L.; Schreiber, S. L.
Score: 33.8, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.07.548101
The aberrant localization of proteins in cells is a key factor in the development of various diseases, including cancer and neurodegenerative disease. To better understand and potentially manipulate protein localization for therapeutic purposes, we engineered bifunctional compounds that bind to proteins in separate cellular compartments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Direct 3D-bioprinting of hiPSC-derived cardiomyocytes to generate functional cardiac tissues
Authors: Esser, T. U.; Anspach, A.; Muenzebrock, K. A.; Kah, D.; Schruefer, S.; Schenk, J.; Heinze, K. G.; Schubert, D. W.; Fabry, B.; Engel, F. B.
Score: 78.6, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.12.544557
3D-bioprinting is a promising technology to produce human tissues as drug screening tool or for organ repair. However, direct printing of living cells has proven difficult. Here, we present a method to directly 3D-bioprint human induced pluripotent stem cell (hiPSC)-derived cardiomyocytes embedded in a collagen-hyaluronic acid ink generating centimeter-sized functional ring- and ventricle-shaped cardiac tissues in an accurate and reproducible manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>ColabDock: inverting AlphaFold structure prediction model for protein-protein docking with experimental restraints
Authors: Feng, S.; Chen, Z.; Zhang, C.; Xie, Y.; Ovchinnikov, S.; Gao, Y. Q.; Liu, S.
Score: 46.6, Published: 2023-07-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.04.547599
Prediction of protein complex structures and interfaces potentially has wide applications and can benefit the study of biological mechanisms involving protein-protein interactions. However, the surface prediction accuracy of traditional docking methods and AlphaFold-Multimer is limited. Here we present ColabDock, a framework that makes use of ColabDesign, but reimplements it for the purpose of restrained complex conformation prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Imaging proteins sensitive to direct fusions using transient peptide-peptide interactions
Authors: Gidden, Z.; Oi, C.; Johnston, E.; Bhaskar, H.; Rosser, S.; Mochrie, S. G. J.; Horrocks, M. H.; Regan, L.
Score: 30.2, Published: 2023-07-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.547312
Fluorescence microscopy enables specific visualization of proteins in living cells and has played an important role in our understanding of protein subcellular location and function. Some proteins, however, show altered localization and/or function when labeled using direct fusions to fluorescent proteins, making them difficult to study in live cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Small extracellular vesicles promote stiffness-mediated metastasis
Authors: Sneider, A.; Liu, Y.; Starich, B.; Du, W.; Marar, C.; Faqih, N.; Ciotti, G. E.; Kim, J. H.; Krishnan, S.; Ibrahim, S.; Igboko, M.; Locke, A.; Lewis, D. M.; Hong, H.; Karl, M.; Vij, R.; Russo, G. C.; Nair, P. R.; Gomez-de-Mariscal, E.; Habibi, M.; Munoz-Barrutia, A.; Gu, L.; Eisinger-Mathason, T. S. K.; Wirtz, D.
Score: 28.2, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.545937
Tissue stiffness is a critical prognostic factor in breast cancer and is associated with metastatic progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Self-extinguishing relay waves enable homeostaticcontrol of human neutrophil swarming
Authors: Strickland, J.; Pan, D.; Godfrey, C.; Kim, J. S.; Hopke, A.; Degrange, M.; Villavicencio, B.; Mansour, M. K.; Zerbe, C. S.; Irimia, D.; Amir, A.; Weiner, O. D.
Score: 563.8, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546744
Neutrophils exhibit self-amplified swarming to sites of injury and infection. How swarming is controlled to ensure the proper level of neutrophil recruitment is unknown. Using an ex vivo model of infection, we find that human neutrophils use active relay to generate multiple pulsatile waves of swarming signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Nitrate reduction capacity of the oral microbiota is impaired in periodontitis: potential implications for systemic nitric oxide availability
Authors: Rosier, B. T.; Johnston, W.; Carda-Dieguez, M.; Simpson, A.; Cabello-Yeves, E.; Piela, K.; Reilly, R.; Artacho, A.; Easton, C.; Burleigh, M.; Culshaw, S.; Mira, A.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.21.23291703
BackgroundThe reduction of nitrate to nitrite by the oral microbiota has been proposed to be important for oral health and results in nitric oxide formation that can improve cardiometabolic conditions, such as hypertension and diabetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Transgene-Free Ex Utero Derivation of A Human Post-Implantation Embryo Model Solely from Genetically Unmodified Naive PSCs
Authors: Oldak, B.; Wildschutz, E.; Bondarenko, V.; Aguilera-Castrejon, A.; Zhao, C.; Tarazi, S.; Comar, M.-Y.; Ashouokhi, S.; Lokshtanov, D.; Roncato, F.; Viukov, S.; Ariel, E.; Rose, M.; Livnat, N.; Shani, T.; Joubran, C.; Cohen, R.; Addadi, Y.; Kedmi, M.; Keren-Shaul, H.; Petropoulos, S.; Lanner, F.; Novershtern, N.; Hanna, J. H.
Score: 1271.3, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Statistical prediction of microbial metabolic traits from genomes
Authors: Li, Z.; Selim, A.; Kuehn, S.
Score: 32.8, Published: 2023-07-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.547261
The metabolic activity of microbial communities is central to their role in biogeochemical cycles, human health, and biotechnology. Despite the abundance of sequencing data characterizing these consortia, it remains a serious challenge to predict microbial metabolic traits from sequencing data alone. Here we culture 96 bacterial isolates individually and assay their ability to grow on 10 distinct compounds as a sole carbon source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage substantially decrease the incidence of electric scooter injuries
Authors: Pakarinen, O.; Kobylin, A.; Harjola, V.-P.; Castren, M.; Vasara, H.
Score: 48.6, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291641
ObjectiveTo investigate the effectiveness of restrictions on top speed and nighttime usage on the incidence of e-scooter-related injuries. DesignA retrospective comparative study. We compared shared e-scooter injuries from two periods: Unrestricted period (1.1-31.8.2021), and Restricted period (1.1.-31.8.2022). SettingGeneral population of Helsinki, Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Comparing the risks of new-onset gastric cancer or gastric diseases in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients exposed to SGLT2I, DPP4I or GLP1A: a population-based cohort study
Authors: Chou, O. H. I.; Chauhan, V. K.; Chung, C. T.; Lu, L.; Lee, T. T. L.; Ng, Z. M. W.; Wang, K. K.; Lee, S.; Liu, H.; Wong, W. T.; Pang, R. T. K.; Kaewdech, A.; Cheung, B. M. Y.; Tse, G.; Zhou, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Design and Analysis Heterogeneity in Observational Studies of COVID-19 Booster Effectiveness: A Review and Case Study
Authors: Meah, S.; Shi, X.; Fritsche, L. G.; Salvatore, M.; Wagner, A.; Martin, E. T.; Mukherjee, B.
Score: 66.1, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.22.23291692
BackgroundObservational vaccine effectiveness (VE) studies based on real-world data are a crucial supplement to initial randomized clinical trials of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccines. However, there exists substantial heterogeneity in study designs and statistical methods for estimating VE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>A Neanderthal/Denisovan GLI3 variant contributes to anatomical variations in mice
Authors: Agata, A.; Ohtsuka, S.; Noji, R.; Gotoh, H.; Ono, K.; Nomura, T.
Score: 51.6, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.547394
Changes in genomic structures underlie phenotypic diversification in organisms. Amino acid-changing mutations affect pleiotropic functions of proteins, although little is known about how mutated proteins are adapted in existing developmental programs. Here we investigate the biological effects of a variant of the GLI3 transcription factor (GLI3R1537C) carried in Neanderthals and Denisovans, which are extinct hominins close to modern humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive profiling of the human intestinal DNA virome and prediction of disease-associated bacterial hosts in severe Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS)
Authors: Hsieh, S.-Y.; Savva, G. M.; Telatin, A.; Tiwari, S. K.; Tariq, M. A.; Newberry, F.; Seton, K. A.; Booth, C.; Bansal, A. S.; Wileman, T.; Andriaenssens, E.; Carding, S. R.
Score: 21.0, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.23291738
Myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) is a disabling disorder of unknown etiology with severely affected patients being house- and/or bedbound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Association Study of Long COVID
Authors: Lammi, V.; Nakanishi, T.; Jones, S. E.; Andrews, S. J.; Karjalainen, J.; Cortes, B.; O&amp;#39;Brien, H. E.; Fulton-Howard, B. E.; Haapaniemi, H. H.; Schmidt, A.; Mitchell, R. E.; Mousas, A.; Mangino, M.; Huerta-Chagoya, A.; Sinnott-Armstrong, N.; Cirulli, E. T.; Vaudel, M.; Kwong, A. S.; Maiti, A. K.; Marttila, M. M.; Batini, C.; Minnai, F.; Dearman, A. R.; Warmerdam, C. R.; Sequeros, C. B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Polygenic risk score prediction accuracy convergence
Authors: Henches, L.; Kim, J.; Yang, Z.; Rubinacci, S.; Pires, G.; Albinana, C.; Boetto, C.; Julienne, H.; Frouin, A.; Auvergne, A.; Suzuki, Y.; Djebali, S.; Delaneau, O.; Ganna, A.; Vilhjalmsson, B.; Prive, F.; Aschard, H.
Score: 33.2, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.546518
Polygenic risk scores (PRS) trained from genome-wide association study (GWAS) results are set to play a pivotal role in biomedical research addressing multifactorial human diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Exhaustive identification of genome-wide binding events of transcriptional regulators with ICEBERG
Authors: Nordin, A.; Pagella, P.; Zambanini, G.; Cantu, C.
Score: 42.4, Published: 2023-07-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.29.547050
Genome-wide protein interaction assays aspire to map the complete binding pattern of gene regulators. How-ever, common practice relies on replication and high stringency statistics which favor false negatives over false positives, thereby excluding portions of signal which may represent biologically relevant events. Here, we present ICEBERG (Increased Capture of Enrichment By Exhaustive Replicate aGgregation), an experimental and analytical pipeline that harnesses large numbers of CUT&amp;amp;RUN replicates to discover the full set of binding events and chart the line between false positives and false negatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>Life after patent: Drug price dynamics and cost-effectiveness analysis
Authors: Serra-Burriel, M.; Martin-Bassols, N.; Perenyi, G.; Vokinger, K. N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-06-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.08.23290510
This study analyzed the effects of patent expiration on drug prices in eight countries (US, UK, Cana-da, Australia, Japan, France, Germany, and Switzerland) and the impact of these price dynamics in cost-effectiveness assessments. First, using an event study design, we showed that average prices of drugs substantially decreased eight years after patent expiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the hype: large language models propagate race-based medicine
Authors: Omiye, J. A.; Lester, J.; Spichak, S.; Rotemberg, V.; Daneshjou, R.
Score: 13.6, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292192
ImportanceLarge language models (LLMs) are being integrated into healthcare systems; but these models recapitulate harmful, race-based medicine. ObjectiveThe objective of this study is to assess whether four commercially available large language models (LLMs) propagate harmful, inaccurate, race-based content when responding to eight different scenarios that historically included race-based medicine or widespread misconceptions around race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The physical and mental health benefits of touch interventions: A comparative systematic review and multivariate meta-analysis
Authors: Packheiser, J.; Hartmann, H.; Fredriksen, K.; Gazzola, V.; Keysers, C.; Michon, F.
Score: 11.1, Published: 2023-06-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.23291651
IntroductionReceiving touch is of critical importance for human well-being. A large number of studies have shown that touch promotes mental and physical health. However, effect sizes differ considerably across studies and potential moderators of touch interventions remain unknown to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Driving uptake of missed routine vaccines in adolescent and adult migrants: a prospective observational mixed-methods pilot study of catch-up vaccination in UK general practice
Authors: Crawshaw, A. F.; Goldsmith, L. P.; Deal, A.; Carter, J.; Knights, F.; Seedat, F.; Lau, K.; Hayward, S. E.; Yong, J.; Fyle, D.; Aspray, N.; Iwami, M.; Ciftci, Y.; Wurie, F.; Majeed, A.; Forster, A. S.; Hargreaves, S.
Score: 6.3, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292165</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>IgG sialylation occurs via the FcRn-mediated recycling pathway in endothelial cells
Authors: Glendenning, L. M.; Reynero, K. M.; Kukan, E. N.; Long, M. D.; Cobb, B. A.
Score: 60.7, Published: 2023-07-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.547255
IgG is a key mediator of immune responses throughout the human body, and the structure of the conserved glycan on the Fc region has been identified as a key inflammatory switch regulating its downstream effects. In particular, the absence of terminal sialic acid has been shown to increase the affinity of IgG for activating Fc receptors, cascading the inflammatory response in a variety of diseases and conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 virologic rebound with nirmatrelvir-ritonavir therapy
Authors: Edelstein, G. E.; Boucau, J.; Uddin, R.; Marino, C.; Liew, M. Y.; Barry, M.; Choudhary, M. C.; Gilbert, R. F.; Reynolds, Z.; Li, Y.; Tien, D.; Sagar, S.; Vyas, T. D.; Kawano, Y.; Sparks, J. A.; Hammond, S. P.; Wallace, Z.; Vyas, J. M.; Barczak, A. K.; Lemieux, J. E.; Li, J. Z.; Siedner, M. J.
Score: 168.7, Published: 2023-06-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23288598</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 spike glycosylation affects function and neutralization sensitivity
Authors: Zhang, F.; Schmidt, F.; Muecksch, F.; Wang, Z.; Gazumyan, A.; Nussenzweig, M. C.; Gaebler, C.; Caskey, M.; Hatziioannou, T.; Bieniasz, P. D.
Score: 81.1, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.547241
The glycosylation of viral envelope proteins can play important roles in virus biology and immune evasion. The spike (S) glycoprotein of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) includes 22 N-linked glycosylation sequons and 17 O-linked glycosites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of AlphaFold Antibody-Antigen Modeling with Implications for Improving Predictive Accuracy
Authors: Yin, R.; Pierce, B. G.
Score: 27.0, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.547832
High resolution antibody-antigen structures provide critical insights into immune recognition and can inform therapeutic design. The challenges of experimental structural determination and the diversity of the immune repertoire underscore the necessity of accurate computational tools for modeling antibody-antigen complexes. Initial benchmarking showed that despite overall success in modeling protein-protein complexes, AlphaFold and AlphaFold-Multimer have limited success in modeling antibody-antigen interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Navigating the chaos of psychedelic neuroimaging: A multi-metric evaluation of acute psilocybin effects on brain entropy
Authors: McCulloch, D. E.-W.; Olsen, A. S.; Ozenne, B.; Stenbaek, D. S.; Armand, S.; Madsen, M. K.; Knudsen, G. M.; Fisher, P. M.
Score: 18.4, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.03.23292164
Investigations into the acute effects of psychedelics on brain imaging have emphasised increased brain entropy as a potential neural correlate. To date, 12 previous studies have reported brain entropy effects, each reporting a single and unique metric, none of which have been examined in an independent cohort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuronal wiring diagram of an adult brain
Authors: Dorkenwald, S.; Matsliah, A.; Sterling, A. R.; Schlegel, P.; Yu, S.-c.; McKellar, C. E.; Lin, A.; Costa, M.; Eichler, K.; Yin, Y.; Silversmith, W.; Schneider-Mizell, C.; Jordan, C. S.; Brittain, D.; Halageri, A.; Kuehner, K.; Ogedengbe, O.; Morey, R.; Gager, J.; Kruk, K.; Perlman, E.; Yang, R.; Deutsch, D.; Bland, D.; Sorek, M.; Lu, R.; Macrina, T.; Lee, K.; Bae, J. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Imprecision nutrition? Duplicate meals result in unreliable individual glycemic responses measured by continuous glucose monitors across three dietary patterns in adults without diabetes
Authors: Hengist, A.; Guo, J.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 145.3, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.14.23291406
BackgroundContinuous glucose monitors (CGMs) are being used to characterize postprandial glycemic responses and thereby provide personalized dietary advice to minimize glycemic excursions. However, the efficacy of such advice depends on reliable CGM responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>A continuous centennial Lateglacial-Early Holocene (15-10 cal kyr BP) palynological record from the Iberian Pyrenees and regional comparisons
Authors: Rull, V.; Blasco, A.; Calero, M. A.; Vegas-Vilarrubia, T.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.02.547433
This paper presents the first continuous (gap-free) Lateglacial-Early Holocene (LGEH) pollen record for the Iberian Pyrenees resolved at centennial resolution. The main aims are (i) to provide a standard chronostratigraphic correlation framework, (ii) to unravel the relationships between vegetation shifts, climatic changes and fire, and (iii) to obtain a regional picture of LGEH vegetation for the Pyrenees and the surrounding lowlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Extended correlation functions for spatial analysis of multiplex imaging data
Authors: Bull, J. A.; Mulholland, E. J.; Leedham, S. J.; Byrne, H. M.
Score: 9.1, Published: 2023-06-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.20.545678
Imaging platforms for generating highly multiplexed histological images are being continually developed and improved. Significant improvements have also been made in the accuracy of methods for automated cell segmentation and classification. However, less attention has focussed on the quantification and analysis of the resulting point clouds which describe the spatial coordinates of individual cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Maternal prenatal immune activation associated with brain tissue microstructure and metabolite concentrations in newborn infants
Authors: Spann, M.; Bansal, R.; Aydin, E.; Pollatou, A.; Alleyne, K.; Bennett, M.; Sawardekar, S.; Cheng, B.; Lee, S.; Monk, C.; Peterson, B.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.01.23292113
ImportanceFew translational human studies have assessed the association of prenatal maternal immune activation with altered brain development and psychiatric risk in newborn offspring. ObjectiveTo identify the effects of maternal immune activation during the 2nd and 3rd trimesters of pregnancy on newborn brain metabolite concentrations, tissue microstructure, and longitudinal motor development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Refining the impact of genetic evidence on clinical success
Authors: Minikel, E. V.; Painter, J. L.; Dong, C. C.; Nelson, M. R.
Score: 45.0, Published: 2023-06-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.23.23291765
The cost of drug discovery and development is driven primarily by failure, with just [~]10% of clinical programs eventually receiving approval. We previously estimated that human genetic evidence doubles the success rate from clinical development to approval. In this study we leverage the growth in genetic evidence over the past decade to better understand the characteristics that distinguish clinical success and failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Discovery of New Broad-Spectrum Anti-Infectives for Eukaryotic Pathogens Using Bioorganometallic Chemistry
Authors: Lin, Y.; Jung, H.; Bulman, C. A.; Ng, J.; Vinck, R.; O&amp;#39;Beirne, C.; Moser, M. S.; Tricoche, N.; Peguero, R.; Li, R. W.; Urban, J. F.; Le Pape, P.; Pagniez, F.; Moretto, M.; Weil, T.; Lustigman, S.; Cariou, K.; Mitreva, M.; Sakanari, J.; Gasser, G.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2023-06-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.546819
Drug resistance observed with many anti-infectives clearly highlights the need for new broad-spectrum agents to treat especially neglected tropical diseases (NTDs) caused by eukaryotic parasitic pathogens including fungal infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 10.4, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary Trajectory of Pattern Recognition Receptors in Plants
Authors: Ngou, B. P. M.; Wyler, M.; Schmid, M. W.; Kadota, Y.; Shirasu, K.
Score: 58.9, Published: 2023-07-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.04.547604
Plants perceive pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs) via pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) to activate PRR-triggered immunity (PTI). Despite extensive research on PTI in model plant species, the evolutionary trajectory and emergence of PRRs remain elusive. Here we conducted a comparative genomic analysis of cell-surface receptors and downstream signalling components among 350 plant species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Trial of Ketamine Masked by Surgical Anesthesia in Depressed Patients
Authors: Lii, T. R.; Smith, A. E.; Flohr, J. R.; Okada, R. L.; Nyongesa, C. A.; Cianfichi, L. J.; Hack, L. M.; Schatzberg, A. F.; Heifets, B. D.
Score: 402.8, Published: 2023-06-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.04.28.23289210
BACKGROUNDKetamine may have antidepressant properties, but its acute psychoactive effects complicate successful masking in placebo-controlled trials. METHODSIn a triple-masked, randomized, placebo-controlled trial, 40 adult patients with major depressive disorder were randomized to a single infusion of ketamine (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>mRNA-1273 vaccine effectiveness against symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19-related hospitalization in children aged 6 months to 5 years
Authors: Aglipay, M.; Maguire, J. L.; Swayze, S.; Tuite, A.; Mamdani, M.; Keown-Stoneman, C.; Birken, C. S.; Kwong, J. C.
Score: 89.5, Published: 2023-06-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.27.23291933
ImportanceData on mRNA-1273 (Moderna) vaccine effectiveness in children aged 6 months to 5 years are limited. ObjectiveTo assess mRNA-1273 vaccine effectiveness against symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and COVID-19-related hospitalization among children aged 6 months to 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>AI-based analysis of the shunt treatment in pre- and post-surgery computed tomography brain scans of iNPH patients
Authors: Shailja, S.; Nguyen, C.; Thanigaivelan, K.; Bhagavatula, V.; Chen, J. W.; Manjunath, B. S.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.28.23292008
BackgroundThis study examines whether quantifiable changes can be detected in ventricular volume in Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus (iNPH) patients that undergo ventriculo-peritoneal shunt procedures. There is no known metric that characterizes the change in ventricular volume for iNPH patients after shunt placement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alterations of the gut microbiome are associated with epigenetic age acceleration and physical fitness
Authors: Torma, F.; Kerepesi, C.; Jokai, M.; Bakonyi, P.; Koltai, E.; Babszki, G.; Ligeti, B.; Kalcsevszki, R.; McGreevy, K. M.; Horvath, S.; Radak, Z.
Score: 1.9, Published: 2023-07-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292191
Epigenetic clocks can measure aging and predict the incidence of diseases and mortality. Higher levels of physical fitness are associated with a slower aging process and a healthier lifespan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>xTrimoPGLM: Unified 100B-Scale Pre-trained Transformer for Deciphering the Language of Protein
Authors: Chen, B.; Cheng, X.; Gengyang, L.-a.; Li, S.; Zeng, X.; Wang, B.; Jing, G.; Liu, C.; Zeng, A.; Dong, Y.; Tang, J.; Song, L.
Score: 74.0, Published: 2023-07-06 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.547496
Protein language models have shown remarkable success in learning biological information from protein sequences. However, most existing models are limited by either autoencoding or autoregressive pre-training objectives, which makes them struggle to handle protein understanding and generation tasks concurrently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Robustness of biomolecular networks suggests functional modules far from the edge of chaos
Authors: Park, K. H.; Costa, F. X.; Rocha, L. M.; Albert, R.; Rozum, J. C.
Score: 8.1, Published: 2023-07-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.06.30.547297
A common feature of complex systems is their ability to balance the flexibility needed to adapt to their environment with the rigidity required for robust function. It has been conjectured that living systems accomplish this by existing at the &amp;#34;edge of chaos&amp;#34;, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
