<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in Hallucinogen-associated Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations in California from 2016-2021
Authors: Tate, S.; Garel, N.; Nash, K.; Lembke, A.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294275
ObjectivesHallucinogens encompass a diverse range of compounds with increasing scientific and public interest. Risks associated with hallucinogen use are poorly understood. This study aims to evaluate the trends in hallucinogen-related emergency department visits and hospitalizations in California from 2016 to 2021, as compared to alcohol and cannabis visits and hospitalizations MethodsWe conducted a descriptive study on publicly available data on diagnosis codes associated with emergency department (ED) visits and hospitalizations from the California Department of Healthcare Access and Information (HCAI) to describe hallucinogen, alcohol, and cannabis associated encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Immunometabolic effects of lactate on B cell function in healthy individuals of different ages
Authors: Romero, M.; Miller, K.; Gelsomini, A.; Garcia, D.; Li, K.; Suresh, D.; Frasca, D.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.07.23293760
Aging is characterized by chronic systemic inflammation and metabolic changes. When we compared B cells from young and elderly donors, we found that aging induces higher oxygen consumption rates, and especially higher extracellular acidification rates, measures of oxidative phosphorylation and of anaerobic glycolysis, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>anesthesia</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/anesthesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/anesthesia/</guid>
      <description>Optimal tracheal tube rotation patterns for navigating through the glottis: an in-silico quantification.
Authors: Schulz, E. B.; Carra Schulz, L. E.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294387
Seeking to unpack some of the anaesthetists&amp;#39; &amp;#34;knack&amp;#34; for intubation, this study examines the effect of various orientations of the tracheal tube on the anterior movement of the tube tip using a computerised 3D model of intubation. The model used sets of coordinates for the upper incisor tip, lower incisor tip and vallecula extracted from mean values reported in a study of 16 volunteers predicted to have easy laryngoscopy and 16 predicted to have difficult laryngoscopy during both gentle laryngoscopy and laryngoscopy under 50N of lifting force, yielding a total of four sets of airway geometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Seeking voluntary passive movement in flies is play-like behavior
Authors: Triphan, T.; Huetteroth, W.
Score: 117.1, Published: 2023-08-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.03.551880
Play-like behaviour (PLB) is pervasive across the animal kingdom, especially in vertebrate species. Invertebrate PLB has been sparsely addressed and those studies have been restricted to social or object interaction. Here, we examined individual PLB in the vinegar fly Drosophila melanogaster by providing voluntary access to a spinning platform - a carousel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Structure and design of Langya virus glycoprotein antigens
Authors: Wang, Z.; McCallum, M.; Yan, L.; Sharkey, W.; Park, Y.-J.; Dang, H. V.; Amaya, M.; Person, A.; Broder, C. C.; Veesler, D. J.
Score: 31.2, Published: 2023-08-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.20.554025
Langya virus (LayV) is a recently discovered henipavirus (HNV), isolated from febrile patients in China, harboring a genome distantly related to that of Nipah virus (NiV) and Hendra virus (HeV). HNV entry into host cells is mediated by the attachment (G) and fusion (F) glycoproteins which are the main targets of neutralizing antibodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>PRO-LDM: Protein Sequence Generation with Conditional Latent Diffusion Models
Authors: Jiang, Z.; Zhang, S.; Huang, R.; Mo, S.; Zhu, L.; Li, P.; Zhang, Z.; Chen, X.; Long, Y.; Xu, R.; Qing, R.
Score: 14.4, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554145
AbstractsProtein design with deep-learning based algorithms represents an emerging and highly promising field in molecular biology. Yet it remains a challenging task due to the complexity of protein sequences. Recent developments in deep generative models such as diffusion model have demonstrated impressive performance in protein structure design, yet left much to be desired in creating new sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Context-Dependent Design of Induced-fit Enzymes using Deep Learning Generates Well Expressed, Thermally Stable and Active Enzymes
Authors: Zimmerman, L.; Alon, N.; Levin, I.; Koganitsky, A.; Shpigel, N.; Brestel, C.; Lapidoth, G. D.
Score: 299.3, Published: 2023-08-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550799
The potential of engineered enzymes in practical applications is often constrained by limitations in their expression levels, thermal stability, and the diversity and magnitude of catalytic activities. De-novo enzyme design, though exciting, is challenged by the complex nature of enzymatic catalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Deep reconstructing generative networks for visualizing dynamic biomolecules inside cells
Authors: Rangan, R.; Khavnekar, S.; Lerer, A.; Johnston, J.; Kelley, R.; Obr, M.; Kotecha, A.; Zhong, E. D.
Score: 107.6, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553799
Advances in cryo-electron tomography (cryo-ET) have produced new opportunities to visualize the structures of dynamic macromolecular machinery in native cellular environments. Here, we describe a machine learning approach that can reconstruct the structural landscape and dynamics of biomolecular complexes present in cryo-ET subtomograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Progressive plasticity during colorectal cancer metastasis
Authors: Moorman, A.; Cambuli, F.; Benitez, E.; Jiang, Q.; Xie, Y.; Mahmoud, A.; Lumish, M.; Hartner, S.; Balkaran, S.; Bermeo, J.; Asawa, S.; Firat, C.; Saxena, A.; Luthra, A.; Sgambati, V.; Luckett, K.; Wu, F.; Li, Y.; Yi, Z.; Masilionis, I.; Soares, K.; Pappou, E.; Yaeger, R.; Kingham, P.; Jarnagin, W.; Paty, P.; Weiser, M. R.; Mazutis, L.; D&amp;#39;Angelica, M.; Shia, J.; Garcia-Aguilar, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Electrocardiogram and Photoplethysmogram-based Heart Rate Variability Are Not Equivalent: A Bayesian Simulation Analysis
Authors: Dewig, H.; Cohen, J. N.; Renaghan, E. J.; Leary, M. E.; Leary, B. K.; Au, J. S.; Tenan, M. S.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294449
Background: Heart rate variability (HRV) is a common measure of autonomic and cardiovascular system function assessed via electrocardiography (ECG). Consumer wearables, commonly employed in epidemiological research, use photoplethysmography (PPG) to report HRV metrics (PRV), although these may not be equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>BioE3 enables the identification of bona fide targets of E3 ligases
Authors: Barroso-Gomila, O.; Merino-Cacho, L.; Muratore, V.; Perez, C.; Taibi, V.; Maspero, E.; Azkargorta, M.; Iloro, I.; Trulsson, F.; Vertegaal, A. C. O.; Mayor, U.; Elortza, F.; Polo, S.; Barrio, R.; Sutherland, J. D.
Score: 59.3, Published: 2023-08-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553883
The post-translational modification of proteins by ubiquitination is a highly regulated process that involves a dynamic, three-step enzymatic cascade, where more than 600 E3 ligases play a critical role in recognizing specific substrates for modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics of chromatin accessibility during human first-trimester neurodevelopment
Authors: Mannens, C. C. A.; Hu, L.; Lonnerberg, P.; Schipper, M.; Reagor, C.; Li, X.; He, X.; Barker, R. A.; Sundstrom, E.; Posthuma, D.; Linnarsson, S.
Score: 26.9, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553878
The human brain is capable of highly complex functions that develops through a tightly organized cascade of patterning events, expressed transcription factors and changes in chromatin accessibility. While extensive datasets exist describing gene expression across the developing brain with single-cell resolution, similar atlases of chromatin accessibility have been primarily focused on the forebrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the landscape pool of ardeid species to landscape structure associated with Japanese encephalitis virus in Australia
Authors: Walsh, M.; Webb, C. E.; Brookes, V.
Score: 9.0, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553798
The geographic extent of Japanese encephalitis virus (JEV), a zoonotic, mosquito-borne virus, increased dramatically in south-eastern Australia over the summer of 2021-2022 resulting in outbreaks in piggeries, 45 cases of human disease, and simultaneous detection of JEV by mosquito and arbovirus surveillance programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Combination low dose sulphonylurea and DPP4 inhibitor have potent glucose effect through augmentation of beta cell function without increase in hypoglycaemia: a randomised crossover study.
Authors: Cordiner, R. L.; Bedair, K.; Mari, A.; Pearson, E. R.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294403
Aims/Hypothesis. it is important to address our use of cheaper generic therapies for type 2 diabetes (T2DM as the global prevalence of type 2 diabetes (T2DM) will surpass 600 million by 2035.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>High proportions of post-exertional malaise and orthostatic intolerance in people living with post-COVID-19 condition: the PRIME post-COVID study
Authors: Pagen, D. M.; Van Herck, M.; van Bilsen, C. J.; Brinkhues, S.; Konings, K.; den Heijer, C. D.; Spruit, M. A.; Hoebe, C. J.; Dukers-Muijrers, N. H.
Score: 258.7, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294204
BackgroundExercise-based treatments can be harmful in people who were SARS-CoV-2 positive and living with post-COVID-19 condition (PL-PCC) and who have post-exertional malaise (PEM) or orthostatic intolerance (OI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Evidence for ecological tuning of novel anuran biofluorescent signals
Authors: Whitcher, C.; Ron, S. R.; Ayala-Varela, F.; Crawford, A.; Herrera-Alva, V.; Castillo-Urbina, E.; Grazziotin, F.; Bowman, R. M.; Lemmon, A. R.; Moriarty Lemmon, E.
Score: 51.4, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.550432
Our study assesses the variability of amphibian biofluorescence and provides insight into its potential functions and role in anuran evolution. Via a field survey across South America, we discovered and documented patterns of biofluorescence in tropical amphibians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Development and Clinical Evaluation of AlcoChange: a Digital Therapeutic for Patients with Alcohol-Related Liver Disease
Authors: Mehta, G.; Lin, S.; PV, B.; Kumar, R.; Balaji, A.; Macdonald, S.; Sheikh, M.; Saeidinejad, M.; Sharma, S.-R.; King, J. J.; Mookerjee, R.; Mcdonagh, L.; Afuwape, S.; Moore, K.; Jalan, R.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293936
Background and aimsMaintenance of abstinence in alcohol-related liver disease (ARLD) is a major unmet therapeutic need. Digital therapeutics can deliver ongoing behavioural therapy, in real-time, for chronic conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Chromosome 20p11.2 deletions cause congenital hyperinsulinism via the likely disruption of FOXA2
Authors: Laver, T. W.; Wakeling, M. N.; Caswell, R. C.; Bunce, B.; Yau, D.; Houghton, J. A.; Hopkins, J. J.; Weedon, M. N.; Saraff, V.; Kershaw, M.; Honey, E.; Murphy, N.; Giri, D.; Nath, S.; Saredo, A. T.; Banerjee, I.; Hussain, K.; Owens, N. D.; Flanagan, S. E.
Score: 23.3, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23294161
Persistent congenital hyperinsulinism (HI) is a rare genetically heterogeneous condition characterised by dysregulated insulin secretion leading to life-threatening hypoglycaemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing In Vitro SMN Protein Expression and Cell Viability through Xeno-Nucleic Acid-Based ASOs in Spinal Muscular Atrophy
Authors: Kilic, O.; Babar, H. A.; Inci, C. C.; Odabas, S. P.; Yelgen, G.; Oltan, S.; Kulac, S.; Tastan, C.
Score: 6.9, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.552929
Spinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA) stands as a devastating ailment arising from the dearth of functional SMN (Survival Motor Neuron) protein due to genetic anomalies within the SMN1 gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Programmable multi-kilobase RNA editing using CRISPR-mediated trans-splicing
Authors: Borrajo, J.; Javanmardi, K.; Griffin, J.; St. Martin, S. J.; Yao, D.; Hill, K.; Blainey, P.; Al-Shayeb, B.
Score: 103.6, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.553620
Current gene editing approaches in eukaryotic cells are limited to single base edits or small DNA insertions and deletions, and remain encumbered by unintended permanent effects and significant challenges in the delivery of large DNA cargo. Here we describe Splice Editing, a generalizable platform to correct gene transcripts in situ by programmable insertion or replacement of large RNA segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>An Interpretable Longitudinal Preeclampsia Risk Prediction Using Machine Learning
Authors: Eberhard, B. W.; Cohen, R. Y.; Rigoni, J.; Bates, D.; Gray, K. J.; Kovacheva, V.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.16.23293946
BackgroundPreeclampsia is a pregnancy-specific disease characterized by new onset hypertension after 20 weeks of gestation that affects 2-8% of all pregnancies and contributes to up to 26% of maternal deaths. Despite extensive clinical research, current predictive tools fail to identify up to 66% of patients who will develop preeclampsia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>ACCORD (ACcurate COnsensus Reporting Document): A reporting guideline for consensus methods in biomedicine developed via a modified Delphi
Authors: Gattrell, W. T.; Logullo, P.; van Zuuren, E. J.; Price, A.; Hughes, E. L.; Blazey, P.; Winchester, C. C.; Tovey, D.; Goldman, K.; Hungin, A. P.; Harrison, N.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294261
Background: In biomedical research, it is often desirable to seek consensus among individuals who have differing perspectives and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Intraepithelial CD15 infiltration identifies high grade anal dysplasia in people with HIV
Authors: Burgos, J.; Mancebo, C.; Massana, N.; Astorga-Gamaza, A.; Castellvi, J.; Landolfi, S.; Curran, A.; Garcia-Perez, J. N.; Falco, V.; Buzon, M. J.; Genesca, M.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294199
Men who have sex with men (MSM) with HIV are at high risk for squamous intraepithelial lesion (SIL) and anal cancer. The identification of local immunological mechanisms involved in the development of anal dysplasia could aid treatment and diagnostics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>The tissue-resident regulatory T cell pool is shaped by transient multi-tissue migration and a conserved residency program
Authors: Burton, O.; Bricard, O.; Tareen, S.; Gergelits, V.; Andrews, S.; Roca, C. P.; Whyte, C.; Junius, S.; Brajic, A.; Pasciuto, E.; Ali, M.; Lemaitre, P.; Schlenner, S. M.; Ishigame, H.; Brown, B.; Dooley, J.; Liston, A.
Score: 89.4, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.553196
The tissues are the site of many of the most important immunological reactions, yet the immunology of the tissues has remained relatively opaque.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Assessing ChatGPT&amp;#39;s Mastery of Bloom&amp;#39;s Taxonomy using psychosomatic medicine exam questions
Authors: Herrmann Werner, A.; Festl-Wietek, T.; Holderried, F.; Herschbach, L.; Griewatz, J.; Masters, K.; Zipfel, S.; Mahling, M.
Score: 8.9, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.18.23294159
IntroductionLarge language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 are increasingly used in medicine and medical education. However, these models are prone to &amp;#34;hallucinations&amp;#34; - outputs that sound convincing while being factually incorrect. It is currently unknown how these errors by LLMs relate to the different cognitive levels defined in Blooms Taxonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 Neutralizing Antibodies Following a Second BA.5 Bivalent Booster
Authors: Wang, Q.; Bowen, A.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R.; Valdez, R.; Stoneman, E.; Gordon, A.; Lihong, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 355.5, Published: 2023-08-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.13.553148
Bivalent COVID-19 mRNA vaccines expressing both the ancestral D614G and Omicron BA.5 spike proteins were introduced in August 2022 with the goal of broadening immunity to emerging SARS-CoV-2 Omicron subvariants. Subsequent studies on bivalent boosters found neutralizing antibody responses similar to boosters with the original monovalent vaccine, likely the result of immunological imprinting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Molecular mechanism of dynein-dynactin activation by JIP3 and LIS1
Authors: Singh, K.; Lau, C.; Manigrasso, G.; Gama, J. B.; Gassmann, R.; Carter, A. P.
Score: 55.3, Published: 2023-08-19 DOI: 10.1101/2022.08.17.504273
Microtubule motors, like cytoplasmic dynein-1, are tightly regulated to prevent inappropriate activity in cells. Dynein functions as a [~]4 MDa complex containing its cofactor dynactin and a cargo-specific coiled-coil adaptor. However, how dynein and dynactin recognise diverse adaptors, how they interact with each other during complex formation, and the role of critical regulators such as LIS1 remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Use of the Selective Cytopheretic Device to Support Critically Ill Children Requiring Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy: A Probable Benefit-Risk Assessment
Authors: Goldstein, S. L.; Ollberding, N. J.; Askenazi, D. J.; Basu, R. K.; Selewski, D. T.; Krallman, K. A.; Yessayan, L.; Humes, H. D.
Score: 7.1, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294378
BackgroundCritically ill children with acute kidney injury (AKI) requiring continuous kidney replacement therapy (CRRT) are at increased risk of death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Transcobalamin Receptor Autoantibodies in Central Vitamin B12 Deficiency
Authors: Pluvinage, J. V.; Ngo, T.; Bartley, C. M.; Bodansky, A.; Alvarenga, B. D.; Zorn, K. C.; Fouassier, C.; Zamecnik, C.; McCann, A.; Huynh, T.; Browne, W.; Tubati, A.; Kondapavulur, S.; Anderson, M. S.; Green, A. J.; Green, R.; Douglas, V.; Louine, M.; Cree, B.; Hauser, S.; Seeley, W.; Holmes, B. B.; Wells, J. A.; Spudich, S.; Farhadian, S.; Ramachandran, P.; Gillum, L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A reproducible and generalizable software workflow for analysis of large-scale neuroimaging data collections using BIDS Apps
Authors: Zhao, C.; Jarecka, D.; Covitz, S.; Chen, Y.; Eickhoff, S. B.; Fair, D. A.; Franco, A. R.; Halchenko, Y. O.; Hendrickson, T. J.; Hoffstaedter, F.; Houghton, A.; Kiar, G.; Macdonald, A.; Mehta, K.; Milham, M. P.; Salo, T.; Hanke, M.; Ghosh, S. S.; Cieslak, M.; Satterthwaite, T. D.
Score: 33.7, Published: 2023-08-18 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Bioactive glycans in a microbiome-directed food for malnourished children
Authors: Hibberd, M. C.; Webber, D. M.; Rodionov, D. A.; Henrissat, S.; Chen, R. Y.; Zhou, C.; Lynn, H. M.; Wang, Y.; Chang, H.-W.; Lee, E. M.; Lelwala-Guruge, J.; Kazanov, M. D.; Arzamasov, A. A.; Leyn, S. A.; Lombard, V.; Terrapon, N.; Henrissat, B.; Castillo, J. J.; Couture, G.; Bacalzo, N. P.; Chen, Y.; Lebrilla, C. B.; Mostafa, I.; Das, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>A CROSS-SECTIONAL SURVEY OF AUSTRALIAN WOMEN&amp;#39;S PERSPECTIVES AND EXPERIENCES OF EXERCISE DURING PREGNANCY, INCLUDING WOMEN THAT EXPERIENCE MENTAL ILLNESS
Authors: Jarbou, N.; Baskerville, K.; Gabra, M.; Mawson, T.; Newell, K.; Nealon, J.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23292807
PurposeThe aim of this study was to develop an understanding of Australian womens perspectives and experiences around exercise during pregnancy, including women that experience mental illnesses such as depression. MethodAn anonymous online survey of women, administered via Qualtrics Australia, was open for 4 weeks between November - December 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Addressing tuberculosis in artisanal and small-scale mining activities in sub-Saharan Africa: meta-analysis and a call for actions
Authors: Mayeri, D. G.; Kambale, R. M.; Bugeme, P. M.; Ngaboyeka, G. A.; Mushagalusa, C.; Zahinda, F. M.; Tamuzi, J. L.; Katoto, P. C.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.24.23294543
Background: Tuberculosis (TB) is a significant health issue in sub-Saharan African (SSA) countries, and artisanal mining (AM) may be a contributing factor. However, no systematic review has investigated the association between AM and TB in SSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Insights into the Mechanisms and Structure of Breakage-Fusion-Bridge Cycles in Cervical Cancer using Long-Read Sequencing
Authors: Rodriguez, I.; Rossi, N. M.; Keskus, A.; Xie, Y.; Ahmad, T.; Bryant, A.; Lou, H.; Godinez Paredes, J.; Milano, R.; Rao, N.; Tulsyan, S.; Boland, J. F.; Luo, W.; Liu, J.; O&amp;#39;Hanlon, T.; Bess, J.; Mukhina, V.; Gaylalova, D.; Yuki, Y.; Malik, L.; Billingsley, K.; Blauwendraat, C.; Carrington, M.; Yeager, M.; Mirabello, L.; Kolmogorov, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>otolaryngology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/otolaryngology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence and risk factors of self-reported audiovestibular symptoms in a population-based sample from rural northeastern Germany
Authors: Ihler, F.; Brzoska, T.; Altindal, R.; Dziemba, O.; Voelzke, H.; Busch, C.-J.; Ittermann, T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23293690
ObjectivesThe senses of hearing and balance are linked by a close anatomical and physiological relationship. A further pathophysiological interaction is supposed but the detailed mechanism and direction remains elusive. Further insight is required into the prevalence of the audiovestibular symptoms hearing loss, tinnitus and dizziness as only scarce information on the combined occurrence is available so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>The three-dimensionally articulated oral apparatus of a Devonian heterostracan sheds light on feeding in Palaeozoic jawless fishes
Authors: Dearden, R. P.; Jones, A.; Giles, S.; Lanzetti, A.; Grohganz, M.; Johanson, Z.; Lautenschlager, S.; Randle, E.; Donoghue, P.; Sansom, I. J.
Score: 14.8, Published: 2023-08-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554283
Attempts to explain the origin and diversification of vertebrates have commonly invoked the evolution of feeding ecology, contrasting the passive suspension feeding of invertebrate chordate and larval lampreys with active predation in living jawed vertebrates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Macrophage-targeted DNA methyltransferase inhibitor SGI-1027 decreases atherosclerosis in ApoE-null mice
Authors: Marquez-Sanchez, A. C.; Manzanares-Guzman, A.; Carriles-Jaimes, R.; Sanchez-Segura, L.; Colin-Castelan, D.; Kamen, D.; Koltsova, E. K.; Maritnez-Antonio, A.; Rodriguez-Rios, D.; Romo-Morales, G. d. C.; Lund, G.; Zaina, S.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.554347
Background and aimsCorrection of vascular DNA hypermethylation may slow atherogenesis. We tested the anti-inflammatory and anti-atherogenic activity of macrophage-targeted DNA methyltransferase (DNMT) inhibitor SGI-1027. Methods, ResultsSGI-1027 was encapsulated into human serum albumin (HSA) nanoparticles (HSANP) functionalized with the PP1 peptide, a macrophage scavenger receptor 1 ligand, fused to a FLAG epitope (S-HSANP-FLAGPP1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Psilocybin desynchronizes brain networks
Authors: Siegel, J. S.; Subramanian, S.; Perry, D. A.; Kay, B. P.; Gordon, E. M.; Laumann, T. O.; Chacko, R. V.; Reneau, T. R.; Metcalf, N. V.; Horan, C.; Schweiger, J. A.; Wong, D.; Bender, D.; Padawer-Curry, J.; Raison, C. L.; Carhart-Harris, R.; Raichle, M. E.; Lenze, E. J.; Snyder, A. Z.; Dosenbach, N. U. F.; Nicol, G. E.
Score: 62.4, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294131</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>A Biotin Targeting Chimera (BioTAC) System to Map Small Molecule Interactomes in situ
Authors: Tao, A. J.; Jiang, J.; Gadbois, G. E.; Goyal, P.; Boyle, B. T.; Mumby, E. J.; Myers, S. A.; English, J. G.; Ferguson, F. M.
Score: 45.1, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.21.554211
Unbiased chemical biology strategies for direct readout of protein interactome remodelling by small molecules provide advantages over target-focused approaches, including the ability to detect previously unknown targets, and the inclusion of chemical off-compete controls leading to high-confidence identifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>A thrombus is formed by a gradient of platelet activation and procoagulant endothelium
Authors: CARMINITA, E.; TOURN, J.; CRESCENCE, L.; BROUILLY, N.; MERRILL-SKOLOFF, G.; MAZHARIAN, A.; DUBOIS, C.; Panicot-Dubois, L.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.550692
IntroductionThe contribution of platelets in thrombosis within microcirculation has been extensively documented in the literature. We previously showed, in vivo, that platelet activation revealed by intracellular calcium mobilization was a crucial step in the growth of thrombi following laser-induced injury, a model of thromboinflammation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The phosphorylation landscape of infection-related development by the rice blast fungus
Authors: Cruz-Mireles, N.; Oses-Ruiz, M.; Derbyshire, P.; Jegousse, C.; Ryder, L. S.; Bautista, M.-J.; Eseola, A. B.; Tang, B.; Yan, X.; Ma, W.; Findlay, K. C.; Were, V.; MacLean, D.; Talbot, N. J.; Menke, F. L. H.
Score: 68.9, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553964
Many of the worlds most devastating crop diseases are caused by fungal pathogens which elaborate specialized infection structures to invade plant tissue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Unravelling the influence of affective stimulation on functional neurological symptoms: A pilot experiment examining potential mechanisms
Authors: Pick, S.; Millman, L. S. M.; Ward, E.; Short, E.; Stanton, B. R.; Reinders, A. A. T. S.; Winston, J. S.; Nicholson, T. R.; Edwards, M. J.; Goldstein, L. H.; David, A. S.; Chalder, T.; Hotopf, M.; Mehta, M. A.
Score: 9.3, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.23.23294462
Background: Differences in affective processing have previously been shown in functional neurological disorder (FND); however, the mechanistic relevance is uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>A Scoping Review of Pacing for Management of Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS): Lessons Learned for the Long COVID Pandemic
Authors: Sanal-Hayes, N.; Mclaughlin, M.; Hayes, L. D. D.; Mair, J.; Ormerod, J.; Carless, D.; Hilliard, N.; Meach, R.; Ingram, J.; Sculthorpe, N.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.10.23293935
BackgroundControversy over treatment for people with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS) is a barrier to appropriate treatment. Energy management or pacing is a prominent coping strategy for people with ME/CFS that involves regulating activity to avoid post exertional malaise (PEM), the worsening of symptoms after an activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Characterizing patterns of DTI variance in aging brains
Authors: Gao, C.; Yang, Q.; Kim, M. E.; Mohd Khairi, N.; Cai, L. Y.; Newlin, N. R.; Kanakaraj, P.; Remedios, L. W.; Krishnan, A. R.; Yu, X.; Yao, T.; Zhang, P.; Schilling, K. G.; Moyer, D.; Archer, D. B.; Resnick, S. M.; Landman, B. A.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2023-08-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23294381
Purpose: As large analyses merge data across sites, a deeper understanding of variance in statistical assessment across the sources of data becomes critical for valid analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Kinesiophobia and physical activity: A systematic review and meta-analysis
Authors: Goubran, M.; Farajzadeh, A.; Lahart, I. M.; Bilodeau, M.; Boisgontier, M. P.
Score: 14.3, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.23294240
AbstractO_ST_ABSObjectiveC_ST_ABSPhysical activity is known to reduce the risk of disability, disease, and mortality. However, in some patients, an excessive, irrational, and debilitating fear of movement (i.e., kinesiophobia) is thought to induce avoidance behaviors, contributing to decreased engagement in physical activity. The aim of this study was to examine whether kinesiophobia is negatively associated with physical activity and what factors influence this relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>JOINT CLINICAL AND MOLECULAR SUBTYPING OF COPD WITH VARIATIONAL AUTOENCODERS
Authors: Maiorino, E.; De Marzio, M.; Weiss, S.; Silverman, E.; Castaldi, P.; Glass, K.
Score: 0.8, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.23294298
Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a complex, heterogeneous disease. Traditional subtyping methods generally focus on either the clinical manifestations or the molecular endotypes of the disease, resulting in domain-specific classifications that may not capture its full complexity. Here, we introduce an integrative approach based on variational autoencoders to integrate clinical and blood gene expression data from the COPDGene cohort study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of JAK-STAT pathway corrects salivary gland inflammation and interferon driven immune activation in Sjögren&amp;#39;s Disease
Authors: Warner, B. M.; Gupta, S.; Yamada, E.; Nakamura, H.; Perez, P.; Pranzatelli, T. J. F.; Dominick, K.; Jang, S.-I.; Abed, M.; Martin, D.; Burbelo, P.; Zheng, C.; French, B.; Alevizos, I.; Khavandgar, Z.; Beach, M.; Pelayo, E.; Walitt, B.; Hasni, S.; Kaplan, M.; Tandon, M.; Magone, M. T.; Kleiner, D.; Chiorini, J.; Baer, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Important enough to show the world&amp;#34;: Using Authentic Research Opportunities and Micropublications to Build Students Science Identities
Authors: Rubenstein, L. D.; Woodruff, K. A.; Taylor, A. M.; Olesen, J. B.; Smaldino, P. J.; Rubenstein, E. M.
Score: 53.0, Published: 2023-08-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.17.553701
Primarily undergraduate institutions (PUIs) often struggle to provide authentic research opportunities that culminate in peer-reviewed publications due to &amp;#34;recipe-driven&amp;#34; lab courses and the comprehensive body of work necessary for traditional scientific publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A sweat lactate sensor for detecting anaerobic threshold in patients with heart failure: a prospective clinical trial (LacS-001)
Authors: KATSUMATA, Y.; Muramoto, Y.; Ishida, N.; Takemura, R.; Nagashima, K.; Ikoma, T.; Kawamatsu, N.; Araki, M.; Goda, A.; Okawara, H.; Sawada, T.; Kawakubo, Y.; Hattori, O.; Yamaoka, K.; Seki, Y.; Ryuzaki, T.; Ikura, H.; Nakashima, D.; Nagura, T.; Nakamura, M.; Sato, K.; Shiraishi, Y.
Score: 2.5, Published: 2023-08-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.15.23294144</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Targeting mosquito X-chromosomes reveals complex transmission dynamics of sex ratio distorting gene drives
Authors: Haber, D. A.; Arien, Y.; Lamdan, L. B.; Alcalay, Y.; Zecharia, C.; Krsticevic, F.; Yonah, E. S.; Avraham, R. D.; Windbichler, N.; Papathanos, P. A.
Score: 13.5, Published: 2023-08-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.20.554004
Engineered sex ratio distorters (SRDs) have been proposed as a powerful component of both self-limiting and self-sustaining genetic control strategies designed to suppress harmful insect pest or disease vector populations such as malaria mosquitoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>LIANA&amp;#43;: an all-in-one cell-cell communication framework
Authors: Dimitrov, D.; Schäfer, P. S. L.; Farr, E.; Rodriguez Mier, P.; Lobentanzer, S.; Dugourd, A.; Tanevski, J.; Ramirez Flores, R. O.; Saez-Rodriguez, J.
Score: 52.1, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553863
The growing availability of single-cell and spatially-resolved transcriptomics has led to the rapidly growing popularity of methods to infer cell-cell communication. Many approaches have emerged, each capturing only a partial view of the complex landscape of cell-cell communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV-2 variants Omicron BA.4/5 and XBB.1.5 significantly escape T cell recognition in solid organ transplant recipients vaccinated against the ancestral strain
Authors: Halvorson, T.; Ivison, S.; Huang, Q.; Ladua, G.; Yotis, D. M.; Mannar, D.; Subramaniam, S.; Ferreira, V. H.; Kumar, D.; Belga, S.; PREVenT Study Group, ; Levings, M.
Score: 15.0, Published: 2023-08-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.14.23293991
BackgroundImmune-suppressed solid organ transplant recipients (SOTRs) display impaired humoral responses to COVID-19 vaccination, but T cell responses are incompletely understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 10:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of human skin microbiome odorants that manipulate mosquito landing behavior
Authors: Coutinho-Abreu, I. V.; Jamshidi, O.; Raban, R.; Atabakhsh, K.; Merriman, J. A.; Fischbach, M. A.; Akbari, O. S.
Score: 44.3, Published: 2023-08-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.19.553996
The resident human skin microbiome is responsible for the production of most of the human scents that are attractive to mosquitoes. Hence, engineering the human skin microbiome to synthesize less of mosquito attractants or produce repellents could potentially reduce bites and prevent the transmission of deadly mosquito-borne pathogens.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
