<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Extracellular Matrix Abnormalities in the Hippocampus of Subjects with Substance Use Disorder
Authors: Valeri, J.; Stiplosek, C.; O&amp;#39;Donovan, S. M.; Sinclair, D.; Grant, K. A.; Bollavarapu, R.; Platt, D. M.; Stockmeier, C. A.; Gisabella, B.; Pantazopoulos, H.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23295222
Contextual triggers are significant factors contributing to relapse in substance use disorders (SUD). Emerging evidence points to a critical role of extracellular matrix (ECM) molecules as mediators of reward memories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Observational Study of Repeat Immunoadsorption (RIA) in Post-COVID ME/CFS Patients with Elevated Beta-2-Adrenergic Receptor Autoantibodies
Authors: Stein, E.; Heindrich, C.; Wittke, K.; Kedor, C.; Kim, L.; Freitag, H.; Krueger, A.; Toelle, M.; Scheibenbogen, C.
Score: 407.8, Published: 2023-09-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.31.23294813
There is increasing evidence for an autoimmune aetiology in post-infectious Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (ME/CFS). SARS-CoV-2 has now become the main trigger for ME/CFS. We have already conducted two small proof-of-concept studies of IgG depletion by immunoadsorption (IA) in post-infectious ME/CFS, which showed efficacy in most patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Flexibility of tandem leaders resolves traffic jams during colony relocation in an ant
Authors: Pathak, M. K.; Annagiri, S.
Score: 26.2, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557616
Ants, renowned for their intricate social behaviors, exhibit remarkable collective movement patterns that enable them to forage and tunnel efficiently. Despite significant research into their navigation skills and traffic avoidance mechanisms mostly in the context of central-place foraging, the dynamics of bi-directional movement during colony relocation remains an underexplored domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Glutamylation of Npm2 and Nap1 acidic disordered regions increases DNA charge mimicry to enhance chaperone efficiency
Authors: Lorton, B. M.; Warren, C.; Ilyas, H.; Nandigrami, P.; Hegde, S.; Cahill, S.; Lehman, S. M.; Shabanowitz, J.; Hunt, D.; Fiser, A.; Cowburn, D.; Shechter, D.
Score: 16.0, Published: 2023-09-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558337
Histone chaperones-structurally diverse, non-catalytic proteins enriched with acidic intrinsically disordered regions (IDRs)-protect histones from spurious nucleic acid interactions and guide their deposition into and out of nucleosomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Complete substitution with modified nucleotides suppresses the early interferon response and increases the potency of self-amplifying RNA
Authors: McGee, J. E.; Kirsch, J. R.; Kenney, D.; Chavez, E.; Shih, T.-Y.; Douam, F.; Wong, W. W.; Grinstaff, M. W.
Score: 25.3, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.557994
Self-amplifying RNA (saRNA) will revolutionize vaccines and in situ therapeutics by enabling protein expression for longer duration at lower doses. However, a major barrier to saRNA efficacy is the potent early interferon response triggered upon cellular entry, resulting in saRNA degradation and translational inhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Rendering protein mutation movies with MutAmore
Authors: Weissenow, K.; Rost, B.
Score: 39.6, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.557870
We introduce MutAmore, a bioinformatics tool that renders individual photos of, e.g., protein three-dimensional (3D) structures for protein mutations into an easily understandable movie format. MutAmore provides a streamlined pipeline casting single amino-acid variations (SAVs) into a dynamic 3D protein mutation movie which provides a qualitative perspective on the mutational landscape of a protein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Secreted footprints let cells switch between confined, oscillatory, and exploratory migration
Authors: Ipina, E. P.; D&amp;#39;Alessandro, J.; Ladoux, B.; Camley, B. A.
Score: 22.6, Published: 2023-09-16 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.557437
For eukaryotic cells to heal wounds, respond to immune signals, or metastasize, they must migrate, often by adhering to extracellular matrix. Cells may also secrete matrix factors, leaving behind a footprint that influences their crawling. Recent experiments showed that epithelial cells on micropatterned adhesive stripes move persistently in regions they have previously crawled over, where footprints have been formed, but barely advance into unexplored regions, creating an oscillatory migration of increasing amplitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of astrocyte-driven pseudolineages reveals clinical stratification and therapeutic targets in Glioblastoma
Authors: Foerster, L. C.; Kaya, O.; Wust, V.; Bekavac, M.; Ziegler, K. C.; Akcay, V.; Stinchcombe, N.; Gesteira Perez, N.; Ma, X.; Sadik, A.; Le, P. U.; Petrecca, K.; Opitz, C.; Liu, H.; Wirtz, C. R.; Anders, S.; Goncalves, A.; Martin-Villalba, A.
Score: 28.3, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.557713
Cancer research has predominantly targeted genetic mutations, while only recently has attention shifted to understanding tumor cell-stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Neurodegeneration is strongly linked to heart failure severity and outcomes: framing the cardiocerebral syndrome
Authors: Wurm, R.; Prausmueller, S.; Ponleitner, M.; Spinka, G.; Weidenhammer, A.; Arfsten, H.; Heitzinger, G.; Panagiotides, N. G.; Bartko, P.; Goliasch, G.; Stoegmann, E.; Hengstenberg, C.; Huelsmann, M.; Pavo, N.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.23295547
Background and ObjectivesCognitive impairment is prevalent in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF), affecting self-care and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Sequential membrane- and protein-bound organelles compartmentalize genomes during phage infection
Authors: Armbruster, E.; Lee, J.; Hutchings, J.; VanderWal, A.; Enustun, E.; Adler, B.; Aindow, A.; Deep, A.; Rodriguez, Z.; Morgan, C.; Ghassemian, M.; Charles, E.; Cress, B.; Savage, D.; Doudna, J.; Pogliano, K.; Corbett, K.; Villa, E.; Pogliano, J.
Score: 38.4, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558163
Eukaryotic viruses assemble compartments required for genome replication, but no such organelles are known to be essential for prokaryotic viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Testing the Limits of Language Models: A Conversational Framework for Medical AI Assessment
Authors: Johri, S.; Jeong, J.; Tran, B. A.; Schlessinger, D. I.; Wongvibulsin, S.; Cai, Z. R.; Daneshjou, R.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 39.3, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295399
Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise for medical diagnosis, but traditional evaluations using static exam questions overlook the complexity of real-world clinical dialogues. We introduce a multi-agent conversational framework where doctor-AI and patient-AI agents interact to diagnose medical conditions, evaluated by a grader-AI agent and medical experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>CXCR3-CXCL11 signaling restricts angiogenesis and promotes pericyte recruitment
Authors: Goeckel, M. E.; Lee, J.; Levitas, A.; Colijn, S.; Mun, G.; Burton, Z.; Chintalapati, B.; Yin, Y.; Abello, J.; Stratman, A. N.
Score: 14.1, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.16.557842
Endothelial cell (EC)-pericyte interactions are known to remodel in response to hemodynamic forces, yet there is a lack of mechanistic understanding of the signaling pathways that underlie these events. Here, we have identified a novel signaling network regulated by blood flow in ECs--the chemokine receptor, CXCR3, and one of its ligands, CXCL11--that delimits EC angiogenic potential and suppresses pericyte recruitment during development through regulation of pdgfb expression in ECs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>A novel spawning survey: identifying spawning times and locations of jack mackerel in a semi-closed bay using environmental DNA analysis
Authors: Tsuji, S.; Murakami, H.; Masuda, R.
Score: 18.9, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.10.557099
Understanding spawning ecology is vital for species/population management and conservation. Conventional surveys for this, however, are generally time- and labour-demanding and invasive. To overcome these challenges, environmental DNA (eDNA) analysis has emerged as a promising spawning survey method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic Review of Treatment of Beta-Cell Monogenic Diabetes
Authors: Naylor, R. N.; Patel, K. A.; Kettunen, J. L. T.; Männistö, J. M. E.; Stoy, J.; Beltrand, J.; Polak, M.; ADA/EASD PMDI, ; Vilsobll, T.; Greeley, S. A. W.; Hattersley, A. T.; Tuomi, T.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.05.12.23289807
Background: Beta-cell monogenic forms of diabetes are the area of diabetes care with the strongest support for precision medicine. We reviewed treatment of hyperglycemia in GCK-related hyperglycemia, HNF1A- HNF4A- and HNF1B-diabetes, Mitochondrial diabetes (MD) due to m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Ventilation during COVID-19 in a school for students with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDD).
Authors: Zand, M. S.; Spallina, S.; Ross, A.; Zandi, K.; Pawlowski, A.; Seplaki, C.; Herington, J.; Corbett, A.; Kaukeinen, K.; Freedman, E.; Holden-Wiltse, J.; Alcantara, L.; Li, D.; Cameron, A.; Beaumont, N.; Dozier, A.; Dewhurst, S.; Foxe, J.
Score: 61.4, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.08.23295268
BackgroundThis study examined the correlation of classroom ventilation (air exchanges per hour (ACH)) and exposure to CO2 [&amp;amp;ge;]1,000 ppm with the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 over a 20-month period in a specialized school for students with intellectual and developmental disabilities (IDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Self-assembling viral histones unravel early nucleosome evolution
Authors: Irwin, N. A. T.; Richards, T. A.
Score: 51.2, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558576
Nucleosomes are a core-component of eukaryotic nuclei, forming the structural basis of chromatin and co-ordinating processes from gene expression to chromosome segregation. Composed of a DNA-protein complex consisting of the four individual histones, H2A, H2B, H3, and H4, the nucleosome and its associated functions were key innovations during eukaryotic evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genetic architecture of telomere length in 462,675 UK Biobank whole-genome sequences
Authors: Burren, O. S.; Dhindsa, R.; Deevi, S. V. V.; Wen, S.; Nag, A.; Mitchell, J.; Hu, F.; Smith, K. R.; Razdan, N.; Olsson, H.; Platt, A.; Codd, V.; Nelson, C.; Samani, N.; March, R.; Wasilewski, S.; Carss, K.; Fabre, M.; Wang, Q.; Pangalos, M.; Petrovski, S.
Score: 13.2, Published: 2023-09-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.23295715
Telomeres protect the ends of chromosomes from damage, and genetic regulation of their length is associated with human disease and ageing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Higher-order combinatorial chromatin perturbations by engineered CRISPR-Cas12a for functional genomics
Authors: Hsiung, C. C.- S.; Wilson, C. M.; Sambold, N. A.; Dai, R.; Chen, Q.; Misiukiewicz, S.; Arab, A.; Teyssier, N.; O&amp;#39;Loughlin, T.; Cofsky, J.; Shi, J.; Gilbert, L. A.
Score: 34.7, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558350
Multiplexed genetic perturbations are critical for testing functional interactions among coding or non-coding genetic elements. Compared to DNA cutting, repressive chromatin formation using CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) avoids genotoxicity and is more effective for perturbing non-coding regulatory elements in pooled assays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell nascent RNA sequencing using click-chemistry unveils coordinated transcription
Authors: Mahat, D. B.; Tippens, N. D.; Martin-Rufino, J. D.; Waterton, S. K.; Fu, J.; Blatt, S. E.; Sharp, P. A.
Score: 43.4, Published: 2023-09-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.558015
Transcription is the primary regulatory step in gene expression. Divergent transcription initiation from promoters and enhancers produces stable RNAs from genes and unstable RNAs from enhancers1-5. Nascent RNA capture and sequencing assays simultaneously measure gene and enhancer activity in cell populations6-9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic aging clock predicts mortality and risk of common age-related diseases in diverse populations
Authors: Argentieri, M. A.; Xiao, S.; Bennett, D.; Winchester, L.; Nevado-Holgado, A. J.; Albukhari, A.; Yao, P.; Mazidi, M.; Lv, J.; Li, L.; Adams, C. J.; Clarke, R.; Amin, N.; Chen, Z.; van Duijn, C. M.
Score: 18.1, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295486
Circulating plasma proteins play key roles in human health and could be used to measure biological aging to predict risk of mortality, disease, and multimorbidity beyond chronological age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-economics/</guid>
      <description>A Literature Review and Meta-Analysis of the Effects of Lockdowns on COVID-19 Mortality - II
Authors: Herby, J.; Jonung, L.; Hanke, S.
Score: 225.6, Published: 2023-09-05 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.30.23294845
The purpose of this systematic review and meta-analysis is to determine the effect of lockdowns on COVID-19 mortality based on available empirical evidence. Lockdowns are defined as the imposition of at least one compulsory, non-pharmaceutical intervention (NPI). We employ a systematic search and screening procedure in which 19,646 studies are identified that could potentially address the purpose of our study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating AI in Clinical Practice: A Scoping Evaluation
Authors: Han, R.; Acosta, J. N.; Shakeri, Z.; Ioannidis, J.; Topol, E.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 86.6, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295381
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a promising tool in healthcare, with numerous studies indicating its potential to perform as well or better than clinicians. However, a considerable portion of these AI models have only been tested retrospectively, raising concerns about their true effectiveness and potential risks in real-world clinical settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare system barriers impacting the care of Canadians with myalgic encephalomyelitis: a scoping review
Authors: Hussein, S.; Eiriksson, L.; MacQuarrie, M.; Merriam, S.; Dalton, M.; Stein, E.; Twomey, R.
Score: 20.4, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295809
Background: Myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME, also known as chronic fatigue syndrome or ME/CFS) is a debilitating, complex, multi-system illness. Developing a comprehensive understanding of the multiple and interconnected barriers to optimal care will help advance strategies and care models to improve quality of life for people living with ME in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the potential population-level impacts of HIV self-testing distribution among key populations in Cote d&amp;#39;Ivoire, Mali, and Senegal: a mathematical modelling analysis
Authors: Silhol, R.; Maheu-Giroux, M.; Soni, N.; Simo Fotso, A.; Rouveau, N.; Vautier, A.; Doumenc-Aidara, C.; Geoffroy, O.; N&amp;#39;Guessan, K. N.; Sidibe, Y.; Kabemba, O. K.; Gueye, P. A.; Mukandavire, C.; Vickerman, P.; Keita, A.; Ndour, C. T.; Ehui, E.; Larmarange, J.; Boily, M.-C.; The ATLAS Team, Score: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Antigenicity and infectivity characterization of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86
Authors: Yang, S.; Yu, Y.; Jian, F.; Song, W.; Yisimayi, A.; Chen, X.; Xu, Y.; Wang, P.; Yu, L.; Wang, J.; Niu, X.; Wang, J.; Xiao, T.; An, R.; Wang, Y.; Gu, Q.; Shao, F.; Jin, R.; Shen, Z.; Wang, Y.; Cao, Y. R.
Score: 653.5, Published: 2023-09-04 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.01.555815
The recently identified SARS-CoV-2 variant, BA.2.86, which carries a substantial number of Spike mutations, has raised a global alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Safety and Immunogenicity of XBB.1.5-Containing mRNA Vaccines
Authors: Chalkias, S.; McGhee, N.; Whatley, J. L.; Essink, B.; Brosz, A.; Tomassini, J. E.; Girard, B.; Wu, K.; Edwards, D. K.; Nasir, A.; Lee, D.; Avena, L. E.; Feng, J.; Deng, W.; Montefiori, D. C.; Baden, L. R.; Miller, J. M.; Das, R.
Score: 3361.5, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.22.23293434
BackgroundSubvariants of the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) omicron XBB-lineage have the potential to escape immunity provided by prior infection or vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Conventional and unconventional T cell responses contribute to the prediction of clinical outcome and causative bacterial pathogen in sepsis patients
Authors: Burton, R. J.; Raffray, L.; Moet, L. M.; Cuff, S. M.; White, D. A.; Baker, S. E.; Moser, B.; O&amp;#39;Donnell, V. B.; Ghazal, P.; Morgan, M. P.; Artemiou, A.; Eberl, M.
Score: 5.7, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295490
Sepsis is characterised by a dysfunctional host response to infection culminating in life-threatening organ failure that requires complex patient management and rapid intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide Characterization of Diverse Bacteriophages Enabled by RNA-Binding CRISPRi
Authors: Adler, B. A.; Al-Shimary, M. J.; Patel, J. R.; Ambruster, E.; Colognori, D.; Charles, E. J.; Miller, K. V.; Lahiri, A.; Trinidad, M.; Boger, R.; Nomburg, J.; Beurnier, S.; Cui, M. L.; Barrangou, R.; Mutalik, V. K.; Schoeniger, J. S.; Pogliano, J. A.; Savage, D. F.; Doudna, J. A.; Cress, B. F.
Score: 70.0, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558157
Bacteriophages constitute one of the largest sources of unknown gene content in the biosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>CCAR1 promotes DNA repair via an unanticipated role in alternative splicing
Authors: Karasu, M. E.; Joseph, B.; Mironov, A.; Schroeder, M. S.; Gvozdenovic, A.; Zavolan, M.; Corn, J. E.
Score: 18.4, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.557780
DNA repair is directly performed by hundreds of core factors and indirectly regulated by thousands of others. We massively expanded a CRISPR inhibition and Cas9-editing screening system to discover factors indirectly modulating homology directed repair (HDR) in the context of [~]18000 individual gene knockdowns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning on electronic medical records identifies distinct subphenotypes of diabetic kidney disease driven by genetic variations in the Rho pathway
Authors: Paranjpe, I.; Wang, X.; Anandakrishnan, N.; Haydak, J.; Van Vleck, T. T.; Defronzo, S.; Li, Z.; Mendoza, A.; Liu, R.; Fu, J.; Forrest, I.; Zhou, W.; Lee, K.; O&amp;#39;Hagan, R.; Dellepiane, S.; Menon, K.; Gulamali, F.; Kamat, S.; Gusella, G. L.; Charney, A. W.; Hofer, I.; Cho, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Millimeter-sized battery-free epidural cortical stimulators
Authors: Woods, J. E.; Singer, A.; Alrashdan, F.; Tan, W.; Tan, C.; Sheth, S. A.; Sheth, S. A.; Robinson, J. T.
Score: 25.3, Published: 2023-09-15 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295460
Refractory neurological and psychiatric disorders are increasingly treated with brain stimulation therapies using implanted neuromodulation devices. Current commercially available stimulation systems, however, are limited by the need for implantable pulse generators and wired power; the complexity of this architecture creates multiple failure points including lead fractures, migration, and infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neurological Imprints of Boys&amp;#39; Love Culture: Shaping Sexual Orientation Identity in the Digital Age&amp;#39;s Young females
Authors: Yanan, C.; Na, A.; Xiaowei, J.; Yingying, C.; Huihui, N.; Shuoyan, H.
Score: 539.3, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558088
With the omnipresence of social media, Boys&amp;#39; Love (BL) culture has found a burgeoning audience among young females. While this cultural phenomenon offers a platform for self-expression to some, its potential implications remain underexplored. This study investigates whether immersion in BL culture impacts the process of young females forming self-recognition and identification of sexual orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Dietary sulfur amino acid restriction in humans with overweight and obesity: a translational randomized controlled trial
Authors: Olsen, T.; Stolt, E.; Ovrebo, B.; Elshorbagy, A.; Tore, E. C.; Lee-Oedegard, S.; Troensegaard, H.; Johannessen, H.; Doeland, B.; Vo, A. A. D.; Dahl, A. F.; Svendsen, K.; Thoresen, M.; Refsum, H.; Rising, R.; Barvikova, K.; Greevenbroek, M. v.; Kozich, V.; Retterstol, K.; Vinknes, K. J.
Score: 3.9, Published: 2023-09-10 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295155</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A clinicogenomic model including GARD predicts outcome for radiation treated patients with HPV&amp;#43; oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma
Authors: Ho, E.; DeCecco, L.; Cavalieri, S.; Sedor, G.; Hoebers, F.; Brakenhoff, R.; Scheckenbach, K.; Poli, T.; Yang, K.; Scarborough, J.; Campbell, S.; Koyfman, S.; Eschrich, S. A.; Caudell, J.; Kattan, M. W.; Licitra, L.; Torres-Roca, J.; Scott, J. G.
Score: 20.3, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.23295538
BackgroundTreatment decision-making in oropharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma (OPSCC) includes clinical stage, HPV status, and smoking history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>orthopedics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/orthopedics/</guid>
      <description>Real-world gait and turning in individuals scheduled for total knee arthroplasty
Authors: Boekesteijn, R. J.; Keijsers, N. L. W.; Defoort, K.; Mancini, M.; Bruning, F. J.; El-Gohary, M.; Geurts, A. C. H.; Smulders, K.
Score: 3.1, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.23295243
ObjectiveTo compare real-world gait and turning between individuals scheduled for total knee arthroplasty (TKA) and healthy controls, using continuous monitoring with inertial measurement units (IMUs). DesignReal-world gait and turning data were collected for 5-7 days in individuals scheduled for TKA (n=34) and healthy controls in the same age range (n=32) using IMUs on the feet and lower back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Savoring Meditation on Positive Emotions and Pain-Related Brain Function: A Mechanistic Randomized Controlled Trial in People With Rheumatoid Arthritis
Authors: Finan, P.; Hunt, C.; Keaser, M. L.; Smith, K.; Lerman, S.; Bingham, C. O.; Barrett, F.; Garland, E. L.; Zeidan, F.; Seminowicz, D. A.
Score: 3.6, Published: 2023-09-08 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.23294949
Positive emotions are a promising target for intervention in chronic pain, but mixed findings across trials to date suggest that existing interventions may not be optimized to efficiently engage the target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Forensic Facial Approximation of Achondroplastic Dwarf from Medieval Cemetery in Central Europe
Authors: Moraes, C.; Krenz-Niedbała, M.; Łukasik, S.; Prada, C. S.
Score: 63.5, Published: 2023-08-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.08.26.553833
Achondroplasia (ACH, achondroplastic dwarfism) represents the most common form of skeletal dysplasia, occurring in c. 4 out of every 100,000 births. This study presents a computer-based facial approximation of the skull of a male individual suffering from ACH, who died at 30-45 years of age and was buried in ekno, Poland between the 9th and 11th centuries AD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Native ultrastructure of fresh human brain vitrified directly from autopsy revealed by cryo-electron tomography with cryo-plasma focused ion beam milling
Authors: Creekmore, B. C.; Kixmoeller, K.; Black, B. E.; Lee, E. B.; Chang, Y.-W.
Score: 26.6, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557623
Ultrastructure of human brain tissue has traditionally been examined using electron microscopy (EM) following chemical fixation, staining, and mechanical sectioning, which limit attainable resolution and introduce artifacts. Alternatively, cryo-electron tomography (cryo-ET) offers the potential to image unfixed cellular samples at higher resolution while preserving their native structures, but it requires samples to be frozen free from crystalline ice and thin enough to image via transmission EM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Atazanavir/ritonavir increased tizoxanide exposure from oral nitazoxanide through pharmacokinetic interaction in healthy volunteers
Authors: Akinloye, A.; Oyedeji, T.; Eniayewu, O.; Adeagbo, B.; Bolaji, O.; Rannard, S.; Owen, A.; Olagunju, A.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295544
Aims: Nitazoxanide is a broad-spectrum antiviral with potential application in a number of viral infections. Its use is limited by gastrointestinal side effects associated with increasing dose. In this study, we investigated the possibility of enhancing the exposure of its active metabolite, tizoxanide, through pharmacokinetic interaction with atazanavir/ritonavir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Self-supervised deep learning uncovers the semantic landscape of drug-induced latent mitochondrial phenotypes
Authors: Natekar, P.; Wang, Z.; Arora, M.; Hakozaki, H.; Schoeneberg, J.
Score: 75.5, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557636
Imaging-based high-content screening aims to identify substances that modulate cellular phenotypes. Traditional approaches screen compounds for their ability to shift disease phenotypes toward healthy phenotypes, but these end point-based screens lack an atlas-like mapping between phenotype and cell state that covers the full spectrum of possible phenotypic responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibition of mammalian mtDNA transcription paradoxically activates liver fatty acid oxidation to reverse diet-induced hepatosteatosis and obesity
Authors: Jiang, S.; Yuan, T.; Kremer, L. S.; Rosenberger, F. A.; Hansen, F. M.; Borg, M.; Rubalcava-Gracia, D.; Mennuni, M.; Filograna, R.; Alsina, D.; Misic, J.; Koolmeister, C.; Ren, L.; Andersson, O.; Unger, A.; Bergbrede, T.; Lucrezia, R. D.; Wilbom, R.; Zierath, J. R.; Krook, A.; Giavalisco, P.; Mann, M.; Larsson, N.-G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Plant-based production of diverse human milk oligosaccharides
Authors: Barnum, C. R.; Paviani, B.; Couture, G.; Masarweh, C.; Chen, Y.; Huang, Y.-P.; Mills, D. A.; Lebrilla, C. B.; Barile, D.; Yang, M.; Shih, P.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558286
Human milk oligosaccharides (HMOs) are a diverse class of carbohydrates that aid in the health and development of infants. The vast health benefits of HMOs have made them a commercial target for microbial production; however, producing the ~130 structurally diverse HMOs at scale has proven difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Prenatal cannabis exposure is associated with focal brain differences that partially mediate associations with increased adolescent psychopathology
Authors: Baranger, D. A.; Miller, A. P.; Gorelik, A. J.; Paul, S. E.; Hatoum, A. S.; Johnson, E. C.; Colbert, S. M. C.; Smyser, C. D.; Rogers, C. E.; Bijsterbosch, J. D.; Agrawal, A.; Bogdan, R.
Score: 5.0, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.23295792
Prenatal cannabis exposure (PCE) is associated with mental health problems, but the neurobiological mechanisms remain unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the population effectiveness of interventions against COVID-19 in France: a modelling study
Authors: Ganser, I.; Buckeridge, D. L.; Heffernan, J. M.; Prague, M.; Thiebaut, R.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.23295425
BackgroundNon-pharmaceutical interventions (NPIs) and vaccines have been widely used to manage the COVID-19 pandemic. However, uncertainty persists regarding the effectiveness of these interventions due to data quality issues, methodological challenges, and differing contextual factors. Accurate estimation of their effects is crucial for future epidemic preparedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Radiomic-Based Prediction of Lesion-Specific Systemic Treatment Response in Metastatic Disease
Authors: Geady, C.; Abbas-Aghababazadeh, F.; Kohan, A.; Schuetze, S.; Shultz, D.; Haibe-Kains, B.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23294942
Despite sharing the same histologic classification, individual tumors in multi metastatic patients may present with different characteristics and varying sensitivities to anticancer therapies. In this study, we investigate the utility of radiomic biomarkers for prediction of lesion-specific treatment resistance in multi metastatic leiomyosarcoma patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>HEART rate variability biofeedback breathing programme for LOng Covid dysautonomia (HEARTLOC): results of a feasibility study
Authors: Corrado, J.; Iftekhar, N.; Halpin, S.; Li, M.; Tarrant, R.; Grimaldi, J.; Simms, A.; O&amp;#39;Connor, R. J.; Casson, A.; Sivan, M.
Score: 10.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.09.23295208
IntroductionPost-covid-19 syndrome, or Long covid (LC) refers to symptoms persisting 12 weeks after Covid-19 infection. LC comprises a wide range of dysautonomia symptoms, including fatigue, breathlessness, palpitations, dizziness, pain and brain fog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Controlled experiment finds no detectable citation bump from Twitter promotion
Authors: Branch, T.; C?te, I. M.; David, S. R.; Drew, J. A.; LaRue, M.; Marquez, M. C.; Parsons, E. C. M.; Rabaiotti, D.; Shiffman, D.; Steen, D. A.; Wild, A. L.
Score: 202.6, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558161
Multiple studies across a variety of scientific disciplines have shown that the number of times that a paper is shared on Twitter (now called X) is correlated with the number of citations that paper receives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Computational design of sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins
Authors: Glasscock, C. J.; Pecoraro, R.; McHugh, R.; Doyle, L. A.; Chen, W.; Boivin, O.; Lonnquist, B.; Na, E.; Politanska, Y.; Haddox, H. K.; Cox, D.; Norn, C.; Coventry, B.; Goreshnik, I.; Vafeados, D.; Lee, G. R.; Gordan, R.; Stoddard, B. L.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 170.1, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558720
Sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins (DBPs) play critical roles in biology and biotechnology, and there has been considerable interest in the engineering of DBPs with new or altered specificities for genome editing and other applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Widespread transcriptional regulation from within transcribed regions in plants
Authors: Voichek, Y.; Hristova, G.; Molla-Morales, A.; Weigel, D.; Nordborg, M.
Score: 108.5, Published: 2023-09-17 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.15.557872
Animals and plants have evolved separately for over 1.5 billion years and independently invented multicellularity, suggesting a possible divergence in their mode of transcription regulation. Here, we set out to elucidate fundamental features of transcription regulatory sequences in plants. Using a massively parallel reporter assay in four species, we show that sequences downstream of the transcription start site (TSS) play a major role in controlling transcription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Historical biogeography of New World Killifishes (Cyprinodontiformes: Funduloidea) recapitulates geographical history in the Gulf of Mexico watershed
Authors: Hernandez, S. G.; Hoagstrom, C. W.; Matamoros, W. A.
Score: 18.6, Published: 2023-09-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556706
We reconstructed the phylogenetic relationships of superfamily Funduloidea with a synthesis of its biogeographic history. We used DNA sequences from five genes for 135 species, with four fossil calibrations, to generate a time-calibrated phylogeny. We estimated diversification rates, ancestral areas (Nearctic or Neotropical), and ancestral habitat (coastal or upland), for each node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
