<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Identifying novel gene dysregulation associated with opioid overdose death: A meta-analysis of differential gene expression in human prefrontal cortex
Authors: Carter, J. K.; Quach, B. C.; Willis, C.; Minto, M. S.; PGC SUD Epigenetics Working Group, ; Hancock, D. B.; Montalvo-Ortiz, J. L.; Corradin, O.; Logan, R. W.; Walss Bass, C.; Maher, B.; Johnson, E. O.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301153
Only recently have human postmortem brain studies of differential gene expression (DGE) associated with opioid overdose death (OOD) been published; sample sizes from these studies have been modest (N = 40-153).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Vocalization Patterns in Laying Hens - An Analysis of Stress-Induced Audio Responses
Authors: Neethirajan, S.
Score: 53.9, Published: 2023-12-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.573338
This study presents a novel approach to understanding chicken vocalizations using advanced machine learning techniques. Employing a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) model, the research aimed to classify and analyze the vocalization patterns of laying hens under various conditions. The dataset comprised vocal recordings from chickens exposed to two distinct stressors - umbrella and dog barking - as well as control groups, across different age stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging co-evolutionary insights and AI-based structural modeling to unravel receptor-peptide ligand-binding mechanisms
Authors: Snoeck, S.; Lee, H. K.; Schmid, M. W.; Bender, K. W.; Neeracher, M. J.; Fernandez-Fernandez, A. D.; Santiago, J.; Zipfel, C.
Score: 26.3, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.575556
Secreted signaling peptides are central regulators of growth, development, and stress responses, but specific steps in the evolution of these peptides and their receptors are not well understood. In addition, the molecular mechanisms of peptide- receptor binding are only known for a few examples, primarily owing to the limited availability of structural capabilities to few laboratories worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Rapid and reversible dissolution of biomolecular condensates using light-controlled recruitment of a solubility tag
Authors: Brumbaugh-Reed, E. H.; Aoki, K.; Toettcher, J. E.
Score: 17.6, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575860
Biomolecular condensates are broadly implicated in both normal cellular regulation and disease. Consequently, several chemical biology and optogenetic approaches have been developed to induce phase separation of a protein of interest. However, few tools are available to perform the converse function--dissolving a condensate of interest on demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>When the pen is mightier than the sword: semi-automatic 2 and 3D image labelling
Authors: Hollandi, R.; Bauer, D.; Diosdi, A.; Schrettner, B.; Toth, T.; Hirling, D.; Hollandi, G.; Harmati, M.; Molnar, J.; Horvath, P.
Score: 38.4, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575658
Data is the driving engine of learning-based algorithms, the creation of which fundamentally determines the performance, accuracy, generalizability and quality of any model or method trained on it. When only skilled or trained personnel can create reliable annotations, assisted software solutions are desirable to reduce the time and effort the expert must spend on labelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>High-throughput analysis of membrane fluidity unveils a hidden dimension in immune cell states
Authors: Andronico, L. A.; Jiang, Y.; Carannante, V.; Iskrak, S.; Sandoz, P. A.; Mikes, J.; Klymchenko, A. S.; Buggert, M.; Osterborg, A.; Onfelt, B.; Brodin, P.; Sezgin, E.
Score: 30.9, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.575649
Cell membranes undergo biophysical remodelling as an adaptation to the surroundings and to perform specific biological functions. However, the extent and relevance of such changes in human immune systems remain unknown, largely due to the lack of high throughput and multidimensional methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Deciphering the diversity and sequence of extracellular matrix and cellular spatial patterns in lung adenocarcinoma using topological data analysis
Authors: Yoon, I. H. R.; Jenkins, R.; Colliver, E.; Zhang, H.; Novo, D.; Moore, D.; Ramsden, Z.; Rullan, A.; Fu, X.; Yuan, Y.; Harrington, H. A.; Swanton, C.; Byrne, H. M.; Sahai, E.
Score: 30.2, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574362
Extracellular matrix (ECM) organization influences cancer development and progression. It modulates the invasion of cancer cells and can hinder the access of immune cells to cancer cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Interpretable Machine Learning Leverages Proteomics to Improve Cardiovascular Disease Risk Prediction and Biomarker Identification
Authors: Climente-Gonzalez, H.; Oh, M.; Chajewska, U.; Hosseini, R.; Mukherjee, S.; Gan, W.; Traylor, M.; Hu, S.; Fatemifar, G.; Del Villar, P. P.; Vernet, E.; Koelling, N.; Du, L.; Abraham, R.; Li, C.; Howson, J. M. M.
Score: 6.5, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301213
Cardiovascular diseases (CVD), primarily coronary heart disease and stroke, rank amongst the leading causes of long-term disability and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>A centromere-derived retroelement RNA localizes in cis and is a core element of the transcriptional landscape of Drosophila centromeres
Authors: Santinello, B.; Sun, R.; Amjad, A.; Hoyt, S. J.; Ouyang, L.; Courret, C.; Drennan, R.; Leo, L.; Larracuente, A. M.; Core, L. M.; O&amp;#39;Neill, R. J.; Mellone, B. G.
Score: 25.2, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.574223
Centromeres are essential chromosomal landmarks that dictate the point of attachment between chromosomes and spindle microtubules during cell division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Environmental and molecular control of tissue-specific ionocyte differentiation in zebrafish
Authors: Peloggia, J.; Lush, M. E.; Tsai, Y.-Y.; Wood, C.; Piotrowski, T.
Score: 24.3, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575421
Organisms adjust their physiology to cope with environmental fluctuations and maintain fitness. These adaptations occur via genetic changes over multiple generations or through acclimation, a set of reversible phenotypic changes that confer resilience to the individual. Aquatic organisms are subject to dramatic seasonal fluctuations in water salinity, which can affect the function of lateral line mechanosensory hair cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>eDITH: an R-package to spatially project eDNA-based biodiversity across river networks with minimal prior information
Authors: Carraro, L.; Altermatt, F.
Score: 30.6, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575835
Ecological and ecosystem monitoring is rapidly shifting towards using environmental DNA (eDNA) data, particularly in aquatic systems. This approach enables a combined coverage of biodiversity across all major organismal groups and the assessment of ecological indices. Yet, most current approaches are not exploiting the full potential of eDNA data, largely interpreting results in a localized perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Community first response for cardiac arrest: comparing phased dispatch policies through Monte Carlo simulation
Authors: van den Berg, P. L.; Henderson, S. G.; Li, H.; Dicker, B.; Jagtenberg, C. J.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301457
Background Advanced Community First Responder (CFR) systems send so-called phased alerts: notifications with built-in time delays. The policy that defines these delays affects response times, CFR workload and the number of redundant CFR arrivals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Metformin mitigates insulin signaling variations induced by COVID-19 vaccine boosters in type 2 diabetes
Authors: Zhai, L.; ZHUANG, M.; Wong, H. K.; Lin, C.; Zhang, J.; Bao, G.; ZHANG, Y.; Xu, S.; Luo, J.; Yuan, S.; Wong, H. L. X.; Bian, Z.-X.
Score: 73.8, Published: 2024-01-02 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.27.23299358
Diabetes is associated with an increased risk of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vulnerability and mortality. COVID-19 vaccines significantly reduce the risks of serious COVID-19 outcomes, but the impact of COVID-19 vaccines including their effectiveness and adverse effects in patients with diabetes are not well known yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Estimated number of lives directly saved by COVID-19 vaccination programs in the WHO European Region, December 2020 to March 2023
Authors: Mesle, M. M.; Brown, J.; Mook, P.; Katz, M. A.; Hagan, J.; Pastore, R.; Nitzan, D.; Benka, B.; Redlberger-Fritz, M.; Bossuyt, N.; Stouten, V.; Vernemmen, C.; Constantinou, E.; Kyncl, J.; Maly, M.; Sanca, O.; Grove Krause, T.; Skafte Vestergaard, L.; Leino, T.; Poukka, E.; Gkolfinopoulou, K.; Mellou, K.; Maria Tsintziloni, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Reproductive innovation enabled radiation in the deep sea during an ecological crisis
Authors: Brownstein, C.; Zapfe, K.; Lott, S.; Harrington, R. C.; Ghezelayagh, A.; Dornburg, A.; Near, T. J.
Score: 105.7, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575380
Major ecological transitions are thought to fuel evolutionary radiations, but whether they are contingent on the evolution of certain traits is unclear. We show that the rapid ecological transition of anglerfishes into pelagic habitats during a period of major global warming coincided with the origins of sexual parasitism, in which male anglerfishes temporarily attach or permanently fuse to females to mate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Clonal hematopoiesis associated non-small cell lung cancer risk is potentiated by small particulate matter air pollution
Authors: Vlasschaert, C.; Buttigieg, M.; Pershad, Y.; Lanktree, M. B.; Aldrich, M. C.; Rauh, M. J.; Bick, A. G.
Score: 26.2, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.24301439
Small particulate matter air pollution (PM2.5) is a recognized driver of non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) among non-smoking individuals. Inhaled PM2.5 recruits pro-inflammatory macrophages to the air-lung interface, which promotes malignant lung epithelial cell growth and progression to overt cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>The neocortical infrastructure for language involves region-specific patterns of laminar gene expression
Authors: Wong, M. M. K.; Sha, Z.; Lutje, L.; Kong, X.-Z.; Velthuijs, N.; van Heukelum, S.; van de Berg, W. D. J.; Jonkman, L. E.; Fisher, S. E.; Francks, C.
Score: 6.2, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.17.575815
The language network of the human brain has core components in the inferior frontal cortex and superior/middle temporal cortex, with left-hemisphere dominance in most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Comparative analysis of multiplexed in situ gene expression profiling technologies
Authors: Hartman, A.; Satija, R.
Score: 138.0, Published: 2024-01-12 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575135
The burgeoning interest in in situ multiplexed gene expression profiling technologies has opened new avenues for understanding cellular behavior and interactions. In this study, we present a comparative benchmark analysis of six in situ gene expression profiling methods, including both commercially available and academically developed methods, using publicly accessible mouse brain datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>geriatric medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/geriatric-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Hypertension: Examining Variable Blood Pressure&amp;#39;s Role in Cognition and Brain Structure
Authors: Morrison, C.; Oliver, M. D.; Kamal, F.; Dadar, M.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.15.24301335
Structured AbstractO_ST_ABSImportanceC_ST_ABSHypertension is a known risk factor for cognitive decline and structural brain changes in aging and dementia. In addition to high blood pressure (BP), individuals may also experience variable BP, meaning that their BP fluctuates between normal and high. It is currently unclear what the effects of variable BP are on cognition and brain structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Deep representation learning for clustering longitudinal survival data from electronic health records
Authors: Qiu, J.; Hu, Y.; Li, F.; Erzurumluoglu, A. M.; Braenne, I.; Whitehurst, C.; Schmitz, J.; de Jong, J.
Score: 2.6, Published: 2024-01-16 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.24301148
Precision medicine can be defined as providing the right treatment to the right patient at the right time, and it requires the ability to identify clinically relevant patient subgroups with high accuracy. The increasing availability of large-scale electronic health records (EHR) datasets has provided major opportunities for artificial intelligence and machine learning in mining such complex datasets for identifying novel disease subtypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>A Healthcare Service Delivery and Epidemiological Model for Investigating Resource Allocation for Health: The Thanzi La Onse Model
Authors: Hallett, T. B.; Mangal, T. D.; Tamuri, A. U.; Arinaminpathy, N.; Cambiano, V.; Chalkley, M.; Collins, J. H.; Cooper, J.; Gillman, M. S.; Giordano, M.; Graham, M. M.; Graham, W.; Janouskova, E.; Jewell, B. L.; Lin, I. L.; Smith, R. M.; Manthalu, G.; Mnjowe, E.; Mohan, S.; Molaro, M.; Ngambi, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hematology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hematology/</guid>
      <description>Proliferative History Is a Novel Driver of Clinical Outcome in Splenic Marginal Zone Lymphoma
Authors: Parker, H.; Mirandari, A.; Jaramillo Oquendo, C.; Duran-Ferrer, M.; Stevens, B.; Buermann, L.; Amarasinghe, H. E.; Thomas, J.; Kadalayil, L.; Carr, L.; Syeda, S.; Sakthipakan, M.; Parry, M.; Davis, Z.; McIver-Brown, N.; Xochelli, A.; Ennis, S.; Scarfo, L.; Ghia, P.; Kalpadakis, C.; Pangalis, G.; Rossi, D.; Wagner, S.; Ahearne, M.; Seifert, M.; Plass, C.; Weichenhan, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>Risk of Emergent Dolutegravir Resistance Mutations In People Living With HIV: A Rapid Scoping Review
Authors: Chu, C.; Tao, K.; Kouamou, V.; Avalos, A.; Scott, J.; Grant, P. M.; Rhee, S.-Y.; McCluskey, S. M.; Jordan, M. R.; Morgan, R. L.; Shafer, R. W.
Score: 2.2, Published: 2024-01-07 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.24300911
BackgroundDolutegravir (DTG) is a cornerstone of global antiretroviral (ARV) therapy (ART) due to its high efficacy and favorable tolerability. However, limited data exist regarding the risk of virological failure (VF) with emergent integrase strand transfer inhibitor (INSTI) drug-resistance mutations (DRMs) in individuals receiving DTG-containing ART.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Intestinal helminth infection impairs vaccine-induced T cell responses and protection against SARS-CoV-2
Authors: Desai, P.; Karl, C. E.; Ying, B.; Liang, C.-Y.; Garcia-Salum, T.; Santana, A. C.; Caten, F. T.; Urban, J. F.; Elbashir, S. M.; Edwards, D. K.; Ribeiro, S. P.; Thackray, L. B.; Sekaly, R.-P. K.; Diamond, M. S.
Score: 52.8, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.575588
Although vaccines have reduced COVID-19 disease burden, their efficacy in helminth infection endemic areas is not well characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Blood transcriptomics reveal persistent SARS-CoV-2 RNA and candidate biomarkers in Long COVID patients
Authors: MENEZES, S. M.; JAMOULLE, M.; Carletto, M. P.; Van Holm, B.; Moens, L.; Meyts, I.; Maes, P.; Van Weyenbergh, J.
Score: 265.1, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.14.24301293
With an estimated 65 million individuals suffering from Long COVID, validated therapeutic strategies as well as non-invasive biomarkers are direly needed to guide clinical management. We used blood digital transcriptomics in search of viral persistence and Long COVID diagnostic biomarkers in a real-world, general practice-based setting with a long clinical follow-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Self-perceived competence and its determinants among pre-intern (PRINT) doctors in Uganda
Authors: Ssewante, N.; Wekha, G.; Nalunkuma, R.; Sentongo, L. K.; Sanyu, B.; Namusoke, M.; Nkwanga, A.; Ahabwe, R.; Nantagya, V. N.; Kalembe, S. E.; Nampeera, C.; Musoke, P.; Kibwika, P. B.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301259
IntroductionUganda still survives way below the recommended doctor-patient ratio. This problem could be solved by increasing the number of doctors produced in the country annually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Lethal Infection of Human ACE2-Transgenic Mice Caused by SARS-CoV-2-related Pangolin Coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR)
Authors: Wei, L.; Liu, S.; Lu, S.; Luo, S.; An, X.; Fan, H.; Chen, W.; Li, E.; Tong, Y.; Song, L.
Score: 4033.2, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.574008
SARS-CoV-2-related pangolin coronavirus GX_P2V(short_3UTR) can cause 100% mortality in human ACE2-transgenic mice, potentially attributable to late-stage brain infection. This underscores a spillover risk of GX_P2V into humans and provides a unique model for understanding the pathogenic mechanisms of SARS-CoV-2-related viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Discovery and Characterization of a Pan-betacoronavirus S2-binding antibody
Authors: Johnson, N. V.; Wall, S.; Kramer, K.; Holt, C.; Periasamy, S.; Richardson, S.; Suryadevara, N.; Andreano, E.; Paciello, I.; Pierleoni, G.; Piccini, G.; Huang, Y.; Ge, P.; Allen, J.; Uno, N.; Shiakolas, A.; Pilewski, K.; Nargi, R.; Abu-Shmais, A.; Sutton, R.; Parks, R.; Haynes, B.; Carnahan, R.; Crowe, J.; Montomoli, E.; Rappuoli, R.; Bukreyev, A.; Ross, T.; Sautto, G.; Georgiev, I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>A pathogenic variant in RAB32 causes autosomal dominant Parkinsons disease and activates LRRK2 kinase
Authors: Gustavsson, E. K.; Follett, J.; Trinh, J.; Barodia, S. K.; Real, R.; Liu, Z.; Grant-Peters, M.; Fox, J. D.; Appel-Cresswell, S.; Stoessl, J. A.; Rajput, A.; Rajput, A. H.; Auer, R.; Tilney, R.; Sturm, M.; Haack, T. B.; Lesage, S.; Tesson, C.; Brice, A.; Vilarino-Gueell, C.; Ryten, M.; Goldberg, M. S.; West, A. B.; Hu, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>A hierarchical atlas of the human cerebellum for functional precision mapping
Authors: Nettekoven, C. R.; Zhi, D.; Shahshahani, L.; Luisa Pinho, A.; Saadon-Grosmann, N.; Buckner, R. L.; Diedrichsen, J.
Score: 67.4, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.557689
The human cerebellum is activated by a wide variety of cognitive and motor tasks. Previous functional atlases have relied on single task-based or resting-state fMRI datasets. Here, we present a functional atlas that integrates information from 7 large-scale datasets, outperforming existing group atlasses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the Epigenetic Impact of Vegan vs. Omnivorous Diets on Aging: Insights from the Twins Nutrition Study (TwiNS)
Authors: Dwaraka, V. B.; Aronica, L.; Carerras-Gallo, N.; Robinson, J. L.; Hennings, T.; Lin, A.; Turner, L.; Smith, R.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Ebel, E. R.; Carter, M. M.; Sonnenburg, E. D.; Sonnenburg, J. L.; Gardner, C. D.
Score: 95.0, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.26.23300543
Geroscience has emerged as a field focusing on interventions to attenuate molecular changes associated with aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Maternal SARS-CoV-2 impacts fetal placental macrophage programs and placenta-derived microglial models of neurodevelopment
Authors: Shook, L.; Batorsky, R.; De Guzman, R.; McCrea, L.; Brigida, S.; Horng, J.; Sheridan, S.; Kholod, O.; Cook, A.; Li, J.; Goods, B.; Perlis, R.; Edlow, A.
Score: 163.3, Published: 2023-12-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.29.23300544
The SARS-CoV-2 virus activates maternal and placental immune responses, which in the setting of other infections occurring during pregnancy are known to impact fetal brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>A high throughput blood-based assay for the early detection of pancreatic cancer
Authors: Montoya Mira, J. L.; Quentel, A.; Patel, R. K.; Keith, D.; Minnier, J.; David, L.; Esener, S. C.; Sears, R. C.; Lopez, C. D.; Sheppard, B. C.; Demirci, U.; Wong, M. H.; Fischer, J. M.
Score: 2.0, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301220
Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) remains one of the deadliest cancers due in part to the cancer being diagnosed is at a late stage when effective treatment options are limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Early evolution of the ecdysozoan body plan
Authors: Wang, D.; Qiang, Y.; Guo, J.; Vannier, J.; Song, Z.; Peng, J.; Zhang, B.; Sun, J.; Yu, Y.; Zhang, Y.; Zhang, T.; Yang, X.; Han, J.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575973
Extant ecdysozoans (moulting animals) are represented by a great variety of vermiform or articulated organisms. However, controversies remain about the nature of their ancestral body plan although the vermiform hypothesis seems to prevail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Innate Immune Activation and Mitochondrial ROS Invoke Persistent Cardiac Conduction System Dysfunction after COVID-19
Authors: Ashok, D.; Liu, T.; Criscione, J.; Prakash, M.; Kim, B.; Chow, J.; Craney, M.; Papanicolaou, K.; Sidor, A.; Foster, D. B.; Pekosz, A.; Villano, J.; Kim, D.-H.; O&amp;#39;Rourke, B.
Score: 32.3, Published: 2024-01-08 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.05.574280
BackgroundCardiac risk rises during acute SARS-CoV-2 infection and in long COVID syndrome in humans, but the mechanisms behind COVID-19-linked arrhythmias are unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Limited Research Investigating the Added Value of MRI in Predicting Future Cognitive Morbidity in Survivors of Paediatric Brain Tumours: A Call to Action for Clinical Neuroimaging Researchers
Authors: Griffiths-King, D. J.; Delivett, C.; Peet, A.; Waite, J.; Novak, J.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2024-01-13 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.24301212
Survivors of pediatric brain tumour patients are at high risk of cognitive morbidity. There is clinical benefit in being able to reliably predict, at the individual patient level, whether a patient will experience these difficulties or not, the degree of impairment, and the domains affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Pharmacogenomic diversity in psychiatry: Challenges and Opportunities in Africa
Authors: Ahmed, M. B.; Mulugeta, A.; Okewole, N.; Schubert, K. O.; Clark, S.; Iyegbe, C.; Amare, A. T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2024-01-20 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.24301341
BackgroundPharmacogenomic studies on psychiatric drugs have slowly identified genetic variations that influence drug metabolism and treatment effectiveness in patients with mental illness. Because most of these studies predominantly centered on people of European descent, there remains a substantial knowledge gap on the clinical implications of current pharmacogenomic evidence in multi-ancestry populations such as Africans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Antibiotics affect the pharmacokinetics of n-butylphthalide in vivo by altering the intestinal microbiota
Authors: Li, X.; Guo, X.; Liu, Y.; Ren, F.; Li, S.; Yang, X.; Liu, J.; Zhang, Z.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2024-01-14 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575425
ObjectiveN-butylphthalide (NBP) is a monomeric compound extracted from natural plant celery seeds, whether intestinal microbiota alteration can modify its pharmacokinetics is still unclear. The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of intestinal microbiota alteration on the pharmacokinetics of NBP and its related mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>NPAS4 is an allostatic regulator of POMC neuronal activity during diet-induced obesity
Authors: Yoon, J. S.; Gamu, D.; Gibson, W. T.; Lynn, F. C.
Score: 12.2, Published: 2024-01-14 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.574247
RationaleObesity is characterized by a chronic positive energy balance and altered function of cell types that regulate food intake. These cell types include proopiomelanocortin (POMC) neurons in the arcuate nucleus (ARC) of the hypothalamus that detect peripheral signals and promote a reduction in food intake upon activation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>LysM-RLK plays an ancestral symbiotic function in plants
Authors: Teyssier, E.; Grat, S.; Rich, M. K.; Delaux, P.-M.; Mbengue, M.
Score: 36.9, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575821
To ensure their water and mineral nutrition, most land plants form arbuscular mycorrhiza (AM) with soil-borne Glomeromycota fungi. This ~450 million years old symbiosis was key in driving land colonisation by plants. In angiosperms, AM is thought to be initiated via the perception by the host plant of AM-fungi derived chito- and lipochito-oligosaccharides leading to the activation of a conserved signalling pathway referred to as the Common Symbiosis Pathway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>The antidepressant effects of vaporized N,N-Dimethyltryptamine: a preliminary report in treatment-resistant depression
Authors: Falchi-Carvalho, M.; Barros, H.; Bolcont, R.; Laborde, S.; Wiessner, I.; Silva, S. R. B.; Montanini, D.; Barbosa, D.; Teixeira, E.; Florence-Vilela, R.; Almeida, R.; Macedo, R. K. A.; Arichelle, F.; J. Pantrigo, E.; Arcoverde, E.; Galvao-Coelho, N.; Araujo, D. B.; Palhano-Fontes, F.
Score: 31.4, Published: 2024-01-04 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.03.23300610
IntroductionN,N-Dimethyltryptamine (DMT), a naturally occurring psychedelic tryptamine contained in the indigenous ayahuasca brew has shown antidepressant effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Overall Health Effects of mRNA COVID-19 Vaccines in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Hoffmann, S. S.; Nielsen, S.; Thysen, S. M.; Duriseti, R.; Benn, C. S.
Score: 1350.4, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.07.23298573
Importance: Phase 3 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines in children and adolescents showed efficacy in preventing COVID-19 infections. Vaccines may have non-specific effects. Objective: Conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis of the phase 3 trials to assess overall and non-specific health effects of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Multi-contrast high-field quality image synthesis for portable low-field MRI using generative adversarial networks and paired data
Authors: Lucas, A.; Arnold, T. C.; Okar, S. V.; Vadali, C.; Kawatra, K. D.; Ren, Z.; Cao, Q.; Shinohara, R. T.; Schindler, M. K.; Davis, K. A.; Litt, B.; Reich, D. S.; Stein, J. M.
Score: 18.3, Published: 2023-12-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.28.23300409
IntroductionPortable low-field strength (64mT) MRI scanners promise to increase access to neuroimaging for clinical and research purposes, however these devices produce lower quality images compared to high-field scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Sleep moderates the effects of exercise on cognition in chronic stroke: secondary analysis of a randomized trial
Authors: Falck, R. S.; Stein, R. G.; Davis, J. C.; Eng, J. J.; Middleton, L. E.; Hall, P. A.; Liu-Ambrose, T.
Score: 0.5, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.24301392
BackgroundExercise (EX) or cognitive and social enrichment (ENRICH) are two promising strategies for promoting cognitive function post-stroke. Sleep may moderate the effects of these interventions on cogntion, whereby intervention effects may be more robust among individuals suffering from poor sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of dietary vitamin C intake levels and the risk of hyperuricemia and gout based on cross-sectional studies and bi-directional Mendelian randomisation
Authors: Peng, Z.; Wang, X.; Deng, q.; Yan, w.; Zhao, w.; Pu, y.; liu, n.; Gu, l.; peng, j.
Score: 3.5, Published: 2024-01-18 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.18.24301481
Background: Vitamin C, a common antioxidant, may be useful for treating hyperuricemia and gout. The aim of this study was to investigate the risk association between dietary vitamin C intake and hyperuricemia/gout and to test for causality using the bi-directional Mendelian randomisation method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Anticipatory Emotions and Academic Performance: The Role of Boredom in a Preservice Teachers&amp;#39; Lab Experience
Authors: Ochoa de Alda, J. A. G.; Marcos-Merino, J. M.; Valares-Masa, C.; Esteban-Gallego, R.
Score: 2.4, Published: 2024-01-17 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.16.575518
Affective experiences within academic contexts significantly influence educational outcomes. Despite this, the literature reveals a gap in generalising these effects to specific classroom activities, partly arising from the absence of suitable instruments to measure emotions in situational educational scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>De novo-designed minibinders expand the synthetic biology sensing repertoire
Authors: Weinberg, Z. Y.; Soliman, S. S.; Kim, M. S.; Chen, I. P.; Ott, M.; El-Samad, H.
Score: 34.2, Published: 2024-01-15 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.12.575267
Synthetic and chimeric receptors capable of recognizing and responding to user-defined antigens have enabled &amp;#34;smart&amp;#34; therapeutics based on engineered cells. These cell engineering tools depend on antigen sensors which are most often derived from antibodies. Advances in the de novo design of proteins have enabled the design of protein binders with the potential to target epitopes with unique properties and faster production timelines compared to antibodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Unraveling the oscillatory dynamics of mRNA metabolism and chromatin accessibility during the cell cycle through integration of single-cell multiomic data
Authors: Nariya, M. K.; Santiago-Algarra, D.; Tassy, O.; Cerciat, M.; Ye, T.; Riba, A.; Molina, N.
Score: 14.5, Published: 2024-01-11 DOI: 10.1101/2024.01.11.575159
The cell cycle is a highly regulated process that ensures the accurate replication and transmission of genetic information from one generation of cells to the next. It is a fundamental biological process and plays a crucial role in development, growth, and maintenance of all living organisms, and its dysregulation can lead to a number of pathologies such as autoimmune diseases, neurodegenerative diseases, and cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Endangered Przewalski&amp;#39;s horse, Equus przewalskii, cloned from historically cryopreserved cells
Authors: Novak, B. J.; Ryder, O. A.; Houck, M. L.; Putnam, A. S.; Walker, K.; Russell, L.; Russell, B.; Walker, S.; Arenivas, S. S.; Aston, L.; Veneklasen, G.; Ivy, J. A.; Koepfli, K.-P.; Rusnak, A.; Simek, J.; Zhuk, A.; Phelan, R.
Score: 22.9, Published: 2024-01-09 DOI: 10.1101/2023.12.20.572538
Two endangered Przewalskis horse stallions were cloned from fibroblast cells cultured and cryopreserved in 1980.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
