<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>addiction medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/addiction-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Chronic Pain, Cannabis Legalization and Cannabis Use Disorder in Veterans Health Administration Patients, 2005 to 2019
Authors: Hasin, D. S.; Wall, M. M.; Alschuler, D.; Mannes, Z. L.; Malte, C.; Olfson, M.; Keyes, K. M.; Gradus, J. L.; Cerda, M.; Maynard, C. C.; Keyhani, S.; Martins, S. S.; Fink, D. S.; Livne, O.; McDowell, Y.; Sherman, S.; Saxon, A. J.
Score: 2.8, Published: 2023-07-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.10.23292453
Abstract/SummaryO_ST_ABSBackgroundC_ST_ABSThe risk for cannabis use disorder (CUD) is elevated among U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Prebiotic Supplements Correct Oral Probiotic Deficiency for Lasting Allergy Relief
Authors: Han, C.
Score: 3.8, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23291433
Allergic rhinitis has increased in the last fifty years from affecting less than a percent to more than twenty-six percent of the population[1]. Today, more than one hundred million people in the US suffer from these seasonal or yearlong allergies[2]. The hygiene hypothesis was proposed 30 years ago as a potential explanation for this phenomenon[3], and we built on that with the specific oral hygiene hypothesis[4].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Four Individually Identified Paired Dopamine Neurons Signal Taste Punishment in Larval Drosophila
Authors: Weber, D.; Vogt, K.; Miroschnikow, A.; Pankratz, M. J.; Thum, A. S.
Score: 8.7, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550661
Dopaminergic neurons (DANs) carry out multiple tasks in the brain, including the transmission of information related to rewards and punishments across various animal species. They are responsible for evaluating sensory input, storing resultant associations as memory, and continuously updating them based on their relevance and reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Targeted protein editing with an antibody-based system
Authors: Rimon, O.; Konc, J.; Roy Chowdhury, V.; Bernardes, G. J. L.; Vendruscolo, M.
Score: 24.0, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.551006
The chemical modification of proteins is one of the major mechanisms used to regulate the trafficking and function of these macromolecules in the cell. It is therefore of great interest to develop tools to exploit this type of modifications for applications in molecular biology, medicine and biotechnology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Single-cell precision nanotechnology in vivo
Authors: MOLBAY, M.; Kick, B.; Zhao, S.; Todorov, M. I.; Ohn, T.-L.; Roth, S.; Simats, A.; Singh, V.; Khalin, I.; Pan, C.; Singh Bhatia, H.; Hellal, F.; Zeidler, R.; Liesz, A.; Plesnila, N.; Dietz, H.; Erturk, A.
Score: 124.7, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550304
Targeting nanoparticle therapeutics with cellular accuracy in whole organisms could open breakthrough opportunities in precision medicine. However, evaluating and fine-tuning the biodistribution of such systems in the whole organism at the cellular level remains a major obstacle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>getphylo: rapid and automatic generation of multi-locus phylogenetic trees
Authors: Booth, T. J.; Shaw, S.; Weber, T.
Score: 32.9, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.550493
Phylogenetic trees are the primary tool for visualising evolutionary relationships. Traditionally, phylogenies are inferred from manually curated sets of marker genes. As available genomic data increases, there is increasing demand for tools to automatically build phylogeny from assembled genomes. Existing tools rely on reference databases of preselected marker genes, limiting their taxonomic scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Reliable protein-protein docking with AlphaFold, Rosetta and replica-exchange
Authors: Harmalkar, A.; Lyskov, S.; Gray, J. J.
Score: 67.6, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.551063
Despite the recent breakthrough of AlphaFold (AF) in the field of protein sequence-to-structure prediction, modeling protein interfaces and predicting protein complex structures remains challenging, especially when there is a significant conformational change in one or both binding partners. Prior studies have demonstrated that AF-multimer (AFm) can predict accurate protein complexes in only up to 43% of cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>Major data analysis errors invalidate cancer microbiome findings
Authors: Gihawi, A.; Ge, Y.; Lu, J.; Puiu, D.; Xu, A.; Cooper, C. S.; Brewer, D. S.; Pertea, M.; Salzberg, S.
Score: 284.7, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550993
We re-analyzed the data from a recent large-scale study that reported strong correlations between microbial organisms and 33 different cancer types, and that created machine learning predictors with near-perfect accuracy at distinguishing among cancers. We found at least two fundamental flaws in the reported data and in the methods: (1) errors in the genome database and the associated computational methods led to millions of false positive findings of bacterial reads across all samples, largely because most of the sequences identified as bacteria were instead human; and (2) errors in transformation of the raw data created an artificial signature, even for microbes with no reads detected, tagging each tumor type with a distinct signal that the machine learning programs then used to create an apparently accurate classifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Global longitudinal strain and plasma biomarkers for prognosis in heart failure complicated by diabetes
Authors: Iyer, N.; Chan, S.-P.; Liew, O. W.; Chong, J. P. C.; Bryant, J.; Le, T.-T.; Cozzone, P.; Eisenhaber, F.; Foo, R.; Richards, A. M.; Lam, C. S. P.; Ugander, M.; Chin, C. W.-L.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.20.23287472
BackgroundHeart failure (HF) and diabetes are associated with increased incidence and worse prognosis of each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>An adaptive biomolecular condensation response is conserved across environmentally divergent species
Authors: Keyport Kik, S.; Christopher, D.; Glauninger, H.; Wong Hickernell, C.; Bard, J. A. M.; Ford, M.; Sosnick, T. R.; Drummond, D. A.
Score: 39.4, Published: 2023-07-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.551061
Cells must sense and respond to sudden maladaptive environmental changes--stresses--to survive and thrive. Across eukaryotes, stresses such as heat shock trigger conserved responses: growth arrest, a specific transcriptional response, and biomolecular condensation of protein and mRNA into structures known as stress granules under severe stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dentistry and oral medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dentistry-and-oral-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Oral health vulnerability and its associated risk factors among tribal elderly people in Bangladesh: a pilot study
Authors: Barua, S.; Bosu, S.; Haque, M. F.; Bosak, L.; Rashid, M. R.; Zaman, S. R.; Rahman, M. F.; Rahman, M. M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293159
BackgroundTribal elderly is a vulnerable population due to their geographic location and lack of access to healthcare services. This study aims to assess the oral health status of tribal elderly in Bangladesh and identify any associated risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>A conserved fertilization complex of Izumo1, Spaca6, and Tmem81 mediates sperm-egg interaction in vertebrates
Authors: Deneke, V. E.; Blaha, A.; Lu, Y.; Draper, J. M.; Phan, C. S.; Panser, K.; Schleiffer, A.; Jacob, L.; Humer, T.; Stejskal, K.; Krssakova, G.; Handler, D.; Kamoshita, M.; Vance, T. D. R.; Roitinger, E.; Lee, J. E.; Ikawa, M.; Pauli, A.
Score: 45.0, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550750
Fertilization, the fusion of sperm and egg, is essential for sexual reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Predictive microbial community changes across a temperature gradient
Authors: Sun, X.; Folmar, J.; Favier, A.; Pyenson, N.; Sanchez, A.; Rebolleda-Gomez, M.
Score: 31.2, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550899
A central challenge in community ecology is predicting the effects of abiotic factors on community assembly. In particular, microbial communities play a central role in the ecosystem, but we do not understand how changing factors like temperature are going to affect community composition or function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Worldwide trends in COVID-19 related attacks against healthcare
Authors: Duffhues, W.; Barten, D.; De Cauwer, H.; Mortelmans, L.; van Osch, F.; Tin, D.; Koopmans, M.; Ciottone, G.
Score: 23.2, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292819
BackgroundDuring the COVID-19 pandemic, violence targeting healthcare reportedly increased. Attacks against healthcare have the potential to impair the public health response and threaten the availability of healthcare services. However, there is little systematic understanding of the extent and characteristics of healthcare attacks in the setting of a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Diabetes Detection from Diabetic Retinopathy-Absent Images Using Deep Learning Methodology
Authors: Rom, Y.; Aviv, R.; Cohen, G. Y.; Friedman, Y. E.; Dvey-Aharon, Z.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-07-31 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.23287515
Aims Diabetes is one of the leading causes of morbidity and mortality in the United States and worldwide. This research aimed to develop an artificial intelligence (AI) machine learning model which can detect the presence of diabetes from fundus imagery of eyes without diabetic eye disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic prediction of common and rare diseases
Authors: Carrasco-Zanini, J.; Pietzner, M.; Davitte, J.; Surendran, P.; Croteau-Chonka, D. C.; Robins, C.; Torralbo, A.; Tomlinson, C.; Fitzpatrick, N.; Ytsma, C.; Kanno, T.; Gade, S.; Freitag, D.; Ziebell, F.; Denaxas, S.; Betts, J. C.; Wareham, N. J.; Hemingway, H.; Scott, R. A.; Langenberg, C.
Score: 33.9, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.23292811
BackgroundFor many diseases there are delays in diagnosis due to a lack of objective biomarkers for disease onset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Fruitless mating with the exes: the irreversible parthenogenesis in a stick insect
Authors: Nozaki, T.; Chikami, Y.; Yano, K.; Sato, R.; Suetsugu, K.; Kaneko, S.
Score: 203.2, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550994
Parthenogenetic lineages, common in many animals, have sparked debate about their evolutionary persistence. Even after the loss of male individuals, males can survive on the genomes; in fact, rarely occurring males were described in many asexual lineages. Theoretical predictions suggest that genes related to male sexual traits in parthenogenetic lineages will decay over long evolutionary times free from the pressure of stabilizing selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Genome-wide analyses reveal widespread genetic overlap between neurological and psychiatric disorders and a convergence of biological associations related to the brain
Authors: Smeland, O. B.; Kutrolli, G.; Bahrami, S.; Fominykh, V.; Parker, N.; Hindley, G.; Rodevand, L.; Jaholkowski, P.; Tesfaye, M.; Parekh, P.; Elvsaashagen, T.; Grotzinger, A. D.; The International Multiple Sclerosis Genetics Consortium (IMSGC), ; The International Headache Genetics Consortium (IHGC), ; Steen, N. E.; van der Meer, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>isGWAS: ultra-high-throughput, scalable and equitable inference of genetic associations with disease
Authors: Foley, C. N.; Kuncheva, Z.; Marioni, R.; Runz, H.; Sun, B.
Score: 39.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.550074
Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have proven a powerful tool for human geneticists to generate biological insights or hypotheses for drug discovery. Nevertheless, a dependency on sensitive individual-level data together with ever-increasing cohort sample sizes, numbers of variants and phenotypes studied put a strain on existing algorithms, limiting the GWAS approach from maximising potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent profiling of multiscale 3D genome organization and gene expression in single mammalian cells
Authors: Zhou, T.; Zhang, R.; Jia, D.; Doty, R. T.; Munday, A. D.; Gao, D.; Xin, L.; Abkowitz, J. L.; Duan, Z.; Ma, J.
Score: 49.0, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.549578
The organization of mammalian genomes within the nucleus features a complex, multiscale three-dimensional (3D) architecture. The functional significance of these 3D genome features, however, remains largely elusive due to limited single-cell technologies that can concurrently profile genome organization and transcriptional activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>PheMIME: An Interactive Web App and Knowledge Base for Phenome-Wide, Multi-Institutional Multimorbidity Analysis
Authors: Zhang, S.; Strayer, N.; Vessels, T.; Choi, K.; Wang, G. W.; Li, Y.; Bejan, C. A.; Hsi, R. S.; Bick, A. G.; Velez Edwards, D. R.; Savona, M. R.; Philips, E. J.; Pulley, J.; Self, W. H.; Hopkins, W. C.; Roden, D. M.; Smoller, J.; Ruderfer, D. M.; Xu, Y.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health policy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-policy/</guid>
      <description>The Introduction of Social Health Insurance and Health Care Seeking Behavior in Urban Ethiopia
Authors: Zarepour, Z.; Mebratie, A.; Shamebo, D.; Shigute, Z.; Alemu, G.; Bedi, A. S.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.05.23292262
ObjectivesIn recent years, to enhance access to and use of health care the government of Ethiopia has introduced voluntary Community Based Health Insurance (CBHI) schemes for the rural and informal sectors of the economy. After years of planning and the ratification of a legal framework the government proposes to introduce a compulsory Social Health Insurance (SHI) program for formal sector employees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence in Biomedicine: Systematic Review
Authors: Gabashvili, I. S.
Score: 12.5, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292672
Artificial Intelligence (AI) is a rapidly progressing technology with its applications expanding exponentially over the past decade. While initial breakthroughs predominantly focused on deep learning and computer vision, recent advancements have facilitated a shift towards natural language processing and beyond. This includes generative models, like ChatGPT, capable of understanding the grammar of software code, analog signals, and molecular structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Megakaryocyte infection by SARS-CoV-2 drives the formation of pathogenic afucosylated IgG antibodies in mice
Authors: Mabrouk, M.; Jalali, F.; Zaid, N.; Naya, A.; Khyatti, M.; Khalki, L.; Guessous, F.; Zaid, Y.
Score: 684.3, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.14.549113
More than 90% of total human plasma immunoglobulin G (IgG) is found in a fucosylated form, but specific IgGs with low core fucosylation (afucosylated IgGs) are found in response to infections with enveloped viruses and to alloantigens on blood cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Multimodal Molecular Imaging Reveals Tissue-Based T Cell Activation and Viral RNA Persistence for Up to Two Years Following COVID-19
Authors: Peluso, M. J.; Ryder, D. M.; Flavell, R.; Wang, Y.; Levi, J.; LaFranchi, B. H.; Deveau, T.-M. M.; Buck, A. M.; Munter, S. E.; Asare, K. A.; Aslam, M.; Koch, W.; Szabo, G.; Hoh, R.; Deswal, M.; Rodriguez, A.; Buitrago, M.; Tai, V.; Shrestha, U.; Lu, S.; Goldberg, S. A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>medical education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/medical-education/</guid>
      <description>Medical Students&amp;#39; Attitudes toward AI in Medicine and their Expectations for Medical Education
Authors: Kimmerle, J.; Timm, J.; Festl-Wietek, T.; Cress, U.; Herrmann-Werner, A.
Score: 9.2, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292877
Artificial intelligence (AI) is used in a variety of contexts in medicine. This involves the use of algorithms and software that analyze digital information to make diagnoses and suggest adapted therapies. It is unclear, however, what medical students know about AI in medicine, how they evaluate its application, and what they expect from their medical training accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Genomic epidemiology of European Aspergillus fumigatus causing COVID-19-associated pulmonary aspergillosis in Europe
Authors: Simmons, B.; Rhodes, J.; Rogers, T.; Talento, A. F.; Griffin, A.; Mansfield, M.; Abdolrasouli, A.; Verweij, P. E.; Bosch, T.; Schelenz, S.; Hemmings, S.; Sheehan, D.; Fisher, M. C.
Score: 37.8, Published: 2023-07-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.550109
The opportunistic fungus Aspergillus fumigatus has been found to cause coinfections in patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 virus infection, leading to COVID-19-associated pulmonary aspergillosis (CAPA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Cryo-EM structure of cell-free synthesized human histamine H2 receptor coupled to heterotrimeric Gs protein in lipid nanodisc environment
Authors: Koeck, Z.; Schnelle, K.; Persechino, M.; Umbach, S.; Schihada, H.; Januliene, D.; Parey, K.; Pockes, S.; Kolb, P.; Doetsch, V.; Moeller, A.; Hilger, D.; Bernhard, F.
Score: 22.0, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.27.550782
Here we describe the cryo-electron microscopy structure of the human histamine 2 receptor (H2R) in an active conformation with bound histamine and in complex with Gs heterotrimeric protein at an overall resolution of 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>Prevalence and characteristics of monogenic disease in adult kidney stone formers
Authors: Anderegg, M. A.; Olinger, E. G.; Bargagli, M.; Geraghty, R.; Pohlmeier, L.; Nater, A.; Bruggmann, R.; Sayer, J. A.; Vogt, B.; Schaller, A.; Fuster, D. G.
Score: 5.5, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292924
Molecular mechanisms of kidney stone formation remain unknown in most patients. Previous studies showed a high heritability of nephrolithiasis, but data on prevalence and characteristics of monogenic disease in unselected adults with nephrolithiasis are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>The coupling between brain connectivity and heartbeat dynamics unveils the altered interoceptive mechanisms in Parkinson&amp;#39;s disease
Authors: Candia-Rivera, D.; Vidailhet, M.; Chavez, M.; de Vico Fallani, F.
Score: 6.8, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23292942
Parkinsons disease (PD) is often known for its classical motor symptoms, but non-motor symptoms are often reported including interoceptive and autonomic dysfunctions. Autonomic dysfunctions, such as cardiovascular, urinary, or thermoregulatory abnormalities, are more prone to be associated with motor and cognitive decline, as well as increase the risk of mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Constructed languages are processed by the same brain mechanisms as natural languages
Authors: Malik-Moraleda, S.; Taliaferro, M.; Shannon, S.; Jhingan, N.; Swords, S.; Peterson, D. J.; Frommer, P.; Okrand, M.; Sams, J.; Cardwell, R.; Freeman, C.; Fedorenko, E.
Score: 125.8, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550667
What constitutes a language? Natural languages share some features with other domains: from math, to music, to gesture. However, the brain mechanisms that process linguistic input are highly specialized, showing little or no response to diverse non-linguistic tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obstetrics and gynecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/obstetrics-and-gynecology/</guid>
      <description>Proteomic studies of human placentas reveal partnerships associated with preeclampsia, diabetes, gravidity, and labor.
Authors: Ho, S. J.; Chaput, D.; Sinkey, R. G.; Garces, A.; New, E. P.; Okuka, M.; Sang, P.; Arlier, S.; Semerci, N.; Steffensen, T. S.; Rutherford, T. J.; Alsina, A. E.; Cai, J.; Anderson, M. L.; Magness, R. R.; Uversky, V. N.; Cummings, D. A. T.; Tsibris, J. C.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.23.23292673</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>occupational and environmental health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/occupational-and-environmental-health/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge and practice of road safety measures among motor-bikers in Bangladesh: a cross-sectional study
Authors: Das, S. K.; Tamannur, T.; Nesa, A.; Al Noman, A.; Dey, P.; Kundu, S. K.; Sultana, H.; Riaz, B. K.; ANM, S. I.; Sharower, G.; Dhar, B. K.; Rahman, M. M.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293162
IntroductionRoad traffic accidents (RTAs) including motorbike accidents are the leading cause of death for teenagers between 15 and 29 and have been a serious concern in low- and middle-income countries like Bangladesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Mistletoe as a Therapeutic Option in Cancer Patients: a scoping review protocol
Authors: Cordeiro, M. M.; Malta, F. A. P. S.; Goncalves, D. C.
Score: 1.6, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.29.23293280
ObjectiveThis scoping review aims to identify, map and provide an overview of the studies investigating the therapeutic use of Viscum Album L. (mistletoe) in cancer patients. By identifying pivotal patterns and research gaps in the existing literature on Viscum therapy, this review intends to offer valuable insights and supportive information to better inform future research efforts in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pain medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pain-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Industry payments to anesthesiologists in the United States between 2014 and 2022
Authors: Murayama, A.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293096
BackgroundFinancial relationships between physicians and the healthcare industry could be beneficial to improve patient care, but could lead to conflicts of interest. However, there was no study specifically evaluating the extent of financial relationships between anesthesiologists and the healthcare industry in the United States. MethodsUsing the Open Payments Database between 2014 and 2022, this longitudinal cross-sectional study examined the size, prevalence and trends of general (non-research) payments made by the healthcare industry to all anesthesiologists in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Identification of Late Pleistocene and Holocene fossil lizards from Hall&amp;#39;s Cave and a primer on morphological variation in North American lizard skulls
Authors: Ledesma, D. T.; Scarpetta, S. G.; Jacisin, J. J.; Meza, A.; Kemp, M. E.
Score: 11.8, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.549934
Fossil identification practices have a profound effect on our interpretation of the past because these identifications form the basis for downstream analyses. Therefore, well-supported fossil identifications are paramount for examining the impact of past environmental changes on populations and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Self-Supervised Learning for Histopathology with Masked Image Modeling
Authors: Filiot, A.; Ghermi, R.; Olivier, A.; Jacob, P.; Fidon, L.; Mac Kain, A.; Saillard, C.; Schiratti, J.-B.
Score: 8.0, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.21.23292757
Computational pathology is revolutionizing the field of pathology by integrating advanced computer vision and machine learning technologies into diagnostic workflows. It offers unprecedented opportunities for improved efficiency in treatment decisions by allowing pathologists to achieve higher precision and objectivity in disease classification, tumor microenvironment description and identification of new biomarkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>One-Year Follow-up of Young People with ME/CFS Following Infectious Mononucleosis by Epstein-Barr Virus
Authors: Pricoco, R.; Meidel, P.; Hofberger, T.; Zietemann, H.; Mueller, Y.; Wiehler, K.; Michel, K.; Paulick, J.; Leone, A.; Haegele, M.; Mayer-Huber, S.; Gerrer, K.; Mittelstrass, K.; Scheibenbogen, C.; Renz-Polster, H.; Mihatsch, L.; Behrends, U.
Score: 57.6, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.23293082
BackgroundInfectious mononucleosis, caused by the Epstein-Barr Virus (EBV-IM), has been linked to the development of myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue-syndrome (ME/CFS) in children, adolescents, and young adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>A new paradigm of intracrine free fatty acid receptor 4 signaling at lipid droplets
Authors: Calebiro, D.; O&amp;#39;Brien, S. L.; Tripp, E.; Smith, G.; Boufersaoui, A.; Roberts, J.; Pike, J. A.; Correia, J.; Miljus, T. A.; Tennant, D. A.; Hudson, B. D.; Milligan, G.; Gerhart-Hines, Z.; Schwartz, T. W.
Score: 15.1, Published: 2023-07-30 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.28.550805
G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs), once thought to be active exclusively at the plasma 2 membrane, have been shown to signal from multiple intracellular membrane compartments, 3 including endosomes and the Golgi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>β-hydroxybutyrate is a metabolic regulator of proteostasis in the aged and Alzheimer disease brain
Authors: Madhavan, S. S.; Roa Diaz, S.; Peralta, S.; Nomura, M.; King, C. D.; Lin, A.; Bhaumik, D.; Shah, S.; Blade, T.; Gray, W.; Chamoli, M.; Eap, B.; Panda, O.; Diaz, D.; Garcia, T. Y.; Stubbs, B. J.; Lithgow, G. J.; Schilling, B.; Verdin, E.; Chaudhuri, A.; Newman, J. C.
Score: 43.0, Published: 2023-07-03 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>The WY domain of an RxLR effector drives interactions with a host target phosphatase to mimic host regulatory proteins and promote Phytophthora infestans infection.
Authors: Bentham, A. R.; Wang, W.; Trusch, F.; Varden, F.; Birch, P. R.; Banfield, M. J.
Score: 24.7, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550319
Plant pathogens manipulate the cellular environment of the host to facilitate infection and colonization, often leading to plant diseases. To accomplish this, many specialized pathogens secrete virulence proteins called effectors into the host cell, which subvert processes such as immune signalling, gene transcription, and host metabolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>You can change your life through sports: Physical activity interventions to improve the health and wellbeing of adults experiencing homelessness: a mixed methods systematic review
Authors: Dawes, J. F.; Rogans-Watson, R.; Broderick, J.
Score: 10.9, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293203
ObjectivesSystematically synthesise evidence of physical activity interventions for people experiencing homelessness (PEH). DesignMixed-methods systematic review. Data sourcesEMBASE, Web of Science, CINAHL, PubMed (MEDLINE), PsycINFO, SPORTDiscus, and Cochrane Library, searched from inception to October 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Familial risk of postpartum psychosis
Authors: Kepinska, A. P.; Robakis, T.; Humphreys, K.; Liu, X.; Kahn, R. S.; Munk-Olsen, T.; Bergink, V.; Mahjani, B.
Score: 15.3, Published: 2023-07-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.20.23292910
BackgroundPostpartum psychosis, a mood disorder triggered by childbirth, is one of the most severe psychiatric conditions, with high risks of suicide and infanticide if untreated. While it is evident that genetic factors play a crucial role in disorder risk, the exact extent of their importance is yet to be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Impact of Community Masking on SARS-CoV-2 Transmission in Ontario after Adjustment for Differential Testing by Age and Sex
Authors: Peng, A.; Bosco, S.; Tuite, A.; Simmons, A.; Fisman, D.
Score: 881.1, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293155
BackgroundUse of masks and respirators for prevention of respiratory infectious disease transmission is not new, but has proven controversial, and even politically polarizing during the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. In the Canadian province of Ontario, mask mandates were introduced by the 34 regional health authorities in an irregular fashion from June to September 2020, creating a quasi-experiment that can be used to evaluate impact of community mask mandates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hip strengthening exercise dosage is not associated with clinical improvements after total hip arthroplasty - a prospective cohort study (the PHETHAS-1 study)
Authors: Madsen, M. N.; Mikkelsen, L. R.; Rathleff, M. S.; Thorborg, K.; Kallemose, T.; Bandholm, T.
Score: 14.5, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.12.23292442
PurposePostoperative rehabilitation exercise is commonly prescribed after total hip arthroplasty (THA), but its efficacy compared to no or minimal rehabilitation exercise has been questioned. Preliminary efficacy would be indicated if a dose-response relationship exists between performed exercise dose and degree of postoperative recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>respiratory medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/respiratory-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Trends in serotype distribution and disease severity in adults hospitalised with Streptococcus pneumoniae infection in Bristol and Bath: a retrospective cohort study, 2006-2022
Authors: Hyams, C.; Challen, R.; Hettle, D.; Amin-Chowdhury, Z.; Grimes, C.; Ruffino, G.; Conway, R.; Heath, R.; North, P.; Malin, A.; Maskell, N. A.; Williams, P.; Williams, O. M.; Ladhani, S. N.; Danon, L.; Finn, A.
Score: 4.1, Published: 2023-07-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.03.30.23287917
BackgroundPaediatric pneumococcal conjugate vaccination (PCV) has reduced adult PCV-serotype disease: PCV7 has greater indirect effects than PCV13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rheumatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rheumatology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-omics analysis in primary T cells elucidates mechanisms behind disease associated genetic loci
Authors: Shi, C.; Zhao, D.; Rossi, S.; Frantzeskos, A.; Ding, J.; Ferrazzano, C.; Wynn, C.; Hum, R.; Richards, E.; Gupta, M.; Yap, C. F.; Plant, D.; Grencis, R.; Martin, P.; Adamson, A.; Eyre, S.; Bowes, J.; Barton, A.; Ho, P.; Rattray, M.; Orozco, G.
Score: 13.6, Published: 2023-07-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.19.23292550
In this study, we present the most extensive dataset of chromatin conformation data with matching gene expression and chromatin accessibility from primary T cells to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT identifies gender disparities in scientific peer review
Authors: Verharen, J. P. H.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2023-07-19 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.18.549552
The peer review process is a critical step in ensuring the quality of scientific research. However, its subjectivity has raised concerns. To investigate this issue, I examined over 500 publicly available peer review reports from 200 published neuroscience papers in 2022-2023. OpenAIs generative artificial intelligence ChatGPT was used to analyze language use in these reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sexual and reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sexual-and-reproductive-health/</guid>
      <description>The MidPIC study: Midwives knowledge, perspectives and learning needs regarding preconception and interconception care
Authors: Bradfield, Z.; Leefhelm, E.; Soh, S.-E.; Black, K.; Boyle, J.; Kuliukas, L.; Harrison, C.; Homer, C. S.; Smith, R. M.; Skouteris, H.
Score: 1.8, Published: 2023-08-01 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.31.23293432
Background: Preconception and interconception care improves the health outcomes of women and communities. Problem: Little is known about how prepared and willing Australian midwives are to provide preconception and interconception care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sports medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/sports-medicine/</guid>
      <description>LigaNET: A multi-modal deep learning approach to predict the risk of subsequent anterior cruciate ligament injury after surgery
Authors: Singh, M.; Han, M.; Karimi, D.; Kim, J. Y.; Flannery, S. W.; BEAR Trial Team, ; Murray, M. M.; Fleming, B. C.; Gholipour, A.; Kiapour, A. M.
Score: 3.2, Published: 2023-07-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.23293102
Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries are a common cause of soft tissue injuries in young active individuals, leading to a significant risk of premature joint degeneration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Gas vesicle-blood interactions enhance ultrasound imaging contrast
Authors: Ling, B.; Ko, J. H.; Stordy, B.; Zhang, Y.; Didden, T. F.; Malounda, D.; Swift, M. B.; Chan, W. C. W.; Shapiro, M. G.
Score: 10.4, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.24.550434
Gas vesicles (GVs) are genetically encoded, air-filled protein nanostructures of broad interest for biomedical research and clinical applications, acting as imaging and therapeutic agents for ultrasound, magnetic resonance, and optical techniques. However, the biomedical applications of GVs as a systemically injectable nanomaterial have been hindered by a lack of understanding of GVs interactions with blood components, which can significantly impact in vivo performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>CURTAIN - A Unique Web-based tool for exploration and sharing of MS-based proteomics data
Authors: Phung, T. K.; Berndsen, K.; Phan, T. L.; Muqit, M. M.; Alessi, D. R.; Nirujogi, R. S.
Score: 26.3, Published: 2023-07-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.25.550405
To facilitate analysis and sharing of mass spectrometry (MS)-based proteomics data we created tools called CURTAIN (https://curtain.proteo.info) and CURTAIN-PTM (https://curtainptm.proteo.info). These enable the non-MS expert to interactively peruse volcano plots; deconvolute primary experimental data to individual replicates that can be visualized in bar charts or violin plots allowing statistical analysis; and export of plots in SVG format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transplantation</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/transplantation/</guid>
      <description>Routine surveillance of kidney allograft rejection using a fully automated urinary CXCL9 and CXCL10 immunoassay
Authors: Tinel, C.; Sauvaget, V.; Aouni, L.; Lamarthee, B.; Leclaire, C.; Legendre, C.; Marquet, P.; Normand, C.; Rabant, M.; Terzi, F.; Anglicheau, D.
Score: 3.0, Published: 2023-07-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.07.26.23293106
BackgroundFor kidney transplant recipients, assessing non-invasively the individualized risk of acute rejection is one of the most unmet need. Urinary chemokines are one of the short-term most promising biomarkers, because of their simple and low-cost analytical method in easily accessible samples, and their high diagnostic performance consistently assessed over the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 10:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>If it&amp;#39;s there, could it be a bear?
Authors: Foxon, F.
Score: 814.5, Published: 2023-07-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.01.14.524058
It has been suggested that the American black bear (Ursus americanus) may be responsible for a significant number of purported sightings of an alleged unknown species of hominid in North America. Previous analyses have identified correlation between sasquatch or bigfoot sightings and black bear populations in the Pacific Northwest using ecological niche models and simple models of expected animal sightings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:29:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
