<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRxiv2</title>
    <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRxiv2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>allergy and immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/allergy-and-immunology/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of immunity induced by Omicron breakthrough infection versus monovalent SARS-CoV-2 intramuscular booster reveals differences in mucosal and systemic antibody responses
Authors: Nantel, S.; Sheikh-Mohamed, S.; Chao, G. Y. C.; Kurtesi, A.; Hu, Q.; Wood, H.; Colwill, K.; Li, Z.; Liu, Y.; Seifried, L.; Bourdin, B.; McGeer, A.; Hardy, W. R.; Rojas, O. L.; Ostrowski, M. A.; Brockman, M. A.; Piccirillo, C. A.; Quach, C.; Rini, J. M.; Gingras, A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>animal behavior and cognition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/animal-behavior-and-cognition/</guid>
      <description>A history of avoidance does not impact extinction learning in male rats
Authors: Lopez-Moraga, A.; Luyten, L.; Beckers, T.
Score: 11.5, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.558816
Pervasive avoidance is one of the central symptoms of all anxiety-related disorders. In treatment, avoidance behaviors are typically discouraged because they are assumed to maintain anxiety. Yet, it is not clear that engaging in avoidance is always detrimental. In this study, we used a platform-mediated avoidance task to investigate the influence of avoidance history on extinction learning in male rats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biochemistry/</guid>
      <description>Target DNA-dependent activation mechanism of the prokaryotic immune system SPARTA
Authors: Finocchio, G.; Koopal, B.; Potocnik, A.; Heijstek, C.; Jinek, M.; Swarts, D. C.
Score: 26.7, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.23.559129
In both prokaryotic and eukaryotic innate immune systems, TIR domains function as NADases that degrade the key metabolite NAD&amp;#43; or generate signaling molecules. Catalytic activation of TIR domains requires oligomerization, but how this is achieved varies in distinct immune systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioengineering</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioengineering/</guid>
      <description>Click editing enables programmable genome writing using DNA polymerases and HUH endonucleases
Authors: da Silva, J. F.; Tou, C. J.; King, E. M.; Eller, M. L.; Ma, L.; Rufino-Ramos, D.; Kleinstiver, B. P.
Score: 109.3, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.557440
Genome editing technologies that install diverse edits can widely enable genetic studies and new therapeutics. Here we develop click editing, a genome writing platform that couples the advantageous properties of DNA-dependent DNA polymerases with RNA-programmable nickases (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>Structural phylogenetics unravels the evolutionary diversification of communication systems in gram-positive bacteria and their viruses
Authors: Moi, D.; Bernard, C.; Steinegger, M.; Nevers, Y.; Langleib, M.; Dessimoz, C.
Score: 210.6, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.558401
Recent advances in AI-based protein structure modeling have yielded remarkable progress in predicting protein structures. Since structures are constrained by their biological function, their geometry tends to evolve more slowly than the underlying amino acids sequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biophysics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/biophysics/</guid>
      <description>Bacterial antiviral defense pathways encode eukaryotic-like ubiquitination systems
Authors: Chambers, L. R.; Ye, Q.; Cai, J.; Gong, M.; Ledvina, H. E.; Zhou, H.; Whiteley, A. T.; Suhandynata, R. T.; Corbett, K. D.
Score: 47.7, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.559546
Ubiquitination and related pathways play crucial roles in protein homeostasis, signaling, and innate immunity1-3. In these pathways, an enzymatic cascade of E1, E2, and E3 proteins conjugates ubiquitin or a ubiquitin-like protein (Ubl) to targetprotein lysine residues4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cancer biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cancer-biology/</guid>
      <description>ecDNA amplification of MYC drives intratumor copy-number heterogeneity and adaptation to stress in PDAC
Authors: Malinova, A.; Schreyer, D.; Fiorini, E.; Pasini, D.; Bevere, M.; D&amp;#39;Agosto, S.; Andreani, S.; Lupo, F.; Veghini, L.; Grimaldi, S.; Pedron, S.; Nourse, C.; Salvia, R.; Malleo, G.; Ruzzenente, A.; Guglielmi, A.; Milella, M.; Lawlor, R. T.; Luchini, C.; Pilarsky, C.; Scarpa, A.; Tuveson, D.; Bailey, P.; Corbo, V.
Score: 19.9, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cardiovascular medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cardiovascular-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Common and Rare Variant Contributions to Bradyarrhythmias from Multi-Ancestry Meta-Analyses
Authors: Weng, L.-C.; Rämö, J. T.; Jurgens, S. J.; Khurshid, S.; Chaffin, M.; Hall, A. W.; Morrill, V. N.; Nauffal, V.; Sun, Y. V.; Beer, D.; Lee, S.; Nadkarni, G.; Duong, T.; Wang, B.; Czuba, T.; Austin, T. R.; Yoneda, Z. T.; Friedman, D. J.; Clayton, A.; Hyman, M. C.; Judy, R. L.; Skanes, A. C.; Orland, K. M.; Treu, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cell biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/cell-biology/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling the ultrastructural landscape of native extracellular matrix via lift-out cryo-FIBSEM and cryo-ET
Authors: Zens, B.; Faessler, F.; Hansen, J. M.; Hauschild, R.; Datler, J.; Hodirnau, V.-V.; Zheden, V.; Alanko, J.; Sixt, M.; Schur, F. K.
Score: 50.8, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.559261
The extracellular matrix (ECM) is a highly hydrated, three-dimensional network composed of various macromolecules and signaling factors. It serves as a structural scaffold for cells and plays an essential role in the regulation of numerous cellular processes, including cell migration, adhesion, and proliferation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dermatology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/dermatology/</guid>
      <description>Testing the Limits of Language Models: A Conversational Framework for Medical AI Assessment
Authors: Johri, S.; Jeong, J.; Tran, B. A.; Schlessinger, D. I.; Wongvibulsin, S.; Cai, Z. R.; Daneshjou, R.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 40.5, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295399
Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise for medical diagnosis, but traditional evaluations using static exam questions overlook the complexity of real-world clinical dialogues. We introduce a multi-agent conversational framework where doctor-AI and patient-AI agents interact to diagnose medical conditions, evaluated by a grader-AI agent and medical experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developmental biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/developmental-biology/</guid>
      <description>Open top multi sample dual view light sheet microscope for live imaging of large multicellular systems
Authors: Moos, F.; Suppinger, S.; de Medeiros, G.; Oost, K.; Boni, A.; Remy, C.; Weevers, S.; Tsiairis, C. D.; Strnad, P.; Liberali, P.
Score: 42.4, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.559925
Multicellular systems grow over the course of weeks from single cells to tissues or even full organisms composed of several thousands of cells, making live imaging of such samples challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ecology/</guid>
      <description>Insect biomass of protected habitats under the impact of arable farming in Germany
Authors: Muehlethaler, R.; Koethe, S.; Hoerren, T.; Sorg, M.; Eichler, L.; Lehmann, G. U. C.
Score: 36.0, Published: 2023-09-24 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.559203
Five years after the well-known study on insect biomass decline in nature protected habitats in Germany over three decades, the project DINA (Diversity of Insects in Nature protected Areas) has investigated the status of insects in 21 selected nature reserves across Germany in the years 2020 and 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emergency medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/emergency-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Alternative Defibrillation Strategies for Refractory Ventricular Fibrillation: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis
Authors: Perna, B.; Guarino, M.; De Fazio, R.; Esposito, L.; Portoraro, A.; Rossin, F.; Remelli, F.; Trevisan, C.; Raparelli, V.; Marasco, G.; Barbara, G.; Petrini, S.; Vason, M.; Spampinato, M. D.; De Giorgio, R.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296188
Background: Cardiac arrest with refractory ventricular fibrillation (rVF) represents a dramatic medical emergency. Despite recent advances, its treatment is challenging and burdened by limited evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>endocrinology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/endocrinology/</guid>
      <description>Glycemic outcomes of a family-focused intervention for adults with type 2 diabetes: Main, mediated, and subgroup effects from the FAMS 2.0 RCT
Authors: Nelson, L. A.; Spieker, A. J.; Greevy, R. A.; Roddy, M. K.; LeStourgeon, L. M.; Bergner, E. M.; El-Rifai, M.; Aikens, J. E.; Wolever, R. Q.; Elasy, T. A.; Mayberry, L. S.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-12 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.11.23295374
AimsFamily/friends Activation to Motivate Self-care (FAMS) is a self-care support intervention delivered via mobile phones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Endemic means change as SARS-CoV-2 evolves
Authors: Otto, S.; MacPherson, A.; Colijn, C.
Score: 28.7, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.23296264
COVID-19 has become endemic, with dynamics that reflect the waning of immunity and re-exposure, by contrast to the epidemic phase driven by exposure in immunologically naive populations. Endemic does not, however, mean constant. Further evolution of SARS-CoV-2, as well as changes in behaviour and public health policy, continue to play a major role in the endemic load of disease and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>evolutionary biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/evolutionary-biology/</guid>
      <description>Strong environmental memory revealed by experimental evolution in static and fluctuating environments
Authors: Abreu, C. I.; Mathur, S.; Petrov, D. A.
Score: 42.1, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.14.557739
Evolution in a static environment, such as a laboratory setting with constant and uniform conditions, often proceeds via large-effect beneficial mutations that may become maladaptive in other environments. Conversely, natural settings require populations to endure environmental fluctuations. A sensible assumption is that the fitness of a lineage in a fluctuating environment is the time-average of its fitness over the sequence of static conditions it encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gastroenterology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/gastroenterology/</guid>
      <description>Trans-biobank Mendelian randomization analyses identify opposing pathways in plasma low-density lipoprotein-cholesterol lowering and gallstone disease
Authors: Yang, G.; Mason, A.; Gill, D.; Schooling, C. M.; Burgess, S.
Score: 5.9, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23296205
Background: Plasma low-density lipoprotein (LDL)-cholesterol is positively associated with coronary artery disease risk while biliary cholesterol promotes gallstone formation. Objectives: We tested the hypothesis that different plasma LDL-cholesterol lowering pathways have distinct effects on biliary cholesterol and thereby risk of gallstone disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetic and genomic medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetic-and-genomic-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Distinct explanations underlie gene-environment interactions in the UK Biobank
Authors: Durvasula, A.; Price, A.
Score: 23.2, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295969
The role of gene-environment (GxE) interaction in disease and complex trait architectures is widely hypothesized, but currently unknown. Here, we apply three statistical approaches to quantify and distinguish three different types of GxE interaction for a given disease/trait and E variable. First, we detect locus-specific GxE interaction by testing for genetic correlation (rg) &amp;lt; 1 across E bins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genetics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genetics/</guid>
      <description>Natural selection drives emergent genetic homogeneity in a century-scale experiment with barley
Authors: Landis, J. B.; Guercio, A. M.; Brown, K. E.; Fiscus, C. J.; Morrell, P. L.; Koenig, D.
Score: 29.1, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.557807
Direct observation is central to our understanding of the process of adaptation, but evolution is rarely documented in a large, multicellular organism for more than a few generations. Here, we observe genetic and phenotypic evolution across a century-scale competition experiment, barley composite cross II (CCII).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>genomics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/genomics/</guid>
      <description>The European Reference Genome Atlas: piloting a decentralised approach to equitable biodiversity genomics
Authors: Mc Cartney, A. M.; Formenti, G.; Mouton, A.; De Panis, D.; Marins, L. S.; Leitao, H. G.; Diedericks, G.; Kirangwa, J.; Morselli, M.; Salces, J.; Escudero, N.; Iannucci, A.; Natali, C.; Svardal, H.; Fernandez, R.; De Pooter, T.; Joris, G.; Strazisar, M.; Wood, J.; Herron, K. E.; Seehausen, O.; Watts, P. C.; Shaw, F.; Davey, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health informatics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-informatics/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating AI in Clinical Practice: A Scoping Evaluation
Authors: Han, R.; Acosta, J. N.; Shakeri, Z.; Ioannidis, J.; Topol, E.; Rajpurkar, P.
Score: 93.2, Published: 2023-09-13 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.12.23295381
BackgroundArtificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a promising tool in healthcare, with numerous studies indicating its potential to perform as well or better than clinicians. However, a considerable portion of these AI models have only been tested retrospectively, raising concerns about their true effectiveness and potential risks in real-world clinical settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>health systems and quality improvement</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/health-systems-and-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare system barriers impacting the care of Canadians with myalgic encephalomyelitis: a scoping review
Authors: Hussein, S.; Eiriksson, L.; MacQuarrie, M.; Merriam, S.; Dalton, M.; Stein, E.; Twomey, R.
Score: 41.8, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295809
BackgroundMyalgic encephalomyelitis (ME, also known as chronic fatigue syndrome or ME/CFS) is a debilitating, complex, multi-system illness. Developing a comprehensive understanding of the multiple and interconnected barriers to optimal care will help advance strategies and care models to improve quality of life for people living with ME in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiv aids</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/hiv-aids/</guid>
      <description>HIV incidence among non-migrating persons following a household migration event: a population-based, longitudinal study in Uganda
Authors: Young, R.; Ssekasanvu, J.; Kagaayi, J.; Ssekubugu, R.; Kigozi, G.; Reynolds, S. J.; Wawer, M. J.; Nonyane, B. A. S.; Nantume, B.; Quinn, T. C.; Tobian, A. A. R.; Santelli, J.; Chang, L. W.; Kennedy, C. E.; Paina, L.; Anglewicz, P. A.; Serwadda, D.; Nalugoda, F.; Grabowski, M. K.
Score: 2.1, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>immunology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/immunology/</guid>
      <description>Immune Correlates of Hyperglycemia and Vaccination in a Non-human Primate Model of Long-COVID
Authors: Palmer, C. S.; Perdios, C.; Abdel-Mohsen, M.; Mudd, J.; Datta, P.; Maness, N.; Lehmicke, G.; Golden, N.; Hellmer, L.; Coyne, C.; Moore Green, K.; Midkiff, C.; Williams, K.; Tiburcio, R.; Fahlberg, M.; Boykin, K.; Kenway, C.; Russell-Lodrigue, K.; Bohm, R.; Blair, R. V.; Dufour, J.; Fischer, T.; Saied, A.; Rappaport, J.
Score: 57.5, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infectious diseases</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/infectious-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Vaccine Effectiveness Against Long COVID in Children: A Report from the RECOVER EHR Cohort
Authors: Razzaghi, H.; Forrest, C.; Hirabayshi, K.; Wu, Q.; Allen, A.; Rao, S.; Chen, Y.; Bunnell, T.; Chrischilles, E. A.; Cowell, L. G.; Cummins, M. R.; Hanauer, D. A.; Higginbotham, M. J.; Horne, B.; Horowitz, C. R.; Jhaveri, R.; Kim, S.; Mishkin, A.; Muszynski, J.; Naggie, S.; Pajor, N. M.; Paranjape, A.; Schwenk, H. T.; Sills, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>intensive care and critical care medicine</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/intensive-care-and-critical-care-medicine/</guid>
      <description>A Phase 2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multi-center trial sub-study for the clinical effects of paridiprubart treatment in hospitalized critically ill patients with COVID-19 ARDS
Authors: Gordon, B.; Allum, F.; Brooks, M.; Rajakulendran, N.; Rampakakis, E.; Sampalis, J.; EB05 Study Investigators, Score: 248.6, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.21.23295853
Background: Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) mortality is predominantly due to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). There are currently limited treatment options for ARDS, a life-threatening condition with different etiologies, secondary to inflammation-induced lung injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microbiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/microbiology/</guid>
      <description>Antigenicity and receptor affinity of SARS-CoV-2 BA.2.86 spike
Authors: Wang, Q.; Guo, Y.; Liu, L.; Schwanz, L. T.; Li, Z.; Ho, J.; Zhang, R. M.; Iketani, S.; Yu, J.; Huang, Y.; Qu, Y.; Valdez, R.; Lauring, A. S.; Gordon, A.; Wang, H. H.; Liu, L.; Ho, D. D.
Score: 158.7, Published: 2023-09-27 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.559214
Although the COVID-19 pandemic has officially ended1, SARS-CoV-2 continues to spread and evolve. Recent infections have been dominated by XBB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>molecular biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/molecular-biology/</guid>
      <description>Inhibiting Glutamine Metabolism Blocks Coronavirus Replication in Mammalian Cells
Authors: Greene, K. S.; Choi, A.; Chen, M.; Yang, N.; Li, R.; Qiu, Y.; Lukey, M. J.; Rojas, K. S.; Shen, J.; Wilson, K. F.; Katt, W. P.; Whittaker, G. R.; Cerione, R. A.
Score: 24.6, Published: 2023-09-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.559756
Developing therapeutic strategies against COVID-19 has gained widespread interest given the likelihood that new viral variants will continue to emerge. Here we describe one potential therapeutic strategy which involves targeting members of the glutaminase family of mitochondrial metabolic enzymes (GLS and GLS2), which catalyze the first step in glutamine metabolism, the hydrolysis of glutamine to glutamate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nephrology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nephrology/</guid>
      <description>The National Registry of Rare Kidney Diseases (RaDaR): design, recruitment, and cross-sectional analyses of 25,880 adults and children with rare kidney diseases in the UK
Authors: Wong, K.; Pitcher, D.; Braddon, F.; Downward, L.; Steenkamp, R.; Annear, N.; Barratt, J.; Bingham, C.; Coward, R. J.; Chrysochou, T.; Game, D.; Griffin, S.; Hall, M.; Johnson, S.; Kanigicherla, D.; Karet Frankl, F.; Kavanagh, D.; Kerecuk, L.; Maher, E. R.; Moochhala, S.; Pinney, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neurology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neurology/</guid>
      <description>Striatal dopamine tone is positively associated with body mass index in humans as determined by PET using dual dopamine type-2 receptor antagonist tracers
Authors: Darcey, V. L.; Guo, J.; Chi, M.; Chung, S. T.; Courville, A. B.; Gallagher, I.; Herscovitch, P.; Howard, R.; La Noire, M.; Milley, L.; Schick, A.; Stagliano, M.; Turner, S.; Urbanski, N.; Yang, S.; Yim, E.; Zhai, N.; Zhou, M. S.; Hall, K. D.
Score: 43.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neurological Imprints of Boys&amp;#39; Love Culture: Shaping Sexual Orientation Identity in the Digital Age&amp;#39;s Young females
Authors: Yanan, C.; Na, A.; Xiaowei, J.; Yingying, C.; Huihui, N.; Shuoyan, H.
Score: 575.7, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558088
With the omnipresence of social media, Boys Love (BL) culture has found a burgeoning audience among young females. While this cultural phenomenon offers a platform for self-expression to some, its potential implications remain underexplored. This study investigates whether immersion in BL culture impacts the process of young females forming self-recognition and identification of sexual orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Are children with disabilities more likely to be malnourished than children without disabilities? Evidence from the Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys in 30 countries
Authors: Rotenberg, S.; Chen, S.; Hunt, X.; Smythe, T.; Kuper, H.
Score: 4.7, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.25.23296066
IntroductionA key Sustainable Development Goal target is to eliminate all forms of malnutrition. Existing evidence suggests children with disabilities are at greater risks of malnutrition, exclusion from nutrition programmes, and mortality from severe acute malnutrition than children without disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oncology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/oncology/</guid>
      <description>Comparative analysis of the spatial distribution of brain metastases across several primary cancers using machine learning and deep learning models
Authors: Mahmoodifar, S.; Pangal, D. J.; Mason, J.; Salhia, B.; Neman, J.; Zada, G.; Newton, P. K.
Score: 5.1, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.19.23295748
ObjectiveBrain metastases (BM) are associated with poor prognosis and increased mortality rates, making them a significant clinical challenge. Therefore, studying BMs can aid in developing better diagnostic tools for their early detection and monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ophthalmology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/ophthalmology/</guid>
      <description>Cost-Benefit Analysis for Universal Cataract Coverage in India for 2018
Authors: Arora, A.; Zadey, S.; Vuddemarry, M.; Iyer, H.; Nimkar, P.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.24.23296031
ImportanceCataract is the leading cause of curable blindness in India needing scale-up of coverage. However, the costs and benefits of such scale-up remain unknown. ObjectiveTo calculate the annual scale-up costs, economic benefits of disease burden averted, and the net benefits of covering cataract needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paleontology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/paleontology/</guid>
      <description>Life in a Central European warm-temperate to subtropical open forest: paleoecology of the rhinocerotids from Ulm-Westtangente (Aquitanian, early Miocene, Germany)
Authors: Hullot, M.; Martin, C.; Blondel, C.; Roessner, G.
Score: 4.2, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.558985
The locality of Ulm-Westtangente yielded the richest vertebrate fauna from the Aquitanian (23.03 to 20.44 Mya; early Miocene) of Germany. Its dating to the Mammal Neogene Zone 2a, a turnover in Cenozoic climate, makes it a crucial source for the understanding of faunal, palaeoecological and palaeoenvironmental specifics of the European Aquitanian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pathology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pathology/</guid>
      <description>Obesity-elicited macrophages shape CD9hi progenitor fate to promote adipose tissue fibrosis and dysfunction
Authors: Askia, H.; Dussaud, S.; Chaves de Oliveira, M.; Oliveira, A.; Poupel, L.; Rebiere, C.; Ouhachi, M.; Manuel, R.; Merabtene, F.; Genser, L.; Aron-Wisnewsky, J.; Moreau, M.; Yvan-Charvet, L.; Ferreira, A.; Huby, T.; Clement, K.; Marcelin, G.; Gautier, E.
Score: 1.5, Published: 2023-09-28 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.559540
Obesity is a life-threatening condition characterized by a maladaptive remodeling of the visceral white adipose tissue (vWAT), including fibrosis, that drives vWAT metabolic alterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pediatrics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pediatrics/</guid>
      <description>Corpus callosum abnormalities at term-equivalent age are associated with language development at two years corrected age in infants born very preterm
Authors: Kojima, K.; Kline, J. E.; Altaye, M.; Kline Fath, B. M.; Parikh, N. A.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-22 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.23295848
We studied the impact of microstructural abnormalities in the corpus callosum on language development in 348 infants born very prematurely. We discovered that the fractional anisotropy of the corpus callosum anterior midbody was a significant predictor of standardized language scores at two years, independent of clinical and social risk factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-therapeutics/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the effects of Dasatinib, Quercetin, and Fisetin on DNA methylation clocks: a longitudinal study on senolytic interventions
Authors: Lee, E.; Carreras-Gallo, N.; Lopez, L.; Turner, L.; Lin, A.; Mendez, T. L.; Went, H.; Tomusiak, A.; Verdin, E.; Corley, M.; Ndhlovu, L.; Smith, R.; Dwaraka, V. B.
Score: 1.0, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295961
Senolytics, small molecules targeting cellular senescence, have emerged as potential therapeutics to enhance health span. However, their impact on epigenetic age remains unstudied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pharmacology and toxicology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/pharmacology-and-toxicology/</guid>
      <description>Self-supervised deep learning uncovers the semantic landscape of drug-induced latent mitochondrial phenotypes
Authors: Natekar, P.; Wang, Z.; Arora, M.; Hakozaki, H.; Schoeneberg, J.
Score: 77.7, Published: 2023-09-14 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557636
Imaging-based high-content screening aims to identify substances that modulate cellular phenotypes. Traditional approaches screen compounds for their ability to shift disease phenotypes toward healthy phenotypes, but these end point-based screens lack an atlas-like mapping between phenotype and cell state that covers the full spectrum of possible phenotypic responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>physiology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/physiology/</guid>
      <description>Lifelong dietary protein restriction accelerates skeletal muscle loss and reduces muscle fibre size by impairing proteostasis and mitochondrial homeostasis
Authors: Ersoy, U.; Kanakis, I.; Alameddine, M.; Pedraza Vazquez, G.; E. Ozanne, S.; Peffers, M. J.; Jackson, M. J.; Goljanek-Whysall, K.; Vasilaki, A.
Score: 13.9, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.559536
The early life environment significantly affects the development of age-related skeletal muscle disorders. However, the long-term effects of lactational protein restriction on skeletal muscle are still poorly defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/plant-biology/</guid>
      <description>Near-infrared imaging of phytochrome-derived autofluorescence in plant nuclei
Authors: Yoshinari, A.; Isoda, R.; Yagi, N.; Sato, Y.; Lindeboom, J. J.; Ehrhardt, D. W.; Frommer, W. B.; Nakamura, M.
Score: 25.0, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.18.558255
Capturing images of the nuclear dynamics within live cells is an essential technique for comprehending the intricate biological processes inherent to plant cell nuclei. While various methods exist for imaging nuclei, including combining fluorescent proteins and dyes with microscopy, there is a dearth of commercially available dyes for live-cell imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>primary care research</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/primary-care-research/</guid>
      <description>Development and validation of the Japanese version of the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Development of Clinical Skills Scale
Authors: Kanakubo, Y.; Sugiyama, Y.; Yoshida, E.; Aoki, T.; Mutai, R.; Matsushima, M.; Okada, T.
Score: 1.1, Published: 2023-09-26 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.26.23296058
IntroductionThe Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Development of Clinical Skills Scale (LGBT-DOCSS) is a validated self-assessment tool for health and mental health professionals who provide care for sexual and gender minority patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psychiatry and clinical psychology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/psychiatry-and-clinical-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation conditions increased invigoration and wanting in depression
Authors: Ferstl, M. S.; Kuehnel, A.; Klaus, J.; Lin, W. M.; Kroemer, N. B.
Score: 15.2, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.28.23296284
Background: Major depressive disorder (MDD) is often marked by impaired motivation and reward processing, known as anhedonia. Many patients do not respond to first-line treatments, and improvements in motivation can be slow, creating an urgent need for rapid interventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>public and global health</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/public-and-global-health/</guid>
      <description>Association of Cognitive Deficits with Sociodemographic Characteristics among Adults with Post-COVID Conditions: Findings from the United States Household Pulse Survey
Authors: Wu, D. J.; Liu, N.
Score: 59.5, Published: 2023-09-25 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23295981
BackgroundPeople infected with COVID-19 may continue to experience symptoms for several weeks or even months after acute infection, a condition known as long COVID. Cognitive problems such as memory loss are among the most commonly reported symptoms of long COVID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>radiology and imaging</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/radiology-and-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Radiomic-Based Prediction of Lesion-Specific Systemic Treatment Response in Metastatic Disease
Authors: Geady, C.; Abbas-Aghababazadeh, F.; Kohan, A.; Schuetze, S.; Shultz, D.; Haibe-Kains, B.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-23 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.22.23294942
Despite sharing the same histologic classification, individual tumors in multi metastatic patients may present with different characteristics and varying sensitivities to anticancer therapies. In this study, we investigate the utility of radiomic biomarkers for prediction of lesion-specific treatment resistance in multi metastatic leiomyosarcoma patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rehabilitation medicine and physical therapy</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/rehabilitation-medicine-and-physical-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Effects of Six Weeks of Supervised Telerehabilitation on Pulmonary Function, Functional Capacity, and Dyspnoea among individuals with Long COVID
Authors: Al Mheiri, A.; Girish, S.; Amaravadi, S. K.
Score: 1.2, Published: 2023-09-29 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.27.23296254
Background: Long COVID, characterized by persistent symptoms post-COVID-19, presents challenges like reduced functional capacity, pulmonary function, and dyspnea. Telerehabilitation, a remote healthcare approach, is gaining attention for its potential to address these issues Objectives: The study aims to determine the effect of telerehabilitation on functional capacity by six-minute walk test (MWT), pulmonary function by pulmonary function test (PFT), dyspnea by modified medical research council (mMRC) and level of physical activity by Global physical activity questionnaire (GPAQ) in individuals with long COVID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientific communication and education</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/scientific-communication-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Controlled experiment finds no detectable citation bump from Twitter promotion
Authors: Branch, T.; C?te, I. M.; David, S. R.; Drew, J. A.; LaRue, M.; Marquez, M. C.; Parsons, E. C. M.; Rabaiotti, D.; Shiffman, D.; Steen, D. A.; Wild, A. L.
Score: 227.5, Published: 2023-09-18 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.17.558161
Multiple studies across a variety of scientific disciplines have shown that the number of times that a paper is shared on Twitter (now called X) is correlated with the number of citations that paper receives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synthetic biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/synthetic-biology/</guid>
      <description>Computational design of sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins
Authors: Glasscock, C. J.; Pecoraro, R.; McHugh, R.; Doyle, L. A.; Chen, W.; Boivin, O.; Lonnquist, B.; Na, E.; Politanska, Y.; Haddox, H. K.; Cox, D.; Norn, C.; Coventry, B.; Goreshnik, I.; Vafeados, D.; Lee, G. R.; Gordan, R.; Stoddard, B. L.; DiMaio, F.; Baker, D.
Score: 189.9, Published: 2023-09-21 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.20.558720
Sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins (DBPs) play critical roles in biology and biotechnology, and there has been considerable interest in the engineering of DBPs with new or altered specificities for genome editing and other applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systems biology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/systems-biology/</guid>
      <description>Multi-SNP combination genome-scale metabolic models identify molecular mechanisms determining genetic interactions in a quantitative trait
Authors: Sasikumar, S.; S, P. K.; Bhatt, N.; Sinha, H.
Score: 11.7, Published: 2023-09-20 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.13.557398
Elucidating genotype-phenotype or variant-to-function relationships remains a pivotal challenge in genetics. Specifically, understanding how genetic interactions among causal quantitative trait nucleotides (QTNs) drive phenotypic variation remains to be determined. Employing genome-scale metabolic modelling, we analysed the metabolic consequences of four causal QTNs, individually and in all combinations, responsible for modulating sporulation efficiency in yeast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zoology</title>
      <link>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trxiv.yorks0n.com/posts/zoology/</guid>
      <description>Heat Tolerance is Affected by the Gut Microbiota in a Vertebrate Ectotherm
Authors: Dallas, J. W.; Kazarina, A.; Lee, S. T. M.; Warne, R. W.
Score: 24.4, Published: 2023-09-07 DOI: 10.1101/2023.09.07.556683
The gut microbiota is known to influence and have regulatory effects in diverse physiological functions of host animals, but only recently has the relationship between host thermal biology and gut microbiota been explored. Here, we examined how early-life manipulations of the gut microbiota in larval amphibians influenced their critical thermal maximum (CTmax) at different acclimation temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
